<doc>
  <docmeta id="113hres513ih">
    <bill congress="113" type="hres" number="513" version="ih"/>
    <revision size="3518" annotations="0" status="complete" id="4" commit-time="2014-07-07T03:12:57Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113hres513ih/4.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <resolution xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" dms-id="HF038E4D9DA9545349E23E64A2B9FCBE5" key="H" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print">
	<metadata>
<dublinCore>
<dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">113 HRES 513 IH: Supporting the goals and ideals of the week of May 3, 2014, through May 10, 2014, as “National Osteogenesis Imperfecta Awareness Week” to celebrate the progress made, and recognize the work yet to be done toward educating our communities, promoting research programs and raising vital resources for doctors, nurses, and healthcare providers and everyone touched by the Osteogenesis Imperfecta community.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">2014-03-11</dc:date>
<dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">113th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session display="yes">2d Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. RES. 513</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20140311">March 11, 2014</action-date>
			<action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="R000576">Mr. Ruppersberger</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>
      </action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">Supporting the goals and ideals of the week of May 3, 2014, through May 10, 2014, as <quote>National Osteogenesis Imperfecta Awareness Week</quote> to celebrate the progress made, and recognize the work yet to be done toward educating our
			 communities, promoting research programs and raising vital resources for
			 doctors, nurses, and healthcare providers and everyone touched by the
			 Osteogenesis Imperfecta community.</official-title>
	</form>
	<preamble>
		<whereas>
      <text>Whereas Osteogenesis Imperfecta (OI), also known as <quote>brittle bone disease</quote> is a genetic disorder characterized by fragile bones that break easily;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the number of people in the United States affected with OI is estimated to be 25,000 to
			 50,000;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas a person with mild OI may experience a few fractures while those with the severe forms may
			 have hundreds in a lifetime;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas OI occurs with equal frequency among males and females and among all racial and ethnic
			 groups;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas at this time, there is no cure;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas it is thought that OI causes many other serious chronic medical conditions such as muscle
			 weakness, joint laxity, fragile skin, hearing loss, brittle teeth,
			 fatigue, easy bleeding and bruising, scoliosis, pulmonary disease, and
			 cardiovascular disease;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas experienced medical care for OI is limited;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas a person is born with this disorder and is affected throughout his or her lifetime;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas despite the challenges of managing OI, most adults and children who have OI lead productive
			 and successful lives; and</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas May 3, 2014, through May 10, 2014, has been designated by the Osteogenesis Imperfecta
			 Foundation as <quote>National Osteogenesis Imperfecta Awareness Week</quote>: Now, therefore, be it</text>
    </whereas>
  </preamble>
	<resolution-body id="H771391C3721F494992CF0A52EF5FCD9C" style="traditional">
		<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HBA708177DF774192941A0D6BAB19AFA8" section-type="undesignated-section">
      <enum/>
      <text>That the <cato:entity-ref entity-id="0050" entity-type="federal-body">House of Representatives</cato:entity-ref>—</text>
			<paragraph id="HF4A0F406B0854D7888141A9F1E250140">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">supports—</text>
				<subparagraph id="H6472C24FF85046DDA6F9E59589D3DE0F">
          <enum>(A)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the goals and ideals of <quote>National Osteogenesis Imperfecta Awareness Week</quote>;</text>
				</subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="HC0297ABEA34544FB986FB9A22AF9E9E8">
          <enum>(B)</enum>
          <text>efforts to educate the people in the United States about Osteogenesis Imperfecta;</text>
				</subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="H9EAC342F6D87410F818AE955A1597E53">
          <enum>(C)</enum>
          <text>efforts to promote research; and</text>
				</subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="HD0A75444C0D74E6FA7AA3A6AC10A2AE6">
          <enum>(D)</enum>
          <text>efforts in raising vital resources for doctors, nurses, and health care providers;</text>
				</subparagraph>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H6E4A5A2727E44EE6B8ADDA4AC7A80F19">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text>recognizes the critical importance of these goals and efforts as part of wellness strategies; and</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H8C10C52B404A4E8BB6C16857E324DC52">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <text>calls on the people of the United States to observe <quote>National Osteogenesis Imperfecta Awareness Week</quote> with appropriate programs and activities.</text>
			</paragraph>
    </section>
  </resolution-body>
</resolution>
</doc>