<doc>
  <docmeta id="113hr3571ih">
    <bill congress="113" type="hr" number="3571" version="ih"/>
    <revision size="28962" annotations="0" status="complete" id="6" commit-time="2013-12-04T23:06:23Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113hr3571ih/6.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H4C6FB44641B24A11AE06B26CE7203180" public-private="public">
  <metadata>
<dublinCore>
<dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">113 HR 3571 IH: International Violence Against Women Act of 2013</dc:title>
<dc:publisher xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">2013-11-21</dc:date>
<dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
    <congress>113th CONGRESS</congress>
    <session>1st Session</session>
    <legis-num>H. R. 3571</legis-num>
    <current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
    <action>
      <action-date date="20131121">November 21, 2013</action-date>
      <action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="S001145">Ms. Schakowsky</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="L000480">Mrs. Lowey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000179">Mr. Engel</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000797">Ms. Wasserman Schultz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001051">Mr. Hanna</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="G000564">Mr. Gibson</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name>
      </action-desc>
    </action>
    <legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
    <official-title>To prevent international violence against women, and for other purposes.</official-title>
  </form>
  <legis-body id="HE1109C6042704F059883AA32FC3E95F3" style="OLC">
    <section id="HDE3375C7B4BE45BCAA68F79582F30BDF" section-type="section-one">
      <enum>1.</enum>
      <header>Short title</header>
      <subsection id="H8ADA0F8FDDF8401C871CE7562120253E">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Short title</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote>
            <short-title>International Violence Against Women Act of 2013</short-title>
          </quote>.</text>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="H35016980A103466C9C572A7F79739B2A">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Table of contents</header>
        <text>The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text>
        <toc>
          <toc-entry idref="HDE3375C7B4BE45BCAA68F79582F30BDF" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title.</toc-entry>
          <toc-entry idref="H427B2C4C900E4A449E41DFCB71AE0B0D" level="section">Sec. 2. Findings.</toc-entry>
          <toc-entry idref="H564397460861423BB9AFB9EB5FBDA087" level="section">Sec. 3. Statement of policy.</toc-entry>
          <toc-entry idref="H390CAE9B811643738DD23B03D88B4A2C" level="title">TITLE I—International prevention of violence against women and girls</toc-entry>
          <toc-entry idref="HA43A2106CB2240269EFA910CEFA3D493" level="subtitle">Subtitle A—Official designations and institutional changes</toc-entry>
          <toc-entry idref="HA7138A1105E049FEA65651EF69330334" level="section">Sec. 101. Office for global women’s issues.</toc-entry>
          <toc-entry idref="H3E58F33CCCDE4AA58BA816A4E860E2EB" level="section">Sec. 102. Senior coordinator for gender equality and women’s empowerment.</toc-entry>
          <toc-entry idref="H5EE65BB78204485C9830CE466F7091CB" level="section">Sec. 103. Briefing.</toc-entry>
          <toc-entry idref="H25B7331D246D485B84F68EC02FE0ACB3" level="subtitle">Subtitle B—Strategy, policy, and programs</toc-entry>
          <toc-entry idref="HED0D53EF6E8949E09656EB12777B0B45" level="section">Sec. 111. United States strategy to prevent and respond to gender-based violence globally.</toc-entry>
          <toc-entry idref="HBDA36EEA5494457BB95746088FFB2906" level="section">Sec. 112. Implementation of the United States strategy to prevent and respond to gender-based violence globally.</toc-entry>
          <toc-entry idref="H29AD2557C9104B3F8D49DB203B666DC6" level="section">Sec. 113. Monitoring the United States strategy to prevent and respond to gender-based violence globally.</toc-entry>
        </toc>
      </subsection>
    </section>
    <section id="H427B2C4C900E4A449E41DFCB71AE0B0D">
      <enum>2.</enum>
      <header>Findings</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">
        <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> makes the following findings:</text>
      <paragraph id="HFC7070B3F1E34EEABBDC700E3540D329">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text>An estimated 1 out of every 3 women throughout the world will be beaten, coerced into sex, or otherwise abused in her lifetime.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H27A4BD01D5D74723A80625B6DFB8C13D">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text>Up to 70 percent of women in some countries report having been victims of domestic violence at some stage in their lives.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H6532A744833142E3B3BE18B0AA8FB2BC">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <text>Sexual violence among adolescents and pre-adolescents is alarmingly high. In 2010, the first nationally representative survey of violence against children in Tanzania found that nearly 3 in 10 females and 1 in 7 males experienced sexual violence prior to the age of 18.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H5B3722CEFEB14621AAD9AC04FDDA5687">
        <enum>(4)</enum>
        <text>The International Men and Gender Equality Survey dataset shows that adult male respondents in 6 countries who had experienced violence as children were significantly more likely to report perpetrating intimate partner violence themselves than their peers who did not experience violence as children.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H4C433D010FC04530BBA4F01141531382">
        <enum>(5)</enum>
        <text>Violence against women and girls impedes progress in meeting many United States global development goals, including efforts to stem maternal mortality and the spread of HIV/AIDS. Approximately 1 in 4 women are abused during pregnancy which has been linked to miscarriage, pre-term labor, low birth weight, fetal distress, and death.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H106E1EB890AB4A4D8E5B6244F4F7D9F2">
        <enum>(6)</enum>
        <text>Country studies indicate that the risk of HIV among women who have experienced violence may be up to 3 times higher than among those who have not. Women who have experienced violence are also at higher risk for contracting HIV, and women living with HIV may be up to 3 times more likely to experience violence than other women. Fear of violence also prevents women from accessing HIV/AIDS information and receiving treatment and counseling.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H51DAD8B763574F1393C6B9BE058B3CF1">
        <enum>(7)</enum>
        <text>The President’s Emergency Plan for AIDS Relief (PEPFAR) supports significant work in the field to mainstream gender-based violence into existing HIV programs. Addressing gender norms and inequities is essential to reducing HIV risk and increasing access to HIV prevention, care and treatment services for women and men.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HA789DA9A52D94AAD86017EBADAC19B82">
        <enum>(8)</enum>
        <text>Increasing women's access to economic opportunities and food security is crucial to preventing and responding to domestic and sexual violence. Inclusive finance and micro-enterprise reduce levels of intimate partner violence and provide economic independence for survivors.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H3170275AECF84DB2A04BA4C7026559DC">
        <enum>(9)</enum>
        <text>Prevalence of sexual violence is higher among persons with disabilities, particularly for adolescents and intimate partners with disabilities, and for men and women with intellectual impairments living in institutions.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HC0EEF73260A643A8A21CA4AA057F8D12">
        <enum>(10)</enum>
        <text>Displaced, refugee, and stateless women and girls in humanitarian emergencies, conflict settings, and natural disasters face extreme violence and threats, including—</text>
        <subparagraph id="HF4ABA84EB06E4D84A3229CB05FB536F7">
          <enum>(A)</enum>
          <text>being forced to exchange sex for food and humanitarian supplies; and</text>
        </subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="H7AA47AC8C44549ACBAA693A6B670040D">
          <enum>(B)</enum>
          <text>being at increased risk of rape, sexual exploitation, and abuse.</text>
        </subparagraph>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HC358C1805FAB46E9BED2AFC704CF8A8F">
        <enum>(11)</enum>
        <text>Rape and sexual assault against women and girls are used to torture, intimidate, and terrorize women and their communities.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H98E5AF2E94AD47C392A522CEAE65C9CD">
        <enum>(12)</enum>
        <text>Early and forced marriage of the girl-child—</text>
        <subparagraph id="H9C43B37F01054437BC959B64053916E8">
          <enum>(A)</enum>
          <text>is a violation of human rights as it denies girls the right to decide when and with whom to marry;</text>
        </subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="HBB485173FE2A45A7A129EE36CA96E9BB">
          <enum>(B)</enum>
          <text>is a harmful practice that deprives girls of their dignity, bringing childhood and adolescence to a premature and unnatural end;</text>
        </subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="H5631E34AEA1845B189AFD1C502D6E7FE">
          <enum>(C)</enum>
          <text>can end girls’ education and can result in bonded labor or enslavement, commercial sexual exploitation, and violence against the victims;</text>
        </subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="H4DD7544A122C4DD4ABD1AB32E998410E">
          <enum>(D)</enum>
          <text>significantly increases the risk of maternal death and morbidity, infant mortality and morbidity, obstetric fistula, and sexually  transmitted diseases, including HIV/AIDS; and</text>
        </subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="H93A45F95B76F4136863E5306009532D0">
          <enum>(E)</enum>
          <text>is perpetuated by poverty, a lack of educational or employment opportunities for girls, parental concerns to ensure sexual relations within marriage, the dowry system, and the perceived lack of value of girls.</text>
        </subparagraph>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HEA279949E93E4F6B944662160E4D1160">
        <enum>(13)</enum>
        <text>World Bank data shows that gender inequality directly corresponds to increased levels of political and economic instability within states.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H3DA2171AF1BE4D56A4204067334206AD">
        <enum>(14)</enum>
        <text>Domestic violence is the most prevalent form of violence against women and prevents women from playing more active roles in the social, economic, and political development of their communities. In humanitarian crises, this global scourge becomes acute, preventing women from helping to rebuild their countries.</text>
      </paragraph>
    </section>
    <section id="H564397460861423BB9AFB9EB5FBDA087">
      <enum>3.</enum>
      <header>Statement of policy</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the policy of the United States—</text>
      <paragraph id="H22935ED582624466927F162E0A49025C">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text>to take effective action to prevent and respond to violence against women and girls around the world, as a matter of basic human rights as well as to promote gender equality, economic growth, and improved public health;</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H8757BB30FC19435790AA191C910F1686">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text>to systematically integrate and coordinate efforts to prevent and respond to violence against women and girls internationally into United States foreign policy and foreign assistance programs, including peacebuilding efforts and humanitarian relief and recovery;</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H48EED8ED08264345A1BC0B2F0F4E64B9">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <text>to support and build local capacity in developing countries, including of governments at all levels and nongovernmental organizations, especially women-led organizations, to prevent and respond to violence against women and girls;</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H4242193517664DA785D3D6E94193B313">
        <enum>(4)</enum>
        <text>to consult, cooperate, coordinate, and collaborate with a wide variety of nongovernmental partners with demonstrated experience in preventing and responding to violence against women and girls, including faith-based organizations and women-led organizations;</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H7BCFDE72BB91404EAA86084F1390CEC7">
        <enum>(5)</enum>
        <text>to employ a multisectoral approach to preventing and responding to violence against women and girls internationally, including activities in the economic, education, health, nutrition, legal, and judicial sectors;</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H795F7622E60A4989A585E5A0CF097AB8">
        <enum>(6)</enum>
        <text>to work at all levels, from the individual to the family, community, local, national and international levels, to prevent and respond to violence against women and girls around the globe;</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H7C35C570481243CAB0DD83D87104DA1C">
        <enum>(7)</enum>
        <text>to enhance training by United States personnel of professional foreign military and police forces and judicial officials to include specific and thorough instruction on preventing and responding to violence against women and girls around the world;</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H42FD5F8307684FDF9B12197992F61B13">
        <enum>(8)</enum>
        <text>to engage men and boys as partners, as an essential element of making sustained reductions in violence against women and girls;</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H0B93C589B56944E6BAD458E8DE54783E">
        <enum>(9)</enum>
        <text>to include the prevention of early and forced marriage as an important part of United States Government efforts to prevent violence against girls and promote gender equality and global health;</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H617D220EAEF7498FBC12493EACB34D73">
        <enum>(10)</enum>
        <text>to require that all United States contractors and grantees establish appropriate policies and take effective measures to prevent violence against women and girls and sexual exploitation and abuse within their workforce;</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HCB4B02B4F44F4D048489E520A84B3770">
        <enum>(11)</enum>
        <text>to exert sustained international leadership to prevent and respond to violence against women and girls, including in bilateral and multilateral fora;</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H840E20281CB2435498D8C4E4D4EE91CC">
        <enum>(12)</enum>
        <text>to implement the United States Strategy to Prevent and Respond to Gender-based Violence Globally; and</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H323E2EB5D2884EF48753290DD527DBD5">
        <enum>(13)</enum>
        <text>to implement the United States National Action Plan on Women, Peace and Security.</text>
      </paragraph>
    </section>
    <title id="H390CAE9B811643738DD23B03D88B4A2C">
      <enum>I</enum>
      <header>International prevention of violence against women and girls</header>
      <subtitle id="HA43A2106CB2240269EFA910CEFA3D493">
        <enum>A</enum>
        <header>Official designations and institutional changes</header>
        <section id="HA7138A1105E049FEA65651EF69330334">
          <enum>101.</enum>
          <header>Office of global women’s issues</header>
          <subsection id="HE4D3F6FB94A84AA1B094E111CADF8E16">
            <enum>(a)</enum>
            <header>Establishment</header>
            <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref> shall establish in the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="190S">Office of the Secretary of the Department of State</cato:entity-ref> an <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Office of Global Women’s Issues" entity-parent-id="190S" proposed="true">Office of Global Women’s Issues</cato:entity-ref> (in this section referred to as the <quote>Office</quote>). The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Office of Global Women’s Issues" entity-parent-id="190S" proposed="true">Office</cato:entity-ref> shall be headed by an <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Ambassador-at-Large for Global Women’s Issues" entity-parent-id="190S" proposed="true">Ambassador-at-Large for Global Women’s Issues</cato:entity-ref>, who shall be appointed by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref>, by and with the advice and consent of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0010">Senate</cato:entity-ref>. The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Ambassador-at-Large for Global Women’s Issues" entity-parent-id="190S" proposed="true">Ambassador-at-Large</cato:entity-ref> shall report directly to the Secretary and shall have the rank and status of Ambassador-at-Large.</text>
          </subsection>
          <subsection id="H9793109EDC3843EA8D48CCD5596BC4BE">
            <enum>(b)</enum>
            <header>Purpose</header>
            <text>In addition to the duties described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="International Violence Against Women Act of 2013/s:101/ss:c" proposed="true">subsection (c)</cato:entity-ref> and those duties determined by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Ambassador-at-Large for Global Women’s Issues" entity-parent-id="190S" proposed="true">Ambassador-at-Large</cato:entity-ref> shall coordinate efforts of the United States Government as directed by the Secretary regarding gender integration and advancing the status of women and girls in United States foreign policy.</text>
          </subsection>
          <subsection id="H39B6451F82D940C8963760FB77464F23">
            <enum>(c)</enum>
            <header>Duties</header>
            <paragraph id="H499690393CA24D899B37C8115DBF4C3E">
              <enum>(1)</enum>
              <header>In general</header>
              <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Ambassador-at-Large for Global Women’s Issues" entity-parent-id="190S" proposed="true">Ambassador-at-Large</cato:entity-ref>—</text>
              <subparagraph id="H394806B08D6D4C26B4D4E16E506110ED">
                <enum>(A)</enum>
                <text>shall direct activities, policies, programs, and funding relating to gender equality and the advancement of women and girls internationally, including those intended to prevent and respond to violence against women and girls, for all bureaus and offices of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Department of State</cato:entity-ref> and in the international programs of all other Federal agencies;</text>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="H3A084FEDF14B4FFBB5D60F3557BFE555">
                <enum>(B)</enum>
                <text>shall actively promote and advance the full integration of gender analysis into the programs, structures, processes, and capacities of all bureaus and offices of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Department of State</cato:entity-ref> and in the international programs of other Federal agencies;</text>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="H461D4F92C214470ABA1E63B9A06AA8D8">
                <enum>(C)</enum>
                <text>shall direct, as appropriate, United States Government resources to respond to needs for gender integration and empowerment of women in United States Government foreign policies and international programs, including to prevent and respond to violence against women and girls internationally;</text>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="HDA8BCD3FF431489EBBC378BE33CB8F52">
                <enum>(D)</enum>
                <text>may design, support, and implement activities regarding empowerment of women internationally, including for the prevention of and response to violence against women and girls internationally;</text>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="HFFB94BF0A81142CB9A7AFF2F8252D8C7">
                <enum>(E)</enum>
                <text>shall conduct regular consultation with civil society organizations working to prevent and respond to violence against women and girls internationally;</text>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="HFDD277C582DB46D696924DC1382AE8CF">
                <enum>(F)</enum>
                <text>shall ensure that programs, projects, and activities designed to prevent and respond to violence against women and girls internationally are subject to rigorous monitoring and evaluation, and that there is a uniform set of indicators and standards for such monitoring and evaluation that is used across all Federal agencies;</text>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="H72141352CEEF486EA41F4DB870AC2FFD">
                <enum>(G)</enum>
                <text>shall serve as the principal advisor to the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref> regarding gender equality, women’s empowerment, and violence against women and girls as a foreign policy matter; and</text>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="H92C4E8A8AA9F4BA58A7984B09ABBCD9D">
                <enum>(H)</enum>
                <text>is authorized to represent the United States in diplomatic and multilateral fora on matters relevant to the status of women and girls, including violence against women and girls internationally.</text>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="H578541BEDC134124B281079B02153991">
              <enum>(2)</enum>
              <header>Information sharing and transparency</header>
              <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref> shall establish in the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="190S">Office of the Secretary of the Department of State</cato:entity-ref> an <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Office of Global Women’s Issues" entity-parent-id="190S" proposed="true">Office of Global Women’s Issues</cato:entity-ref> (in this section referred to as the <quote>Office</quote>). The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Office of Global Women’s Issues" entity-parent-id="190S" proposed="true">Office</cato:entity-ref> shall be the central repository of data on all United States programs, projects, and activities that relate to prevention and response to violence against women and girls, and shall produce a full accounting of United States Government spending on such programs, projects, and activities.</text>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
        </section>
        <section id="H3E58F33CCCDE4AA58BA816A4E860E2EB">
          <enum>102.</enum>
          <header>Senior coordinator for gender equality and women’s empowerment</header>
          <subsection id="H5379A922326E436D8090806D6835E3EB">
            <enum>(a)</enum>
            <header>Establishment</header>
            <text>There is established in the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7200">United States Agency for International Development</cato:entity-ref> a <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Senior Coordinator for Gender Equality and Women’s Empowerment" entity-parent-id="7200" proposed="true">Senior Coordinator for Gender Equality and Women’s Empowerment</cato:entity-ref>, who shall report to the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7200">Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development</cato:entity-ref> and who shall conduct the activities of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7200">Administrator</cato:entity-ref> under this Act.</text>
          </subsection>
          <subsection id="H7096C54B07A943049153B7B094E3540A">
            <enum>(b)</enum>
            <header>In general</header>
            <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Senior Coordinator for Gender Equality and Women’s Empowerment" entity-parent-id="7200" proposed="true">Senior Coordinator for Gender Equality and Women’s Empowerment</cato:entity-ref>—</text>
            <paragraph id="H6E9613718A3346DA8B2B393ADC01A391">
              <enum>(1)</enum>
              <text>shall direct activities, policies, programs, and funding of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7200">United States Agency for International Development</cato:entity-ref> relating to gender equality and women’s empowerment, including those intended to prevent and respond to violence against women and girls;</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="HE8A4AB4941144AE79CB23C37B3E3981F">
              <enum>(2)</enum>
              <text>shall actively promote and advance the full integration of gender analysis into the programs, structures, processes, and capacities of all bureaus and offices of the Agency as dictated by the USAID Gender Equality and Female Empowerment Policy;</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="H4F2BDD5C98C24B749DA4E4C260A28906">
              <enum>(3)</enum>
              <text>shall direct Agency resources for gender equality and women’s empowerment, including to prevent and respond to violence against women and girls internationally;</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="H3879AA24888D4897827E9CC3266072C1">
              <enum>(4)</enum>
              <text>may design, support, and implement activities led by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7200">Agency</cato:entity-ref> regarding gender equality and women’s empowerment, including for the prevention and response of violence against women and girls internationally;</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="H21B37A0F46854A9DB8D0FD7711644E8C">
              <enum>(5)</enum>
              <text>shall conduct regular consultation with civil society organizations working to prevent and respond to violence against women and girls internationally;</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="HCEECEB8FBBA04A7F8464B8D36E79E246">
              <enum>(6)</enum>
              <text>shall serve as the principal advisor to the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7200">Administrator</cato:entity-ref> regarding gender equality, women's empowerment, and violence against women and girls; and</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="HF3129E5BFBA540F88484731504E0F68B">
              <enum>(7)</enum>
              <text>shall track and analyze monitoring and evaluation data and findings on international prevention and response programs of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7200">Agency</cato:entity-ref>, consistent with Agency-wide monitoring and evaluation activities, and in order to assist in the preparation of the comprehensive strategy developed under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="International Violence Against Women Act of 2013/s:111" proposed="true">section 111</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
        </section>
        <section id="H5EE65BB78204485C9830CE466F7091CB">
          <enum>103.</enum>
          <header>Briefing</header>
          <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Ambassador-at-Large for Global Women’s Issues" entity-parent-id="190S" proposed="true">Ambassador-at-Large</cato:entity-ref> and <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Senior Coordinator for Gender Equality and Women’s Empowerment" entity-parent-id="7200" proposed="true">Senior Coordinator</cato:entity-ref> shall brief the appropriate congressional committees on international violence against women and girls prevention and response strategies, programming, and associated outcomes, and shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees an assessment of human and financial resources necessary to fulfill the purposes and duties of this Act.</text>
        </section>
      </subtitle>
      <subtitle id="H25B7331D246D485B84F68EC02FE0ACB3">
        <enum>B</enum>
        <header>Strategy, policy, and programs</header>
        <section id="HED0D53EF6E8949E09656EB12777B0B45">
          <enum>111.</enum>
          <header>United States strategy to prevent and respond to gender-based violence globally</header>
          <subsection id="H88CB47C0B5AB463296B5160BD12987C6">
            <enum>(a)</enum>
            <header>Global strategy requirement</header>
            <text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter for five years, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Ambassador-at-Large for Global Women’s Issues" entity-parent-id="190S" proposed="true">Ambassador-at-Large</cato:entity-ref>, in consultation with the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Senior Coordinator for Gender Equality and Women’s Empowerment" entity-parent-id="7200" proposed="true">Senior Coordinator</cato:entity-ref>, shall develop or update a United States global strategy to prevent and respond to violence against women and girls. Such strategy shall be transmitted to the appropriate congressional committees and made publicly available on the Internet.</text>
          </subsection>
          <subsection id="HB05EE70232544847B19CE27176A6C97D">
            <enum>(b)</enum>
            <header>Initial strategy</header>
            <text>For the purposes of this section, the <quote>United States Strategy to Prevent and Respond to Gender-Based Violence Globally</quote>, issued in August 2012, shall be deemed to fulfill the initial requirement of <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="International Violence Against Women Act of 2013/s:111/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
          </subsection>
          <subsection id="HD27F029AA03A4DC8A5FC14F523BA2429">
            <enum>(c)</enum>
            <header>Implementation plan</header>
            <text>Not later than 60 days after submission of the strategy under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="International Violence Against Women Act of 2013/s:111/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Ambassador-at-Large for Global Women’s Issues" entity-parent-id="190S" proposed="true">Ambassador-at-Large</cato:entity-ref>, in consultation with the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Senior Coordinator for Gender Equality and Women’s Empowerment" entity-parent-id="7200" proposed="true">Senior Coordinator</cato:entity-ref>, shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees an implementation plan detailing how the strategy will be implemented in the upcoming five fiscal years, including the budget resources requested, and the specific activities to be supported, by each Executive agency under the strategy.</text>
          </subsection>
          <subsection id="H8B0902A90A004BFEB81C15970BD767D9">
            <enum>(d)</enum>
            <header>Collaboration and coordination</header>
            <text>In developing the strategy under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="International Violence Against Women Act of 2013/s:111/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Ambassador-at-Large for Global Women’s Issues" entity-parent-id="190S" proposed="true">Ambassador-at-Large</cato:entity-ref> and <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Senior Coordinator for Gender Equality and Women’s Empowerment" entity-parent-id="7200" proposed="true">Senior Coordinator</cato:entity-ref> shall consult with—</text>
            <paragraph id="H4DCD696C3E4944ECAFD63D9C9547D6B1">
              <enum>(1)</enum>
              <text>the heads of relevant Federal agencies;</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="H514D058E78D04A6284F564B8082D9E33">
              <enum>(2)</enum>
              <text>the Senior Policy Operating Group on Trafficking in Persons; and</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="H0091192B2DA046EEB07941DCC4F26C89">
              <enum>(3)</enum>
              <text>representatives of civil society and multi-lateral organizations with demonstrated experience in addressing violence against women and girls or promoting gender equality internationally.</text>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection id="HC9A1B58036994868886C33BD62BE3030">
            <enum>(e)</enum>
            <header>Content</header>
            <text>The implementation plan required under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="International Violence Against Women Act of 2013/s:111/ss:c" proposed="true">subsection (c)</cato:entity-ref> shall—</text>
            <paragraph id="HF71972A4E474412986AE1C0A6E6041E6">
              <enum>(1)</enum>
              <text>identify eligible low-income and lower-middle income countries with significant levels of violence against women and girls, including within displaced communities, that have the governmental or nongovernmental organizational capacity to manage and implement gender-based violence prevention and response program activities and should, when possible, be geographically, ethnically, and culturally diverse from one another;</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="H3B5F363AEDF34E9AA8456B0C563873DB">
              <enum>(2)</enum>
              <text>select 5 to 20 of the eligible countries identified under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="International Violence Against Women Act of 2013/s:111/ss:e/p:1" proposed="true">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref> in which to develop comprehensive and holistic individual country plans that incorporate at least two of the program activities listed in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="International Violence Against Women Act of 2013/s:112/ss:b" proposed="true">section 112(b)</cato:entity-ref>;</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="H456A6E7624874A5A860329BCAEF46236">
              <enum>(3)</enum>
              <text>assess and describe the current or potential capacity of the government of each eligible country selected under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="International Violence Against Women Act of 2013/s:111/ss:e/p:2" proposed="true">paragraph (2)</cato:entity-ref> and civil society organizations in each such eligible country to address and respond to violence against women and girls;</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="HD670F27DC7E44169AABFD42C1BDF3281">
              <enum>(4)</enum>
              <text>identify coordination mechanisms with Federal agencies that—</text>
              <subparagraph id="HB8AFD1264DB84775AA2BAD73F03DD6EE">
                <enum>(A)</enum>
                <text>have existing programs relevant to the strategy;</text>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="H58DC43670EC948B195C3F0814D206768">
                <enum>(B)</enum>
                <text>will be involved in new program activities; and</text>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="HC2EF8B9BFAA44D278F8EA5A6B8CE46AD">
                <enum>(C)</enum>
                <text>are engaged in broader United States strategies around development;</text>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="HD10E9A161D3A4929A510364E91918465">
              <enum>(5)</enum>
              <text>describe the monitoring and evaluation mechanisms established for each eligible country, and their intended use in assessing overall progress in prevention and response;</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="H700B6CF3C1B64D55944824A52D2AEF6B">
              <enum>(6)</enum>
              <text>project general levels of resources needed to achieve the stated objectives in each eligible country, including an accounting of—</text>
              <subparagraph id="H79CF09E748E048E6873DBD214A01B719">
                <enum>(A)</enum>
                <text>activities and funding already expended by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Department of State</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7200">United States Agency for International Development</cato:entity-ref>, other Federal agencies, other donor country governments, and other multilateral institutions; and</text>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="H8C5B74DBFCC442C98238FB7652D50CFB">
                <enum>(B)</enum>
                <text>leveraged private sector resources;</text>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="HB4CEBF84D2664EACB3E4D62317C7332A">
              <enum>(7)</enum>
              <text>integrate gender analysis into the strategy for each country; and</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="H0C821A180C504F639E27F4F3BC239948">
              <enum>(8)</enum>
              <text>include, as appropriate, strategies designed to accommodate the needs of stateless, disabled, internally displaced, refugee, or religious or ethnic minority women and girls.</text>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
        </section>
        <section id="HBDA36EEA5494457BB95746088FFB2906">
          <enum>112.</enum>
          <header>Implementation of the United States strategy to prevent and respond to gender-based violence globally</header>
          <subsection id="H0BC0AC9B50054908AF71CD762B485AD3">
            <enum>(a)</enum>
            <header>In general</header>
            <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref> and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7200">Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development</cato:entity-ref> are authorized to provide assistance to prevent and respond to violence against women and girls internationally.</text>
          </subsection>
          <subsection id="HADC3C4133B3047EDA0DD245FB7677CBF">
            <enum>(b)</enum>
            <header>Program activities supported</header>
            <text>Assistance provided to each country selected under sub<cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="International Violence Against Women Act of 2013/s:111/ss:e/p:2" proposed="true">section 111(e)(2)</cato:entity-ref> should include at least two of the following activities:</text>
            <paragraph id="H4DE3AD28A0C04E0E9672C92DC9CEDFEC">
              <enum>(1)</enum>
              <text>Development and implementation of programs that work to change social norms and attitudes so that violence against women and girls is neither condoned nor tolerated.</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="HB9623AA2EBDF45038392502DD5462E5D">
              <enum>(2)</enum>
              <text>Promotion of accessible quality educational and literacy opportunities for women and girls.</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="HBA9E1D190E4B40EC91D3D2EEBB9721AC">
              <enum>(3)</enum>
              <text>Promotion of access to economic opportunities, including by increasing distribution, credit, property, and inheritance rights for women and girls.</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="H23F93F3EBE9542A8A5573806971C92A1">
              <enum>(4)</enum>
              <text>Development and enforcement of civil and criminal legal and judicial sanctions, protections, trainings, and capacity.</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="HD4D552C2C45143DA9FF71BDA6071DFDA">
              <enum>(5)</enum>
              <text>Enhancement of the health sector capacity to detect, prevent, and respond to violence against women and girls.</text>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection id="H76EF9339D63C454E976A218484220B86">
            <enum>(c)</enum>
            <header>Building local capacity</header>
            <text>Not less than 10 percent of the amount of assistance provided to an eligible country under this section should be provided to community-based nongovernmental organizations, with priority given to nongovernmental organizations led by women.</text>
          </subsection>
        </section>
        <section id="H29AD2557C9104B3F8D49DB203B666DC6">
          <enum>113.</enum>
          <header>Monitoring the United States strategy to prevent and respond to gender-based violence globally</header>
          <subsection id="H068E595F1BF44ED3970690F029F2E14F">
            <enum>(a)</enum>
            <header>In general</header>
            <text>In each strategy submitted under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="International Violence Against Women Act of 2013/s:111/ss:a" proposed="true">section 111(a)</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Ambassador-at-Large for Global Women’s Issues" entity-parent-id="190S" proposed="true">Ambassador-at-Large</cato:entity-ref> and <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Senior Coordinator for Gender Equality and Women’s Empowerment" entity-parent-id="7200" proposed="true">Senior Coordinator</cato:entity-ref> shall include an analysis of best practices for preventing and addressing violence against women and girls internationally, which shall include—</text>
            <paragraph id="H439717E73ADA4CAD96684A52BBA872D4">
              <enum>(1)</enum>
              <text>a description of successful efforts by foreign governments, multilateral institutions, nongovernmental organizations, educational organizations, and faith-based organizations in preventing and responding to violence against women and girls;</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="HE510025FC48442B2990E5F911F8F087B">
              <enum>(2)</enum>
              <text>recommendations related to best practices, effective strategies, and improvements to enhance the impact of prevention and response efforts; and</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="HDA18A14CDD664B0C8B5986F9601A9280">
              <enum>(3)</enum>
              <text>the impact of activities funded by the strategy in preventing and reducing violence against women and girls internationally.</text>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection id="H24EFF4743652480DB8F44D21CC5C99E4">
            <enum>(b)</enum>
            <header>Amendments</header>
            <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Foreign Assistance Act of 1961">Foreign Assistance Act of 1961</cato:entity-ref> is amended—</text>
            <paragraph id="H4ACCBC9AA0C9424190C2CB2D2615DD70">
              <enum>(1)</enum>
              <text>in <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
                  <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Foreign Assistance Act of 1961/s:116/ss:d">section 116(d)</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2151n">
                  <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/22/2151n/d">22 U.S.C. 2151n(d)</cato:entity-ref>
                </external-xref>)</cato:entity>—</text>
              <subparagraph id="H7A745ADF922541E68521E56058A8AA04">
                <enum>(A)</enum>
                <text>in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Foreign Assistance Act of 1961/s:116/ss:d/p:11/sp:C">paragraph (11)(C)</cato:entity-ref>, by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="HAE8ED7F248DD4A0386DB192FACE4F94F">
                <enum>(B)</enum>
                <text>in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Foreign Assistance Act of 1961/s:116/ss:d/p:12/sp:C/cl:ii">paragraph (12)(C)(ii)</cato:entity-ref>, by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="H8ABE6F85308A47BAA0F5F0649B37F2FE">
                <enum>(C)</enum>
                <text>by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text>
                <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6F7DD71887D04585A972042010E5A481" style="OLC">
                  <paragraph id="H53BF791C7413499DBD637F8F484096BA">
                    <enum>(13)</enum>
                    <text>wherever applicable, the nature and extent of violence against women and girls.</text>
                  </paragraph>
                  <after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block>
                </quoted-block>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="HAA28A7C733CD43E59D149AC83719A001">
              <enum>(2)</enum>
              <text>in <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
                  <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Foreign Assistance Act of 1961/s:502B">section 502B</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2304">
                  <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/22/2304">22 U.S.C. 2304</cato:entity-ref>
                </external-xref>)</cato:entity>—</text>
              <subparagraph id="HB07E4AC7BBDB4677A0F4D43DB2CE67F4">
                <enum>(A)</enum>
                <text>by redesignating the second subsection designated as <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Foreign Assistance Act of 1961/s:502B/ss:i">subsection (i)</cato:entity-ref> as <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Foreign Assistance Act of 1961/s:502B/ss:j" proposed="true">subsection (j)</cato:entity-ref>; and</text>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="H5EC3D600456D420183994B5BD446FA91">
                <enum>(B)</enum>
                <text>by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text>
                <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H617CF64CE9B5449A9EBBB106651F6742" style="OLC">
                  <subsection id="H3BE85ABFC9824705A141376FDEA2C229">
                    <enum>(k)</enum>
                    <header>Inclusion of information relating to violence against women and girls</header>
                    <text>The report required by <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Foreign Assistance Act of 1961/s:502B/ss:b">subsection (b)</cato:entity-ref> shall include, wherever applicable, the nature and extent of violence against women and girls.</text>
                  </subsection>
                  <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
                </quoted-block>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection id="H6DD340D0FCE74A50A6BD9B3314933BC1">
            <enum>(c)</enum>
            <header>Monitoring and evaluation</header>
            <text>In coordination with relevant officials, and consistent with the monitoring and evaluation policies of their respective agencies, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Ambassador-at-Large for Global Women’s Issues" entity-parent-id="190S" proposed="true">Ambassador-at-Large</cato:entity-ref> and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Senior Coordinator for Gender Equality and Women’s Empowerment" entity-parent-id="7200" proposed="true">Senior Coordinator</cato:entity-ref> shall develop a plan for monitoring and independent evaluation of programs, projects, and activities carried out under this Act. The plan shall—</text>
            <paragraph id="HF51BB4C527E74AB0B67EE41C96B160C7">
              <enum>(1)</enum>
              <text>apply rigorous monitoring and evaluation methodologies to focus on learning, accountability, and policymaking, choosing from among a wide variety of qualitative, quantitative, summative, and formative methods common in the field of social scientific inquiry, including impact evaluations; and</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="H472DF4C7778E4FBF854C177B74196CC0">
              <enum>(2)</enum>
              <text>be included in the implementation plan required under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="International Violence Against Women Act of 2013/s:111/ss:c" proposed="true">section 111(c)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection id="H99894C9EEC55437A903BE61ED8265FB7">
            <enum>(d)</enum>
            <header>Research and data collection</header>
            <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7200">Administrator</cato:entity-ref> shall—</text>
            <paragraph id="HEA7246C58D2541F3888D2A7AD4EF7B5F">
              <enum>(1)</enum>
              <text>produce original research or analysis of effective interventions to prevent or respond to violence against women and girls internationally;</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="H5079478AFF5B4443BB2B16FA064E9D07">
              <enum>(2)</enum>
              <text>collect and analyze new or existing data on the scope and extent of all forms of violence against women and girls internationally, including under-documented forms of violence and violence against marginalized groups;</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="HF4BC3977CF764D399FF92DA6B56DCEE9">
              <enum>(3)</enum>
              <text>conduct research on effective interventions to respond to violence against women and girls internationally, including efforts to scale up effective programming; and</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="HF7B6B8B867AD4B3A9EF1866AA1212F01">
              <enum>(4)</enum>
              <text>support systemic data collection using internationally comparable indicators, norms, and methodologies for measuring the scope, prevalence, and incidence of violence against women and girls internationally.</text>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
        </section>
      </subtitle>
    </title>
  </legis-body>
</bill>
</doc>