<doc><docmeta id="113hr495ih">
    <bill congress="113" type="hr" number="495" version="ih"/>
    <revision id="4" commit-time="2013-03-13T21:20:30+00:00" comitter="/users/favila.xml" doc="/docs/113hr495ih/4.xml" status="complete"><description>Edited via AKN</description></revision>
</docmeta><bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HF0875386DCD24763B5DF54FB3BA490C8" public-private="public">
	<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>113th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 495</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20130205">February 5, 2013</action-date>
			<action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="R000580">Mr. Roskam</sponsor> (for
			 himself and <cosponsor name-id="K000188">Mr. Kind</cosponsor>) introduced the
			 following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name>
      </action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To make the Internal Revenue Service Free File Program
		  permanent.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H6E8BD6B08DD94F5BA9DF0600BAEEA12A" style="OLC">
		<section id="HE564FE826F2846A784C8C1BA74C4368F" section-type="section-one">
      <enum>1.</enum>
      <header>Short title</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the
			 <quote>
          <short-title>Free File Program Act of
			 2013</short-title>
        </quote>.</text>
		</section>
    <section id="HA6C07934423D4BD9A3FBC231F72E242B">
      <enum>2.</enum>
      <header>Findings</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Congress finds the following:</text>
			<paragraph id="H3A72736758EF4B459EA1936C78131C2B">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text>The Internal
			 Revenue Service (IRS) Free File program as established by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2050">IRS</cato:entity-ref> pursuant to
			 public rulemaking and set forth in the Federal Register, Vol. 67, No. 213,
			 Monday, November 4, 2002, pages 67247–67251, and in implementing agreements and
			 governing rules and requirements between the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2050">IRS</cato:entity-ref> and the tax software and
			 electronic industry in 2002, 2005, and 2009, has been successful and
			 significant in the efforts of the Federal Government to increase the electronic
			 filing of individual income tax returns.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H3FB7F08D39B4451186A5248FAD733FF8">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text>By the end of the
			 current tax return filing season around 40,000,000 Federal individual income
			 tax returns will have been prepared and filed electronically for free under the
			 IRS Free File program.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H2A23197CBA8D431AB37F55F3830E1E3C">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <text>The IRS Free File
			 program offers Federal individual income tax return preparation and electronic
			 filing services to more than 70 percent of taxpayers, approximately 98,000,000
			 taxpayers at the end of the current tax filing period, at no cost to the
			 taxpayers or to the Federal Government from tax software and electronic filing
			 companies participating in the program, currently 16 companies.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H7932720A09FF40F78DF6C894394E41AD">
        <enum>(4)</enum>
        <text>By the end of the
			 current tax return filing season, it is estimated that the IRS Free File
			 program will have saved taxpayers approximately $1,110,000,000 and will have
			 saved the Federal Government hundreds of millions of dollars.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H8BFF564367D141CE87DE83094457BF44">
        <enum>(5)</enum>
        <text>Under the IRS Free
			 File program, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2050">IRS</cato:entity-ref> and the companies participating in the program have made
			 substantial improvements to the program to provide better products and services
			 to eligible taxpayers.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HD69A8A53A917451B98F0E039482B3FCB">
        <enum>(6)</enum>
        <text>The IRS Free File
			 program must be maintained in order to reach and maintain Congress’ goal as set
			 forth in the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Service Restructuring and Reform Act of 1998">Internal Revenue Service Restructuring and Reform Act of 1998</cato:entity-ref> of
			 having 80 percent of all Federal individual income tax returns filed
			 electronically.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HE4AE8AC75A204BC18D054E8285D443A1">
        <enum>(7)</enum>
        <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2050">IRS</cato:entity-ref> and the
			 participating tax preparation companies have integrated the IRS Free File
			 program with State tax systems to enable taxpayers to also file their State tax
			 returns in conjunction with their IRS Free File filings.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H7FC56C7315DD4D27A85D992B301CDA67">
        <enum>(8)</enum>
        <text>Twenty-two States
			 and the District of Columbia now operate a Free File program patterned after
			 the IRS Free File program again at no cost to the State taxpayers or the State
			 governments.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HB5F66EBCF8C148E9A6788FDA568E0C8E">
        <enum>(9)</enum>
        <text>At the end of the
			 current tax return filing season, it is estimated that the Free File States
			 will have saved hundreds of millions of dollars collectively.</text>
			</paragraph>
    </section>
    <section id="H902F6ED8878E40CABC63FC2C5ECE61E1">
      <enum>3.</enum>
      <header>Internal Revenue
			 Service Free File Program</header>
			<subsection id="H82D0D360CEDB48B8B93E3185AF78ED4E">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary of
			 the Treasury</cato:entity-ref>, or his delegate, is authorized and directed to continue to
			 implement and operate the Internal Revenue Service (IRS) Free File program as
			 established by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2050">IRS</cato:entity-ref> in the public rulemaking of November 4, 2002, and
			 subsequent agreements and governing rules established pursuant thereto in 2002,
			 2005, and 2009.</text>
			</subsection>
      <subsection id="HEE3CB9C15A6144D1BF65DF2271CBA89D">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <text>The IRS Free File
			 program shall continue to provide free online individual income tax preparation
			 and electronic filing services to lower income, working poor, underprivileged,
			 disadvantaged, or underserved populations that comprise 70 percent of the
			 lowest income taxpayers.</text>
			</subsection>
      <subsection id="HBEC2E345A1954844866F2E1177D232BF">
        <enum>(c)</enum>
        <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2050">Internal
			 Revenue Service</cato:entity-ref> shall continue to work cooperatively with the private sector
			 technology industry through the Free File Alliance in providing free individual
			 income tax preparation and electronic filing services and shall not compete
			 with the private sector in providing these services to taxpayers, nor acquire,
			 develop, or deploy enabling systems to duplicate or replace private tax
			 preparation services.</text>
			</subsection>
      <subsection id="HD62679CAD545490F99DEEF2EF44B897B">
        <enum>(d)</enum>
        <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary of
			 the Treasury</cato:entity-ref>, or his delegate, may not establish, develop, sponsor, acquire, or
			 make available individual income tax preparation software or electronic filing
			 services that are offered under the IRS Free File program, except through the
			 IRS Free File program, the Internal Revenue Service’s Taxpayer Assistance
			 Centers, Tax Counseling for the Elderly, and volunteer income tax assistance
			 (VITA) programs.</text>
			</subsection>
    </section>
  </legis-body>
</bill></doc>