<doc>
  <docmeta id="113hr4246ih">
    <bill congress="113" type="hr" number="4246" version="ih"/>
    <revision size="5945" annotations="0" status="complete" id="3" commit-time="2014-03-24T22:13:24Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113hr4246ih/3.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HDD9272EA7E074AE88C55E8EB7592DF00" public-private="public">
	<metadata>
<dublinCore>
<dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">113 HR 4246 IH: Good Samaritan Protection for Construction, Architectural, and Engineering Volunteers Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">2014-03-13</dc:date>
<dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>113th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>2d Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 4246</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20140313">March 13, 2014</action-date>
			<action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="R000578">Mr. Reichert</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="M001142">Mr. Matheson</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001139">Mr. Gary G. Miller of California</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>
      </action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To provide construction, architectural, and engineering entities with qualified immunity from
			 liability for negligence when providing services or equipment on a
			 volunteer basis in response to a declared emergency or disaster.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H47E011AF419D4457812EF5F28EAE5056" style="OLC">
		<section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H10114D29710745E19DB3C7770E39FF3E" section-type="section-one">
      <enum>1.</enum>
      <header>Short title</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote>
          <short-title>
            <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Good Samaritan Protection for Construction, Architectural, and Engineering Volunteers Act" proposed="true">Good Samaritan Protection for Construction, Architectural, and Engineering Volunteers Act</cato:entity-ref>
          </short-title>
        </quote>.</text>
		</section>
    <section id="HF8F2E2B5CEF34CDCA4C04F5C6CE52B40">
      <enum>2.</enum>
      <header>Findings</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> finds the following:</text>
			<paragraph id="HD1A169CB22BF4EB9A6D82E6C76A19C86">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The construction, architectural, and engineering industries provide a valuable service in times of
			 disasters and emergencies.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HBEDCB24F865B48D79914FF567A33E3B7">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text>The construction, architectural, and engineering industries answered the call on September 11,
			 2001, and the days afterwards to assist in the search, recovery, and
			 clean-up efforts in New York City and Arlington, Virginia, as well as in
			 the aftermath of Hurricane Katrina.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H58188153F3454B2DAEAD21202B0D2493">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <text>The expertise and equipment brought forth for the search, recovery, and other efforts greatly
			 advanced and improved the efficiency of these efforts.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HEAB2D59FEBAB420D979DE83AA9F06A10">
        <enum>(4)</enum>
        <text>Such efforts by the construction, architectural, and engineering industries make it safer for
			 police, firefighters, and other rescue workers to work on search and
			 recovery efforts.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H1F2F348D90AC4D5180B8E0892208CFEA">
        <enum>(5)</enum>
        <text>The services provided by the construction, architectural, and engineering industries improve the
			 safety of the public by the assessment, containment, and mitigation of
			 conditions that threaten life and property.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H0FACB26FD99842F2B031EFE269F79FFE">
        <enum>(6)</enum>
        <text>Construction companies and architectural and engineering entities were faced with lawsuits as a
			 result of their voluntary efforts on behalf of their fellow citizens in
			 New York City and the Gulf Coast.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H11437EB87A8C4C6C985904EC59C22E19">
        <enum>(7)</enum>
        <text>Providing construction contractors and architectural and engineering entities qualified immunity
			 from liability when providing services in this type of volunteer activity
			 helps to ensure that such services will be available in the future in
			 times of need.</text>
			</paragraph>
    </section>
    <section id="H0D66657287F84751A325CF2DFDA32805">
      <enum>3.</enum>
      <header>Provision of qualified immunity from liability for negligence to construction, architectural, and
			 engineering entities when providing services or equipment on a volunteer
			 basis in response to a declared emergency or disaster</header>
			<subsection id="HF8158D13FFEF431F80C3D22C39385E27">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Liability protection</header>
        <text>When a construction entity provides emergency construction assistance, or an architectural or
			 engineering entity provides emergency architectural or engineering
			 assistance, on a voluntary basis, in good faith, and without expectation
			 of compensation, and the entity or an employee of such entity negligently
			 causes harm, the entity and the employee, if applicable, are not jointly,
			 severally, or individually liable in damages for that harm. Nothing in
			 this section shall be construed as providing immunity for gross negligence
			 or willful misconduct.</text>
			</subsection>
      <subsection id="HD5F2AC040F014E2DA66AB021397F6744">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Definitions</header>
        <text>In this section:</text>
				<paragraph id="H1984C4B40CF74B7A8DED103A6D3CF81D">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>construction entity</term> means a person, sole proprietorship, partnership, limited liability company, or corporation in the
			 regular business of providing construction assistance.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H62022EFEE3AA496480106CE5A6B72E46">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>The term <term>architectural or engineering entity</term> means a person, sole proprietorship, partnership, limited liability company, or corporation in the
			 regular business of providing architectural or engineering assistance.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HCDF3E0B288CC4328B70C4BBEA3BEE57C">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>construction assistance</term> means materials, labor, equipment, or services for construction-related activities, including
			 construction, demolition, repair, clean-up, alteration, and remediation.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HBF8C655CBB544BDB9341EDD204EB208E">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
          <text>The term <term>architectural or engineering assistance</term> means professional services of an architectural or engineering nature, as defined by State law, if
			 applicable, that are required to be performed or approved by a licensed
			 professional architect or engineer.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HCFAB05C7CE3C445696442B04CD78D907">
          <enum>(5)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The terms <term>emergency construction assistance</term> and <term>emergency architectural or engineering assistance</term> mean construction assistance and architectural or engineering assistance, respectively, provided—</text>
					<subparagraph id="HC5FEE6C21CAA45EB90F128C537093E06">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>at the direction of a public official acting in an official capacity; and</text>
					</subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H1114FC09028E4C38B3248BE3700BC542">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in response to or arising out of a declared Federal, State, or local emergency or disaster, whether
			 the assistance is provided before or after the formal declaration of
			 emergency or disaster.</text>
					</subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="H7D426702D9BD4FB48638516F896A19C8">
        <enum>(c)</enum>
        <header>Relationship to State law</header>
				<paragraph id="H22B25984FB2348F4B1174615869D672B">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>Preemption</header>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This section preempts the laws of any State to the extent that such laws are inconsistent with this
			 section, except that it does not preclude a State from providing a higher
			 amount of protection from liability, or from providing reimbursement for
			 costs or expenses as authorized by State or local law.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H022445EE5A044516BA242CACE5CBEF8B">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Workers compensation</header>
          <text>This section does not apply to liability under workers compensation laws.</text>
				</paragraph>
      </subsection>
    </section>
  </legis-body>
</bill>
</doc>