<doc>
  <docmeta id="113hr3606ih">
    <bill congress="113" type="hr" number="3606" version="ih"/>
    <revision size="5084" annotations="0" status="complete" id="4" commit-time="2013-12-05T22:39:37Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113hr3606ih/4.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H38A82CC33BF44F4C802138D0103FFB77" public-private="public">
  <metadata>
<dublinCore>
<dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">98 HR 3606 IH: Emigrant Wilderness Historical Use Preservation Act of 2013</dc:title>
<dc:publisher xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">2013-11-21</dc:date>
<dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
    <congress>113th CONGRESS</congress>
    <session>1st Session</session>
    <legis-num>H. R. 3606</legis-num>
    <current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
    <action>
      <action-date date="20131121">November 21, 2013</action-date>
      <action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="M001177">Mr. McClintock</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S001192">Mr. Stewart</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="N000181">Mr. Nunes</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name>
      </action-desc>
    </action>
    <legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
    <official-title>To permit certain activities to be conducted on Federal land within the Emigrant Wilderness of Stanislaus National Forest in the State of California at the level at which such activities were conducted on such land before the wilderness designation, and for other purposes.</official-title>
  </form>
  <legis-body id="H39B04556BAA34474B9CFC17EA4D53A73" style="OLC">
    <section id="H2DD8CE86F2F843D39F724174AD2BCA4B" section-type="section-one">
      <enum>1.</enum>
      <header>Short title</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote>
          <short-title>Emigrant Wilderness Historical Use Preservation Act of 2013</short-title>
        </quote>.</text>
    </section>
    <section id="H774C70A62CE946BFA86EC0D6EA9ACC56">
      <enum>2.</enum>
      <header>Purpose</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the purpose of this Act to ensure that—</text>
      <paragraph id="H9520D21FA790409C96464DA9D5AF16C7">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an increasing population within the vicinity of the Emigrant Wilderness of Stanislaus National Forest in the State of California does not cause the Emigrant Wilderness to lose its untrammeled and unimpaired wilderness character;</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HE8C6F72609C64338B64527FCF2B256F7">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Federal land comprising the Emigrant Wilderness retains the types of activities and level of access the land had when the land was designated as wilderness; and</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HEBC0374B6EE646B199CEC482AD178002">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <text>future generations of Americans continue to have the opportunity for a true wilderness experience consistent with what existed when the Emigrant Wilderness was designated.</text>
      </paragraph>
    </section>
    <section id="H26108B02C9B44E68B472F4E2E1E4E3E6">
      <enum>3.</enum>
      <header>Continuation of historical activities and access to Federal land comprising Emigrant Wilderness, Stanislaus National Forest, California</header>
      <subsection id="H0ED8DCE2B0F74F779EB8F065B3DD9EE5">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>In general</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This section modifies and supplements the provisions of law otherwise applicable to the Emigrant Wilderness of Stanislaus National Forest in the State of California, as originally designated by <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="public-law" value="public-law/93/632/s:2/ss:b">section 2(b) of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/93/632">Public Law 93–632</external-xref>
            </cato:entity-ref> (<cato:entity-ref entity-type="statute-at-large" value="statute-at-large/88/2154">88 Stat. 2154</cato:entity-ref>; <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/16/1132/note">
              <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1132">
            16 U.S.C. 1132
          </external-xref> note</cato:entity-ref>)</cato:entity> and expanded by <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="public-law" value="public-law/98/425/s:101/ss:a/p:9">section 101(a)(9) of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/98/425">Public Law 98–425</external-xref>
            </cato:entity-ref> (<cato:entity-ref entity-type="statute-at-large" value="statute-at-large/98/1620">98 Stat. 1620</cato:entity-ref>; <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/16/1132/note">
              <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1132">
            16 U.S.C. 1132
          </external-xref> note</cato:entity-ref>)</cato:entity> (in this section referred to as the <term>Emigrant Wilderness</term>).</text>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="H426DD91DE39245AB8D01116D6A34A4AE">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Preservation of historical activities and level of use</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1200">Secretary of Agriculture</cato:entity-ref> shall take such actions as may be necessary to ensure that, within the area designated as the Emigrant Wilderness, the level of use, allotted user days, and activities by commercial outfitters and guides within that area shall not rise above or be restricted below the historical level of use, allotted user days, and activities by commercial outfitters and guides within that area that existed as of the date of the original designation of the Emigrant Wilderness on January 3, 1975.</text>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="H46F50FEB23E64C71A2D0A5B413624E6B">
        <enum>(c)</enum>
        <header>Types of activities and impact</header>
        <text>The historical use and activities in the Emigrant Wilderness, including commercial outfitting and guiding, camping, pack stock grazing, and campfires, are traditional uses that are consistent with and part of an unconfined recreational experience, and the signs of use created by these historical uses are to be considered substantially unnoticeable and acceptable as long as they do not exceed the level present at the time of wilderness designation. The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1200">Secretary of Agriculture</cato:entity-ref> shall take such actions to ensure that these traditional uses neither exceed nor are restricted below the level of use at the time the Emigrant Wilderness was designated, as required by <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Emigrant Wilderness Historical Use Preservation Act of 2013/s:3/ss:b" proposed="true">subsection (b)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="H5E6B0BEE495C41A59C7ADB3C2F5A5904">
        <enum>(d)</enum>
        <header>Commercial pack and saddle stock use</header>
        <text>Because commercial pack and saddle stock use existed at the time the Emigrant Wilderness was designated, the level of this use at the time of designation is the extent necessary for these traditional activities and will not be allowed to exceed or be reduced below the highest level of such use in the preceding 10 years.</text>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="HAF733ECF32FD43E1A0B737C939C6F7AE">
        <enum>(e)</enum>
        <header>Historical use of trails, roads, paths, campsites, meadows, and cross-Country areas</header>
        <text>The historical use of trails, roads, paths, campsites, meadows, and cross-country areas in the Emigrant Wilderness by recreational and commercial pack and saddle stock, including horses, mules, donkeys, and ponies, shall be allowed to continue. The uses include travel on designated system trails and historic user trails, as well as cross-country travel, grazing, camping, campsites, and campfires.</text>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="HC2E17046EADD4CA2A37EDB10B8A7087F">
        <enum>(f)</enum>
        <header>Drift fences</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The use of drift fences that are in existence as of the date of the enactment of this Act or were previously in existence at the time of designation of the Emigrant Wilderness shall be allowed and maintained.</text>
      </subsection>
    </section>
  </legis-body>
</bill>
</doc>