<doc>
  <docmeta id="113hres691ih">
    <bill congress="113" type="hres" number="691" version="ih"/>
    <revision size="3223" annotations="0" status="complete" id="4" commit-time="2014-07-29T18:22:57Z" committer="zwilliams" doc="113hres691ih/4.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <resolution xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" dms-id="H46933CBEA04646B5BBC17CD145531C83" key="H" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print">
	<metadata>
<dublinCore>
<dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">113 HRES 691 IH: Supporting the goals and ideals of National Community Gardening Awareness Month.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">2014-07-25</dc:date>
<dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">113th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session display="yes">2d Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. RES. 691</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20140725">July 25, 2014</action-date>
			<action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="M001163">Ms. Matsui</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="M001143">Ms. McCollum</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000933">Mr. Moran</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000597">Ms. Pingree of Maine</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000312">Mr. McGovern</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000574">Mr. Blumenauer</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="L000551">Ms. Lee of California</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>
      </action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">Supporting the goals and ideals of National Community Gardening Awareness Month.</official-title>
	</form>
	<preamble>
		<whereas>
      <text>Whereas countless American families live with hunger every day;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas countless American families do not have access to fresh produce in their neighborhoods;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas community gardens conserve limited resources and promote sustainability;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas community gardens provide an important and nutritious source of fresh produce donations for
			 local food pantries and social service agencies;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas community gardens enable individuals to gain control over the quality, variety, and cost of
			 their food supply;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas community gardening encourages Americans of diverse cultural and economic backgrounds to
			 work together, foster a better sense of community, and improve the quality
			 of their lives;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas community-based youth and school gardening programs encourage personal self-esteem and a
			 healthy attitude toward learning;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas community gardening and greening projects provide a catalyst for neighborhood and community
			 development;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas community gardens reduce city heat and preserve open spaces for both present and future
			 generations;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas community gardens and other green spaces provide a more livable environment in American
			 municipalities and present a positive local image to a community's
			 residents and visitors; and</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas August is an appropriate month to designate as National Community Gardening Awareness
			 Month: Now, therefore, be it</text>
    </whereas>
  </preamble>
	<resolution-body id="H55DBDCA718374F75A42A3E2A58BB1D5F" style="traditional">
		<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H0FEB28384C684C0F80EF5236A68D1AA5" section-type="undesignated-section">
      <enum/>
      <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the <cato:entity-ref entity-id="0050" entity-type="federal-body">House of Representatives</cato:entity-ref> supports the goals and ideals of National Community Gardening
			 Awareness Month, including—</text>
			<paragraph id="HFEC6589C56D0436DB1236D1A11E27BDA">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">raising awareness about the importance of community gardens and urban agriculture;</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H3424F643BB714E07839E41F77715AF4D">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text>improving access to public land for the creation of sustainable food projects;</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HBA213BB1908A4D8A99D3B4A48899BD2E">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <text>encouraging further growth of community gardens and other opportunities that increase food
			 self-reliance, improve fitness, contribute to a cleaner environment, and
			 enhance community development; and</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H200FB2D2A3874780BC2A1C47BFD45F5D">
        <enum>(4)</enum>
        <text>supporting cooperative efforts among Federal, State, and local governments and nonprofit
			 organizations to promote the development and expansion of community
			 gardens and to increase their accessibility to disadvantaged population
			 groups.</text>
			</paragraph>
    </section>
  </resolution-body>
</resolution>
</doc>