<doc>
  <docmeta id="113hres199ih">
    <bill congress="113" type="hres" number="199" version="ih"/>
    <revision size="4436" annotations="0" status="complete" id="4" commit-time="2013-05-19T16:08:04Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113hres199ih/4.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <resolution xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" dms-id="H1BE54D0F51F04C1FA74A3082843BBEB8" key="H" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print">
  <metadata>
    <dublinCore>
      <title>113 HRES 199 IH: National Celiac Awareness Month</title>
      <publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</publisher>
      <date>2013-05-06</date>
      <format>text/xml</format>
      <language>EN</language>
      <rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</rights>
    </dublinCore>
  </metadata>
  <form>
    <distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code>
    <congress display="yes">113th CONGRESS</congress>
    <session display="yes">1st Session</session>
    <legis-num>H. RES. 199</legis-num>
    <current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
    <action display="yes">
      <action-date date="20130506">May 6, 2013</action-date>
      <action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="M001143">Ms. McCollum</sponsor>(for
			 herself,<cosponsor name-id="L000480">Mrs. Lowey</cosponsor>,<cosponsor name-id="R000577">Mr. Ryan of Ohio</cosponsor>,<cosponsor name-id="M000312">Mr. McGovern</cosponsor>,<cosponsor name-id="B001245">Ms. Bordallo</cosponsor>,<cosponsor name-id="M001160">Ms. Moore</cosponsor>,<cosponsor name-id="C000714">Mr. Conyers</cosponsor>, and<cosponsor name-id="R000053">Mr. Rangel</cosponsor>) submitted the following
			 resolution; which was referred to the<committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and
			 Commerce</committee-name>
      </action-desc>
    </action>
    <legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
    <official-title display="yes">Expressing support for designation of May
		  2013 as<quote>
        <short-title>National Celiac Awareness
		  Month</short-title>
      </quote>.</official-title>
  </form>
  <preamble>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas celiac disease is one of the most common genetic
			 conditions in the world;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas 1 in 133 people in the United States, the
			 equivalent of 1 percent of the Nation’s population, has celiac disease;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas 95 percent of people in the United States with
			 celiac disease remain undiagnosed;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the grains wheat, rye, and barley contain a
			 protein which triggers an immune response in persons with celiac disease,
			 causing damage to the lining of the small intestine;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the only course of treatment for celiac disease is
			 strict adherence to the medically prescribed gluten-free diet;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas individuals with celiac disease may have a range
			 of symptoms including anemia, weight loss, abdominal pain, osteoporosis, short
			 stature, diarrhea, constipation, depression, and migraines;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the length of time for an adult to be diagnosed
			 with celiac disease is 6 years from the onset of symptoms;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas celiac disease is a serious life-long condition
			 that affects children, women, and men in every age group;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas delays in the diagnosis of celiac disease result
			 in increased health care costs to patients, employers, and the Federal
			 Government;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas other serious autoimmune disorders such as
			 rheumatoid arthritis, systemic lupus, and Sjogren's syndrome are associated
			 with delays in the diagnosis of celiac disease;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas 10 percent of persons with type 1 diabetes have
			 celiac disease;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas individuals with Down syndrome are at increased
			 risk of having celiac disease;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas 30 percent of new diagnoses occur in persons over
			 the age of 60;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas 10 percent of people with celiac disease suffer
			 from associated neurological conditions such as peripheral neuropathy and
			 ataxia;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the United States will host the 15th International
			 Celiac Disease Symposium (ICDS) in Chicago, Illinois, in September 2013;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the global conference will bring together experts
			 in the study, treatment, and management of celiac disease and gluten-related
			 disorders;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the<cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Food Allergen Labeling and Consumer Protection Act of 2004">Food Allergen Labeling and Consumer Protection
			 Act of 2004</cato:entity-ref>mandated the establishment of Federal standards for gluten-free
			 foods to aid persons with celiac disease;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas individuals with celiac disease need basic
			 information about food product ingredients to effectively manage their chronic
			 health condition; and</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the 2004 National Institutes of Health Consensus
			 Development Conference on Celiac Disease found that consultation with a skilled
			 dietitian and identification and treatment of nutritional deficiencies were key
			 elements in the management of celiac disease: Now, therefore, be it</text>
    </whereas>
  </preamble>
  <resolution-body id="H40C9316A3E7243E4939DA02FFD9F4061" style="traditional">
    <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H7E7EAA0C4AE84C8CADE038486B4763FB" section-type="undesignated-section">
      <enum/>
      <text>That the<cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0050">House of
			 Representatives</cato:entity-ref>—</text>
      <paragraph id="HCCF923270E0E414185FE3C9DA9A7527F">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text>supports the
			 designation of<quote>
            <short-title>National Celiac
			 Awareness Month</short-title>
          </quote>;</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H7E52A3417B4142BF901DB6F384481531">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recognizes the efforts of advocates and
			 organizations that encourage awareness, promote research, and provide
			 education, support, and hope to those impacted by celiac disease;</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HBCDE4E0A29844AFB9590AC95D1C55265">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <text>supports research
			 funding to find a cure for celiac disease; and</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H25EA4B2337B74020929E176F8D0EB735">
        <enum>(4)</enum>
        <text>supports and
			 encourages all people in the United States to observe<quote>
            <short-title>National Celiac Awareness Month</short-title>
          </quote>with
			 appropriate events and activities.</text>
      </paragraph>
    </section>
  </resolution-body>
</resolution>
</doc>