<doc><docmeta id="113hr685ih">
    <bill congress="113" type="hr" number="685" version="ih"/>
    <revision id="11" commit-time="2013-04-01T21:18:07+00:00" comitter="/users/favila.xml" doc="/docs/113hr685ih/11.xml" status="complete"><description/></revision>
</docmeta><bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H4FC47D07074545008E15760851343861" public-private="public">
	<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>113th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 685</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20130214">February 14, 2013</action-date>
			<action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="J000174">Mr. Sam Johnson of
			 Texas</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="H001064">Mr. Heck of
			 Washington</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to
			 the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial
			 Services</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on
			 <committee-name committee-id="HHA00">House Administration</committee-name>, for
			 a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for
			 consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the
			 committee concerned</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To award a Congressional Gold Medal to the American
		  Fighter Aces, collectively, in recognition of their heroic military service and
		  defense of our country’s freedom throughout the history of aviation
		  warfare.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="HBE731C93F184480FB355F741D8E18052" style="OLC">
		<section id="H086C0BA9D69A4A88A0C5A5BAC275B289" section-type="section-one">
      <enum>1.</enum>
      <header>Short title</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote>American
			 Fighter Aces Congressional Gold Medal Act</quote>.</text>
		</section>
    <section id="H802F616E40584DB2BDBD620280A7300E">
      <enum>2.</enum>
      <header>Findings</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> finds the following:</text>
			<paragraph id="HE41B99F583F747BE943214A1C5AFCC1C">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text>An American
			 Fighter Ace is a fighter pilot who has served honorably in a United States
			 military service and who has destroyed 5 or more confirmed enemy aircraft in
			 aerial combat during a war or conflict in which American armed forces have
			 participated.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H91025EE9256247929146031BA94C6790">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text>Beginning with
			 World War I, and the first use of airplanes in warfare, military services have
			 maintained official records of individual aerial victory credits during every
			 major conflict. Of more than 60,000 United States military fighter pilots that
			 have taken to the air, less than 1,500 have become Fighter Aces.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HA660361A3850496FBC1F922276C76BFE">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <text>Americans became
			 Fighter Aces in the Spanish Civil War, Sino-Japanese War, Russian Civil War,
			 Arab-Israeli War, and others. Additionally, American military groups’ recruited
			 United States military pilots to form the American Volunteer Group, Eagle
			 Squadron, and others that produced American-born Fighter Aces fighting against
			 axis powers prior to Pearl Harbor.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H565943545BB24324A31C394B40C1DB6B">
        <enum>(4)</enum>
        <text>The concept of a
			 Fighter Ace is that they fought for freedom and democracy across the globe,
			 flying in the face of the enemy to defend freedom throughout the history of
			 aerial combat. American-born citizens became Fighter Aces flying under the flag
			 of United States allied countries and became some of the highest scoring
			 Fighter Aces of their respective wars.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H16A2F9E2716848D4B884214F73EC2AAF">
        <enum>(5)</enum>
        <text>American Fighter
			 Aces hail from every State in the Union, representing numerous ethnic,
			 religious, and cultural backgrounds.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H3273C9559AF746ECA0B8F176ECB11B69">
        <enum>(6)</enum>
        <text>Fighter Aces
			 possess unique skills that have made them successful in aerial combat. These
			 include courage, judgment, keen marksmanship, concentration, drive,
			 persistence, and split-second thinking that makes an Ace a war fighter with
			 unique and valuable flight driven skills.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H39DD9A5C4BDE4845A9E703395C447D9C">
        <enum>(7)</enum>
        <text>The Aces’
			 training, bravery, skills, sacrifice, attention to duty, and innovative spirit
			 illustrate the most celebrated traits of the United States military, including
			 service to country and the protection of freedom and democracy.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H9FBCB4FFC5664C019B58E272BC5037AD">
        <enum>(8)</enum>
        <text>American Fighter
			 Aces have led distinguished careers in the military, education, private
			 enterprise, and politics. Many have held the rank of General or Admiral and
			 played leadership roles in multiple war efforts from WWI to Vietnam through
			 many decades. In some cases they became the highest ranking officers for
			 following wars.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H2F815055DDAF4C22A2ED22677E8A192D">
        <enum>(9)</enum>
        <text>The extraordinary
			 heroism of the American Fighter Ace boosted American morale at home and
			 encouraged many men and women to enlist to fight for America and democracy
			 across the globe.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HEDF833D8DC4F41CEB69370C707B61CD5">
        <enum>(10)</enum>
        <text>Fighter Aces were
			 among America’s most-prized military fighters during wars. When they rotated
			 back to the United States after combat tours, they trained cadets in fighter
			 pilot tactics that they had learned over enemy skies. The teaching of combat
			 dogfighting to young aviators strengthened our fighter pilots to become more
			 successful in the skies. The net effect of this was to shorten wars and save
			 the lives of young Americans.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HB3FA911CC91B4F1C9DEA3509A92E5B6E">
        <enum>(11)</enum>
        <text>Following
			 military service, many Fighter Aces became test pilots due to their superior
			 flying skills and quick thinking abilities.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H03CA81FEDE20426D9BAC6D8D8A6F48E1">
        <enum>(12)</enum>
        <text>Richard Bong was
			 America’s top Ace of all wars scoring a confirmed 40 enemy victories in WWII.
			 He was from Poplar, Wisconsin, and flew the P–38 Lightning in all his combat
			 sorties flying for the 49th Fighter Group. He was killed in 1945 during a P–80
			 test flight in which the engine flamed out on takeoff.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HB6B3C79C85E444AEA7D663D29BB5F4BF">
        <enum>(13)</enum>
        <text>The American
			 Fighter Aces are one of the most decorated military groups in American history.
			 Twenty-two Fighter Aces have achieved the rank of Admiral in the Navy.
			 Seventy-nine Fighter Aces have achieved the rank of General in the Army,
			 Marines, and Air Force. Nineteen Medals of Honor have been awarded to
			 individual Fighter Aces.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H420D9A19EE8146E9A6E8D6E90066B57B">
        <enum>(14)</enum>
        <text>The American
			 Fighter Aces Association has existed for over 50 years as the primary
			 organization with which the Aces have preserved their history and told their
			 stories to the American public. The Association established and maintains the
			 Outstanding Cadet in Airmanship Award presented annually at the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="570B">United States
			 Air Force Academy</cato:entity-ref>; established and maintains an awards program for outstanding
			 fighter pilot <quote>lead-in</quote> trainee graduates from the Air Force,
			 Navy, and Marine Corps; and sponsors a scholarship program for descendants of
			 American Fighter Aces.</text>
			</paragraph>
    </section>
    <section id="HFAC166E1C91A44828B04C71526755EE9">
      <enum>3.</enum>
      <header>Congressional
			 gold medal</header>
			<subsection id="H6340800771384B5F8E90905391EB0314">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Presentation
			 authorized</header>
        <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Speaker" entity-parent-id="0050">Speaker of the House of Representatives</cato:entity-ref> and the
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-parent-id="0010" value="President pro tempore">President pro tempore of the Senate</cato:entity-ref> shall make appropriate arrangements for the
			 presentation, on behalf of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref>, of a single gold medal of appropriate
			 design in honor of the American Fighter Aces, collectively, in recognition of
			 their heroic military service and defense of our country’s freedom, which has
			 spanned the history of aviation warfare.</text>
			</subsection>
      <subsection id="H040520BBE7C1438D8E7D52EFC01AD02B">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Design and
			 striking</header>
        <text>For the purposes of the award referred to in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="American Fighter Aces Congressional Gold Medal Act/s:3/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection
			 (a)</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary of the Treasury</cato:entity-ref> shall strike the gold medal with suitable
			 emblems, devices, and inscriptions, to be determined by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
			</subsection>
      <subsection id="HDB0245378C5F4B0CA239B0E98DD76680">
        <enum>(c)</enum>
        <header>Smithsonian
			 institution</header>
				<paragraph id="H7C6BC70CF8AA4951865FDE358CD4EC39">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>In
			 general</header>
          <text>Following the award of the gold medal in honor of the
			 American Fighter Aces, the gold medal shall be given to the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="3300">Smithsonian
			 Institution</cato:entity-ref>, where it will be available for display as appropriate and
			 available for research.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H2F18761F7B9E486CA4CA0F307C2E282E">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Sense of the
			 Congress</header>
          <text>It is the sense of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> that the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="3300">Smithsonian
			 Institution</cato:entity-ref> should make the gold medal awarded pursuant to this Act available
			 for display elsewhere, particularly at appropriate locations associated with
			 the American Fighter Aces, and that preference should be given to locations
			 affiliated with the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="3300">Smithsonian Institution</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
				</paragraph>
      </subsection>
    </section>
    <section id="H1F75CCA4BFC84316BD4B49BC71312B16">
      <enum>4.</enum>
      <header>Duplicate
			 medals</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> may
			 strike and sell duplicates in bronze of the gold medal struck pursuant to
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="American Fighter Aces Congressional Gold Medal Act/s:3" proposed="true">section 3</cato:entity-ref> under such regulations as the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> may prescribe, at a price
			 sufficient to cover the cost thereof, including labor, materials, dies, use of
			 machinery, and overhead expenses, and the cost of the gold medal.</text>
		</section>
    <section id="H0F31C4FC8BE14271863C583099D953F2">
      <enum>5.</enum>
      <header>National
			 medals</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">The medal struck
			 pursuant to this Act is a national medal for purposes of <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc-chapter/31/51">chapter 51 of title
			 31, United States Code</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
		</section>
    <section id="H0146FD5DE9C1481DB79FEBDA798709F8">
      <enum>6.</enum>
      <header>Authority To use
			 fund amounts; proceeds of sale</header>
			<subsection id="H849BCD2DCFD04F96AAC7897416D5B014">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Authority To use
			 fund amounts</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">
          <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="auth-auth-approp">There is
			 authorized to be charged against the <cato:property name="funds-source">United States Mint Public Enterprise Fund</cato:property>,
			 an amount not to exceed <cato:funds-and-year amount="40000">$40,000</cato:funds-and-year> <cato:property name="purpose">to pay for the cost of the medal authorized
			 under <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="American Fighter Aces Congressional Gold Medal Act/s:3" proposed="true">section 3</cato:entity-ref>
            </cato:property>.</cato:entity>
        </text>
			</subsection>
      <subsection id="HC03C282C40434E25A0AC828B47916B80">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Proceeds of
			 sale</header>
        <text>Amounts received from the sale of duplicate bronze medals
			 under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="American Fighter Aces Congressional Gold Medal Act/s:4" proposed="true">section 4</cato:entity-ref> shall be deposited in the United States Mint Public Enterprise
			 Fund.</text>
			</subsection>
    </section>
  </legis-body>
</bill></doc>