<doc>
  <docmeta id="113hres391eh">
    <bill congress="113" type="hres" number="391" version="eh"/>
    <revision size="4750" annotations="0" status="complete" id="3" commit-time="2013-11-15T17:34:03Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113hres391eh/3.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <resolution xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" dms-id="Hbc53aea5-cb3c-439d-abd7-61f598bbcbfb" key="H" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Engrossed-in-House" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" stage-count="1"> 
<metadata>
<dublinCore>
<dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">113 HRES 391 EH: Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 992) to amend provisions in section 716 of the Dodd-Frank Wall Street Reform and Consumer Protection Act relating to Federal assistance for swaps entities, and providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 2374) to amend the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 to provide protections for retail customers, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">2013-10-29</dc:date>
<dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="no">IV</distribution-code>
<congress display="no">113th CONGRESS</congress>
<session display="no">1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. RES. 391</legis-num>
<current-chamber display="yes">In the House of Representatives, U. S.,</current-chamber>
<action>
<action-date date="20131029">October 29, 2013</action-date>
</action>
<legis-type display="yes">RESOLUTION</legis-type>
<official-title display="no">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 992) to amend provisions in section 716 of the Dodd-Frank Wall Street Reform and Consumer Protection Act relating to Federal assistance for swaps entities, and providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 2374) to amend the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 to provide protections for retail customers, and for other purposes.</official-title>
</form>
<resolution-body id="H9d357332-4b2f-435b-874c-54c58a400b81" style="traditional">
<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H4ccf507b-d0b4-4049-b536-5f1752dbf2cc" section-type="undesignated-section">
      <enum/>
      <text>That upon the adoption of this resolution it shall be in order to consider in the House the bill (<cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="113 HR 992" proposed="true">H.R. 992</cato:entity-ref>) to amend provisions in <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Dodd-Frank Wall Street Reform and Consumer Protection Act/s:716">section 716 of the Dodd-Frank Wall Street Reform and Consumer Protection Act</cato:entity-ref> relating to Federal assistance for swaps entities. All points of order against consideration of the bill are waived. The bill shall be considered as read. All points of order against provisions in the bill are waived. The previous question shall be considered as ordered on the bill to final passage without intervening motion except: (1) one hour of debate equally divided among and controlled by the chair and ranking minority member of the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="committee" entity-id="HAG00">Committee on Agriculture</cato:entity-ref> and the chair and ranking minority member of the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="committee" entity-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</cato:entity-ref>; (2) one motion to recommit.</text>
    </section>
<section id="H7FF40611DEE8499F997ECADC241096E7">
      <enum>2.</enum>
      <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon adoption of this resolution it shall be in order to consider in the House the bill (<cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="113 HR 2374" proposed="true">H.R. 2374</cato:entity-ref>) to amend the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Securities Exchange Act of 1934">Securities Exchange Act of 1934</cato:entity-ref> to provide protections for retail customers, and for other purposes. All points of order against consideration of the bill are waived. In lieu of the amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="committee" entity-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</cato:entity-ref> now printed in the bill, an amendment in the nature of a substitute consisting of the text of Rules Committee Print 113–23 shall be considered as adopted. The bill, as amended, shall be considered as read. All points of order against provisions in the bill, as amended, are waived. The previous question shall be considered as ordered on the bill, as amended, and on any further amendment thereto, to final passage without intervening motion except: (1) one hour of debate equally divided and controlled by the chair and ranking minority member of the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="committee" entity-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</cato:entity-ref>; (2) the further amendment printed in the report of the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="committee" entity-id="HRU00">Committee on Rules</cato:entity-ref> accompanying this resolution, if offered by Representative George Miller of California or his designee, which shall be in order without intervention of any point of order, shall be considered as read, shall be separately debatable for 20 minutes equally divided and controlled by the proponent and an opponent, and shall not be subject to a demand for division of the question; and (3) one motion to recommit with or without instructions.</text>
    </section>
<section id="H78A34304B82A40F0B2CFE8E3D6078843">
      <enum>3.</enum>
      <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Continuing Appropriations Act, 2014/s:1002">section 1002 of the Continuing Appropriations Act, 2014</cato:entity-ref>—</text>
<subsection id="H9F24FE4F62AF4CA784CC581D538FFBCB">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a motion to proceed under such section—</text>
<paragraph id="H89E715C6996C43C9BC89080ED17A40A4">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">may be offered even if the committee to which a joint resolution has been referred has not reported or been discharged; and</text>
        </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H3CC7C223048B4E999A5AA8987AAC20A2">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall be in order only on the legislative day of Tuesday, October 29, 2013, or the legislative day of Wednesday, October 30, 2013; and</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
<subsection id="H37E4649202FE4F4AA0360DE5AF31D4DF">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <text>a joint resolution under such section shall be debatable for one hour equally divided and controlled by the proponent and an opponent.</text>
      </subsection>
    </section>
<section id="H9F95A542672943819663A83DA4327D27">
      <enum>4.</enum>
      <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">On any legislative day during the period from October 31, 2013, through November 11, 2013—</text>
<subsection id="HFCC675759E8C4AB0A2F9E925028A85E4">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Journal of the proceedings of the previous day shall be considered as approved;</text>
      </subsection>
<subsection id="HEF98D49B9611455DB33ABAEA1952D34F">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <text>the Chair may at any time declare the House adjourned to meet at a date and time, within the limits of clause 4, section 5, article I of the Constitution, to be announced by the Chair in declaring the adjournment.</text>
      </subsection>
    </section>
<section id="H2ADB6A05EB994080A0366588C3289D92">
      <enum>5.</enum>
      <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" value="Speaker of the House of Representatives" entity-parent-id="0050">Speaker</cato:entity-ref> may appoint Members to perform the duties of the Chair for the duration of the period addressed by <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="113 HRES 391/s:4" proposed="true">section 4 of this resolution</cato:entity-ref> as though under clause 8(a) of rule I.</text>
    </section>
</resolution-body>
<attestation>
    <attestation-group>
      <attestor display="no">Karen L. Haas,</attestor>
      <role>Clerk.</role>
    </attestation-group>
  </attestation>
</resolution>
</doc>