<doc>
  <docmeta id="113hres260rh">
    <bill congress="113" type="hres" number="260" version="rh"/>
    <revision size="5117" annotations="0" status="complete" id="3" commit-time="2013-08-05T18:07:57Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113hres260rh/3.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <resolution xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" dms-id="H959a3e18-e207-4211-b055-57911c8f258f" key="H" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Reported-in-House" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>113 HRES 260 RH: Providing for further consideration of the bill (H.R. 1960) to authorize appropriations for fiscal year 2014 for military activities of the Department of Defense and for military construction, to prescribe military personnel strengths for such fiscal year, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2013-06-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code>
		<calendar display="yes">House Calendar No. 32</calendar>
		<congress display="yes">113th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session display="yes">1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. RES. 260</legis-num>
		<associated-doc display="yes" role="report">Report No.
		  113–108</associated-doc>
		<current-chamber display="yes">IN THE HOUSE OF
		  REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20130613" legis-day="20130612">June 13 (legislative
			 day, June 12), 2013</action-date>
			<action-desc>
        <cosponsor name-id="N000185">Mr. Nugent</cosponsor>, from
			 the <committee-name committee-id="HRU00">Committee on Rules</committee-name>,
			 reported the following resolution; which was referred to the House Calendar and
			 ordered to be printed</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">Providing for further consideration of the
		  bill (H.R. 1960) to authorize appropriations for fiscal year 2014 for military
		  activities of the Department of Defense and for military construction, to
		  prescribe military personnel strengths for such fiscal year, and for other
		  purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<resolution-body id="Hf9768f32-0af1-44e8-b786-cd35524d6748" style="traditional">
		<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H8112bf9f-189c-44d2-876f-0050db692a03" section-type="undesignated-section">
      <enum/>
      <text>That at any time after the adoption
			 of this resolution the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" value="Speaker of the House of Representatives" entity-parent-id="0050">Speaker</cato:entity-ref> may, pursuant to clause 2(b) of rule XVIII,
			 declare the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0050">House</cato:entity-ref> resolved into the Committee of the Whole House on the state
			 of the Union for further consideration of the bill (<cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="113 HR 1960" proposed="true">H.R. 1960</cato:entity-ref>) to authorize
			 appropriations for fiscal year 2014 for military activities of the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="9700">Department
			 of Defense</cato:entity-ref> and for military construction, to prescribe military personnel
			 strengths for such fiscal year, and for other purposes. No further general
			 debate shall be in order.</text>
		</section>
    <section id="HF0797DCFF65A4BC99FD9A5B727150A29">
      <enum>2.</enum>
      <subsection commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H60ED4284019E4B3389BE582E303B772E">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In lieu of the amendment in the nature of a
			 substitute recommended by the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="committee" entity-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</cato:entity-ref> now printed in the
			 bill, it shall be in order to consider as an original bill for the purpose of
			 amendment under the five-minute rule an amendment in the nature of a substitute
			 consisting of the text of Rules Committee Print 113-13, modified by the
			 amendment printed in part A of the report of the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="committee" entity-id="HRU00">Committee on Rules</cato:entity-ref>
			 accompanying this resolution. That amendment in the nature of a substitute
			 shall be considered as read. All points of order against that amendment in the
			 nature of a substitute are waived.</text>
			</subsection>
      <subsection id="HD439726E84E449E48E8622714B2F8898">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <text>No amendment to
			 the amendment in the nature of a substitute made in order as original text
			 shall be in order except those printed in part B of the report of the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="committee" entity-id="HRU00">Committee
			 on Rules</cato:entity-ref> and amendments en bloc described in section 3 of this resolution.</text>
			</subsection>
      <subsection id="H77A720D3CA804E9894946BFCCCE1EAC1">
        <enum>(c)</enum>
        <text>Each amendment
			 printed in part B of the report of the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="committee" entity-id="HRU00">Committee on Rules</cato:entity-ref> shall be considered
			 only in the order printed in the report, may be offered only by a Member
			 designated in the report, shall be considered as read, shall be debatable for
			 the time specified in the report equally divided and controlled by the
			 proponent and an opponent, shall not be subject to amendment, and shall not be
			 subject to a demand for division of the question in the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0050">House</cato:entity-ref> or in the
			 Committee of the Whole.</text>
			</subsection>
      <subsection id="H43256B69AA704FECBB780E65D59D1758">
        <enum>(d)</enum>
        <text>All points of
			 order against amendments printed in part B of the report of the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="committee" entity-id="HRU00">Committee on
			 Rules</cato:entity-ref> or against amendments en bloc described in <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="113 HRES 260/s:3" proposed="true">section 3 of this resolution</cato:entity-ref>
			 are waived.</text>
			</subsection>
    </section>
    <section id="H75C9EDB9E26742799069DAF83015F59D">
      <enum>3.</enum>
      <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It shall be in order at any time for the
			 chair of the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="committee" entity-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</cato:entity-ref> or his designee to offer amendments en
			 bloc consisting of amendments printed in part B of the report of the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="committee" entity-id="HRU00">Committee
			 on Rules</cato:entity-ref> accompanying this resolution not earlier disposed of. Amendments en
			 bloc offered pursuant to this section shall be considered as read, shall be
			 debatable for 20 minutes equally divided and controlled by the chair and
			 ranking minority member of the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="committee" entity-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</cato:entity-ref> or their designees,
			 shall not be subject to amendment, and shall not be subject to a demand for
			 division of the question in the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0050">House</cato:entity-ref> or in the Committee of the Whole. The
			 original proponent of an amendment included in such amendments en bloc may
			 insert a statement in the Congressional Record immediately before the
			 disposition of the amendments en bloc.</text>
		</section>
    <section id="HF2FD9724F23D4F71A28E4E7B36C3842F">
      <enum>4.</enum>
      <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">At the conclusion of consideration of the
			 bill for amendment the Committee shall rise and report the bill to the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0050">House</cato:entity-ref>
			 with such amendments as may have been adopted. Any Member may demand a separate
			 vote in the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0050">House</cato:entity-ref> on any amendment adopted in the Committee of the Whole to the
			 bill or to the amendment in the nature of a substitute made in order as
			 original text. The previous question shall be considered as ordered on the bill
			 and amendments thereto to final passage without intervening motion except one
			 motion to recommit with or without instructions.</text>
		</section>
  </resolution-body>
	<endorsement>
		<action-date>June 13 (legislative day, June 12), 2013</action-date>
		<action-desc>Referred to the House Calendar and ordered to be
		  printed</action-desc>
	</endorsement>
</resolution>
</doc>