<doc>
  <docmeta id="113hr3212eh">
    <bill congress="113" type="hr" number="3212" version="eh"/>
    <revision size="55064" annotations="0" status="complete" id="5" commit-time="2014-01-06T16:40:59Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113hr3212eh/5.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <bill bill-stage="Engrossed-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H883F0D06596A44FEA3BE8D8B052FCD5B" public-private="public" stage-count="1"> 
<metadata>
<dublinCore>
<dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">113 HR 3212 EH: Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2013</dc:title>
<dc:publisher xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"/>
<dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="no">I</distribution-code>
<congress>113th CONGRESS</congress>
    <session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. R. 3212</legis-num>
<current-chamber display="no">IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">To ensure compliance with the 1980 Hague Convention on the Civil Aspects of International Child Abduction by countries with which the United States enjoys reciprocal obligations, to establish procedures for the prompt return of children abducted to other countries, and for other purposes.</official-title>
</form>
<legis-body id="H993EEB13EBD042108D182722D511893A" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HE72D462468904AD4BE78F3FD7D9346B5" section-type="section-one">
      <enum>1.</enum>
      <header>Short title and table of contents</header>
<subsection id="HA5148D894C6B43A1AB1EB55AA2B5C9BF">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Short title</header>
        <text>This Act may be cited as the <quote>
            <short-title>Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2013</short-title>
          </quote>.</text>
      </subsection>
<subsection id="H534D57D116ED468A9F419A5070919E9E">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Table of contents</header>
        <text>The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text>
<toc container-level="legis-body-container" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded" lowest-level="section" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" regeneration="yes-regeneration">
<toc-entry idref="HE72D462468904AD4BE78F3FD7D9346B5" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title and table of contents.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="H3072466932D04C1CAF3D3A3C7B047D70" level="section">Sec. 2. Findings; sense of Congress; purposes.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="H58AF3C0168E2470E96B7FE61C03D361F" level="section">Sec. 3. Definitions.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="HBD1310EA24124B0698AB80A61A08F0AE" level="title">Title I—Department of State Actions</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="H20E247A528AF4A2D831953A8D1197CCA" level="section">Sec. 101. Annual report.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="H9DCE5FF6F5B24E4D8FCF401833728BB3" level="section">Sec. 102. Standards and assistance.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="H9A0C6542324E44A7AC386B1E78D7EAE2" level="section">Sec. 103. Memorandum of understanding.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="H566CB1E271094287833A4A18CDFBC174" level="section">Sec. 104. Notification of congressional representatives.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="HDFBCFDBF572F48D48C72C8052182CC54" level="title">Title II—Presidential Actions</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="H5AC567E29CC34585AA9015B8EF9FD1EF" level="section">Sec. 201. Presidential actions in response to unresolved cases.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="HB02DBD03717244459C91DA48C79DEBAE" level="section">Sec. 202. Presidential actions in response to patterns of noncooperation in cases of international child abductions.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="H736055E091D34FE799A9D3087BDB1DB6" level="section">Sec. 203. Consultations with foreign governments.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="H4E6C8EAA5B52459CBA89C38BF83A5762" level="section">Sec. 204. Report to Congress.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="H6A892B19D7294BEFAD364D1A17D73CCF" level="section">Sec. 205. Presidential actions.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="HF02C073DFCE44C1281FFD2FBF8ABCBF4" level="section">Sec. 206. Presidential waiver.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="H8770BA92A55B419782978AC57883FE86" level="section">Sec. 207. Publication in Federal Register.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="HBB8FAB486465416EADC771518756F84C" level="section">Sec. 208. Termination of Presidential actions.</toc-entry>
        </toc>
      </subsection>
    </section>
<section id="H3072466932D04C1CAF3D3A3C7B047D70">
      <enum>2.</enum>
      <header>Findings; sense of Congress; purposes</header>
<subsection id="H449E4355E0EE41469FDCA748EBF6CBC4">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Findings</header>
        <text>Congress finds the following:</text>
<paragraph id="H5E00EDF5E85443ADB860CAB15F2320D9">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>Sean Goldman, a United States citizen and resident of New Jersey, was abducted from the United States in 2004 and separated from his father, David Goldman, who spent nearly six years battling for the return of his son from Brazil before Sean was finally returned to Mr. Goldman’s custody on December 24, 2009.</text>
        </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HBA4B984C84664C439198D4CD2C8C3B71">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>The Department of State’s Office of Children’s Issues, which serves as the Central Authority of the United States for the purposes of the 1980 Hague Convention on the Civil Aspects of International Child Abduction, has received thousands of requests since 2007 for assistance in the return to the United States of children who have been abducted by a parent or other legal guardian to another country. For a variety of reasons reflecting the significant obstacles to the recovery of abducted children, as well as the legal and factual complexity involving such cases, not all cases are reported to the Central Authority of the United States.</text>
        </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HE474831239FE46088B057BF83C3491E7">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <text>More than one thousand outgoing international child abductions are reported to the Central Authority of the United States every year.</text>
        </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H439C85F319ED4988819DEE70AB676C66">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
          <text>Only about half of the children abducted from the United States to countries with which the United States enjoys reciprocal obligations under the Hague Abduction Convention are returned to the United States.</text>
        </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H6380B13B61ED448AAA40C25E246C3D60">
          <enum>(5)</enum>
          <text>The United States and Convention countries have expressed their desire, through the Hague Abduction Convention, <quote>
              <short-title>to protect children internationally from the harmful effects of their wrongful removal or retention and to establish procedures to ensure their prompt return to the State of their habitual residence, as well as to secure protection for rights of access.</short-title>
            </quote>.</text>
        </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H81B65B18E5EC43829E7F1845FA750A41">
          <enum>(6)</enum>
          <text>Compliance by the United States and Convention countries depends on the actions of their designated central authorities, the performance of their judiciaries as reflected in the legal process and decisions rendered to enforce or effectuate the Hague Abduction Convention, and the ability and willingness of their law enforcement to insure the swift enforcement of orders rendered pursuant to the Hague Abduction Convention.</text>
        </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HB75917D02EAE4AF1BD4025CCEBBEDA0A">
          <enum>(7)</enum>
          <text>According to data compiled by the Central Authority of the United States, approximately 40 percent of abduction cases and access cases involve children taken from the United States to countries with which the United States does not have Hague Abduction Convention obligations or other agreements relating to the resolution of abduction cases and access cases.</text>
        </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H52D4C4A59E4D480B918C73857E8AAA07">
          <enum>(8)</enum>
          <text>According to the Department of State’s April 2010 Report on Compliance with the Hague Convention on the Civil Aspects of International Child Abduction, <quote>
              <short-title>parental child abduction jeopardizes the child and has substantial long-term consequences for both the child and the left-behind parent.</short-title>
            </quote>.</text>
        </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H342F2AD18DE34F8290588E148B8B3C97">
          <enum>(9)</enum>
          <text>Abducted children are at risk of serious emotional and psychological problems and have been found to experience anxiety, eating problems, nightmares, mood swings, sleep disturbances, aggressive behavior, resentment, guilt and fearfulness, and as adults may struggle with identity issues, personal relationships, and parenting.</text>
        </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HD46C0244B4CC4E6AB762957869BFEF3A">
          <enum>(10)</enum>
          <text>Left-behind parents may encounter substantial psychological and emotional problems, and few have the extraordinary financial resources necessary to pursue individual civil or criminal remedies in both the United States and a foreign country, even where available, or to engage in repeated foreign travel to attempt to procure the return of their children by evoking diplomatic and humanitarian remedies.</text>
        </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H7174E5B541674649AA91C9B6BA86ACF6">
          <enum>(11)</enum>
          <text>Left-behind parents who are military parents may be unable to leave their military duties to pursue multinational litigation or take leave to attend multiple court proceedings, and foreign authorities may not schedule proceedings to accommodate such duties.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
<subsection id="H575092E8F9454D8EBA4E6B1754F4BF00">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Sense of Congress</header>
        <text>It is the sense of <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> that the United States should set a strong example for Convention countries in the timely location and return of abducted children in the United States whose habitual residence is not the United States.</text>
      </subsection>
<subsection id="HEEF24BA5E4CE497582B171D7DC836681">
        <enum>(c)</enum>
        <header>Purposes</header>
        <text>The purposes of this Act are to—</text>
<paragraph id="H7C9A40B6A82E4F13A4E54E1915493FC9">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>protect children whose habitual residence is the United States from the harmful effects of abduction and to assist left-behind parents to have access to their abducted child in a safe and predictable manner, wherever the child is located, while an abduction case is pending;</text>
        </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HEDFE29CF801347C6A9376574E8B505E9">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>provide left-behind parents, including military parents, their advocates, and judges the information they need to enhance the resolution of abduction cases and access cases through established legal procedures, risk assessment tools, and the practical means for overcoming obstacles to recovering an abducted child;</text>
        </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H29562780049D4BDD90777FD87BED2D8E">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <text>establish measured, effective, and predictable actions to be undertaken by the President on behalf of abducted children whose habitual residence is the United States at the time of the abduction;</text>
        </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HB992D82AE4874C1193D1D53D2468D646">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
          <text>promote an international consensus that it is in the interest of children to have any issues related to their care and custody determined in the country of their habitual residence;</text>
        </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H12CDD100ADEB4CFAA79925E7BAC30E68">
          <enum>(5)</enum>
          <text>provide the necessary training for officials of the United States Armed Forces and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="9700">Department of Defense</cato:entity-ref> to establish policies and provide services to military parents that address the unique circumstances of abductions and violations of rights of access that may occur with regard to military dependent children; and</text>
        </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H172AD122C8DD4B92B1160A7A8D92F1EE">
          <enum>(6)</enum>
          <text>encourage the effective implementation of international mechanisms, particularly those established pursuant to the Hague Abduction Convention, to achieve reciprocity in the resolution of abductions and to protect children from the harmful effects of an abduction.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
    </section>
<section id="H58AF3C0168E2470E96B7FE61C03D361F">
      <enum>3.</enum>
      <header>Definitions</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text>
<paragraph id="H97260637B2C94C889ED18633E210CA5C">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <header>Abducted child</header>
        <text>The term <term>abducted child</term> means a child who is the victim of an abduction.</text>
      </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HEA25E6C7BB5C40978AD420634794F173">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <header>Abduction</header>
        <text>The term <term>abduction</term> means—</text>
<subparagraph id="HDE1293F7C03E4E6F8F511FEA79C20BD4">
          <enum>(A)</enum>
          <text>the alleged wrongful removal of a child from the child’s country of habitual residence;</text>
        </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H761C8332AB414E7A8443738BDED83671">
          <enum>(B)</enum>
          <text>the alleged wrongful retention of a child outside the child’s country of habitual residence; or</text>
        </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HFABDD218B98C4AA7B808A87AD8E3002F">
          <enum>(C)</enum>
          <text>the alleged wrongful removal or retention of a military dependent child from the exercise of rights of custody of a military parent.</text>
        </subparagraph>
      </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H959BB73A621146EBB0FE17614F60EA72">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <header>Abduction case</header>
        <text>The term <term>abduction case</term> means a case involving an application filed with the Central Authority of the United States by a left-behind parent for the resolution of an abduction.</text>
      </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HA8E91C288E71441EB4A2E9AEE54DDD2D">
        <enum>(4)</enum>
        <header>Access case</header>
        <text>The term <term>access case</term> means a case involving an application filed with the Central Authority of the United States by a left-behind parent for the establishment of rights of access.</text>
      </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HD7DD4A68B108403997485B4D7430B537">
        <enum>(5)</enum>
        <header>Annual report</header>
        <text>The term <term>Annual Report</term> means the Annual Report on International Child Abduction required under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2013/s:101" proposed="true">section 101</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
      </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HDF3FD99BE98A4E4DAB2DBFA1201C755E">
        <enum>(6)</enum>
        <header>Application</header>
        <text>The term <term>application</term> means—</text>
<subparagraph id="HA0127C98AD9B4211BAEC90B0F4B8BCD4">
          <enum>(A)</enum>
          <text>in the case of a Convention country, the application required pursuant to article 8 of the Hague Abduction Convention;</text>
        </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H34B8AD61210E4AEFA9880355687731F1">
          <enum>(B)</enum>
          <text>in the case of an MOU country, the formal document required pursuant to the provisions of the applicable MOU to request the return of an abducted child or to request rights of access, as applicable; and</text>
        </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H29B8161D890843479BB362FD90814A01">
          <enum>(C)</enum>
          <text>in the case of a nonparty country, the formal request by the Central Authority of the United States to the Central Authority of such country requesting the return of an abducted child or for rights of access to an abducted child.</text>
        </subparagraph>
      </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HF0F7EF42FE054842960AC998CBA1A651">
        <enum>(7)</enum>
        <header>Appropriate congressional committees</header>
        <text>The term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="committee" entity-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives</cato:entity-ref> and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="committee" entity-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
      </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H18B1A42C7AE44515812BF2DEEA9F4607">
        <enum>(8)</enum>
        <header>Central authority</header>
        <text>The term <term>Central Authority</term> means—</text>
<subparagraph id="H7519E9AFFA7F4B10BAE56B98A2E8555E">
          <enum>(A)</enum>
          <text>in the case of a Convention country, the meaning given such term in article 6 of the Hague Abduction Convention;</text>
        </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H2C3770DDC8774CA7B123BF3BA97DDB50">
          <enum>(B)</enum>
          <text>in the case of an MOU country, the official entity designated by the government of the MOU country within the applicable MOU pursuant to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2013/s:103/ss:b/p:1" proposed="true">section 103(b)(1)</cato:entity-ref> to discharge the duties imposed on the entity in such MOU; and</text>
        </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H671333B9E05E4131BB52114EC88B7857">
          <enum>(C)</enum>
          <text>in the case of a nonparty country, the foreign ministry of such country.</text>
        </subparagraph>
      </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H405FEC1FA73D420D9F8A11EA98EA044A">
        <enum>(9)</enum>
        <header>Child</header>
        <text>The term <term>child</term> means an individual who has not attained the age of 16.</text>
      </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HCE36E83EA5224219AC76C5DE14ECA059">
        <enum>(10)</enum>
        <header>Convention country</header>
        <text>The term <term>Convention country</term> means a country other than the United States that has ratified, acceded, or succeeded to the Hague Abduction Convention and with respect to which the United States has entered into a reciprocal agreement pursuant to the Hague Abduction Convention.</text>
      </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H4A584633DC134CDDA1C2FCB32E40CFE4">
        <enum>(11)</enum>
        <header>Hague abduction convention</header>
        <text>The term <term>Hague Abduction Convention</term> means the Convention on the Civil Aspects of International Child Abduction, done at The Hague on October 25, 1980.</text>
      </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H22E379126F2A4A8796325B00BC6408C1">
        <enum>(12)</enum>
        <header>Left-behind parent</header>
        <text>The term <term>left-behind parent</term> means an individual or entity, either individually or jointly, who alleges that an abduction has occurred that is in breach of rights of custody—</text>
<subparagraph id="HE3F59AF621A940C9A12D9EABC2C90C4B">
          <enum>(A)</enum>
          <text>attributed to such individual or entity, as applicable; and</text>
        </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HC3F91DEC08A244949361A9B1EEE5BD5E">
          <enum>(B)</enum>
          <text>exercised at the time of the abduction or that would have been exercised but for the abduction.</text>
        </subparagraph>
      </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HCBDC098577E1491B9C73E9730CBA3D04">
        <enum>(13)</enum>
        <header>Legal residence</header>
        <text>The term <term>legal residence</term> means the congressional district and State in which an individual either is residing, or if an individual is residing temporarily outside the United States, the congressional district and State to which the individual intends to return.</text>
      </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H82B5910195E04ACEA76F1EF85E023475">
        <enum>(14)</enum>
        <header>Military dependent child</header>
        <text>The term <term>military dependent child</term> means a child whose habitual residence is the United States according to United States law even though the child is residing outside the United States with a military parent.</text>
      </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HE75EB54D97FD46CB8131751C099FC9B4">
        <enum>(15)</enum>
        <header>Military parent</header>
        <text>The term <term>military parent</term> means an individual who has rights of custody over a child and who is serving outside the United States as a member of the United States Armed Forces.</text>
      </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HE2920F9A5773446D848A655D341964ED">
        <enum>(16)</enum>
        <header>MOU</header>
        <text>The term <term>MOU</term> means a memorandum of understanding between the United States and a country that is not a Convention country to resolve abduction cases and access cases.</text>
      </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H51B2632C9C704E3FB6139CE2E6298E05">
        <enum>(17)</enum>
        <header>MOU country</header>
        <text>The term <term>MOU country</term> means a country with respect to which the United States has entered into an MOU.</text>
      </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HCDE6EA216AAE4F148D1E0C1B3EF9FC1F">
        <enum>(18)</enum>
        <header>Nonparty country</header>
        <text>The term <term>nonparty country</term> means a country that is neither a Convention country nor an MOU country.</text>
      </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H6E78E52BA5DA4D9898B87EE32BE0E029">
        <enum>(19)</enum>
        <header>Pattern of noncooperation</header>
<subparagraph id="H5259B04240894631A485FBC003B57400">
          <enum>(A)</enum>
          <header>In general</header>
          <text>The term <term>pattern of noncooperation</term> means the persistent failure—</text>
<clause id="H88D897F2D4AA4B4EA32661E39A2806F9">
            <enum>(i)</enum>
            <text>of a Convention country to implement and abide by the provisions of the Hague Abduction Convention; and</text>
          </clause>
<clause id="H4BFAD7AF15D34457BAEF5C4D3CF690A9">
            <enum>(ii)</enum>
            <text>of an MOU country to implement and abide by the provisions of the applicable MOU.</text>
          </clause>
        </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H14AACEFD6E1A4C25B5BA734EC1F428DF">
          <enum>(B)</enum>
          <header>Criteria</header>
          <text>Such persistent failure may be evidenced by one or more of the following criteria:</text>
<clause id="H0CAF8CCE9F4B483EADCD53E166322014">
            <enum>(i)</enum>
            <text>The existence of 10 or more unresolved abduction cases.</text>
          </clause>
<clause id="H6C490DFDB199408AB6525EAEFAEF135F">
            <enum>(ii)</enum>
            <text>The failure of the Central Authority of the country to fulfill its responsibilities pursuant to the Hague Abduction Convention or the MOU, as applicable.</text>
          </clause>
<clause id="H1559B8BF9B1A4C7EBB6BEC8C3F87D390">
            <enum>(iii)</enum>
            <text>The failure of the judicial or administrative branch, as applicable, of the national government of the country to implement and comply with the provisions of the Hague Abduction Convention or the MOU, as applicable.</text>
          </clause>
<clause id="H1E228C005F5E4CFDB1FBD9C6142DE3F9">
            <enum>(iv)</enum>
            <text>The failure of law enforcement to locate abducted children or to enforce return orders or determinations of rights of access rendered by the judicial or administrative authorities of the national government of the country in abduction cases or access cases.</text>
          </clause>
        </subparagraph>
      </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H1803D30948BE4847A9DC47578BD18F14">
        <enum>(20)</enum>
        <header>Rights of access</header>
        <text>The term <term>rights of access</term> means the rights of contact between a child and a left-behind parent provided as a provisional measure while an abduction case is pending, by operation of law or by reason of judicial or administrative determination or by agreement having legal effect, under the law of the country in which the child is located.</text>
      </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HA64F072F9351403D995CB3385333DE15">
        <enum>(21)</enum>
        <header>Rights of custody</header>
        <text>The term <term>rights of custody</term> means rights of care and custody of an abducted child, including the right to determine the place of residence of an abducted child—</text>
<subparagraph id="HFC005F3A1F514870A7A75979658AC6E2">
          <enum>(A)</enum>
          <text>attributed to an individual or entity, either individually or jointly, and</text>
        </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H325B021B2B18455D968B9C7E2BD6870F">
          <enum>(B)</enum>
          <text>arising by operation of law or by reason of a judicial or administrative decision, or by reason of an agreement having legal effect,</text>
        </subparagraph>
        <continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph">under the law of the country in which the child was an habitual resident immediately before the abduction.</continuation-text>
      </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H0DAA95A15706416089F1C265678B0ED3">
        <enum>(22)</enum>
        <header>Unresolved abduction case</header>
<subparagraph id="H27F1B16F18B344209003B5F8A57916C8">
          <enum>(A)</enum>
          <header>In general</header>
          <text>Subject to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2013/s:3/p:22/sp:B" proposed="true">subparagraph (B)</cato:entity-ref>, the term <term>unresolved abduction case</term> means an abduction case that remains unresolved for a period that exceeds 180 days after the date on which the completed application for return of the child is submitted for determination to the judicial or administrative authority, as applicable, in the country in which the child is located.</text>
        </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H67721313BDB940C3AD7E76CAA4D5E575">
          <enum>(B)</enum>
          <header>Resolution of case</header>
          <text>An abduction case shall be considered to be resolved if—</text>
<clause id="H1D9418D6E8DB41A7979BE8B32BE0E0C8">
            <enum>(i)</enum>
            <text>the child is returned to the country of habitual residence, pursuant to the Hague Abduction Convention or MOU, if applicable;</text>
          </clause>
<clause id="H68E94C263EEF4C2E85196E95E6C3ED79">
            <enum>(ii)</enum>
            <text>the judicial or administrative branch, as applicable, of the national government of the country in which the child is located has implemented and is complying with the provisions of the Hague Abduction Convention or the MOU, as applicable, and a final determination is made by such judicial or administrative branch that the child will not be returned to the country of habitual residence; or</text>
          </clause>
<clause id="H0D4D9E5009D247488D28404711F0F9DF">
            <enum>(iii)</enum>
            <text>the child attains the age of 16.</text>
          </clause>
        </subparagraph>
      </paragraph>
    </section>
<title id="HBD1310EA24124B0698AB80A61A08F0AE">
      <enum>I</enum>
      <header>Department of State Actions</header>
<section id="H20E247A528AF4A2D831953A8D1197CCA">
        <enum>101.</enum>
        <header>Annual report</header>
<subsection id="HE51DD4DFFF5749BDB480696021006876">
          <enum>(a)</enum>
          <header>In general</header>
          <text>Not later than March 31 of each year, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref> shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees an Annual Report on International Child Abduction.</text>
        </subsection>
<subsection id="H16AE36286739486BB782CEF6CCC35123">
          <enum>(b)</enum>
          <header>Contents</header>
          <text>Each Annual Report shall include the following:</text>
<paragraph id="H6332A49470F749DFAE21D8919F32A9A9">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A list of all countries with respect to which there were one or more abduction cases during the preceding year that identifies whether each such country is a Convention country, an MOU country, or a nonparty country.</text>
          </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H33586BB1049F4A78928F8085C32E99E3">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <text>For each country with respect to which there were 5 or more abduction cases during the preceding year:</text>
<subparagraph id="HF6EE1AFDD58249C692F176C8F43FFFC3">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>The number of abduction cases and the number of access cases, respectively, reported during the preceding year.</text>
            </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H6E7F43C2A1504DF69B072F77F0713C54">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>The number of abduction cases and the number of access cases, respectively, that are pending as of March 1 of the year in which such Annual Report is submitted.</text>
            </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H62D684B87D7D499A9B9D4C3EF28E6083">
              <enum>(C)</enum>
<clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H9B4EC29BE0104F89A8441ED17CB9A194">
                <enum>(i)</enum>
                <text>For Convention and MOU countries, the number of abduction cases and the number of access cases, respectively, that were pending at any point for more than 180 days after the date on which the Central Authority of the United States transmitted the complete application for each such case to the Central Authority of such country, and were not submitted by the Central Authority to the judicial or administrative authority, as applicable, of such country within the 180-day period.</text>
              </clause>
<clause id="HB42324CA990942D1B688F957E66A26E7" indent="up1">
                <enum>(ii)</enum>
                <text>The reason for the delay in submission of each case identified in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2013/s:101/ss:b/p:2/sp:C/cl:i" proposed="true">clause (i)</cato:entity-ref> by the Central Authority of such country to the judicial or administrative authority.</text>
              </clause>
            </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H432B0B0BECF44865B0F99A078C211E0E">
              <enum>(D)</enum>
              <text>The number of unresolved abduction cases, and the length of time each case has been pending.</text>
            </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HBBEF961F01DD4AA2A1E11CC0752FFA91">
              <enum>(E)</enum>
              <text>The number of unresolved abduction cases in which a completed application has been filed and law enforcement has failed to locate the abducted child or to enforce a return order rendered by the judicial or administrative authorities of such country.</text>
            </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H83132CA099BA472A959F74122ADC3DA3">
              <enum>(F)</enum>
              <text>The median time required for resolution of abduction cases during the preceding year, to be measured from the date on which the application with respect to the abduction case is transmitted by the Central Authority of the United States to the Central Authority of such country to the date on which the abduction case is resolved.</text>
            </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H87A969E385024701AA9B7A04700A6A0D">
              <enum>(G)</enum>
              <text>The total number and the percentage of the total number of abduction cases and access cases, respectively, resolved during the preceding year.</text>
            </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HBEC60D41F2114DA6B95F4FB7DB48AC3A">
              <enum>(H)</enum>
              <text>Detailed information about each unresolved abduction case described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2013/s:101/ss:b/p:2/sp:E" proposed="true">subparagraph (E)</cato:entity-ref> and on actions taken by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Department of State</cato:entity-ref> to resolve such case, including the specific actions taken by the United States chief of mission in such country.</text>
            </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H07EDB71534F14215A6BD5106E61B38BA">
              <enum>(I)</enum>
              <text>Recommendations to improve resolution of abduction cases and access cases.</text>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HAA9BC3B40C8747A19F24420C31CF26CD">
            <enum>(3)</enum>
            <text>The number of abducted children from the United States who were returned to the United States from Convention countries, MOU countries, and nonparty countries, respectively.</text>
          </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HB3C7CE3B51E0493591C224794F07F294">
            <enum>(4)</enum>
            <text>A list of Convention countries and MOU countries that have failed to comply with any of their obligations under the Hague Abduction Convention or the MOU, as applicable, with respect to the resolution of abduction cases and access cases.</text>
          </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H4E6B06C2C3A64DE683028CAF5F17D6BA">
            <enum>(5)</enum>
            <text>A list of countries demonstrating a pattern of noncooperation, and a summary of the criteria on which the determination of a pattern of noncooperation for each country is based.</text>
          </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HA15A8E2E95A74370B1F74BAE8F78B829">
            <enum>(6)</enum>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H02B1833D924F466FA8BAF3805BA386F5">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>Information on efforts by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref> to encourage other countries to become signatories to the Hague Abduction Convention or to enter into an MOU.</text>
            </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HA05B5BD8232144CEA9E6AD6524393D4A" indent="up1">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>The efforts referred to in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2013/s:101/ss:b/p:6/sp:A" proposed="true">subparagraph (A)</cato:entity-ref> shall include efforts to address pending abduction cases and access cases in such countries.</text>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HCE0695E0C17E45469CFE54A9089F0AB5">
            <enum>(7)</enum>
            <text>A description of the efforts of the Secretary of State to encourage Convention countries and MOU countries to facilitate the work of nongovernmental organizations within their respective countries that assist left-behind parents.</text>
          </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H8EEEC49080A74B6F8651C986B249F3E0">
            <enum>(8)</enum>
            <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The number of cases which were successfully resolved without abducted children being returned to the United States from Convention countries, MOU countries, and nonparty countries, respectively.</text>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
<subsection id="HEE7330F1494C46188DD704DCEAE681ED">
          <enum>(c)</enum>
          <header>Exception</header>
          <text>The Annual Report shall not include—</text>
<paragraph id="H97B483BB8BC34A33AEF8006491336F54">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <text>the names of left-behind parents or children involved in abduction cases or access cases; or</text>
          </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H63D79BD7B53642859E605935B1DBD472">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <text>information that may identify a party involved in an abduction case or access case unless the party stipulates in writing to the Central Authority of the United States that such information may be included in the Annual Report.</text>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
<subsection id="H26E3A80989BF47B38A1DED13E431DBEF">
          <enum>(d)</enum>
          <header>Additional thematic sections</header>
          <text>Each Annual Report shall also include—</text>
<paragraph id="HB2F878416F4A4849AB3CF482E54AB3F7">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <text>information on the number of unresolved abduction cases affecting left-behind parents who are military parents and a summary of assistance offered to such left-behind parents;</text>
          </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H021C0CE1BAC5443A9D5485063A91382E">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <text>information on the use of airlines in abductions, voluntary airline practices to prevent abductions, and recommendations for best airline practices to prevent abductions;</text>
          </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H3AF2BC7A29E34D0A8AB312703A68F091">
            <enum>(3)</enum>
            <text>information on actions taken by the Central Authority of the United States to train domestic judges in application of the Hague Abduction Convention; and</text>
          </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H2866842C9DA849B0A3B1A633DABCB2B6">
            <enum>(4)</enum>
            <text>information on actions taken by the Central Authority of the United States to train United States Armed Forces legal assistance personnel, military chaplains, and military family support center personnel about abductions, the risk of loss of access to children, and the legal frameworks available to resolve such cases.</text>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
<subsection id="H9D6F76C652E344B39158A5E85B338711">
          <enum>(e)</enum>
          <header>Repeal of the Hague Convention Compliance Report</header>
          <text>
            <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Foreign Affairs Reform and Restructuring Act of 1998/s:2803">Section 2803 of the Foreign Affairs Reform and Restructuring Act of 1998</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/11611">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/42/11611">42 U.S.C. 11611</cato:entity-ref>
            </external-xref>)</cato:entity> is repealed.</text>
        </subsection>
      </section>
<section id="H9DCE5FF6F5B24E4D8FCF401833728BB3">
        <enum>102.</enum>
        <header>Standards and assistance</header>
        <text display-inline="no-display-inline">The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref> shall ensure that United States diplomatic and consular missions abroad—</text>
<paragraph id="H2B1BE28A63244DF1B2BB1074166F8AA2">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>maintain a consistent reporting standard with respect to abduction cases and access cases involving abducted children in the country in which such mission is located for purposes of the Annual Report;</text>
        </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H9F0AB0ABE98541C1BB10FD16C7D2076B">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>designate at least one official in each such mission to assist left-behind parents from the United States who are visiting such country to resolve cases involving an abduction or rights of access; and</text>
        </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H9A8D897BE2F04B459A9AB8774492B641">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <text>monitor developments in cases involving abducted children in the country in which such mission is located.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </section>
<section id="H9A0C6542324E44A7AC386B1E78D7EAE2">
        <enum>103.</enum>
        <header>Memorandum of understanding</header>
<subsection id="H505A8AECC4B340C39DE58D7A0724DC02">
          <enum>(a)</enum>
          <header>In general</header>
          <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref> should seek to enter into an MOU with every country that is not a Convention country and is unlikely to become a Convention country in the forseeable future, that includes—</text>
<paragraph id="H23159743C6D047338AB7038138A218A9">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <text>identification of the Central Authority;</text>
          </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H8FB665A00A4449629976FFA7037A452E">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <text>a protocol to identify, locate, and effectuate the return of an abducted child identified in an abduction case not later than 6 weeks after the application with respect to the abduction case has been submitted to the judicial or administrative authority, as applicable, of the country in which the abducted child is located;</text>
          </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H3970F2E541A1481F946455C02551ED70">
            <enum>(3)</enum>
            <text>a protocol for the establishment and protection of the rights of access;</text>
          </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HD60737F902D447958B10D8C091379E5F">
            <enum>(4)</enum>
            <text>identification of the judicial or administrative authority that will promptly adjudicate abduction cases and access cases;</text>
          </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HAA70BB8CDBDE4D5688E9405475101628">
            <enum>(5)</enum>
            <text>identification of a law enforcement agency and available law enforcement mechanisms and procedures to ensure the immediate enforcement of an order issued by the authority identified pursuant to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2013/s:103/ss:a/p:4" proposed="true">paragraph (4)</cato:entity-ref> to return an abducted child to a left-behind parent, including by—</text>
<subparagraph id="H050DF1B05AE349A3860E5BAD36C4F507">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>conducting an investigation to ascertain the location of the abducted child;</text>
            </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H3DA51D1313C744409DE8FF90D57BDD7F">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>providing protection to the abducted child after such child is located; and</text>
            </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HD4EDD76BEE164A958930555AB44CC014">
              <enum>(C)</enum>
              <text>retrieving the abducted child and making the appropriate arrangements for such child to be returned to the country of habitual residence;</text>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H466AF3B2554E4B31B47DB497CC38B764">
            <enum>(6)</enum>
            <text>a protocol to establish periodic visits between a United States embassy or consular official and an abducted child to allow the official to ascertain the child’s location and welfare; and</text>
          </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HCF245FBB7FCA4AECB16F69925583117C">
            <enum>(7)</enum>
            <text>such other provisions as determined to be appropriate by the Secretary of State.</text>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
<subsection id="H242CC0D7CBED4166A19EEDCB77F89AC2">
          <enum>(b)</enum>
          <header>Rule of construction</header>
<paragraph id="H5155F98B01CA45E1A88842D97AF09F12">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <header>In general</header>
            <text>Nothing in this Act shall be construed to prohibit the United States from proposing and entering into a memorandum of understanding with a Convention country to further clarify the reciprocal obligations of the United States and the Convention country under the Hague Abduction Convention.</text>
          </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HFC49F7A90D78423EA2751A40DE28B083">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <header>Treatment of obligations of convention country</header>
            <text>In those instances in which there is a memorandum of understanding as described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2013/s:103/ss:b/p:1" proposed="true">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref>, the obligations of the Convention country under such memorandum shall be considered to be obligations of such country under the Hague Abduction Convention for purposes of this Act.</text>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
      </section>
<section id="H566CB1E271094287833A4A18CDFBC174">
        <enum>104.</enum>
        <header>Notification of congressional representatives</header>
<subsection id="H9C73FE9B0B0B4D32BE33DC90CB60A281">
          <enum>(a)</enum>
          <header>Notification</header>
          <text>Except as provided in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2013/s:104/ss:b" proposed="true">subsection (b)</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref> shall notify in writing the Member of Congress and Senators representing the legal residence of a left-behind parent when such parent reports an abduction to the Central Authority of the United States.</text>
        </subsection>
<subsection id="H2BC0AE6F098A4DB298A3D34D92087147">
          <enum>(b)</enum>
          <header>Exception</header>
          <text>The notification requirement under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2013/s:104/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref> shall not apply if the left-behind parent does not consent to the notification described in such subsection.</text>
        </subsection>
<subsection id="H142B0396DA4A4FBFB655555AB9BAC3CD">
          <enum>(c)</enum>
          <header>Timing</header>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">At the request of any person who is a left-behind parent, including a left-behind parent who previously reported an abduction to the Central Authority of the United States before the date of the enactment of this Act, notification of a Member of Congress, in accordance with <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2013/s:104/ss:a" proposed="true">subsections (a)</cato:entity-ref> and <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2013/s:104/ss:b" proposed="true">(b)</cato:entity-ref>, shall be provided as soon as is practicable.</text>
        </subsection>
<subsection id="HF6DD4DFCD1EB40ECB2E604B129067ABB">
          <enum>(d)</enum>
          <header>Member of congress defined</header>
          <text>In this section, the term <term>Member of Congress</term> means a Representative in, or Delegate or Resident Commissioner to, the Congress.</text>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </title>
<title id="HDFBCFDBF572F48D48C72C8052182CC54">
      <enum>II</enum>
      <header>Presidential Actions</header>
<section id="H5AC567E29CC34585AA9015B8EF9FD1EF">
        <enum>201.</enum>
        <header>Presidential actions in response to unresolved cases</header>
<subsection id="H402017D245904A27A1107605AF09030D">
          <enum>(a)</enum>
          <header>Response to international child abductions</header>
<paragraph id="HB3361908C93E4B219DF851E596FCAB97">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <header>United states policy</header>
            <text>It shall be the policy of the United States to—</text>
<subparagraph id="HAB55D28DB5014044B23E4FD77447E2B5">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>promote the best interest of children abducted from the United States by establishing legal rights and procedures for their prompt return and by promoting such rights and procedures through actions that ensure the enforcement of reciprocal international obligations; and</text>
            </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H56D89909243543BFBF2F7ADDA8A3BC35">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>recognize the international character of the Hague Abduction Convention, and the need for reciprocity pursuant to and the uniform international interpretation of the Hague Abduction Convention, by promoting the timely resolution of abduction cases through one or more of the actions described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2013/s:205" proposed="true">section 205</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H14D452C529E24BFCB1B58D4B84393647">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <header>Requirement of presidential action</header>
            <text>Whenever the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> determines that the government of a foreign country has failed to resolve an unresolved abduction case, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> shall oppose such failure through one or more of the actions described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2013/s:201/ss:b" proposed="true">subsection (b)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
<subsection id="H631A5D68C36146A898CAD3A7B006286A">
          <enum>(b)</enum>
          <header>Presidential actions</header>
<paragraph id="H973011AE509040F29E9D9E327905B24A">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <header>In general</header>
            <text>Subject to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2013/s:201/ss:b/p:2" proposed="true">paragraphs (2)</cato:entity-ref> and <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2013/s:201/ss:b/p:3" proposed="true">(3)</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref>, in consultation with the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref>, shall, as expeditiously as practicable in response to the failure described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2013/s:201/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref> by the government of a foreign country, take one or more of the actions described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2013/s:205/ss:a/p:1..13" proposed="true">paragraphs (1) through (13) of section 205(a)</cato:entity-ref> (or commensurate action as provided in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2013/s:205/ss:b" proposed="true">section 205(b)</cato:entity-ref>) with respect to such country.</text>
          </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H0D3FDB8E0A16438BA1AAD4490DA08AC5">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <header>Deadline for actions</header>
<subparagraph id="HFA631730D7CE45028546A4C942E0858E">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <header>In general</header>
              <text>Except as provided in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2013/s:201/ss:b/p:2/sp:B" proposed="true">subparagraph (B)</cato:entity-ref>, not later than March 31 of each year, the President shall take one or more of the actions described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2013/s:205/ss:a/p:1..13" proposed="true">paragraphs (1) through (13) of section 205(a)</cato:entity-ref> (or commensurate action as provided in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2013/s:205/ss:b" proposed="true">section 205(b)</cato:entity-ref>) with respect to each foreign country the government of which has failed to resolve an unresolved abduction case that is pending as of such date.</text>
            </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HA6B3F2EF620049D89AAF258E61DBC48F">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <header>Exception</header>
              <text>In the case of an action under any of <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2013/s:205/ss:a/p:10..13" proposed="true">paragraphs (10) through (13) of section 205(a)</cato:entity-ref> (or commensurate action as provided in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2013/s:205/ss:b" proposed="true">section 205(b)</cato:entity-ref>)—</text>
<clause id="HA382411AE0414BBBB6079713B94F884F">
                <enum>(i)</enum>
                <text>the action may only be taken after the requirements of <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2013/s:203" proposed="true">sections 203</cato:entity-ref> and <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2013/s:204" proposed="true">204</cato:entity-ref> have been satisfied; and</text>
              </clause>
<clause id="H47C698AB347A4FEC9EAEEC6DF162699C">
                <enum>(ii)</enum>
                <text>the March 31 deadline to take the action shall not apply.</text>
              </clause>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H7C51A44845984A4FA2C8D686628A13AC">
            <enum>(3)</enum>
            <header>Authority for delay of presidential actions</header>
            <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> may delay action described in any of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2013/s:205/ss:a/p:10..13" proposed="true">paragraphs (10) through (13) of section 205(a)</cato:entity-ref> (or commensurate action as provided in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2013/s:205/ss:b" proposed="true">section 205(b)</cato:entity-ref>), as required under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2013/s:201/ss:b/p:2" proposed="true">paragraph (2)</cato:entity-ref>, if the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> determines and certifies to the appropriate congressional committees that an additional, specified period of time is necessary for a continuation of negotiations that have been commenced with the country to resolve the unresolved case.</text>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
<subsection id="H1D81EF2789E84E6783AFB3FD1C17D2BE">
          <enum>(c)</enum>
          <header>Implementation</header>
<paragraph id="H7FA2BDFDD12E41B78BD59264C7873C34">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <header>In general</header>
            <text>In carrying out <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2013/s:201/ss:b" proposed="true">subsection (b)</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> shall—</text>
<subparagraph id="H7F4347737FDC475E904AABF5138534F3">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>take one or more actions that most appropriately respond to the nature and severity of the failure to resolve the unresolved abduction cases; and</text>
            </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H063B2A39732A406FBA11988ECAD1FC82">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>seek to the fullest extent possible to target action as narrowly as practicable with respect to the agencies or instrumentalities of the foreign government that are responsible for such failures, in ways that respect the separation of powers and independence of the judiciary in foreign countries.</text>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H7A8ACDDA6C424E159513A3A9883DC618">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <header>Guidelines for presidential actions</header>
            <text>In addition to the guidelines under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2013/s:201/ss:c/p:1" proposed="true">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref>, in determining whether to take one or more actions under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2013/s:205/ss:a/p:10..13" proposed="true">paragraphs (10) through (13) of section 205(a)</cato:entity-ref> (or commensurate action as provided in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2013/s:205/ss:b" proposed="true">section 205(b)</cato:entity-ref>), shall seek to minimize any adverse impact on—</text>
<subparagraph id="HC364DBE92CBF49B6847D55943B3B3238">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>the population of the country whose government is targeted by the action or actions; and</text>
            </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HFB67359DA7C34CB2AFBA4348977FBD6F">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>the humanitarian activities of United States and foreign nongovernmental organizations in the country.</text>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
      </section>
<section id="HB02DBD03717244459C91DA48C79DEBAE">
        <enum>202.</enum>
        <header>Presidential actions in response to patterns of noncooperation in cases of international child abductions</header>
<subsection id="H9BEEEFF303634263A3725EC2B5252E55">
          <enum>(a)</enum>
          <header>Response to a pattern of noncooperation</header>
<paragraph id="HB3585652FA0143BC9B3B97FAF66D3DA6">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <header>United states policy</header>
            <text>It shall be the policy of the United States to—</text>
<subparagraph id="H7A25D5DF43264417B5D7C452C2F3266E">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>oppose institutional or other systemic failures of foreign governments to fulfill their obligations pursuant to the Hague Abduction Convention or MOU, as applicable, to resolve abduction cases and access cases; and</text>
            </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H150058514FFA4CB2AD0FE14152A3BEB8">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>promote reciprocity pursuant to and compliance with the Hague Abduction Convention by Convention countries and compliance with the applicable MOU by MOU countries.</text>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H825BD91B9CDA45729EAECD5895ACDCA4">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <header>Requirement of presidential action</header>
            <text>Whenever the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> determines that the government of a foreign country has engaged in a pattern of noncooperation, the President shall promote the resolution of the unresolved abduction cases through one or more of the actions described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2013/s:202/ss:c" proposed="true">subsection (c)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
<subsection id="H7CBD639FB83C481A90A1D7B5620F968A">
          <enum>(b)</enum>
          <header>Designations of countries with patterns of noncooperation in cases of international child abduction</header>
<paragraph id="HB148BD0FF4B348319760A69F4FAAA8C9">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <header>Annual review</header>
<subparagraph id="HD1E9D81838274AD08079981AA299EA7F">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <header>In general</header>
              <text>Not later than March 31 of each year, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> shall review the status of abduction cases and access cases in each foreign country to determine whether the government of such country has engaged in a pattern of noncooperation during the preceding 12 months or since the date of the last review of such country under this subparagraph, whichever period is longer. The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> shall designate each country the government of which has engaged in a pattern of noncooperation as a Country With a Pattern of Noncooperation.</text>
            </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H2E5EEB3755C541AC9A1E988307065493">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <header>Basis of review</header>
              <text>Each review conducted under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2013/s:202/ss:b/p:1/sp:A" proposed="true">subparagraph (A)</cato:entity-ref> shall be based upon information contained in the latest Annual Report and on any other evidence available.</text>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HF65FA4D82A5145349DA59E773E1502EA">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <header>Determinations of responsible parties</header>
            <text>For the government of each country designated as a Country With a Pattern of Noncooperation under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2013/s:202/ss:b/p:1/sp:A" proposed="true">paragraph (1)(A)</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> shall seek to determine the agencies or instrumentalities of such government that are responsible for the pattern of noncooperation by such government in order to appropriately target actions under this section in response.</text>
          </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H1977229144704FEA8DA484E9FED09715">
            <enum>(3)</enum>
            <header>Congressional notification</header>
            <text>Whenever the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> designates a country as a Country With a Pattern of Noncooperation under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2013/s:202/ss:b/p:1/sp:A" proposed="true">paragraph (1)(A)</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> shall, as soon as practicable after such designation is made, transmit to the appropriate congressional committees—</text>
<subparagraph id="HAA28529CEB0543F8A4030914FBD23B96">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>the designation of the country, signed by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref>; and</text>
            </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HEBB2211D59654CE8ABA71C90EB69F113">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>the identification, if any, of responsible agencies or instrumentalities determined under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2013/s:202/ss:b/p:2" proposed="true">paragraph (2)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
<subsection id="HE5ABFDB8739D46109D5DAC7CD9A4EE49">
          <enum>(c)</enum>
          <header>Presidential actions with respect to a country with a pattern of noncooperation</header>
<paragraph id="H3074053DCA5B450DA1B35F6C2B462566">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <header>In general</header>
            <text>Subject to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2013/s:202/ss:c/p:2" proposed="true">paragraphs (2)</cato:entity-ref> and <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2013/s:202/ss:c/p:3" proposed="true">(3)</cato:entity-ref> with respect to each Country With a Pattern of Noncooperation designated under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2013/s:202/ss:b/p:1/sp:A" proposed="true">subsection (b)(1)(A)</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> shall, after the requirements of <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2013/s:203" proposed="true">sections 203</cato:entity-ref> and <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2013/s:204" proposed="true">204</cato:entity-ref> have been satisfied, but not later than 90 days (or 180 days in case of a delay under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2013/s:202/ss:c/p:2" proposed="true">paragraph (2)</cato:entity-ref>) after the date of such designation of the country under such subsection, take one or more of the actions under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2013/s:205/ss:a/p:10..13" proposed="true">paragraphs (10) through (13) of section 205(a)</cato:entity-ref> (or commensurate action as provided in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2013/s:205/ss:b" proposed="true">section 205(b)</cato:entity-ref>).</text>
          </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H9AF578D89CF240B597F700B435AC919A">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <header>Authority for delay of presidential actions</header>
            <text>If, on or before the date that the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> is required to take action under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2013/s:202/ss:c/p:1" proposed="true">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> determines and certifies to the appropriate congressional committees that a single, additional period of time not to exceed 90 days is necessary—</text>
<subparagraph id="H1139F8A764AD4C6A872BF78359F4858B">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>for a continuation of negotiations that have been commenced with the government of a country described in such paragraph to bring about a cessation of the pattern of noncooperation by such country, or</text>
            </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HDF13493794FE4342848829D8047F9AF0">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>for a review of corrective action taken by such country after designation of such country as a Country With a Pattern of Noncooperation under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2013/s:202/ss:b/p:1/sp:A" proposed="true">subsection (b)(1)(A)</cato:entity-ref> or in anticipation that corrective action will be taken by such country during such 90-day period,</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph">the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> shall not be required to take such action until the expiration of such period of time.</continuation-text>
          </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H1E16265AE3D34EA08EAD923260DA383C">
            <enum>(3)</enum>
            <header>Exception for ongoing presidential action</header>
<subparagraph id="HC87D1F4988464F7EB433D605869D95A8">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <header>In general</header>
              <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> shall not be required to take action under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2013/s:202/ss:c/p:1" proposed="true">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref> with respect to a Country With a Pattern of Noncooperation if—</text>
<clause id="H7B919F6CBEBB4623B964EBED40EBD70B">
                <enum>(i)</enum>
                <text>the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> has taken action pursuant to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2013/s:202/ss:c/p:1" proposed="true">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref> with respect to such country in a preceding year, such action is in effect at the time such country is designated as a Country with a Pattern of Noncooperation under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2013/s:202/ss:b/p:1/sp:A" proposed="true">subsection (b)(1)(A)</cato:entity-ref>, and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> submits to the appropriate congressional committees the information described in section 204 regarding the actions in effect with respect to such country; or</text>
              </clause>
<clause id="H2DC47FC50CA14CC5BAFA569C6FDCC021">
                <enum>(ii)</enum>
                <text>subject to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2013/s:202/ss:c/p:3/sp:B" proposed="true">subparagraph (B)</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> determines that such country is subject to multiple, broad-based sanctions imposed in significant part in response to human rights abuses and that such sanctions also satisfy the requirements of this subsection.</text>
              </clause>
            </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H539AA86E0C484CC2A3B34771283E64B2">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <header>Additional requirements</header>
              <text>If the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> makes a determination under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2013/s:202/ss:c/p:3/sp:A/cl:ii" proposed="true">subparagraph (A)(ii)</cato:entity-ref>—</text>
<clause id="H7124EA476A234009B262C9F0BDA10966">
                <enum>(i)</enum>
                <text>the report under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2013/s:204" proposed="true">section 204</cato:entity-ref> and, as applicable, the publication in the Federal Register under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2013/s:208" proposed="true">section 208</cato:entity-ref>, shall specify the specific sanction or sanctions that the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> has determined satisfy the requirements of this subsection; and</text>
              </clause>
<clause id="HCA9805046F9D41D6B09EB1CE61F474AA">
                <enum>(ii)</enum>
                <text>such sanctions shall remain in effect subject to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2013/s:209" proposed="true">section 209</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
              </clause>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
<subsection id="HD92E4B644CD54F09B992ED2DCF8DD864">
          <enum>(d)</enum>
          <header>Rule of construction</header>
          <text>A determination under this section that a foreign country has engaged in a pattern of noncooperation shall not be construed to require the termination of assistance or other activities with respect to such country under any other provision of law, including <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Foreign Assistance Act of 1961/s:116">section 116</cato:entity-ref> or <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Foreign Assistance Act of 1961/s:502B">502B of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2151">
              <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc/22/2151/n">22 U.S.C. 2151(n)</cato:entity-ref>
            </external-xref> or <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc/22/2304">2304</cato:entity-ref>).</text>
        </subsection>
      </section>
<section id="H736055E091D34FE799A9D3087BDB1DB6">
        <enum>203.</enum>
        <header>Consultations with foreign governments</header>
        <text display-inline="no-display-inline">As soon as practicable after the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> makes a determination under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2013/s:201" proposed="true">section 201</cato:entity-ref> in response to failures to resolve unresolved abduction cases and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> decides to take action under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2013/s:205/ss:a/p:10..13" proposed="true">paragraphs (10) through (13) of section 205(a)</cato:entity-ref> (or commensurate action as provided in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2013/s:205/ss:b" proposed="true">section 205(b)</cato:entity-ref>) with respect to that country, or not later than 90 days after the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> designates a country as a country with a pattern of noncooperation pursuant to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2013/s:202/ss:b/p:1/sp:a" proposed="true">section 202(b)(1)(a)</cato:entity-ref>, the President shall—</text>
<paragraph id="HE12F921A394B4980A5AA674E2EF89FA0">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>request consultation with the government of such country regarding the failures giving rise to designation of that country as a Country With a Pattern of Noncooperation regarding the pattern of noncooperation or to action under section 201; and</text>
        </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H1545031B36A54B1D889EB71023065AF0">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>if agreed to, enter into such consultations with such country, privately or publicly.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </section>
<section id="H4E6C8EAA5B52459CBA89C38BF83A5762">
        <enum>204.</enum>
        <header>Report to Congress</header>
<subsection id="H871CCEB258C045C4A7D402EFAF819D4B">
          <enum>(a)</enum>
          <header>In general</header>
          <text>Subject to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2013/s:204/ss:b" proposed="true">subsection (b)</cato:entity-ref>, not later than 90 days after the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> makes a determination under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2013/s:201">section 201</cato:entity-ref> in response to failures to resolve unresolved abduction cases and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> decides to take action under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2013/s:205/ss:a/p:10..13" proposed="true">paragraphs (10) through (13) of section 205(a)</cato:entity-ref> (or commensurate action as provided in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2013/s:205/ss:b" proposed="true">section 205(b)</cato:entity-ref>) with respect to that country, or not later than 90 days after the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> designates a country as a Country With a Pattern of Noncooperation pursuant to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2013/s:202/ss:b/p:1/sp:A" proposed="true">section 202(b)(1)(A)</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> shall transmit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on the following:</text>
<paragraph id="HDCCE1914688E4547B22690E5E0FD36BE">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <header>Identification of presidential actions</header>
            <text>An identification of the action or actions described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2013/s:205/ss:a" proposed="true">section 205(a)</cato:entity-ref> (or commensurate action as provided in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2013/s:205/ss:b" proposed="true">section 205(b)</cato:entity-ref>) to be taken with respect to such country.</text>
          </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H2DE45FECBC0342B5ACF2078F9093BB3C">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <header>Description of violations</header>
            <text>A description of the failure to resolve an unresolved case or the pattern of noncooperation, as applicable, giving rise to the action or actions to be taken by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
          </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H23A064C59E514CA2B8B508BD2D21CAFF">
            <enum>(3)</enum>
            <header>Purpose of presidential actions</header>
            <text>A description of the purpose of the action or actions.</text>
          </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H0C052E75EA194739B500BD7D0441A0B1">
            <enum>(4)</enum>
            <header>Evaluation</header>
<subparagraph id="HC81643D234184D45836E42C5EF4BC173">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <header>Description</header>
              <text>An evaluation, in consultation with the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref>, the parties described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2013/s:203/ss:b" proposed="true">section 203(b)</cato:entity-ref>, and other parties the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> determines appropriate, of the anticipated impact of the Presidential action upon—</text>
<clause id="HEAADB5A0A3264D4B93FC7419A975A6FA">
                <enum>(i)</enum>
                <text>pending abduction cases in such country;</text>
              </clause>
<clause id="HE3B8DA21D4624E21820287843967A641">
                <enum>(ii)</enum>
                <text>the government of such country;</text>
              </clause>
<clause id="HC83469EC10664E3DB2DA9801B873B3E8">
                <enum>(iii)</enum>
                <text>the population of such country;</text>
              </clause>
<clause id="H5683333CEA6B42368D8FAEE4D16B9C79">
                <enum>(iv)</enum>
                <text>the United States economy;</text>
              </clause>
<clause id="H4FE5B9345FD240AEA4FBFB1E4F3DB469">
                <enum>(v)</enum>
                <text>other interested parties; and</text>
              </clause>
<clause id="H24190E540E9A49D6A12CD221B891B627">
                <enum>(vi)</enum>
                <text>if such country is a Convention country or an MOU country, the reciprocal fulfillment of obligations pursuant to such Convention or applicable MOU, as applicable.</text>
              </clause>
            </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HF1EFE88B8DDA48EEA379BDFDFD5A423A">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <header>Form</header>
              <text>The evaluation under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2013/s:204/ss:a/p:4/sp:A" proposed="true">subparagraph (A)</cato:entity-ref> shall be transmitted in unclassified form, but may contain a classified annex if necessary.</text>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H53D58CBC7F604D7F8BDD5099F25CF3CB">
            <enum>(5)</enum>
            <header>Statement of policy options</header>
            <text>A statement that noneconomic policy options designed to resolve the unresolved case or bring about the cessation of the pattern of noncooperation have reasonably been exhausted, including the consultations required in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2013/s:203" proposed="true">section 203</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
<subsection id="H7D0407F6B71D412FB5E0AFE848DA166B">
          <enum>(b)</enum>
          <header>Delay in transmittal of report</header>
          <text>If, on or before the date that the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> is required to submit a report under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2013/s:204/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref> to the appropriate congressional committees, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> determines and certifies to such committees that a single, additional period of time not to exceed 90 days is necessary pursuant to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2013/s:202/ss:c/p:2" proposed="true">section 202(c)(2)</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> shall not be required to submit the report to such committees until the expiration of such period of time.</text>
        </subsection>
      </section>
<section id="H6A892B19D7294BEFAD364D1A17D73CCF">
        <enum>205.</enum>
        <header>Presidential actions</header>
<subsection id="HB2B3D19B8D8743F991DBFF61B95D6EA1">
          <enum>(a)</enum>
          <header>Description of presidential actions</header>
          <text>Except as provided in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2013/s:205/ss:c" proposed="true">subsection (c)</cato:entity-ref>, the Presidential actions referred to in this subsection are the following:</text>
<paragraph id="HFA55845DAF3B44C1A0D03A500EEED471">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <text>A private demarche.</text>
          </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H2A99434AD5524CBF843AF83F62340D5A">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <text>An official public demarche.</text>
          </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H0F8B81433A9846A98F61818171B00BCA">
            <enum>(3)</enum>
            <text>A public condemnation.</text>
          </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HAE34A11864DF4207B088B020964B0A17">
            <enum>(4)</enum>
            <text>A public condemnation within one or more multilateral fora.</text>
          </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H8BCA00867D184CB8ABD11CE63201C54F">
            <enum>(5)</enum>
            <text>The delay or cancellation of one or more scientific exchanges.</text>
          </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H879D5A224A004A6F9430EBE9117AB0AC">
            <enum>(6)</enum>
            <text>The delay or cancellation of one or more cultural exchanges.</text>
          </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H54BA47A9BEEC4CD1BC3CF799632529E1">
            <enum>(7)</enum>
            <text>The denial of one or more working, official, or state visits.</text>
          </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HB318C675AF154FA1A74E0F5CC5073F92">
            <enum>(8)</enum>
            <text>The delay or cancellation of one or more working, official, or state visits.</text>
          </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H6A6B4E092E244310A96C9069F08749CB">
            <enum>(9)</enum>
            <text>A formal request to the foreign country concerned to extradite an individual who is engaged in abduction and who has been formally accused of, charged with, or convicted of an extraditable offense.</text>
          </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HF3E7E1A633F8440C81E7EE188D452AB4">
            <enum>(10)</enum>
            <text>The withdrawal, limitation, or suspension of United States development assistance in accordance with <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Foreign Assistance Act of 1961/s:116">section 116 of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2151n">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/22/2151n">22 U.S.C. 2151n</cato:entity-ref>
              </external-xref>)</cato:entity>.</text>
          </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H320DB88DD2DE4768906A23C0CBEC3451">
            <enum>(11)</enum>
            <text>The withdrawal, limitation, or suspension of United States security assistance in accordance with <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Foreign Assistance Act of 1961/s:502B">section 502B of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2304">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/22/2304">22 U.S.C. 2304</cato:entity-ref>
              </external-xref>)</cato:entity>.</text>
          </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H234F11D196A842E7BB39FC8E6CDEB1F0">
            <enum>(12)</enum>
            <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The withdrawal, limitation, or suspension of assistance to the central government of a country pursuant to <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Foreign Assistance Act of 1961/pt:II/ch:4">chapter 4 of part II of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2346">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/22/2346/etseq">22 U.S.C. 2346 et seq</cato:entity-ref>.</external-xref>;</cato:entity> relating to the Economic Support Fund).</text>
          </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HB482965DD19A41A4BA7F3210B287941A">
            <enum>(13)</enum>
            <text>Ordering the heads of the appropriate United States agencies not to issue any (or a specified number of) specific licenses, and not to grant any other specific authority (or a specified number of authorities), to export any goods or technology to such government or to the agency or instrumentality of such government determined by the President to be responsible for such unresolved case or pattern of noncooperation, as applicable, under—</text>
<subparagraph id="H042CF3666A5D4BEA8C725B14850BCDFF">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Export Administration Act of 1979">Export Administration Act of 1979</cato:entity-ref> (as continued in effect under the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="International Emergency Economic Powers Act">International Emergency Economic Powers Act</cato:entity-ref>);</text>
            </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H1669116EBB0346428703F1472E81DC2C">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Arms Export Control Act">Arms Export Control Act</cato:entity-ref>;</text>
            </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HB0D4079F634B4A9F88FC60E91A833F1A">
              <enum>(C)</enum>
              <text>the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Atomic Energy Act of 1954">Atomic Energy Act of 1954</cato:entity-ref>; or</text>
            </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H3BCA4AFC76C64CE1A8A10BAF6AAC93E5">
              <enum>(D)</enum>
              <text>any other statute that requires the prior review and approval of the United States Government as a condition for the export or re-export of goods or services.</text>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
<subsection id="HE1D1E0E4F9E649209D2327EC8B129F46">
          <enum>(b)</enum>
          <header>Commensurate action</header>
          <text>Except as provided in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2013/s:205/ss:c" proposed="true">subsection (c)</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> may substitute any other action authorized by law for any action described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2013/s:205/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref> if such action is commensurate in effect to the action substituted and if such action would further the purposes of this Act as specified in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2013/s:2/ss:c" proposed="true">section 2(c)</cato:entity-ref>. The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> shall seek to take all appropriate and feasible actions authorized by law to resolve the unresolved case or to obtain the cessation of such pattern of noncooperation, as applicable. If commensurate action is taken under this subsection, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> shall transmit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on such action, together with an explanation for taking such action.</text>
        </subsection>
<subsection id="HE47AA7C72E8D4738B31ED7375F35D9C0">
          <enum>(c)</enum>
          <header>Exceptions</header>
<paragraph id="H23CF8F5224C042EC879F6EFE18A62982">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <header>Humanitarian exception</header>
            <text>Any action taken pursuant to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2013/s:205/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref> or <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2013/s:205/ss:b" proposed="true">(b)</cato:entity-ref> may not prohibit or restrict the provision of medicine, medical equipment or supplies, food, or other life-saving humanitarian assistance.</text>
          </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H5B4DD8D84EF348BDAD9CCB2DBA01E8CD">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <header>Defense and national security exception</header>
            <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> shall not be required to apply or maintain any action under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2013/s:205" proposed="true">section 205</cato:entity-ref>—</text>
<subparagraph id="HDF7AB88E0C484BF3851F79D33C6734A3">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>in the case of procurement of defense articles or defense services—</text>
<clause id="HAC7C97B152D248B5BA352905832E00A8">
                <enum>(i)</enum>
                <text>under existing contracts or subcontracts, including the exercise of options for production quantities, to satisfy requirements essential to the national security of the United States;</text>
              </clause>
<clause id="H40AB9A047EDD49BC9B44C1202E7EE2BD">
                <enum>(ii)</enum>
                <text>if the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> determines in writing and transmits to the appropriate congressional committees a report that the government or the agency or instrumentality of such government to which such action would otherwise be applied is a sole source supplier of such defense articles or services, that such defense articles or services are essential, and that alternative sources are not readily or reasonably available; or</text>
              </clause>
<clause id="HC4CF7B76357549F38789613174675259">
                <enum>(iii)</enum>
                <text>if the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> determines in writing and transmits to the appropriate congressional committees a report that such defense articles or services are essential to the national security of the United States under defense co-production agreements; or</text>
              </clause>
            </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H00D372667D004CE0B52F4FB54EB032CD">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>to products or services provided under contracts entered into before the date on which the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> publishes in the Federal Register notice of such action in accordance with <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2013/s:208" proposed="true">section 208</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
      </section>
<section id="HF02C073DFCE44C1281FFD2FBF8ABCBF4">
        <enum>206.</enum>
        <header>Presidential waiver</header>
<subsection id="H40FF4A30937B465FB8D93C3E6299287F">
          <enum>(a)</enum>
          <header>In general</header>
          <text>Subject to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2013/s:206/ss:b" proposed="true">subsection (b)</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> may waive the application of any of the actions described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2013/s:205/ss:a/p:10..13" proposed="true">paragraphs (10) through (13) of section 205(a)</cato:entity-ref> (or commensurate action as provided in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2013/s:205/ss:b" proposed="true">section 205(b)</cato:entity-ref>) with respect to a country, if the President determines and so reports to the appropriate congressional committees that—</text>
<paragraph id="H8B7427063A774B0EB223FF1E7FCA65C5">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <text>the government of such country has satisfactorily resolved any abduction case giving rise to the application of any of such actions and—</text>
<subparagraph id="H83B0AFADB7084256B311E126D56FBE54">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>if such country is a Convention country, such country has taken measures to ensure future compliance with the provisions of the Hague Abduction Convention;</text>
            </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H81A5F8560F64419CABAA506C83DFC16A">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>if such country is an MOU country, such country has taken measures to ensure future compliance with the provisions of the MOU at issue; or</text>
            </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HEF171C2715DC4A3D93EF2F71AB4577AC">
              <enum>(C)</enum>
              <text>if such country was a nonparty country at the time the abductions or denials of rights of access resulting in the abduction cases or access cases occurred, such country has become a Convention country or an MOU country;</text>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H8B8FEFF820D84868B32CDC96F8066BD7">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <text>the exercise of such waiver authority would further the purposes of this Act; or</text>
          </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H6D54A08874DD4C8DB64A8229B8630AD2">
            <enum>(3)</enum>
            <text>the important national interest of the United States requires the exercise of such waiver authority.</text>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
<subsection id="H642A0A7F55544DE28AB76E2247454838">
          <enum>(b)</enum>
          <header>Congressional notification</header>
          <text>Not later than the date of the exercise of a waiver under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2013/s:206/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> shall notify the appropriate congressional committees of such waiver or the intention to exercise such waiver, together with a detailed justification thereof.</text>
        </subsection>
      </section>
<section id="H8770BA92A55B419782978AC57883FE86">
        <enum>207.</enum>
        <header>Publication in Federal Register</header>
<subsection id="H404211E50101463981595ACAADC37234">
          <enum>(a)</enum>
          <header>In general</header>
          <text>Subject to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2013/s:207/ss:b" proposed="true">subsection (b)</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> shall ensure publication in the Federal Register of the following:</text>
<paragraph id="H111D4453490E4729B1F5A53276CFF678">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <header>Determinations of governments, agencies, instrumentalities of countries with patterns of noncooperation</header>
            <text>Any designation of a country that the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> has designated as a Country With a Pattern of Noncooperation under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2013/s:202/ss:b/p:1/sp:A" proposed="true">section 202(b)(1)(A)</cato:entity-ref>, together with, when applicable and to the extent practicable, the identities of agencies or instrumentalities determined to be responsible for such pattern of noncooperation.</text>
          </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HB16508C66B19468AA46100FA57C3A511">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <header>Presidential actions</header>
            <text>A description of any action under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2013/s:205/ss:a/p:10..13" proposed="true">paragraphs (10) through (13) of section 205(a)</cato:entity-ref> (or commensurate action as provided in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2013/s:205/ss:b" proposed="true">section 205(b)</cato:entity-ref>) and the effective date of such action.</text>
          </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HB279D13E5C074247BEB058E59D3809CC">
            <enum>(3)</enum>
            <header>Delays in transmittal of presidential action reports</header>
            <text>Any delay in transmittal of a report required under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2013/s:204" proposed="true">section 204</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
          </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HF777FE1ABF714D52B1BBD372E448F259">
            <enum>(4)</enum>
            <header>Waivers</header>
            <text>Any waiver issued under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2013/s:206" proposed="true">section 206</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
<subsection id="H44B801CDBE844B389AEF031BE73B9A2C">
          <enum>(b)</enum>
          <header>Limited disclosure of information</header>
          <text>The President may limit publication of information under this section in the same manner and to the same extent as the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> may limit the publication of findings and determinations described in <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Foreign Assistance Act of 1961/s:654/ss:c">section 654(c) of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2414">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/22/2414/c">22 U.S.C. 2414(c)</cato:entity-ref>
            </external-xref>)</cato:entity>, if the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> determines that the publication of such information—</text>
<paragraph id="H603256EBA23F4F7B8A50EEA332C4C41A">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <text>would be harmful to the national security of the United States; or</text>
          </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H229C02A3EDC54F4BA55748CAE78DA76D">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <text>would not further the purposes of this Act.</text>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
      </section>
<section id="HBB8FAB486465416EADC771518756F84C">
        <enum>208.</enum>
        <header>Termination of Presidential actions</header>
        <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Any action taken under this Act or any amendment made by this Act with respect to a foreign country shall terminate on the earlier of the following two dates:</text>
<paragraph id="HFCAE9D0FF5A348218CDA6ED740A3C1DA">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>Not later than two years after the effective date of such action unless expressly reauthorized by law.</text>
        </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HBDDC6132D7D84D15960827D1ED98FD5D">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>The date on which the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> transmits to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> a certification containing a determination of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> that the government of such country has resolved any unresolved abduction case or has taken substantial and verifiable steps to correct the pattern of noncooperation at issue, as applicable, that gave rise to such action.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </section>
    </title> 
</legis-body>
<attestation>
    <attestation-group>
      <attestation-date date="20131211" chamber="House">Passed the House of Representatives December 11, 2013.</attestation-date>
      <attestor display="no">Karen L. Haas,</attestor>
      <role>Clerk.</role>
    </attestation-group>
  </attestation>
<endorsement display="yes"/>
</bill>
</doc>