<doc>
  <docmeta id="113hr839ih">
    <bill congress="113" type="hr" number="839" version="ih"/>
    <revision size="6698" annotations="0" id="5" commit-time="2013-03-26T20:39:00+00:00" committer="favila" doc="113hr839ih/5.xml" status="complete">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H148D6CC4EC9D4BE1960166893C4FA822" key="H" public-private="public"> 
<form> 
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>113th CONGRESS</congress> <session>1st Session</session> 
<legis-num>H. R. 839</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date>February 26, 2013</action-date> 
<action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="R000583">Mr. Rooney</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="A000210">Mr. Andrews</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name>
      </action-desc> 
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To require the lender or servicer of a home mortgage, upon a request by the homeowner for a short sale, to make a prompt decision whether to allow the sale.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H65983BA9152A4075968987E3548B2411" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H7D4EEA6109804D03B3B1AF503326967A" section-type="section-one">
      <enum>1.</enum>
      <header>Short title</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote>
          <short-title>Prompt Notification of Short Sales Act</short-title>
        </quote>.</text> </section>
<section id="H24F9B568CFA84C3E9FE3088072A8FA6F">
      <enum>2.</enum>
      <header>Definitions</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">For purposes of this Act, the following definitions shall apply:</text> 
<subsection id="HB2E1FC7BAB6F4E608766E1322E12B4DB">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Residential mortgage loan</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>residential mortgage loan</term> means any consumer credit transaction that is secured by a mortgage, deed of trust, or other equivalent consensual security interest on a dwelling or on residential real property that includes a dwelling, other than a consumer credit transaction under an open end credit plan or an extension of credit relating to a plan described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc/11/101//53D">section 101(53D) of title 11, United States Code</cato:entity-ref>.</text> </subsection>
<subsection id="H39777C7FE1DB4ECA8DD2F4153A6B68A3">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Securitization vehicle</header>
        <text>The term <term>securitization vehicle</term> means a trust, special purpose entity, or other legal structure that is used to facilitate the issuing of securities, participation certificates, or similar instruments backed by or referring to a pool of assets that includes residential mortgage loans (or instruments that are related to residential mortgage loans, such as credit-linked notes).</text> </subsection>
<subsection id="H1D4AA9D5C97345C79FFDEA2280ED6B56">
        <enum>(c)</enum>
        <header>Servicer</header>
        <text>The term <term>servicer</term> has the same meaning as in <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Truth in Lending Act/s:129A">section 129A of the Truth in Lending Act</cato:entity-ref> (<cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/15/1639a">15 U.S.C. 1639a</cato:entity-ref>)</cato:entity>, except that such term includes a person who makes or holds a residential mortgage loan (including a pool of residential mortgage loans), if such person also services the loan.</text> </subsection>
<subsection id="HA0FA0745C64E4B07B3099F7911E0EA53">
        <enum>(d)</enum>
        <header>Short sale</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>short sale</term> means the sale of the dwelling or residential real property that is subject to the mortgage, deed or trust, or other security interest that secures a residential mortgage loan that—</text> 
<paragraph id="H6BA812E261B543DDB27C000DD68E26EC">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>will result in proceeds in an amount that is less than the remaining amount due under the mortgage loan; and</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H86E041E9D3AA46DBB41175A88507840D">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>requires authorization by the securitization vehicle or other investment vehicle or holder of the mortgage loan, or the servicer acting on behalf of such a vehicle or holder.</text> </paragraph>
      </subsection>
    </section>
<section id="H86EC15F6E42C46F095C6B6DB82B31E76">
      <enum>3.</enum>
      <header>Prompt notifications and decision regarding short sale</header> 
<subsection id="HF54950C53C584674BC50FDB11A6629D6">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Requirement for prompt notifications, decisions</header> 
<paragraph id="H85B51F725035411CA3D946730C3BD8DE">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>Notifications</header> 
<subparagraph id="HAC9CEDB40F6E44E19FF51B98E5394A7E">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <header>In general</header>
            <text>Each servicer shall provide in writing to a mortgagor of a residential mortgage loan—</text> 
<clause id="H706E2F9B049C4772B5B16737BD82BD9F">
              <enum>(i)</enum>
              <text>an acknowledgment of receipt of a written request of the mortgagor, not later than 3 days after the date of such receipt;</text> </clause>
<clause id="HC1E818346C4345248BE2087737C09FF5">
              <enum>(ii)</enum>
              <text>a notice of any missing or incomplete information required with respect to such request, not later than 5 days after the date of such receipt; and</text> </clause>
<clause id="H61BFAAAED0144948BAD3874843AAE952">
              <enum>(iii)</enum>
              <text>a definitive response to such request approving or denying such request, not later than 30 days after the date of such receipt.</text> </clause>
          </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H17D08B9570A7477DA07FF8304A379E80">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <header>Exceptional circumstances</header>
            <text>In any case in which a servicer is unable to provide a decision with respect to a written request of a mortgagor of a residential mortgage loan during the 30-day period required by <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Prompt Notification of Short Sales Act/s:3/ss:a/p:1/sp:A" proposed="true">subparagraph (A)</cato:entity-ref>, such period may be extended to not later than 60 days after the date of receipt of a completed application, except that the servicer shall, verbally or in writing—</text> 
<clause id="HA4AD3DC956614D6CB31E19EE4698C92D">
              <enum>(i)</enum>
              <text>notify the mortgagor during the initial 30-day period that the application is still under review; and</text> </clause>
<clause id="H549A6877B009496A9DCA53BC47D18E19">
              <enum>(ii)</enum>
              <text>each week thereafter provide to the mortgagor a status update indicating the reasons why a decision is pending beyond the required 30-day period.</text> </clause>
          </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HF5E92BA3D471491187E44FCA51C13BDF">
            <enum>(C)</enum>
            <header>Applicability</header>
            <text>
              <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Prompt Notification of Short Sales Act/s:3/ss:a/p:1/sp:A" proposed="true">Subparagraph (A)</cato:entity-ref> shall apply, except as provided in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Prompt Notification of Short Sales Act/s:3/ss:b" proposed="true">subsection (b)</cato:entity-ref>, and notwithstanding any other provision of law or of any contract, including a contract between a servicer of a residential mortgage loan and a securitization vehicle or other investment vehicle.</text> </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HC2A3DF80ACB340E4A785B657FA2774F4">
            <enum>(D)</enum>
            <header>Content</header>
            <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A written response by a servicer under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Prompt Notification of Short Sales Act/s:3/ss:a/p:1/sp:A" proposed="true">subparagraph (A)</cato:entity-ref> shall specify a decision on whether such request has been denied, approved, or that such request has been approved subject to specified changes.</text> </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H5FA7388BA9B44C9E98B91FA4CF2E47A1">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Mortgagor submission</header>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">
            <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Prompt Notification of Short Sales Act/s:3/ss:a/p:1" proposed="true">Paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref> shall apply in any case in which the mortgagor under a residential mortgage loan submits to the servicer thereof—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H71696C07877E45A9853D1C41293E6DB5">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a written offer for a short sale of the dwelling or residential real property that is subject to the mortgage, deed of trust, or other security interest that secures the mortgage loan; and</text> </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HD5100DEB0353452283FA81E450DF478C">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">all information required by the servicer in connection with such a request (including a copy of an executed contract between the owner of the dwelling or property and the prospective buyer that is subject to approval by the servicer).</text> </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H4265EE00C8A24752B2E3B28DB5B8E75A">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <header>Civil actions authorized</header>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An aggrieved individual may bring an action in a court of competent jurisdiction, asserting a violation of this Act. Aggrieved individuals may be awarded all appropriate relief, including equitable relief, and a monetary award of $1,000 per violation, plus reasonable attorneys’ fees, or such higher amount as may be appropriate in the case of an established pattern or practice of such failures.</text> </paragraph>
      </subsection>
<subsection id="H889904297ED14420971C045F38125BF2">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Inapplicability to certain existing mortgages</header>
        <text>
          <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Prompt Notification of Short Sales Act/s:3/ss:a" proposed="true">Subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref> shall not apply with respect to any residential mortgage with respect to which the mortgagor and the mortgagee or servicer have entered into a written agreement before the date of enactment of this Act explicitly providing a procedure or terms for approval of a short sale.</text> </subsection>
<subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7FD84E871FAB4E54B558F183FB2FB3DF">
        <enum>(c)</enum>
        <header>Treatment of other time limits</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This section may not be construed to preempt, annul, or otherwise affect any other provision of law or of any contract or program that provides a shorter period than is provided under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Prompt Notification of Short Sales Act/s:3/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref> for a decision by the servicer of a residential mortgage loan regarding a short sale of the dwelling or residential real property that is subject to the mortgage, deed or trust, or other security interest that secures the mortgage loan.</text> </subsection>
    </section>
</legis-body> 
</bill>
</doc>