<doc>
  <docmeta id="113hres657eh">
    <bill congress="113" type="hres" number="657" version="eh"/>
    <revision size="3018" annotations="0" status="complete" id="4" commit-time="2014-07-22T20:53:02Z" committer="zwilliams" doc="113hres657eh/4.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <resolution xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" dms-id="H22CC89AE096048799D8DC12A7A04522F" key="H" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Engrossed-in-House" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" stage-count="1"> 
<metadata>
<dublinCore>
<dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">113 HRES 657 EH: Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives regarding United States support for the State of Israel as it defends itself against unprovoked rocket attacks from the Hamas terrorist organization.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">2014-07-11</dc:date>
<dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="no">IV</distribution-code> 
<congress display="no">113th CONGRESS</congress> 
<session display="no">2d Session</session> 
<legis-num>H. RES. 657</legis-num> 
<current-chamber display="yes">In the House of Representatives, U. S.,</current-chamber>
<action>
<action-date date="20140711">July 11, 2014</action-date>
</action> 
<legis-type display="yes">RESOLUTION</legis-type> 
<official-title display="no">Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives regarding United States support for the State of Israel as it defends itself against unprovoked rocket attacks from the Hamas terrorist organization.</official-title> 
</form> 
<preamble> 
<whereas>
      <text>Whereas Hamas is a United States-designated terrorist organization whose charter calls for the destruction of the State of Israel;</text> </whereas>
<whereas>
      <text>Whereas Hamas continues to reject the Quartet’s core principles—recognize Israel’s right to exist, renounce violence, and accept previous Israeli-Palestinian agreements;</text> </whereas>
<whereas>
      <text>Whereas Hamas has killed hundreds of Israelis and dozens of Americans in rocket attacks and suicide bombings;</text> </whereas>
<whereas>
      <text>Whereas since Israel’s withdrawal from Gaza in 2005, Hamas and other terrorist groups have fired thousands of rockets at Israel;</text> </whereas>
<whereas>
      <text>Whereas since June 2014, Hamas has fired nearly 300 rockets at Israel;</text> </whereas>
<whereas>
      <text>Whereas Hamas’s weapons arsenal includes approximately 12,000 rockets that vary in range;</text>
    </whereas>
<whereas>
      <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas Iran has long provided material support to Hamas and Palestinian Islamic Jihad, including assistance that has enabled these terrorist organizations to produce longer-range rockets capable of striking Tel Aviv and Jerusalem;</text>
    </whereas>
<whereas>
      <text>Whereas innocent Israeli civilians are indiscriminately targeted by Hamas rocket attacks;</text>
    </whereas>
<whereas>
      <text>Whereas the United States and Israel have cooperated on missile defense projects, including Iron Dome, David’s Sling, and the Arrow Anti-Missile System, projects designed to thwart a diverse range of threats, including short-range missiles and rockets fired by non-state actors, such as Hamas; </text>
    </whereas>
<whereas>
      <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas the United States has provided $235,000,000 in fiscal year 2014 for Iron Dome research, development, and production;</text>
    </whereas>
<whereas>
      <text>Whereas, during the most recent rocket attacks from Gaza, Iron Dome has successfully intercepted dozens of rockets that were launched against Israeli population centers; and</text>
    </whereas>
<whereas>
      <text>Whereas 5 million Israelis are currently living under the threat of rocket attacks from Gaza: Now, therefore, be it</text>
    </whereas>
  </preamble> 
<resolution-body id="H2BF332EC14124C049F0EEDC146C1E3D7" style="traditional"> 
<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HA94326FD41284B93B88E0DC2D9CB14D4" section-type="undesignated-section">
      <enum/>
      <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the <cato:entity-ref entity-id="0050" entity-type="federal-body">House of Representatives</cato:entity-ref>—</text> 
<paragraph id="HFFED8AECCC994BAD8247B073B4D2AF57">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text>reaffirms its support for Israel’s right to defend its citizens and ensure the survival of the State of Israel;</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H4EAAE1B23D2A45B9B8C0B58FE5800628">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text>condemns the unprovoked rocket fire at Israel; and</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H4DC4723E27E24FAE831D249AAE1ED837">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <text>calls on Hamas to immediately cease all rocket and other attacks against Israel.</text> </paragraph>
    </section>
</resolution-body> 
<attestation>
    <attestation-group>
      <attestor display="no">Karen L. Haas,</attestor>
      <role>Clerk.</role>
    </attestation-group>
  </attestation>
</resolution>
</doc>