<doc>
  <docmeta id="113hconres47ih">
    <bill congress="113" type="hconres" number="47" version="ih"/>
    <revision size="3967" annotations="0" status="complete" id="3" commit-time="2013-08-02T15:25:58Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113hconres47ih/3.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <resolution xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" dms-id="HDBE66FF2C3204A2298CCA5B26F19A9A6" key="H" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" resolution-type="house-concurrent" star-print="no-star-print">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>113 HCON 47 IH: Calling for a democratically elected government for the people of the Federal Democratic Republic of Nepal.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2013-07-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">113th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session display="yes">1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. CON. RES. 47</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20130730">July 30, 2013</action-date>
			<action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="L000560">Mr. Larsen of
			 Washington</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="K000381">Mr.
			 Kilmer</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="H001064">Mr. Heck of
			 Washington</cosponsor>) submitted the following concurrent resolution; which
			 was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign
			 Affairs</committee-name>
      </action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>CONCURRENT RESOLUTION</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">Calling for a democratically elected
		  government for the people of the Federal Democratic Republic of
		  Nepal.</official-title>
	</form>
	<preamble>
		<whereas>
      <text>Whereas the people of the Federal Democratic Republic of
			 Nepal seek to become a people with a democratically elected government through
			 free and fair elections;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the people of the nation of Nepal seek a
			 government based on democratic values and norms earning the faith and consent
			 of the governed;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the Government of Nepal should be a national
			 government, promoting law and order, and the enforcement of laws through a
			 legal system derived from a national constitution;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the Government of Nepal should guarantee universal
			 human rights, including freedom of speech, the press, assembly, religion, and
			 due process under the law;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the Government of Nepal should also protect the
			 people of Nepal and strive to provide basic needs such as clean air, water,
			 electricity, food, shelter, and health care;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the people of the United States seek the
			 establishment of free and fair democratic elections for all people
			 everywhere;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the people of the United States and the people of
			 Nepal have enjoyed over 60 years of peaceful relations;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the United States has a compelling national
			 interest in the security, stability, and development of Nepal;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the United States seeks to maintain gains in peace
			 and security, further the Nepali transition to a democratic government, support
			 the continued delivery of needed social services, provide effective health care
			 solutions to the Nepali people, and address the challenges of food insecurity
			 and climate change;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the United States and Nepal have long promoted
			 open trade and investment between the two countries, establishing a framework
			 agreement for bilateral talks to promote bilateral trade and investment;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the United States has long exported agricultural
			 products, aircraft parts, optic and medical instruments, low-value shipments,
			 and machinery to Nepal, and Nepal has enjoyed exporting textile floor
			 coverings, apparel, headgear, and leather to the United States; and</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas both the United States and Nepal have benefitted
			 from an open and fair trade framework: Now, therefore, be it</text>
		</whereas>
  </preamble>
	<resolution-body id="H96E5518D3ADB46BB95EABD620F4B0C7C" style="traditional">
		<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HB48D45571DB14D26A37A65FFB64BD6D6" section-type="undesignated-section">
      <enum/>
      <text>That <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref>—</text>
			<paragraph id="HF3392E044DD1481B81002FDB2A858089">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">welcomes the free and fair elections for
			 the people of the Federal Democratic Republic of Nepal;</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HBFA883A2D7EA4EE59BAE3C54F48A1D45">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text>encourages the use
			 of all efforts, energies, and diligence to help the people of Nepal to
			 effectively participate in the electoral process;</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H3DA1185469F54D779AD63BA3BB3DAD3C">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <text>joins with the
			 international community in providing the resources necessary to hold free,
			 fair, and timely elections, facilitate a peaceful transition of power, and
			 establish a government that will protect the rights of the people; and</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H29D11610232841288BE630962742E113">
        <enum>(4)</enum>
        <text>supports the
			 efforts of the people of Nepal to maintain self-determination for their general
			 welfare and the welfare of future generations.</text>
			</paragraph>
    </section>
  </resolution-body>
</resolution>
</doc>