<doc>
  <docmeta id="113hres423ih">
    <bill congress="113" type="hres" number="423" version="ih"/>
    <revision size="4051" annotations="0" status="complete" id="4" commit-time="2013-12-03T20:59:27Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113hres423ih/4.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <resolution xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" dms-id="HC70EB0647EAA4AD3AF742B4743AD5B6F" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"> 
<metadata>
<dublinCore>
<dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">113 HRES 423 IH: Honoring the life, legacy, and example of Congressman Leo J. Ryan 35 years after his tragic death.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">2013-11-19</dc:date>
<dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code> 
<congress display="yes">113th CONGRESS</congress>
<session display="yes">1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. RES. 423</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action display="yes"> 
<action-date date="20131119">November 19, 2013</action-date> 
<action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="W000808">Ms. Wilson of Florida</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S001175">Ms. Speier</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001080">Ms. Chu</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001034">Mr. Honda</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000030">Mr. Farr</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000215">Ms. Eshoo</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000551">Ms. Lee of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000215">Mr. Waxman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001036">Mrs. Capps</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000032">Ms. Jackson Lee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000312">Mr. McGovern</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001193">Mr. Swalwell of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000179">Mrs. Napolitano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000579">Mr. Lowenthal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000725">Mr. George Miller of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001038">Mr. Crowley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000933">Mr. Moran</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001252">Mr. Barrow of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H000324">Mr. Hastings of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000620">Mr. Delaney</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="L000480">Mrs. Lowey</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHA00">Committee on House Administration</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
</action> 
<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type> 
<official-title display="yes">Honoring the life, legacy, and example of Congressman Leo J. Ryan 35 years after his tragic death.</official-title> 
</form> 
<preamble> 
<whereas>
      <text>Whereas the Honorable Leo J. Ryan served in the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0050">House of Representatives</cato:entity-ref> from 1972 to 1978 and championed causes related to equality, freedom, and human rights;</text>
    </whereas> 
<whereas>
      <text>Whereas Congressman Ryan, as presiding chairman of the California Assembly committee overseeing prison reform, entered Folsom Prison in 1970 under a pseudonym in an effort to uncover alleged abuses against convicts in California's prisons;</text>
    </whereas> 
<whereas>
      <text>Whereas Congressman Ryan, while serving in the California Assembly, chose to serve as a substitute teacher in the Watts neighborhood of Los Angeles in order to investigate the conditions following the Watts Riots;</text>
    </whereas> 
<whereas>
      <text>Whereas Congressman Ryan, after hearing reports of United States citizens being held against their will in a prison camp atmosphere within the Guyana settlement of the People’s Temple organization, went on a fact finding mission to Jonestown, Guyana;</text>
    </whereas> 
<whereas>
      <text>Whereas on November 14, 1978, Congressman Ryan flew to Georgetown, Guyana along with a delegation of 18 people, including now-Congresswoman <cato:entity-ref entity-type="person" entity-id="S001175">Jackie Speier</cato:entity-ref> of California as his legal advisor;</text>
    </whereas> 
<whereas>
      <text>Whereas on November 18, 1978, Congressman Ryan, 3 journalists, and a defecting member of the People’s Temple were killed by gunfire, which wounded 9 others, including Congresswoman Speier;</text>
    </whereas> 
<whereas>
      <text>Whereas 909 members of the People’s Temple committed suicide shortly after the murders on the airstrip;</text>
    </whereas> 
<whereas>
      <text>Whereas <cato:entity-ref entity-type="person" entity-id="S001175">Congresswoman Jackie Speier</cato:entity-ref> had to endure the pain of 5 gunshot wounds for more than 22 hours before help arrived;</text>
    </whereas> 
<whereas>
      <text>Whereas Congressman Ryan is one of a small number of Members of Congress who have been killed in the line of duty; and</text>
    </whereas> 
<whereas>
      <text>Whereas Congressman Ryan dedicated his life to the cause of democracy, freedom, and human rights for the people of California, the United States, and the world: Now, therefore, be it</text>
    </whereas>
  </preamble> 
<resolution-body style="traditional" id="H93D96D1B6AAB40118E1BB5D4CE602CEA"> 
<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H42445AD5963B4C158ECC1B593775CC9C">
      <text>That the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0050">House of Representatives</cato:entity-ref>—</text> 
<paragraph id="H7FF757673F2A48BA8A30120B93221359">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">honors the legacy of Congressman Leo J. Ryan for his lifelong commitment to objective fact-finding and for his extraordinary commitment to advancing freedom and basic human rights at home and abroad;</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBBC1BF2A4C8147DE959DCA7EFC313118">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text>honors the bravery of Congressman Ryan and his team members, including now-Congresswoman <cato:entity-ref entity-type="person" entity-id="S001175">Jackie Speier</cato:entity-ref>, for undertaking a dangerous yet essential fact-finding mission in Guyana;</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3A1CEFD712964D7F95AEDFC59F8F1356">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <text>extends its condolences to all those affected by the Jonestown tragedy;</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4C3050E4A1854409A4FAF3484308FAAF">
        <enum>(4)</enum>
        <text>reiterates its continued support for the safety of all government officials traveling on behalf of the United States on fact-finding missions; and</text>
      </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HF490E4ADA40C47D8B568066B6FADD4F6">
        <enum>(5)</enum>
        <text>calls upon the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" value="Speaker of the House of Representatives" entity-parent-id="0050">Speaker of the House of Representatives</cato:entity-ref> to establish protocols for memorializing Members who die in the line of duty.</text>
      </paragraph>
    </section> 
</resolution-body> 
</resolution>
</doc>