<doc>
  <docmeta id="113hres164eh">
    <bill congress="113" type="hres" number="164" version="eh"/>
    <revision size="17462" annotations="0" status="complete" id="4" commit-time="2013-08-05T16:28:26Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113hres164eh/4.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <resolution xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" dms-id="Had98ed08-cbdd-4884-b9b7-908b8f2dea8f" key="H" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Engrossed-in-House" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" stage-count="1"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>113 HRES 164 EH: Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 624) to provide for the sharing of certain cyber threat intelligence and cyber threat information between the intelligence community and cybersecurity entities, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2013-04-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="no">IV</distribution-code> 
<congress display="no">113th CONGRESS</congress> 
<session display="no">1st Session</session> 
<legis-num>H. RES. 164</legis-num> 
<current-chamber display="yes">In the House of Representatives, U. S.,</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20130417">April 17, 2013</action-date> 
</action> 
<legis-type display="yes">RESOLUTION</legis-type> 
<official-title display="no">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 624) to provide for the sharing of certain cyber threat intelligence and cyber threat information between the intelligence community and cybersecurity entities, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<resolution-body id="Hda38267f-45f1-4d64-9d0f-ee36d8a7c415" style="traditional"> 
<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="Hc856bc36-925e-49e7-ae43-22e22b548d9b" section-type="undesignated-section">
      <enum/>
      <text>That at any time after the adoption of this resolution the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" value="Speaker of the House of Representatives" entity-parent-id="0050">Speaker</cato:entity-ref> may, pursuant to clause 2(b) of rule XVIII, declare the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0050">House</cato:entity-ref> resolved into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for consideration of the bill (<cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="113 HR 624" proposed="true">H.R. 624</cato:entity-ref>) to provide for the sharing of certain cyber threat intelligence and cyber threat information between the intelligence community and cybersecurity entities, and for other purposes. The first reading of the bill shall be dispensed with. All points of order against consideration of the bill are waived. General debate shall be confined to the bill and shall not exceed one hour equally divided and controlled by the chair and ranking minority member of the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="committee" entity-id="HIG00">Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence</cato:entity-ref>. After general debate the bill shall be considered for amendment under the five-minute rule. In lieu of the amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="committee" entity-id="HIG00">Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence</cato:entity-ref> now printed in the bill, it shall be in order to consider as an original bill for the purpose of amendment under the five-minute rule an amendment in the nature of a substitute consisting of the text of Rules Committee Print 113–7. That amendment in the nature of a substitute shall be considered as read. All points of order against that amendment in the nature of a substitute are waived. No amendment to that amendment in the nature of a substitute shall be in order except those printed in the report of the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="committee" entity-id="HRU00">Committee on Rules</cato:entity-ref> accompanying this resolution. Each such amendment may be offered only in the order printed in the report, may be offered only by a Member designated in the report, shall be considered as read, shall be debatable for the time specified in the report equally divided and controlled by the proponent and an opponent, shall not be subject to amendment, and shall not be subject to a demand for division of the question in the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0050">House</cato:entity-ref> or in the Committee of the Whole. All points of order against such amendments are waived. At the conclusion of consideration of the bill for amendment the Committee shall rise and report the bill to the House with such amendments as may have been adopted. Any Member may demand a separate vote in the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0050">House</cato:entity-ref> on any amendment adopted in the Committee of the Whole to the bill or to the amendment in the nature of a substitute made in order as original text. The previous question shall be considered as ordered on the bill and amendments thereto to final passage without intervening motion except one motion to recommit with or without instructions.</text> </section> 
<section id="HF589CA1CCC204534A4ADC598AA3394C0">
      <enum>2.</enum>
      <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of this resolution, the amendment specified in <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="113 HR 624/s:3" proposed="true">section 3</cato:entity-ref> shall be in order as though printed as the last amendment in <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="House Report 113–41">House Report 113–41</cato:entity-ref> if offered by <cato:entity-ref entity-type="person" entity-id="M001157">Representative McCaul of Texas</cato:entity-ref> or his designee. That amendment shall be debatable for 10 minutes equally divided and controlled by the proponent and an opponent.</text>
    </section> 
<section id="H2987408BE68048B99DC86731A1CFAFDD">
      <enum>3.</enum>
      <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendment referred to in <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="113 HRES 164/s:2" proposed="true">section 2</cato:entity-ref> is as follows: After <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="113 HR 624/s:1" proposed="true">section 1</cato:entity-ref>, insert the following new section (and renumber subsequent sections accordingly):</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H73F76D32D9BD477A9B8E6D9A7869F683" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<section id="HEC641C896D1C4A46A6FD1E9FCAB98CE3">
          <enum>2.</enum>
          <header>Federal Government coordination with respect to cybersecurity</header> 
<subsection id="HE1F00366A73C43ADAF9A6608FC3B8E19">
            <enum>(a)</enum>
            <header>Coordinated activities</header>
            <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Federal Government shall conduct cybersecurity activities to provide shared situational awareness that enables integrated operational actions to protect, prevent, mitigate, respond to, and recover from cyber incidents.</text>
          </subsection> 
<subsection id="H9E7C1B71C6D04C59BE387369CC05F7B3">
            <enum>(b)</enum>
            <header>Coordinated information sharing</header> 
<paragraph id="HAC496422005E49BFA0B1B13DDA5A80BF">
              <enum>(1)</enum>
              <header>Designation of coordinating entity for cyber threat information</header>
              <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> shall designate an entity within the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7000">Department of Homeland Security</cato:entity-ref> as the civilian Federal entity to receive cyber threat information that is shared by a cybersecurity provider or self-protected entity in accordance with <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="National Security Act of 1947/s:1104/ss:b" proposed="true">section 1104(b) of the National Security Act of 1947</cato:entity-ref>, as added by <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="113 HR 624/s:3/ss:a" proposed="true">section 3(a)</cato:entity-ref> of this Act, except as provided in <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="113 HR 624/s:2/ss:b/p:2" proposed="true">paragraph (2)</cato:entity-ref> and subject to the procedures established under <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="113 HR 624/s:2/ss:b/p:4" proposed="true">paragraph (4)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
            </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF2D16DD6BC1041AD968C894B4582808E">
              <enum>(2)</enum>
              <header>Designation of a coordinating entity for cybersecurity crimes</header>
              <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> shall designate an entity within the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1500">Department of Justice</cato:entity-ref> as the civilian Federal entity to receive cyber threat information related to cybersecurity crimes that is shared by a cybersecurity provider or self-protected entity in accordance with <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="National Security Act of 1947/s:1104/ss:b" proposed="true">section 1104(b) of the National Security Act of 1947</cato:entity-ref>, as added by <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="113 HR 624/s:3/ss:a" proposed="true">section 3(a) of this Act</cato:entity-ref>, subject to the procedures under <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="113 HR 624/s:2/ss:b/p:4" proposed="true">paragraph (4)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
            </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFE43628282C94620AFD1BC9AEDAFC0BB">
              <enum>(3)</enum>
              <header>Sharing by coordinating entities</header>
              <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The entities designated under <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="113 HR 624/s:2/ss:b/p:1" proposed="true">paragraphs (1)</cato:entity-ref> and <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="113 HR 624/s:2/ss:b/p:2" proposed="true">(2)</cato:entity-ref> shall share cyber threat information shared with such entities in accordance with <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="National Security Act of 1947/s:1104/ss:b" proposed="true">section 1104(b) of the National Security Act of 1947</cato:entity-ref>, as added by <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="113 HR 624/s:3/ss:a" proposed="true">section 3(a) of this Act</cato:entity-ref>, consistent with the procedures established under <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="113 HR 624/s:2/ss:b/p:4" proposed="true">paragraphs (4)</cato:entity-ref> and <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="113 HR 624/s:2/ss:b/p:5" proposed="true">(5)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
            </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE4CD812A2F0B446B88E23D74434E264B">
              <enum>(4)</enum>
              <header>Procedures</header>
              <text>Each department or agency of the Federal Government receiving cyber threat information shared in accordance with <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="National Security Act of 1947/s:1104/ss:b" proposed="true">section 1104(b) of the National Security Act of 1947</cato:entity-ref>, as added by <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="113 HR 624/s:3/ss:a" proposed="true">section 3(a) of this Act</cato:entity-ref>, shall establish procedures to—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HF0BCEA46441247EEB7F2BF3D50351063">
                <enum>(A)</enum>
                <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">ensure that cyber threat information shared with departments or agencies of the Federal Government in accordance with such <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="National Security Act of 1947/s:1104/ss:b" proposed="true">section 1104(b)</cato:entity-ref> is also shared with appropriate departments and agencies of the Federal Government with a national security mission in real time;</text>
              </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H31CBF8A05EA84909B84AB6983C6B9C82">
                <enum>(B)</enum>
                <text>ensure the distribution to other departments and agencies of the Federal Government of cyber threat information in real time; and</text>
              </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H54EB3AFE47A44BC096665A727790D4FD">
                <enum>(C)</enum>
                <text>facilitate information sharing, interaction, and collaboration among and between the Federal Government; State, local, tribal, and territorial governments; and cybersecurity providers and self-protected entities.</text> </subparagraph>
            </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB11838DC7A45431E9842B38AD6A703AE" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <enum>(5)</enum> <header>Privacy and civil liberties</header> 
<subparagraph id="H72FBD67E11BB401689D810207EA9DB82"> <enum>(A)</enum> <header>Policies and procedures</header> <text>The <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7000">Secretary of Homeland Security</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1500">Attorney General</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" value="Director of National Intelligence">Director of National Intelligence</cato:entity-ref>, and the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="9700">Secretary of Defense</cato:entity-ref> shall jointly establish and periodically review policies and procedures governing the receipt, retention, use, and disclosure of non-publicly available cyber threat information shared with the Federal Government in accordance with <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="National Security Act of 1947/s:1104/ss:b" proposed="true">section 1104(b) of the National Security Act of 1947</cato:entity-ref>, as added by <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="113 HR 624/s:3/ss:a" proposed="true">section 3(a) of this Act</cato:entity-ref>. Such policies and procedures shall, consistent with the need to protect systems and networks from cyber threats and mitigate cyber threats in a timely manner—</text> 
<clause id="H2FE0B2583C2C4707AE95A576AD601BAE"> <enum>(i)</enum> <text>minimize the impact on privacy and civil liberties;</text> </clause> 
<clause id="HC3E3A439B9B84171BC735D0DC71E6CEA"> <enum>(ii)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">reasonably limit the receipt, retention, use, and disclosure of cyber threat information associated with specific persons that is not necessary to protect systems or networks from cyber threats or mitigate cyber threats in a timely manner;</text> </clause> 
<clause id="H952288C280904586A733E734CBDD364E"> <enum>(iii)</enum> <text>include requirements to safeguard non-publicly available cyber threat information that may be used to identify specific persons from unauthorized access or acquisition;</text> </clause> 
<clause id="H7AA8B77A4FF04BF5A7E08ECC9FC6B951"> <enum>(iv)</enum> <text>protect the confidentiality of cyber threat information associated with specific persons to the greatest extent practicable; and</text> </clause> 
<clause id="H1D5CEA0B4E8C4C3ABDB39EFDA5B6831F"> <enum>(v)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not delay or impede the flow of cyber threat information necessary to defend against or mitigate a cyber threat.</text> </clause> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF321F6B9AF6D460FB6304E7C5D101788"> <enum>(B)</enum> <header>Submission to Congress</header> <text>The <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7000">Secretary of Homeland Security</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1500">Attorney General</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" value="Director of National Intelligence">Director of National Intelligence</cato:entity-ref>, and the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="9700">Secretary of Defense</cato:entity-ref> shall, consistent with the need to protect sources and methods, jointly submit to <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> the policies and procedures required under <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="113 HR 624/s:2/ss:b/p:5/sp:A" proposed="true">subparagraph (A)</cato:entity-ref> and any updates to such policies and procedures.</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6CDEE0148673461EA3CBB64B6F98874A"> <enum>(C)</enum> <header>Implementation</header> <text>The head of each department or agency of the Federal Government receiving cyber threat information shared with the Federal Government under such <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="National Security Act of 1947/s:1104/ss:b" proposed="true">section 1104(b)</cato:entity-ref> shall—</text> 
<clause id="H3610483BD3B74685AF6CB089EED19A5F"> <enum>(i)</enum> <text>implement the policies and procedures established under <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="113 HR 624/s:2/ss:b/p:5/sp:A" proposed="true">subparagraph (A)</cato:entity-ref>; and</text> </clause> 
<clause id="H39320436DEFB4450B40AA798B59F49D1"> <enum>(ii)</enum> <text>promptly notify the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7000">Secretary of Homeland Security</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1500">Attorney General</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" value="Director of National Intelligence">Director of National Intelligence</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="9700">Secretary of Defense</cato:entity-ref>, and the appropriate congressional committees of any significant violations of such policies and procedures.</text> </clause> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5CB2166E4A7242A49D92E7C53D7BBA9B"> <enum>(D)</enum> <header>Oversight</header> <text>The <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7000">Secretary of Homeland Security</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1500">Attorney General</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" value="Director of National Intelligence">Director of National Intelligence</cato:entity-ref>, and the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="9700">Secretary of Defense</cato:entity-ref> shall jointly establish a program to monitor and oversee compliance with the policies and procedures established under <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="113 HR 624/s:2/ss:b/p:5/sp:A" proposed="true">subparagraph (A)</cato:entity-ref>.</text> </subparagraph> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9948F0E8514B4A27A48CA2823294269B">
              <enum>(6)</enum>
              <header>Information sharing relationships</header>
              <text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H843B93469957409793D15461125AF326">
                <enum>(A)</enum>
                <text>alter existing agreements or prohibit new agreements with respect to the sharing of cyber threat information between the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="9700">Department of Defense</cato:entity-ref> and an entity that is part of the defense industrial base;</text>
              </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H903BD0897D774828B8BA0A31FA0B31B3">
                <enum>(B)</enum>
                <text>alter existing information-sharing relationships between a cybersecurity provider, protected entity, or self-protected entity and the Federal Government;</text>
              </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA786C31BAFA348E98DA851F05A166480">
                <enum>(C)</enum>
                <text>prohibit the sharing of cyber threat information directly with a department or agency of the Federal Government for criminal investigative purposes related to crimes described in <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="National Security Act of 1947/s:1104/ss:c/p:1" proposed="true">section 1104(c)(1) of the National Security Act of 1947</cato:entity-ref>, as added by <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="113 HR 624/s:3/ss:a" proposed="true">section 3(a) of this Act</cato:entity-ref>; or</text>
              </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H1776463BD54347B7B0744A6761E850F6">
                <enum>(D)</enum>
                <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">alter existing agreements or prohibit new agreements with respect to the sharing of cyber threat information between the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Department of Treasury</cato:entity-ref> and an entity that is part of the financial services sector.</text>
              </subparagraph> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H82BD91A21D1B4221A248B339216A28F2">
              <enum>(7)</enum>
              <header>Technical assistance</header> 
<subparagraph id="H6110FC4E8DC24BB5B01BD74DF89CB622">
                <enum>(A)</enum>
                <header>Discussions and assistance</header>
                <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this section shall be construed to prohibit any department or agency of the Federal Government from engaging in formal or informal technical discussion regarding cyber threat information with a cybersecurity provider or self-protected entity or from providing technical assistance to address vulnerabilities or mitigate threats at the request of such a provider or such an entity.</text>
              </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H774B3F84C84248969CBC844327BA7B0C">
                <enum>(B)</enum>
                <header>Coordination</header>
                <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any department or agency of the Federal Government engaging in an activity referred to in <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="113 HR 624/s:2/ss:b/p:7/sp:A" proposed="true">subparagraph (A)</cato:entity-ref> shall coordinate such activity with the entity of the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7000">Department of Homeland Security</cato:entity-ref> designated under <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="113 HR 624/s:2/ss:b/p:1" proposed="true">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref> and share all significant information resulting from such activity with such entity and all other appropriate departments and agencies of the Federal Government.</text>
              </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H144E90D306C24EE291A90FE9EE38F9A4">
                <enum>(C)</enum>
                <header>Sharing by designated entity</header>
                <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Consistent with the policies and procedures established under <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="113 HR 624/s:2/ss:b/p:5" proposed="true">paragraph (5)</cato:entity-ref>, the entity of the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7000">Department of Homeland Security</cato:entity-ref> designated under <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="113 HR 624/s:2/ss:b/p:1" proposed="true">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref> shall share with all appropriate departments and agencies of the Federal Government all significant information resulting from—</text> 
<clause id="HD00EAD84877C4A7F964B2F7C5BB25E2E">
                  <enum>(i)</enum>
                  <text>formal or informal technical discussions between such entity of the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7000">Department of Homeland Security</cato:entity-ref> and a cybersecurity provider or self-protected entity about cyber threat information; or</text>
                </clause> 
<clause id="HC6284845871946C8B9E69F07F20991B3">
                  <enum>(ii)</enum>
                  <text>any technical assistance such entity of the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7000">Department of Homeland Security</cato:entity-ref> provides to such cybersecurity provider or such self-protected entity to address vulnerabilities or mitigate threats.</text>
                </clause>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection> 
<subsection id="HE9EE6AE702B14BB5A7FC5AD92DCE0324" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <enum>(c)</enum> <header>Reports on information sharing</header> 
<paragraph id="H343B10E485EE48C1967484525C3C9177"> <enum>(1)</enum> <header>Inspector General of the Department of Homeland Security report</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7004">Inspector General of the Department of Homeland Security</cato:entity-ref>, in consultation with the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1504">Inspector General of the Department of Justice</cato:entity-ref>, the Inspector General of the Intelligence Community, the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="97EX">Inspector General of the Department of Defense</cato:entity-ref>, and the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" value="Privacy and Civil Liberties Oversight Board">Privacy and Civil Liberties Oversight Board</cato:entity-ref>, shall annually submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report containing a review of the use of information shared with the Federal Government under <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="National Security Act of 1947/s:1104/ss:b" proposed="true">subsection (b) of section 1104 of the National Security Act of 1947</cato:entity-ref>, as added by <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="113 HR 624/s:3/ss:a" proposed="true">section 3(a) of this Act</cato:entity-ref>, including—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H7CDF7593E4864CA08892B7414E28373E"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>a review of the use by the Federal Government of such information for a purpose other than a cybersecurity purpose;</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H1E3BDB9C289F411A859FA671294FCC9E"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text>a review of the type of information shared with the Federal Government under such subsection;</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6090138060BF4401986AC50AF3AB18B3"> <enum>(C)</enum> <text>a review of the actions taken by the Federal Government based on such information;</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA63E0BA968F44A2783CFD999BA2045C0"> <enum>(D)</enum> <text>appropriate metrics to determine the impact of the sharing of such information with the Federal Government on privacy and civil liberties, if any;</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H4CA164C3E7F44CFD90D8539877453B56" commented="no"> <enum>(E)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a list of the departments or agencies receiving such information;</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H1476DCF01A6543E487BA6226F0B33A19"> <enum>(F)</enum> <text>a review of the sharing of such information within the Federal Government to identify inappropriate stovepiping of shared information; and</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HFA2A02224CF64D2591D0D4948521EF0F"> <enum>(G)</enum> <text>any recommendations of the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7004">Inspector General of the Department of Homeland Security</cato:entity-ref> for improvements or modifications to the authorities under such section.</text> </subparagraph> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3F3E98BD94574E4BBA9A093F00A22333"> <enum>(2)</enum> <header>Privacy and civil liberties officers report</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" value="Officer for Civil Rights and Civil Liberties" entity-parent-id="7000">Officer for Civil Rights and Civil Liberties of the Department of Homeland Security</cato:entity-ref>, in consultation with the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" value="Privacy and Civil Liberties Oversight Board">Privacy and Civil Liberties Oversight Board</cato:entity-ref>, the Inspector General of the Intelligence Community, and the senior privacy and civil liberties officer of each department or agency of the Federal Government that receives cyber threat information shared with the Federal Government under such <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="National Security Act of 1947/s:1104/ss:b" proposed="true">subsection (b)</cato:entity-ref>, shall annually and jointly submit to <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> a report assessing the privacy and civil liberties impact of the activities conducted by the Federal Government under <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="National Security Act of 1947/s:1104" proposed="true">such section 1104</cato:entity-ref>. Such report shall include any recommendations the Civil Liberties Protection Officer and Chief Privacy and Civil Liberties Officer consider appropriate to minimize or mitigate the privacy and civil liberties impact of the sharing of cyber threat information under <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="National Security Act of 1947/s:1104" proposed="true">such section 1104</cato:entity-ref>.</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7CDCCFD9E4254A7CB07ACCB64E2B24D1"> <enum>(3)</enum> <header>Form</header> <text>Each report required under <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="113 HR 624/s:2/ss:c/p:1" proposed="true">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref> or <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="113 HR 624/s:2/ss:c/p:2" proposed="true">(2)</cato:entity-ref> shall be submitted in unclassified form, but may include a classified annex.</text> </paragraph> </subsection> 
<subsection id="H2ABF395B7F1A4CC6BEE8B544367E5AFF">
            <enum>(d)</enum>
            <header>Definitions</header>
            <text>In this section:</text> 
<paragraph id="H2A610C1C827C4FD58C8175094F753C6C">
              <enum>(1)</enum>
              <header>Appropriate congressional committees</header>
              <text>The term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H5906526092BC4D9CABEE3BC1FA7F290D">
                <enum>(A)</enum>
                <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="committee" entity-id="HHM00">Committee on Homeland Security</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="committee" entity-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="committee" entity-id="HIG00">Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence</cato:entity-ref>, and the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="committee" entity-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives</cato:entity-ref>; and</text>
              </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HBEA5DE388CC14515AC271469792668C1">
                <enum>(B)</enum>
                <text>the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="committee" entity-id="SSGA00">Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="committee" entity-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="committee" entity-id="SLIN00">Select Committee on Intelligence</cato:entity-ref>, and the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="committee" entity-id="SSAS00">Committee on Armed Services of the Senate</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H50C2C0B3215E422A9D0DFA278B107774">
              <enum>(2)</enum>
              <header>Cyber threat information, cyber threat intelligence, cybersecurity crimes, cybersecurity provider, cybersecurity purpose, and self-protected entity</header>
              <text>The terms <term>cyber threat information</term>, <term>cyber threat intelligence</term>, <term>cybersecurity crimes</term>, <term>cybersecurity provider</term>, <term>cybersecurity purpose</term>, and <term>self-protected entity</term> have the meaning given those terms in <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="National Security Act of 1947/s:1104" proposed="true">section 1104 of the National Security Act of 1947</cato:entity-ref>, as added by <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="113 HR 624/s:3/ss:a" proposed="true">section 3(a) of this Act</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
            </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB27B1429804348499C3B313F995ECB2C">
              <enum>(3)</enum>
              <header>Intelligence community</header>
              <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>intelligence community</term> has the meaning given the term in <cato:entity entity-type="law-citation">
                  <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="National Security Act of 1947/s:3/p:4">section 3(4) of the National Security Act of 1947</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/401a">
                    <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/50/401a//4">50 U.S.C. 401a(4)</cato:entity-ref>
                  </external-xref>)</cato:entity>.</text>
            </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HEE8460950DCA4903B001D764CB5409B2">
              <enum>(4)</enum>
              <header>Shared situational awareness</header>
              <text>The term <term>shared situational awareness</term> means an environment where cyber threat information is shared in real time between all designated Federal cyber operations centers to provide actionable information about all known cyber threats. </text>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
        </section> <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
      </quoted-block>
    </section> 
<section id="HEFA0FCEAAE1D4C86BB37E40B6F45731C" section-type="undesignated-section">
      <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Page 5, strike line 6 and all that follows through page 6, line 7.</text>
    </section> 
<section id="HCCE7D6F3732A45E48E1EBEEDEC6E7B3D" section-type="undesignated-section">
      <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Page 7, beginning on line 17, strike <quote>by the department or agency of the Federal Government receiving such cyber threat information</quote>.</text>
    </section>
<section id="H5EDC82666057429A92FAE60AE412368A" section-type="undesignated-section">
      <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Page 13, strike line 13 and all that follows through page 15, line 23.</text>
    </section>
<section id="H5DFDC7F703B7461E927B66875F797639" section-type="undesignated-section">
      <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Page 17, strike line 15 and all that follows through page 19, line 19.</text>
    </section> 
</resolution-body> 
<attestation>
    <attestation-group>
      <attestor display="no">Karen L. Haas,</attestor>
      <role>Clerk.</role>
    </attestation-group>
  </attestation> 
</resolution>
</doc>