<doc>
  <docmeta id="113hr3222ih">
    <bill congress="113" type="hr" number="3222" version="ih"/>
    <revision size="6541" annotations="0" status="complete" id="5" commit-time="2013-10-07T20:51:21Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113hr3222ih/5.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HC794D73705FD4FFCBA771132FA99076F" public-private="public">
  <metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>113 HR 3222 IH: Flushing Remonstrance Study Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2013-09-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
    <congress>113th CONGRESS</congress>
    <session>1st Session</session>
    <legis-num>H. R. 3222</legis-num>
    <current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
    <action>
      <action-date date="20130930">September 30, 2013</action-date>
      <action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="M001188">Ms. Meng</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name>
      </action-desc>
    </action>
    <legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
    <official-title>To authorize the Secretary of the Interior to conduct a special resource study of sites associated with the 1657 signing of the Flushing Remonstrance in Queens, New York, and for other purposes.</official-title>
  </form>
  <legis-body id="HCC20B3D1470C40A493C63080DE9CDE4E" style="OLC">
    <section id="H991AF204AE5C43579F58888C145B478B" section-type="section-one">
      <enum>1.</enum>
      <header>Short title</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote>
          <short-title>Flushing Remonstrance Study Act</short-title>
        </quote>.</text>
    </section>
    <section id="H365A91FC479E401EA5044FAA5969A76A">
      <enum>2.</enum>
      <header>Findings</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">
        <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> finds the following:</text>
      <paragraph id="HDDC266848B3045B3A106537AB19C8E83">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text>Dutch involvement in North America started with Henry Hudson’s 1609 voyage on the ship, Half Moon, employed by the Dutch East India Company.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HD225AA1199304E31AC7D271D7D76454A">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text>After 1640, New Netherland gradually began to transform from a chain of trading posts into a settlement colony.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HFC0926E72ED74D54952379082682396C">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <text>As Dutch and English settlers moved closer to one another, they began to assimilate in what would later become Queens County.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H21935A6C211D4C309EBEF3BEE6745AA0">
        <enum>(4)</enum>
        <text>The Dutch and English settlements had not been without conflict. Although the Dutch Republic was well known for its toleration of other faiths, Director General Peter Stuyvesant and his council thought that liberty of worship should not be granted to Quakers.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H1A710C2DC8434B7DAE05F88F73C012C2">
        <enum>(5)</enum>
        <text>When Quakers began to arrive in Flushing, the colonial government issued an ordinance that formally banned the practice of all religions outside of the Dutch Reformed Church.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HBA1E85200EA5493B8BB5B920A2F47ED9">
        <enum>(6)</enum>
        <text>On December 27, 1657, 30 Flushing residents signed what was later called the Flushing Remonstrance, objecting to this order. None of the remonstrance’s authors were Quakers.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H0EFBF871D4E44ED98A69B56A2A019E5F">
        <enum>(7)</enum>
        <text>Dutch colonial authorities proceeded to arrest the signers of the Flushing Remonstrance. In 1662, John Bowne defied the ban and allowed Quakers to hold services in his house. Bowne was fined and banished to the Dutch Republic for showing contempt for secular authority.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HE28C09F859A94CE6811AA29707C97498">
        <enum>(8)</enum>
        <text>Bowne was later exonerated after appealing to the guarantees of religious liberty before the Dutch West India Company and returned to Flushing in 1664. The colony later fell to British control on September 24, 1664.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H0E5DE68A681C4066909B8FF94AA56DA2">
        <enum>(9)</enum>
        <text>The Flushing Remonstrance is now considered by many to be instrumental in the development of religious liberty in the United States and a precursor to the First Amendment to the United States Constitution.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HF454175AF5F04F879C9E919A6723F9C7">
        <enum>(10)</enum>
        <text>In 1957, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1800">United States Postal Service</cato:entity-ref> released a 3-cent postage stamp commemorating the 300th Anniversary of the signing of the Flushing Remonstrance which read, <term>Religious Freedom in America</term>.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H089E13AAD5FC4DC79F2CA0AAEB314AA0">
        <enum>(11)</enum>
        <text>Queens remained rural and agricultural through the 18th and 19th Centuries. Although its Dutch identity diminished, the tolerance of diversity that has harbored Quakers and other religious sects in the Dutch Colonial period continues to this day. Queens is the most ethnically diverse urban area in the world, with a population of over 2,200,000 representing over 100 different nations and speaking over 138 different languages.</text>
      </paragraph>
    </section>
    <section id="HEF3DC94EBB764B4C84D67ED2C9D6B46A">
      <enum>3.</enum>
      <header>Definitions</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">As used in this Act:</text>
      <paragraph id="H4D49B5DE6FFC4F4B8A5D01BB8EDE42C5">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <header>Secretary</header>
        <text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1400">Secretary of the Interior</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HD3DD337EDAFD4C14AA030EB20C7934E5">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <header>Study area</header>
        <text>The term <term>study area</term> means the John Bowne House located at 3701 Bowne Street, Queens, New York, the Friends Meeting House located at 137–17 Northern Boulevard, Queens, New York, and other resources in the vicinity of Flushing related to the history of religious freedom during the era of the signing of the Flushing Remonstrance.</text>
      </paragraph>
    </section>
    <section id="HBB8FFB039A044182B5E931C93C1E58C3">
      <enum>4.</enum>
      <header>Special resource study</header>
      <subsection id="H073BF977414641BCB8C05B0562759C25">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Study</header>
        <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1400">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall conduct a special resource study of the study area.</text>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="H96E3842886044591B67813643E4BC6DC">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Contents</header>
        <text>In conducting the study under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Flushing Remonstrance Study Act/s:4/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1400">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall—</text>
        <paragraph id="HBF8CC8A76B394F408205E813115D2458">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">evaluate the national significance of the study area’s resources based on their relationship to the history of religious freedom associated with the signing of the Flushing Remonstrance;</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H1BBC1EFCF54140199BAA887E56ABCF2C">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>determine the suitability and feasibility of designating resources within the study area as a unit of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="National Park System" entity-parent-id="1443">National Park System</cato:entity-ref>;</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H60D0FFC85F184C2BA7A0818277CFB5E6">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <text>consider other alternatives for preservation, protection, and interpretation of the study area by Federal, State, or local governmental entities, or private and nonprofit organizations;</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H6642A2EF0F03415BB8D6F998C08C2A6A">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
          <text>identify properties related to the John Bowne House that could potentially meet criteria for designation as a National Historic Landmark;</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H043606BCBCD0466F9BFA97DC02C7636B">
          <enum>(5)</enum>
          <text>consult with interested Federal, State, or local governmental entities, private and nonprofit organizations, or any other interested individuals;</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H56ADBC6BFFEE4D9D83E3342D16FFC8F0">
          <enum>(6)</enum>
          <text>evaluate the impact of the proposed action on the flow of commerce and commercial activity, job opportunities, and any adverse economic effects that could not be avoided if the proposal is implemented; and</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H0907A4F01D30485696A0492E5BA77579">
          <enum>(7)</enum>
          <text>identify cost estimates for any Federal acquisition, development, interpretation, operation, and maintenance associated with the alternatives.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="H2A9878424B4F4F0D9BABBE875061C34F">
        <enum>(c)</enum>
        <header>Applicable law</header>
        <text>The study required under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Flushing Remonstrance Study Act/s:4/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref> shall be conducted in accordance with <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="National Park Service General Authorities Act/s:8">section 8 of National Park Service General Authorities Act</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1a">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/16/1a–5">16 U.S.C. 1a–5</cato:entity-ref>
            </external-xref>)</cato:entity>.</text>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="H5C60DF859AF34A188696A4E275927147">
        <enum>(d)</enum>
        <header>Report</header>
        <text>Not later than 3 years after the date on which funds are first made available for the study under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Flushing Remonstrance Study Act/s:4/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1400">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall submit to the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="committee" entity-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives</cato:entity-ref> and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="committee" entity-id="SSEG00">Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate</cato:entity-ref> a report containing the results of the study and any conclusions and recommendations of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1400">Secretary</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
      </subsection>
    </section>
  </legis-body>
</bill>
</doc>