<doc>
  <docmeta id="113hr2954rh">
    <bill congress="113" type="hr" number="2954" version="rh"/>
    <revision size="5029" annotations="0" status="complete" id="4" commit-time="2014-01-24T23:26:19Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113hr2954rh/4.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <bill bill-stage="Reported-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H36D8597668E3475BB42B1B23B0BC8C45" public-private="public">
  <metadata>
<dublinCore>
<dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">113 HR 2954 RH: To authorize Escambia County, Florida, to convey certain property that was formerly part of Santa Rosa Island National Monument and that was conveyed to Escambia County subject to restrictions on use and reconveyance.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">2013-08-01</dc:date>
<dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IB</distribution-code>
    <calendar display="yes">Union Calendar No. 214</calendar>
    <congress display="yes">113th CONGRESS</congress>
    <session display="yes">1st Session</session>
    <legis-num>H. R. 2954</legis-num>
    <associated-doc display="yes" role="report">[Report No. 113–296]</associated-doc>
    <current-chamber display="yes">IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
    <action>
      <action-date date="20130801">August 1, 2013</action-date>
      <action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="M001144">Mr. Miller of Florida</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name>
      </action-desc>
    </action>
    <action>
      <action-date>December 16, 2013</action-date>
      <action-desc>Committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union and ordered to be printed<pagebreak/>
      </action-desc>
    </action>
    <legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
    <official-title display="yes">To authorize Escambia County, Florida, to convey certain property that was formerly part of Santa Rosa Island National Monument and that was conveyed to Escambia County subject to restrictions on use and reconveyance.<pagebreak/>
    </official-title>
  </form>
  <legis-body id="H0F683AA384FD4DCC9D121C00DA3A2F2A" style="OLC">
    <section id="H6A3E9B8B6CAE4E57A6A239B09DA5803D" section-type="section-one">
      <enum>1.</enum>
      <header>Conveyance of property</header>
      <subsection id="HB3A3DA725FB74364961D848230BA8161">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Conveyance free of restrictions</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding the restrictions on conveyance of property located on Santa Rosa Island, Florida, contained in the <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Act of July 30, 1946">Act of July 30, 1946</cato:entity-ref> (chapter 699; <cato:entity-ref entity-type="statute-at-large" value="statute-at-large/70/712">70 Stat. 712</cato:entity-ref>)</cato:entity>, and the deed to the property from the United States to Escambia County, Florida, dated January 15, 1947, Escambia County may, at its discretion, convey or otherwise dispose of all of its right, title, and interest (in whole or in part), in and to any portion of the property that was conveyed to it pursuant to that Act and deed, to any person or entity, free from any restriction on conveyance or reconveyance imposed by the United States in that Act or deed. Any conveyance under this subsection shall be subject to the conditions set forth in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="113 HR 2954/s:1/ss:c" proposed="true">subsection (c)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="H9095166F34DC40A9AF6E90B9A745CE16">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Leasehold interests</header>
        <text>No person or entity holding a leasehold interest in the property as of the date of the enactment of this Act shall be required to involuntarily accept a fee interest in lieu of their leasehold interest in the property.</text>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="H4416DB1B1EF54942B407A27A185021CB">
        <enum>(c)</enum>
        <header>Conditions</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any conveyance under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="113 HR 2954/s:1/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref> shall be subject to the following conditions:</text>
        <paragraph id="HF89F82FDD2C24862B83D5D840C3FE913">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than two calendar years after the date of the enactment of this Act, Escambia County shall convey to Santa Rosa County all right, title, and interest held in and to any portion of the property that was conveyed to Escambia County under the Act and deed that fall in the jurisdictional boundaries of Santa Rosa County, Florida. The conveyance by Escambia County to Santa Rosa County shall be absolute and shall terminate any subjugation of Santa Rosa County to Escambia County or any regulation of Santa Rosa County by Escambia County. Santa Rosa County shall not be required to pay any sum for the subject property other than actual costs associated with the conveyance.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H95BF1DC2E1BA4F53B149140B651283EC">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>Santa Rosa County or any other person to which property is conveyed under this Act may reconvey property, or any portion of property, conveyed to it under this section.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H6E813474ACED4981BC1D2892E0F4A43A">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <text>For all properties defined under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="113 HR 2954/s:1/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref> the leaseholders, or owners are free to pursue incorporation, annexation, or any other governmental status so long as all other legal conditions required for doing so are followed.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H14653519F768449F96246149B06D7330">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each property defined under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="113 HR 2954/s:1/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref> is under the jurisdiction of the county and any other local government entity in which the property is located.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HB9ED199AC84A485ABC754210D454C2E8">
          <enum>(5)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any proceeds from the conveyance of any property defined under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="113 HR 2954/s:1/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref> by Escambia County or Santa Rosa County, other than direct and incidental costs associated with such conveyance, shall be considered windfall profits and shall revert to the United States.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HFAA9B54956A14A73BE6FB1AD9418C431">
          <enum>(6)</enum>
          <text>Escambia County and Santa Rosa County shall in perpetuity preserve those areas on Santa Rosa Island currently dedicated to conservation, preservation, public, recreation, access and public parking in accordance with resolutions heretofore adopted by the Board of County Commissioners of each respective county.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6E4903C668444A4AAD216E124862ED7D">
        <enum>(d)</enum>
        <header>Determination of compliance</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Escambia County and Santa Rosa County shall have no deadline or requirement to make any conveyance or reconveyance of any property defined under subsection (a) other than the conveyance required under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="113 HR 2954/s:1/ss:c/p:1" proposed="true">subsection (c)(1)</cato:entity-ref>. Each county may establish terms for conveyance or reconveyance, subject to the conditions set forth in this Act and applicable State law.</text>
      </subsection>
    </section>
  </legis-body>
  <endorsement display="yes">
    <action-date>December 16, 2013</action-date>
    <action-desc>Committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union and ordered to be printed</action-desc>
  </endorsement>
</bill>
</doc>