<doc>
  <docmeta id="113hr3585ih">
    <bill congress="113" type="hr" number="3585" version="ih"/>
    <revision size="5398" annotations="0" status="complete" id="3" commit-time="2013-11-29T19:50:34Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113hr3585ih/3.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H550CB15C94834DE3A79CEF368B3D0F26" public-private="public">
  <metadata>
<dublinCore>
<dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">113 HR 3585 IH: Walter Patterson and Werner Foerster Justice and Extradition Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">2013-11-21</dc:date>
<dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
    <congress>113th CONGRESS</congress>
    <session>1st Session</session>
    <legis-num>H. R. 3585</legis-num>
    <current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
    <action>
      <action-date date="20131121">November 21, 2013</action-date>
      <action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="S000522">Mr. Smith of New Jersey</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S001165">Mr. Sires</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name>
      </action-desc>
    </action>
    <legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
    <official-title>To direct the President to submit to Congress a report on fugitives currently residing in other countries whose extradition is sought by the United States and related matters.</official-title>
  </form>
  <legis-body id="H62EE97C74936465FB4376BE4929D393D" style="OLC">
    <section id="HF078C979FB834EFEBE46EBC9263416FC" section-type="section-one">
      <enum>1.</enum>
      <header>Short title</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote>
          <short-title>Walter Patterson and Werner Foerster Justice and Extradition Act</short-title>
        </quote>.</text>
    </section>
    <section id="H267A67BD398C4E59B5B68760A71C88CE">
      <enum>2.</enum>
      <header>Findings and purpose</header>
      <subsection id="H5821BF1BA26E483384FED5109871A26F">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Findings</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">
          <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> finds the following:</text>
        <paragraph id="H02BD5D48028F4888967BBF3AEBECBBBE">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>Extradition is the formal surrender of a person by one state to another state for prosecution or punishment.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H692B797DFCEE47EAAE5574A968E358C8">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>Refusal by other nations to extradite or otherwise render to the United States fugitives within their jurisdiction who have been convicted of committing crimes on United States soil impedes the judicial process and undermines the rule of law.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HD2BF5698480C49F3B4073417F865963D">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <text>The United States has bilateral extradition treaties with more than 100 nations and an extradition agreement with the European Union.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H408FF2BE42DF4B168A35208E604FAAA5">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
          <text>The United States has bilateral extradition treaties with Portugal and Cuba.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HBDE6316FD47748BD945C16E37E294692">
          <enum>(5)</enum>
          <text>The failure to bring criminal fugitives to justice in the United States is an affront to the victims of those crimes.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H113BB4E25E474CD1ACD6F980CB5AB7A6">
          <enum>(6)</enum>
          <text>The refusal of Portugal, a close ally and good friend of the United States, to extradite George Wright, convicted of the 1962 murder of Walter Patterson, fugitive from justice since his 1970 escape from the Bayside State Prison in New Jersey, is a deplorable example of a failure to extradite, and has caused ongoing suffering and stress to Mr. Patterson’s surviving family and friends.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HD606F583526F4FCE82AF68A560592BAC">
          <enum>(7)</enum>
          <text>The refusal of Cuba to extradite or otherwise render Joanne Chesimard, an escaped convict who fled to Cuba after killing Werner Foerster, New Jersey State Trooper, is a deplorable example of a failure to extradite or otherwise render, and has caused ongoing suffering and stress to Mr. Foerster’s surviving family and friends.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H7D942DEC15BE437B860346DC1ABA223E">
          <enum>(8)</enum>
          <text>The refusals to extradite George Wright and Joanne Chesimard are emblematic of a number of such refusals from other nations, such that United States policies and efforts to secure extradition and the extradition policies of countries from which the United States seeks extradition and rendition bear further examination.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H3FB25B7DE64247F19727DCD25A0A3247">
          <enum>(9)</enum>
          <text>Such examination will be promoted by the issuance of a public report on the status of extradition requests by the United States and related matters.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="H189DCDD9FF2E4EA59B23EEDC0596502A">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Purpose</header>
        <text>The purpose of this Act is to provide information necessary to evaluate and thereby strengthen United States Government efforts to extradite fugitives.</text>
      </subsection>
    </section>
    <section id="HFBCC758A805844A599ED1B0BF1C099AC">
      <enum>3.</enum>
      <header>Report</header>
      <subsection id="HE4E4E888CE1C4B22A411D766825F548A">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>In general</header>
        <text>Not later than 270 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, and not later than the end of each 12-month period thereafter, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on—</text>
        <paragraph id="H56B8D5766F9F4A488F9EB2D72A378DF1">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>the number of fugitives, and others for whom the United States Government is seeking extradition or rendition, currently residing in other countries whose extradition is sought by the United States and a list of those countries;</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H11ABF28B9C2E4AAB9AD6F35B2BE89765">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>diplomatic and other efforts, if any, the United States has undertaken to secure the return of such fugitives;</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H88C1BE11CC7C4E749CD80585AF561296">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <text>the average length of time these cases have been outstanding;</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H657C2FDA61F0435EA3FF8DE34F85FBCF">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
          <text>how many of these cases have been resolved to the satisfaction of the United States;</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HEE893DFACEB34402A76C825600EC7E74">
          <enum>(5)</enum>
          <text>factors that have been barriers to the resolution of these cases; and</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HB3D803F58280467486BF38208EB10B70">
          <enum>(6)</enum>
          <text>information on the number of United States citizens whose extradition has been sought by other countries during the past 5 years, a list of those countries seeking extradition, and the outcomes of those requests.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="H810E04D2B00244F29669AA46162105D9">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Form</header>
        <text>The report required by <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Walter Patterson and Werner Foerster Justice and Extradition Act/s:3/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref> shall be submitted in unclassified form, but may include a classified annex if necessary.</text>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="H4F2CE158A30E481A978348536A60B961">
        <enum>(c)</enum>
        <header>Definition</header>
        <text>In this section, the term <quote>appropriate congressional committees</quote> means—</text>
        <paragraph id="H67B418ABF153425C88AF13606C983826">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="committee" entity-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</cato:entity-ref> and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="committee" entity-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives</cato:entity-ref>; and</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HF318B05C8FDA42F6A0B17E78AF375903">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="committee" entity-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations</cato:entity-ref> and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="committee" entity-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
    </section>
  </legis-body>
</bill>
</doc>