<doc>
  <docmeta id="113hres651ih">
    <bill congress="113" type="hres" number="651" version="ih"/>
    <revision size="2633" annotations="0" status="complete" id="4" commit-time="2014-07-10T20:26:52Z" committer="zwilliams" doc="113hres651ih/4.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <resolution xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" dms-id="H2E751F465F21443BB3E76A2C5EBC9846" key="H" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print">
	<metadata>
<dublinCore>
<dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">113 HRES 651 IH: Expressing support for the network of experienced and accredited wildlife rehabilitation centers across the United States and honoring their important work in protecting native wildlife.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">2014-06-26</dc:date>
<dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">113th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session display="yes">2d Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. RES. 651</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20140626">June 26, 2014</action-date>
			<action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="S000583">Mr. Smith of Texas</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="M001179">Mr. Marino</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000933">Mr. Moran</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000413">Mr. Whitfield</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000265">Mr. Petri</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Y000065">Mr. Yoho</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000291">Mrs. Ellmers</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001101">Ms. Clark of Massachusetts</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000191">Mr. DeFazio</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000216">Ms. DeLauro</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000378">Mr. Kinzinger of Illinois</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="H001068">Mr. Huffman</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name>
      </action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">Expressing support for the network of experienced and accredited wildlife rehabilitation centers
			 across the United States and honoring their important work in protecting
			 native wildlife.</official-title>
	</form>
	<preamble>
		<whereas>
      <text>Whereas across the United States, wildlife rehabilitators take in hundreds of thousands of wild
			 animals every year that have been orphaned, injured, or become sick;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the purpose of wildlife rehabilitators is to restore health and subsequently to release
			 wild animals indigenous to the United States;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas many of the wild animals cared for by rehabilitators are protected by Federal and State
			 laws;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas rehabilitators are often volunteers and are not directly funded by Federal or State natural
			 resources or wildlife agencies;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas most wildlife rehabilitators instead incur significant costs to fund their activities,
			 paying for everything from incubators to expensive specialty food;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas in addition to significant financial expenditures, wildlife rehabilitators also spend
			 substantial time and energy caring for and bringing native wildlife back
			 to health;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas members of the general public cannot meet the specialized needs of wild animals, and the
			 United States needs a professional network of trained individuals to
			 provide this care; and</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas most wild animals are orphaned or injured and rehabilitators give them a second chance:
			 Now, therefore, be it</text>
    </whereas>
  </preamble>
	<resolution-body id="H88A996AFFAE9414B9156D4B459A11EBC" style="traditional">
		<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H79A1E96BAD234AD296E1601854F4A6DE" section-type="undesignated-section">
      <enum/>
      <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the <cato:entity-ref entity-id="0050" entity-type="federal-body">House of Representatives</cato:entity-ref> recognizes the importance of experienced and accredited wildlife
			 rehabilitation centers and their numerous contributions to the humane
			 treatment of animals throughout the United States.</text>
		</section>
  </resolution-body>
</resolution>
</doc>