<doc>
  <docmeta id="113hconres58eh">
    <bill congress="113" type="hconres" number="58" version="eh"/>
    <revision size="2505" annotations="0" status="complete" id="3" commit-time="2013-10-17T22:29:10Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113hconres58eh/3.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <resolution xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" dms-id="HD4FFFC2BE47C41829A1495CFBC183661" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Engrossed-in-House" resolution-type="house-concurrent" star-print="no-star-print" key="H" stage-count="1"> 
<metadata>
<dublinCore>
<title>113 HCON 58 EH: Expressing the sense of Congress regarding the need for the continued availability of religious services to members of the Armed Forces and their families during a lapse in appropriations.</title>
<publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</publisher>
<date/>
<format>text/xml</format>
<language>EN</language>
<rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="no">IV</distribution-code> 
<congress display="yes">113th CONGRESS</congress> 
<session display="yes">1st Session</session> 
<legis-num>H. CON. RES. 58</legis-num> 
<current-chamber display="no">IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<legis-type>CONCURRENT RESOLUTION</legis-type> 
<official-title display="no">Expressing the sense of Congress regarding the need for the continued availability of religious services to members of the Armed Forces and their families during a lapse in appropriations.</official-title> 
</form> 
<preamble> 
<whereas>
      <text>Whereas the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="9700">Department of Defense</cato:entity-ref> has determined that some military chaplains and other personnel, including contract personnel, hired to perform duties of a military chaplain are not able to perform religious services on military installations during a lapse in appropriations;</text>
    </whereas> 
<whereas>
      <text>Whereas this determination threatens the ability of members of the Armed Services and their families to exercise their First Amendment rights to worship and participate in religious activities; and</text>
    </whereas> 
<whereas>
      <text>Whereas the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1400">Department of the Interior</cato:entity-ref> has permitted the performance of First Amendment activities in areas controlled by the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1443">National Park Service</cato:entity-ref> despite the lapse in appropriations: Now, therefore, be it</text>
    </whereas>
  </preamble> 
<resolution-body style="traditional" id="HA038B570798243C393E2FE8E63CD1CBB"> 
<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H0E2018AB6194445FAD3D93606A4FF2AF">
      <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref>—</text> 
<paragraph id="H77860B75BFDA4C87A5C7752CCCBC2602">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text>recognizes that the performance of religious services and the provision of ministry are protected activities under the First Amendment of the United States Constitution;</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H361FA262F4E54D5EBFD07AB5623F03F8">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text>urges and intends that the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="9700">Secretary of Defense</cato:entity-ref> permit the performance of religious services on property owned or maintained by the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="9700">Department of Defense</cato:entity-ref>, during any lapse in appropriations, in the same manner and to the same extent as such religious services are otherwise available; and</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7DE48190393449FB8D91FA6EC1ADFD43">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">urges and intends that the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="9700">Secretary of Defense</cato:entity-ref> permit military chaplains and other personnel, including contract personnel, hired to perform duties of a military chaplain to perform religious services and ministry, during any lapse in appropriations, in the same manner and to the same extent as such chaplains and other personnel are otherwise permitted to perform religious services and ministry.</text>
      </paragraph>
    </section> 
</resolution-body> 
<attestation>
    <attestation-group>
      <attestation-date date="20131005" chamber="House">Passed the House of Representatives October 5, 2013.</attestation-date>
      <attestor display="no">Karen L. Haas,</attestor>
      <role>Clerk.</role>
    </attestation-group>
  </attestation>
<endorsement display="yes"/>
</resolution>
</doc>