<doc>
  <docmeta id="113hr2877ih">
    <bill congress="113" type="hr" number="2877" version="ih"/>
    <revision size="5937" annotations="0" status="complete" id="3" commit-time="2013-08-08T19:44:09Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113hr2877ih/3.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HDB2F1BB6659A44B3BB04CCB34A02D8BE" public-private="public">
	<metadata>
<dublinCore>
<title>113 HR 2877 IH: To prevent certain discriminatory taxation of natural gas pipeline property.</title>
<publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</publisher>
<date>2013-07-31</date>
<format>text/xml</format>
<language>EN</language>
<rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>113th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 2877</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20130731">July 31, 2013</action-date>
			<action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="F000461">Mr. Flores</sponsor> (for
			 himself, <cosponsor name-id="G000410">Mr. Gene Green of Texas</cosponsor>,
			 <cosponsor name-id="M001179">Mr. Marino</cosponsor>,
			 <cosponsor name-id="C001063">Mr. Cuellar</cosponsor>,
			 <cosponsor name-id="O000168">Mr. Olson</cosponsor>, and
			 <cosponsor name-id="M001149">Mr. Michaud</cosponsor>) introduced the following
			 bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee
			 on the Judiciary</committee-name>
      </action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To prevent certain discriminatory taxation of natural gas
		  pipeline property.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H7A90D14FBD644E4CBBBEED7219422457" style="OLC">
		<section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8D72DAD6DFD8475FB57A40691B104B4E" section-type="section-one">
      <enum>1.</enum>
      <header>Limitation on discriminatory
			 taxation of natural gas pipeline property</header>
			<subsection id="H1264332D44514C5D97689D9684EDFE63">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Definitions</header>
        <text>For
			 purposes of section:</text>
				<paragraph id="H18C994F0F99D4A9EBBC9A34E7D170D9F">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>Assessment</header>
          <text>The
			 term <term>assessment</term> means valuation for a property tax levied by a
			 taxing authority.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HDF1D144A45FC43AF850D114A33291839">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Assessment
			 jurisdiction</header>
          <text>The term <term>assessment jurisdiction</term> means
			 a geographical area used in determining the assessed value of property for ad
			 valorem taxation.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HFC8EAB12999A43AAA5C6AC39272C28B0">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <header>Commercial and
			 industrial property</header>
          <text>The term <term>commercial and industrial
			 property</term> means property (excluding natural gas pipeline property, public
			 utility property, and land used primarily for agricultural purposes or timber
			 growth) devoted to commercial or industrial use and subject to a property tax
			 levy.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H8A5DD0BE91014507879A601CA89911CA">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
          <header>Natural gas
			 pipeline property</header>
          <text>The term <term>natural gas pipeline
			 property</term> means all property, real, personal, and intangible, owned or
			 used by a natural gas pipeline providing transportation or storage of natural
			 gas, subject to the jurisdiction of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="8990">Federal Energy Regulatory
			 Commission</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H2618579A166746ECA3DA2CA5759B6407">
          <enum>(5)</enum>
          <header>Public utility
			 property</header>
          <text>The term <term>public utility property</term> means
			 property (excluding natural gas pipeline property) that is devoted to public
			 service and is owned or used by any entity that performs a public service and
			 is regulated by any governmental agency.</text>
				</paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="H5C3EB8CB55D443E9AA6BAFB78946C52D">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Discriminatory
			 Acts</header>
        <text>The acts specified in this subsection unreasonably burden
			 and discriminate against interstate commerce. A State, subdivision of a State,
			 authority acting for a State or subdivision of a State, or any other taxing
			 authority (including a taxing jurisdiction and a taxing district) may not do
			 any of the following such acts:</text>
				<paragraph id="H51B319A3FBC640DCAA898976C3A88109">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>Assess natural gas
			 pipeline property at a value that has a higher ratio to the true market value
			 of the natural gas pipeline property than the ratio that the assessed value of
			 other commercial and industrial property in the same assessment jurisdiction
			 has to the true market value of the other commercial and industrial
			 property.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H092A14C2DD1D44209FCE2076403DD7EC">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>Levy or collect a
			 tax on an assessment that may not be made under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="113 HR 2877/s:1/ss:b/p:1" proposed="true">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H43C9AF1E499840539CAA46EC4B070314">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <text>Levy or collect an
			 ad valorem property tax on natural gas pipeline property at a tax rate that
			 exceeds the tax rate applicable to commercial and industrial property in the
			 same assessment jurisdiction.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H390CF42E9D2A41F8B2D1E36A94C815E2">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
          <text>Impose any other
			 tax that discriminates against a natural gas pipeline providing transportation
			 subject to the jurisdiction of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="8990">Federal Energy Regulatory Commission</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
				</paragraph>
      </subsection>
    </section>
    <section id="H5AE7D2CE31F040D79E660B23C012FEA5">
      <enum>2.</enum>
      <header>Jurisdiction of
			 courts; relief</header>
			<subsection id="H5497776D538245FAAF48B904A05D92DB">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Grant of
			 Jurisdiction</header>
        <text>Notwithstanding <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc/28/1341">
            <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/28/1341">section 1341</external-xref> of title 28, United
			 States Code</cato:entity-ref>, and notions of comity, and without regard to the amount in
			 controversy or citizenship of the parties, the district courts of the United
			 States shall have jurisdiction, concurrent with other jurisdiction of the
			 courts of the United States, of States, and of all other taxing authorities and
			 taxing jurisdictions, to prevent a violation of <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="113 HR 2877/s:1" proposed="true">section 1</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
			</subsection>
      <subsection id="H06DB87CF125B4ADFBD9B190BD2F3888A">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Relief</header>
        <text>Except
			 as otherwise provided in this subsection, relief may be granted under this Act
			 only if the ratio of assessed value to true market value of natural gas
			 pipeline property exceeds by at least 5 percent the ratio of assessed value to
			 true market value of other commercial and industrial property in the same
			 assessment jurisdiction. If the ratio of the assessed value of other commercial
			 and industrial property in the assessment jurisdiction to the true market value
			 of all other commercial and industrial property cannot be determined to the
			 satisfaction of the court through the random-sampling method known as a sales
			 assessment ratio study (to be carried out under statistical principles
			 applicable to such a study), each of the following shall be a violation of
			 section 1 for which relief under this Act may be granted:</text>
				<paragraph id="H536D7505E9A348DD87167423DA28DFE9">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>An assessment of
			 the natural gas pipeline property at a value that has a higher ratio of
			 assessed value to the true market value of the natural gas pipeline property
			 than the ratio of the assessed value of all other property (excluding public
			 utility property) subject to a property tax levy in the assessment jurisdiction
			 has to the true market value of all other property (excluding public utility
			 property).</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H6C1349AD386C4DD490CB28C8C1060CC4">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>The collection of
			 an ad valorem property tax on the natural gas pipeline property at a tax rate
			 that exceeds the tax rate applicable to all other taxable property (excluding
			 public utility property) in the taxing jurisdiction.</text>
				</paragraph>
      </subsection>
    </section>
  </legis-body>
</bill>
</doc>