<doc>
  <docmeta id="113hr3980ih">
    <bill congress="113" type="hr" number="3980" version="ih"/>
    <revision size="13328" annotations="0" status="complete" id="6" commit-time="2014-02-05T21:26:27Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113hr3980ih/6.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H30628AA051454B2DABE3393BDA2006B6" public-private="public">
  <metadata>
<dublinCore>
<dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">113 HR 3980 IH: Water Supply Permitting Coordination Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">2014-01-31</dc:date>
<dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
    <congress>113th CONGRESS</congress>
    <session>2d Session</session>
    <legis-num>H. R. 3980</legis-num>
    <current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
    <action>
      <action-date date="20140131">January 31, 2014</action-date>
      <action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="M001177">Mr. McClintock</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="L000571">Mrs. Lummis</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name>
      </action-desc>
    </action>
    <legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
    <official-title>To authorize the Secretary of the Interior to coordinate Federal and State permitting processes related to the construction of new surface water storage projects on lands under the jurisdiction of the Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Agriculture and to designate the Bureau of Reclamation as the lead agency for permit processing, and for other purposes.</official-title>
  </form>
  <legis-body id="H828E793554784530B588D1206CD6B16E" style="OLC">
    <section id="H4B5879D03F714DA6A18A378AB16ECF30" section-type="section-one">
      <enum>1.</enum>
      <header>Short title</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote>
          <short-title>
            <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" proposed="true" value="Water Supply Permitting Coordination Act" entity-type="act">Water Supply Permitting Coordination Act</cato:entity-ref>
          </short-title>
        </quote>.</text>
    </section>
    <section id="H4CCEE5C032B34D28AFFE7DAFCC66FFD5">
      <enum>2.</enum>
      <header>Definitions</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text>
      <paragraph id="HEBA7C6DAEF93450484547BAD8AADDE54">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <header>Secretary</header>
        <text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1400" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of the Interior</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H525EB8A125F646168E152CF39BBFAE16">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <header>Bureau</header>
        <text>The term <term>Bureau</term> means the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1425" entity-type="federal-body">Bureau of Reclamation</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H9BD97CB390BD455DB1491C8D6A9E0D4B">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <header>Qualifying projects</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>qualifying projects</term> means new surface water storage projects constructed on lands administered by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1400" entity-type="federal-body">Department of the Interior</cato:entity-ref> or the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1200" entity-type="federal-body">Department of Agriculture</cato:entity-ref>, exclusive of any easement, right-of-way, lease, or any private holding.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H084BCC93077C43AE8D3555CED561D04B">
        <enum>(4)</enum>
        <header>Cooperating agencies</header>
        <text>The term <term>cooperating agency</term> means a Federal agency with jurisdiction over a review, analysis, opinion, statement, permit, license, or other approval or decision required for a qualifying project under applicable Federal laws and regulations, or a State agency subject to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Water Supply Permitting Coordination Act/s:3/ss:c" proposed="true">section 3(c)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
      </paragraph>
    </section>
    <section id="HC3D7DA8A34AB4994B3CAECCB8B52074D">
      <enum>3.</enum>
      <header>Establishment of lead agency and cooperating agencies</header>
      <subsection id="H9120BF7D4AF44D5BA1C484962EA34EED">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Establishment of Lead Agency</header>
        <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1425" entity-type="federal-body">Bureau of Reclamation</cato:entity-ref> is established as the lead agency for purposes of coordinating all reviews, analyses, opinions, statements, permits, licenses, or other approvals or decisions required under Federal law to construct qualifying projects.</text>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="H75C56D687D194C5B8BAC9739E1EE920B">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Identification and Establishment of Cooperating Agencies</header>
        <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1425" entity-type="federal-body">Commissioner of the Bureau</cato:entity-ref> shall—</text>
        <paragraph id="H85DC1AB310BD4FE0B88E58E768FE52FE">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>identify, as early as practicable upon receipt of an application for a qualifying project, any Federal agency that may have jurisdiction over a review, analysis, opinion, statement, permit, license, approval, or decision required for a qualifying project under applicable Federal laws and regulations; and</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HC1A59FA745E548C38A9DC90FC2BA2D97">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>notify any such agency, within a reasonable timeframe, that the agency has been designated as a cooperating agency in regards to the qualifying project unless that agency responds to the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1425" entity-type="federal-body">Bureau</cato:entity-ref> in writing, within a timeframe set forth by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1425" entity-type="federal-body">Bureau</cato:entity-ref>, notifying the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1425" entity-type="federal-body">Bureau</cato:entity-ref> that the agency—</text>
          <subparagraph id="H5AF650F82CE046ADA19E9345934458F8">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>has no jurisdiction or authority with respect to the qualifying project;</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="HC3477C033E8B4C81B4EBE3877D0AD30F">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>has no expertise or information relevant to the qualifying project or any review, analysis, opinion, statement, permit, license, or other approval or decision associated therewith; or</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="HFBEB3DEBEAC94F85BFAECDA18E206003">
            <enum>(C)</enum>
            <text>does not intend to submit comments on the qualifying project or conduct any review of such a project or make any decision with respect to such project in a manner other than in cooperation with the Bureau.</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="H5485929A6C6F4C49A6F6F4F8A155996D">
        <enum>(c)</enum>
        <header>State Authority</header>
        <text>A State in which a qualifying project is being considered may choose, consistent with State law—</text>
        <paragraph id="H8C860B48360E4FD4A42EB4A88BB9E231">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>to participate as a cooperating agency; and</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HCF78B3A0FF3146B096144ED3D807DEC4">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>to make subject to the processes of this Act all State agencies that—</text>
          <subparagraph id="H0611DB707265416398A7A8ED2A48B3FD">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>have jurisdiction over the qualifying project;</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="HB81203CF1B10422F9E311295DFC34089">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>are required to conduct or issue a review, analysis, or opinion for the qualifying project; or</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="HDD33C1CA0FCC4C8E8C368DAC62FF1E6F">
            <enum>(C)</enum>
            <text>are required to make a determination on issuing a permit, license, or approval for the water resource project.</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
    </section>
    <section id="HD415E75D5EEF4A44A8A458CFA03EE506">
      <enum>4.</enum>
      <header>Bureau responsibilities</header>
      <subsection id="HBB586BC021E54E12B4F3AEE578FCB9F8">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>In general</header>
        <text>The principal responsibilities of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1425" entity-type="federal-body">Bureau</cato:entity-ref> under this Act are to—</text>
        <paragraph id="H216AF40938874955A2CED6A84800AC71">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>serve as the point of contact for applicants, State agencies, Indian tribes, and others regarding proposed projects;</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H78476E40EE5546B7B2B484F1151AF0C5">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>coordinate preparation of unified environmental documentation that will serve as the basis for all Federal decisions necessary to authorize the use of Federal lands for qualifying projects; and</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H474EB917D88745FA8F5B7441DA8706B6">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <text>coordinate all Federal agency reviews necessary for project development and construction of qualifying projects.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="H689BE821B5604065AD1E8878D27A787E">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Coordination process</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1425" entity-type="federal-body">Bureau</cato:entity-ref> shall have the following coordination responsibilities:</text>
        <paragraph id="HAFC45E702F184AEFBEA411FBBF897DE9">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>Pre-application coordination</header>
          <text>Notify cooperating agencies of proposed qualifying projects not later than 30 days after receipt of a proposal and facilitate a preapplication meeting for prospective applicants, relevant Federal and State agencies, and Indian tribes to—</text>
          <subparagraph id="H893A782EE15C4C8BBEDEEFF8C80AA4E8">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>explain applicable processes, data requirements, and applicant submissions necessary to complete the required Federal agency reviews within the time frame established; and</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="HE816A65DA4224148B48AFBE8B46EBBBA">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>establish the schedule for the qualifying project.</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H3F1460A743EA4CDC91993175CE62E7D2">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Consultation with cooperating agencies</header>
          <text>Consult with the cooperating agencies throughout the Federal agency review process, identify and obtain relevant data in a timely manner, and set necessary deadlines for cooperating agencies.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H70B8EA7E1E214238B1E9DB3348B95B20">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <header>Schedule</header>
          <text>Work with the qualifying project applicant and cooperating agencies to establish a project schedule. In establishing the schedule, the Bureau shall consider, among other factors—</text>
          <subparagraph id="H0FA3ED892FBC4A298C900275D209867B">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>the responsibilities of cooperating agencies under applicable laws and regulations;</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H81A5EB684E134FF685723DE5B1A0B418">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>the resources available to the cooperating agencies and the non-Federal qualifying project sponsor, as applicable;</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H845D26DECCA34F1798B5A3E3A472EA23">
            <enum>(C)</enum>
            <text>the overall size and complexity of the qualifying project;</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H4DC7F009DD38420C929B35DAC1228985">
            <enum>(D)</enum>
            <text>the overall schedule for and cost of the qualifying project; and</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="HC6A06048CD6F46FEAE6CE6FD3381C0C1">
            <enum>(E)</enum>
            <text>the sensitivity of the natural and historic resources that may be affected by the qualifying project.</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HA46133173A6D415A94A7B6217BA20F50">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
          <header>Environmental compliance</header>
          <text>Prepare a unified environmental review document for each qualifying project application, incorporating a single environmental record on which all cooperating agencies with authority to issue approvals for a given qualifying project shall base project approval decisions. Help ensure that cooperating agencies make necessary decisions, within their respective authorities, regarding Federal approvals in accordance with the following timelines:</text>
          <subparagraph id="HC789D74093814889B516198ED21639D3">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>Not later than one year after acceptance of a completed project application when an environmental assessment and finding of no significant impact is determined to be the appropriate level of review under the <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
                <cato:entity-ref value="National Environmental Policy Act of 1969" entity-type="act">National Environmental Policy Act of 1969</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4321">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/42/4321/etseq">42 U.S.C. 4321 et seq</cato:entity-ref>.</external-xref>)</cato:entity>.</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H618CA7A4DD7949B98CD777B59202F947">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>Not later than one year and 30 days after the close of the public comment period for a draft environmental impact statement under the <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
                <cato:entity-ref value="National Environmental Policy Act of 1969" entity-type="act">National Environmental Policy Act of 1969</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4321">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/42/4321/etseq">42 U.S.C. 4321 et seq</cato:entity-ref>.</external-xref>)</cato:entity>, when an environmental impact statement is required under the same.</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HB56922651FEF4609BE4E590AE72E5D87">
          <enum>(5)</enum>
          <header>Consolidated administrative record</header>
          <text>Maintain a consolidated administrative record of the information assembled and used by the cooperating agencies as the basis for agency decisions.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H1E7EED726BB740AA83EB066B7A211859">
          <enum>(6)</enum>
          <header>Project data records</header>
          <text>To the extent practicable and consistent with Federal law, ensure that all project data is submitted and maintained in generally accessible electronic format, compile, and where authorized under existing law, make available such project data to cooperating agencies, the qualifying project applicant, and to the public.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HF1CC87BCC2EF4CC0B9C658D9680485E2">
          <enum>(7)</enum>
          <header>Project manager</header>
          <text>Appoint a project manager for each qualifying project. The project manager shall have authority to oversee the project and to facilitate the issuance of the relevant final authorizing documents, and shall be responsible for ensuring fulfillment of all Bureau responsibilities set forth in this section and all cooperating agency responsibilities under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Water Supply Permitting Coordination Act/s:5" proposed="true">section 5</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
    </section>
    <section id="HF511DCA90E01442BB2367A9EF4335F4D">
      <enum>5.</enum>
      <header>Cooperating agency responsibilities</header>
      <subsection id="H1F4B8A5BDD3D4239B705B9481FA0251C">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Adherence to Bureau Schedule</header>
        <text>Upon notification of an application for a qualifying project, all cooperating agencies shall submit to the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1425" entity-type="federal-body">Bureau</cato:entity-ref> a timeframe under which the cooperating agency reasonably considers it will be able to complete its authorizing responsibilities. The Bureau shall use the timeframe submitted under this subsection to establish the project schedule under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Water Supply Permitting Coordination Act/s:4" proposed="true">section 4</cato:entity-ref>, and the cooperating agencies shall adhere to the project schedule established by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1425" entity-type="federal-body">Bureau</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="H9DAB5C86C9A54B6CA414BE324F55B92C">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Environmental Record</header>
        <text>Cooperating agencies shall submit to the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1425" entity-type="federal-body">Bureau</cato:entity-ref> all environmental review material produced or compiled in the course of carrying out activities required under Federal law consistent with the project schedule established by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1425" entity-type="federal-body">Bureau</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="H512CABC8F7014E7CA1D49A408E5ECAA8">
        <enum>(c)</enum>
        <header>Data Submission</header>
        <text>To the extent practicable and consistent with Federal law, the cooperating agencies shall submit all relevant project data to the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1425" entity-type="federal-body">Bureau</cato:entity-ref> in a generally accessible electronic format subject to the project schedule set forth by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1425" entity-type="federal-body">Bureau</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
      </subsection>
    </section>
    <section id="HA90E7E2F0F904141B6944223F24F2C03">
      <enum>6.</enum>
      <header>Funding to process permits</header>
      <subsection id="HAF018034AE3C444199C1686C7FF644D4">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>In general</header>
        <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1400" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary</cato:entity-ref>, after public notice in accordance with the <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
            <cato:entity-ref value="Administrative Procedures Act" entity-type="act">Administrative Procedures Act</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/5/553">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/5/553">5 U.S.C. 553</cato:entity-ref>
          </external-xref>)</cato:entity>, may accept and expend funds contributed by a non-Federal public entity to expedite the evaluation of a permit of that entity related to a qualifying project or activity for a public purpose under the jurisdiction of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1400" entity-type="federal-body">Department of the Interior</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="H694AA1C8397E49C0967B56BA9B996EE6">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Effect on permitting</header>
        <paragraph id="H9E8F0101A6F84410A6FD117B87DA5E0B">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>In general</header>
          <text>In carrying out this section, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1400" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall ensure that the use of funds accepted under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" proposed="true" value="Water Supply Permitting Coordination Act/s:6/ss:a" entity-type="act">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref> will not impact impartial decisionmaking with respect to permits, either substantively or procedurally.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H1B167CC84B124CAE96A61F756CEA481B">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Evaluation of permits</header>
          <text>In carrying out this section, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1400" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall ensure that the evaluation of permits carried out using funds accepted under this section shall—</text>
          <subparagraph id="H936A511446AB48C0B3E58BB8925D9A16">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>be reviewed by the Regional Director of the Bureau of Reclamation, or the Regional Director’s designee, of the region in which the qualifying project or activity is located; and</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H8D16656063244A9C9E986C87A4F45E6F">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>use the same procedures for decisions that would otherwise be required for the evaluation of permits for similar projects or activities not carried out using funds authorized under this section.</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph commented="no" id="H67C55DC94A9C4DDB9706CEE25FC280F9">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <header>Impartial decisionmaking</header>
          <text>In carrying out this section, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1400" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> and the cooperating agencies receiving funds under this section for qualifying projects shall ensure that the use of the funds accepted under this section for such projects shall not—</text>
          <subparagraph commented="no" id="H5D8FBCF668074F24AB9BE8D03AFB4795">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>impact impartial decisionmaking with respect to the issuance of permits, either substantively or procedurally; or</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph commented="no" id="HF916F180CDEB4670B0B6BDB3CA554A09">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>diminish, modify, or otherwise affect the statutory or regulatory authorities of such agencies.</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="H09C24BDC3031485CAA12C264F6806EA6">
        <enum>(c)</enum>
        <header>Limitation on use of funds</header>
        <text>None of the funds accepted under this section shall be used to carry out a review of the evaluation of permits required under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" proposed="true" value="Water Supply Permitting Coordination Act/s:6/ss:b/p:2/sp:A" entity-type="act">subsection (b)(2)(A)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="HB0197DA656CE4863AA5FD64FC39D1C30">
        <enum>(d)</enum>
        <header>Public availability</header>
        <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1400" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall ensure that all final permit decisions carried out using funds authorized under this section are made available to the public, including on the Internet.</text>
      </subsection>
    </section>
  </legis-body>
</bill>
</doc>