<doc>
  <docmeta id="113hr5259ih">
    <bill congress="113" type="hr" number="5259" version="ih"/>
    <revision size="19674" annotations="0" status="complete" id="4" commit-time="2014-08-13T22:17:29Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113hr5259ih/4.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H929F87A06D2648EAA10EA75399C5B7A5" public-private="public">
	<metadata>
<dublinCore>
<dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">113 HR 5259 IH: Investing for Tomorrow’s Schools Act of 2014</dc:title>
<dc:publisher xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">2014-07-30</dc:date>
<dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>113th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>2d Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 5259</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20140730">July 30, 2014</action-date>
			<action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="H001068">Mr. Huffman</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and the Workforce</committee-name>
      </action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To establish State infrastructure banks for education.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="HFC7E0DFEDC2C4C43AD86AFD97793318E" style="OLC">
		<section id="H75C4FBFF97184B75B2CED23224C20F2D" section-type="section-one">
      <enum>1.</enum>
      <header>Short title</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote>
          <short-title>
            <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Investing for Tomorrow’s Schools Act of 2014" proposed="true">Investing for Tomorrow’s Schools Act of 2014</cato:entity-ref>
          </short-title>
        </quote>.</text>
		</section>
    <section id="HB92B835106354D1998F1090524D3BA0D">
      <enum>2.</enum>
      <header>State infrastructure bank pilot program</header>
			<subsection id="H298AE50FCFDA42498D88756C404117EF">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Establishment</header>
				<paragraph id="HE55D4E4558964B11B0BE2F5B9C1658F0">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>Cooperative agreements</header>
          <text>Subject to the provisions of this section, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="2000" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of the Treasury</cato:entity-ref>, in consultation with the
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="9100" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of Education</cato:entity-ref>, may enter into cooperative agreements with States
			 for the establishment of State infrastructure banks and multistate
			 infrastructure banks for making loans—</text>
					<subparagraph id="HEB91E0D2995F42BC8AFA1FB08AD10320">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>to local educational agencies for building or repairing elementary or secondary schools which
			 provide free public education (as such terms are defined in <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965/s:14101">section 14101
			 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/8801">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/20/8801">20 U.S.C. 8801</cato:entity-ref>
              </external-xref>)</cato:entity>);</text>
					</subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H7E538CB5BB514119A62E0AF7CF7399D8">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>to public libraries for building or repairing library facilities;</text>
					</subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H03A1D6541FF1420FABCBB2F3274B93CC">
            <enum>(C)</enum>
            <text>to eligible charter school entities for use for the objective described in <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965/s:5224/p:2">section 5224(2) of such
			 Act</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7223c">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/20/7223c//2">20 U.S.C. 7223c(2)</cato:entity-ref>
              </external-xref>)</cato:entity> consistent with <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965/t:V/pt:B/spt:2">subpart 2 of part B of title V</cato:entity-ref> of
			 such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7223">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/20/7223/etseq">20 U.S.C. 7223 et seq.</cato:entity-ref>
              </external-xref>)</cato:entity>; and</text>
					</subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="HE78E9BC03A1D49C99953176BD2B3E442">
            <enum>(D)</enum>
            <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to community learning centers to connect and improve broadband services.</text>
					</subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H9707380D3B4A449CADFD26B6DF5C359C">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Interstate compacts</header>
          <text>Congress grants consent to two or more of the States, entering into a cooperative agreement under
			 paragraph (1) with the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="2000" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of the Treasury</cato:entity-ref> for the establishment of
			 a multistate infrastructure bank, to enter into an interstate compact
			 establishing such bank in accordance with this section.</text>
				</paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="HBB879E2D51ED40B09B962D28323218B1">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Funding</header>
        <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="2000" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of the Treasury</cato:entity-ref>, in consultation with the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="9100" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of Education</cato:entity-ref>, shall make grants
			 to State infrastructure banks and multistate infrastructure banks in a
			 State in a cooperative agreement under subsection (a)(1) to provide
			 initial capital for loans provided under this section. Each bank shall
			 apply repayments of principal and interest on loans to the making of
			 additional loans. The Secretary shall take final action on an application
			 for a grant under this subsection within 90 days of the date of the
			 submission of such application.</text>
			</subsection>
      <subsection id="H4962E62C76D34AD388B533A1E70E63F2">
        <enum>(c)</enum>
        <header>Infrastructure bank requirements</header>
        <text>In order to establish an infrastructure bank under this section, each State establishing the bank
			 shall—</text>
				<paragraph id="H8D0B5EF6D95A4B58A1AE7036E53BD40B">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>contribute, at a minimum, in each account of the bank from non-Federal sources an amount equal to
			 25 percent of the amount of each capitalization grant made to the State
			 and contributed to the bank under subsection (b);</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HA25C78B0242141FAB6D87FB746C85A25">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>identify an operating entity of the State as recipient of the grant if the entity has the capacity
			 to manage loan funds and issue debt instruments of the State for purposes
			 of leveraging the funds;</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HB3DDB9440BE04F18BB9712C4E38A5025">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <text>allow such funds to be used as reserve for debt issued by the State so long as proceeds are
			 deposited in the fund for loan purposes;</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H75553EED43F0429CB5B7F3F6A4EC7659">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
          <text>ensure that investment income generated by funds contributed to an account of the bank will be—</text>
					<subparagraph id="H86B76F37F1F04CF995FB8169224C080C">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>credited to the account;</text>
					</subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="HB951E9EFD0E34EE19E78F9C8BD69AFC5">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>available for use in providing loans to projects eligible for assistance from the account; and</text>
					</subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="HC7D9F88FC8104A3E91FB0539F137CC9A">
            <enum>(C)</enum>
            <text>invested in United States Treasury securities, bank deposits, or such other financing instruments
			 as the Secretary may approve to earn interest to enhance the leveraging of
			 projects assisted by the bank;</text>
					</subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H019AC8924EE847C4901EB456C58E1F48">
          <enum>(5)</enum>
          <text>ensure that any loan from the bank to an eligible charter school entity, local educational agency,
			 public library, or community learning center will bear interest at or
			 below the lowest interest rates being offered for bonds the income from
			 which is exempt from Federal taxation, as determined by the State, to make
			 the project that is the subject of the loan feasible;</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HD82F26D336DD4854805EB6971AEDD747">
          <enum>(6)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">ensure that repayment of any loan from the bank to an eligible charter school entity, local
			 educational agency, public library, or community learning center will
			 commence not later than 1 year after the project has been completed;</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H40D34D67A7BA4579A5CAB12712A723DB">
          <enum>(7)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">ensure that the term for repaying any loan to an eligible charter school entity, local educational
			 agency, public library, or community learning center will not exceed 30
			 years after the date of the first payment on the loan under paragraph (5);</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph commented="no" id="H51FDA4D727F143558C47BD57ED3D43CD">
          <enum>(8)</enum>
          <text>ensure that the funds loaned annually that are used under subsection (a)(1)(C) are limited to a
			 percentage of the total funds loaned that does not exceed the percentage
			 of elementary and secondary school students in the State enrolled in
			 charter schools during the most recent school year for which enrollment
			 data are available;</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H40D14CEFBD404A8D8D34FA25F964455D">
          <enum>(9)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">ensure that the funds loaned annually under subsection (a)(1)(D) are used exclusively to connect
			 and improve broadband services; and</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HD57B49E212E749BB88B0F535DBCCAB2B">
          <enum>(10)</enum>
          <text>require the bank to make an annual report to the Secretary on its status and make such other
			 reports as the Secretary may require by guidelines.</text>
				</paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="HD1E3C46368234ED29D9282E9F271074A">
        <enum>(d)</enum>
        <header>Forms of assistance from infrastructure banks</header>
				<paragraph id="HCF161722F7904FE88DE64619D461BC8C">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>In general</header>
          <text>An infrastructure bank established under this section may make loans in an amount equal to all or
			 part of the cost of carrying out a project eligible for assistance under
			 this section.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H662738957728449A9BED681D97CEB457">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Applications for loans</header>
          <text>An application to an infrastructure bank for a loan shall include—</text>
					<subparagraph id="H129DB79517CA4C93A6C246E85CD30139">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>in the case of a renovation project, a description of each architectural, civil, structural,
			 mechanical, or electrical deficiency to be corrected with funds under a
			 loan and the priorities to be applied;</text>
					</subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="HD4F79129AD034070A7AD5418F49BE12F">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>a description of the criteria used by the applicant to determine the type of corrective action
			 necessary for the renovation of a facility;</text>
					</subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="HA58E7C54265D414490B4C4C446CE8A17">
            <enum>(C)</enum>
            <text>a description of improvements to be made and a cost estimate for the improvements;</text>
					</subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H72962F96D48741D9B12AF222C92E3841">
            <enum>(D)</enum>
            <text>a description of how work undertaken with the loan will promote the conservation of energy, water,
			 or waste; and</text>
					</subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H5E5CCC4A2DC846F3ACED59C8795F5C3E">
            <enum>(E)</enum>
            <text>such other information as the infrastructure bank may require.</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph">An infrastructure bank shall take final action on a completed application submitted to it within 90
			 days after the date of its submission.</continuation-text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H4DFD5F86CFAE4DC38CFBADB9DDBAF616">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <header>Criteria for loans</header>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In considering applications for a loan to an eligible charter school entity, local educational
			 agency, public library, or community learning center, an infrastructure
			 bank shall consider—</text>
					<subparagraph id="H26E4FD955B1644A6BB8F316E61881ED2">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the extent to which the eligible charter school entity, local educational agency, public library,
			 or community learning center involved lacks the fiscal capacity, including
			 the ability to raise funds through the full use of such agency’s bonding
			 capacity and otherwise, to undertake the project for which the loan would
			 be used without the loan;</text>
					</subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H820E9978219244E18FF1DEC5E59226F7">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>in the case of a local educational agency, the threat that the condition of the physical plant in
			 the project poses to the safety and well-being of students;</text>
					</subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="HF97F97258BE94BC280A3EAEE406C118E">
            <enum>(C)</enum>
            <text>the demonstrated need for the construction, reconstruction, or renovation based on the condition of
			 the facility in the project;</text>
					</subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H5A1AB9F40BCD4614B85FFC76E5480403">
            <enum>(D)</enum>
            <text>the age of such facility; and</text>
					</subparagraph>
          <subparagraph commented="no" id="H72494717AA6446FA9D222486BA09233B">
            <enum>(E)</enum>
            <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">demonstrated need to connect and improve broadband services in the local community.</text>
					</subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="H99BD8E6D88564653BF54496516DF6A1F">
        <enum>(e)</enum>
        <header>Qualifying projects</header>
				<paragraph id="H3D06C38DC7604C8BB0B8FB7CF92361D9">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>In general</header>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to subsection (a)(1), a project is eligible for a loan from an infrastructure bank if it is
			 a project that consists of—</text>
					<subparagraph id="H2EBC0F84FC4C4341860DC686995338CA">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>the construction of new elementary or secondary schools to meet the needs imposed by enrollment
			 growth;</text>
					</subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="HC54961ACDB89411486CE69D0FBD988D7">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>the repair, rebuilding, or upgrading of classrooms or structures related to academic learning,
			 including the repair of leaking roofs, crumbling walls, inadequate
			 plumbing, poor ventilation equipment, and inadequate heating or light
			 equipment;</text>
					</subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="HD212F510F6494360965EC2A1084FEAC5">
            <enum>(C)</enum>
            <text>an activity to increase physical safety at the educational facility involved;</text>
					</subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H0A11562267464CA2B238A866E72B0538">
            <enum>(D)</enum>
            <text>an activity to enhance the educational facility involved to provide access for students, teachers,
			 and other individuals with disabilities;</text>
					</subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H7187805D1E3145E895E2B93C537DF447">
            <enum>(E)</enum>
            <text>an activity to address environmental or health hazards at the educational facility involved, such
			 as poor ventilation, indoor air quality, or lighting;</text>
					</subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="HC67613ADC9F04D94B78F431736735504">
            <enum>(F)</enum>
            <text>the provision of basic infrastructure that facilitates educational technology, such as
			 communications outlets, electrical systems, power outlets, or a
			 communication closet;</text>
					</subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H6CA86846E2BC4138ABE49273D79B1587">
            <enum>(G)</enum>
            <text>work that will bring an educational facility into conformity with the requirements of—</text>
						<clause id="H58EA211B94D8424F8621E5C836883950">
              <enum>(i)</enum>
              <text>environmental protection or health and safety programs mandated by Federal, State, or local law if
			 such requirements were not in effect when the facility was initially
			 constructed; and</text>
						</clause>
            <clause id="H2FC164FD6B0B4CB6BBD05FDDAFC1734A">
              <enum>(ii)</enum>
              <text>hazardous waste disposal, treatment, and storage requirements mandated by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Resource Conservation and Recovery Act of 1976">Resource Conservation
			 and Recovery Act of 1976</cato:entity-ref> or similar State laws;</text>
						</clause>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H74E46188625B475B988CA97982EA90A0">
            <enum>(H)</enum>
            <text>work that will enable efficient use of available energy resources;</text>
					</subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="HBB2D08CD07424F069F336F06A4C5C988">
            <enum>(I)</enum>
            <text>work that will reduce reliance on fossil fuels and expand use of solar power, wind power, and other
			 renewable energy resources;</text>
					</subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="HC0E324F6C8C44C53807D93A7203EE19E">
            <enum>(J)</enum>
            <text>work to detect, remove, or otherwise contain asbestos hazards in educational facilities;</text>
					</subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H14E0F3CC1D0E4DBBB333470E6D47A448">
            <enum>(K)</enum>
            <text>work to construct new public library facilities or repair or upgrade existing public library
			 facilities;</text>
					</subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H6B5EF066D8324553A4CF810916EB7612">
            <enum>(L)</enum>
            <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">work to connect entities described in subsection (a)(1) to broadband services, and to improve such
			 connections for such entities; or</text>
					</subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="HE6F87FF0667D472CA3F675FF91DC994B">
            <enum>(M)</enum>
            <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">measures designed to reduce or eliminate human exposure to classroom noise and environmental noise
			 pollution.</text>
					</subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HB5C0F5F1BCFE42B8AAD66FB5E15168ED">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Davis-bacon</header>
          <text>The wage requirements of the <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">Act of March 3, 1931 (referred to as the <quote>
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Davis-Bacon Act">Davis-Bacon Act</cato:entity-ref>
            </quote>, <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/40/276a">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/40/276a/etseq">40 U.S.C. 276a et seq.</cato:entity-ref>
            </external-xref>)</cato:entity> shall apply with respect to individuals employed on the projects
			 described in paragraph (1).</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H0EF7C6B24D69406E9D2EA3B4BF828521">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <header>Green practices</header>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An entity using a loan under this section to fund a new construction or renovation project
			 described in paragraph (1) shall ensure that the project is certified,
			 verified, or consistent with State laws, regulations, and any applicable
			 provisions of—</text>
					<subparagraph id="H9203727FEE5542BEB4DAC6F7F27DFE2F">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>the LEED Green Building Rating System;</text>
					</subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="HF195A3F3945642DB862A01B24C88BEF3">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>Living Building Challenge;</text>
					</subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H9F829BD83E444596AE3B5319A708F563">
            <enum>(C)</enum>
            <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the CHPS green building rating program developed by the Collaborative for High Performance Schools;
			 or</text>
					</subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H67EE8B2A2F984FB2A263D6E8263A3775">
            <enum>(D)</enum>
            <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a program that—</text>
						<clause id="HEAABE7CB979945D4AEDF2C0370771572">
              <enum>(i)</enum>
              <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has equivalent or more stringent standards;</text>
						</clause>
            <clause id="HBF5F89FEA79A46379E2716B90D4979A6">
              <enum>(ii)</enum>
              <text>is adopted by the State or another jurisdiction with authority over the entity; and</text>
						</clause>
            <clause id="H4D1744D722994C83B49AC3AD69C3D823">
              <enum>(iii)</enum>
              <text>includes a verifiable method to demonstrate compliance with such program.</text>
						</clause>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="H9B563CFD7F694C208DDCCD28465C343A">
        <enum>(f)</enum>
        <header>Supplementation</header>
        <text>Any loan made by an infrastructure bank shall be used to supplement and not supplant other Federal,
			 State, and local funds available.</text>
			</subsection>
      <subsection id="H5BE15E36E45541B3BF7B87029BE567D6">
        <enum>(g)</enum>
        <header>Limitation on repayments</header>
        <text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the repayment of a loan from an infrastructure bank
			 under this section may not be credited towards the non-Federal share of
			 the cost of any project.</text>
			</subsection>
      <subsection id="H3217D873EB984D9EA85A345CDCB24A21">
        <enum>(h)</enum>
        <header>Secretarial requirements</header>
        <text>In administering this section, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="2000" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of the Treasury</cato:entity-ref> shall specify procedures and
			 guidelines for establishing, operating, and providing assistance from an
			 infrastructure bank.</text>
			</subsection>
      <subsection id="H13B9B203C97248EAAE65D6140DC8ECA1">
        <enum>(i)</enum>
        <header>United States not obligated</header>
        <text>The contribution of Federal funds into an infrastructure bank established under this section shall
			 not be construed as a commitment, guarantee, or obligation on the part of
			 the United States to any third party, nor shall any third party have any
			 right against the United States for payment solely by virtue of the
			 contribution. Any security or debt financing instrument issued by the
			 infrastructure bank shall expressly state that the security or instrument
			 does not constitute a commitment, guarantee, or obligation of the United
			 States.</text>
			</subsection>
      <subsection id="H891C9300A6CA48E095C5A47750A9BE59">
        <enum>(j)</enum>
        <header>Management of Federal funds</header>
        <text>
          <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc/31/3335">Sections <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/31/3335">3335</external-xref>
          </cato:entity-ref> and <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc/31/6503">
            <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/31/6503">6503</external-xref> of title 31, United States Code</cato:entity-ref>, shall not apply to funds contributed under
			 this section.</text>
			</subsection>
      <subsection id="H6D01188C6607437383D5AF0759A38BA1">
        <enum>(k)</enum>
        <header>Program administration</header>
        <text>For each of fiscal years 2015 through 2019, a State may expend not to exceed 2 percent of the
			 Federal funds contributed to an infrastructure bank established by the
			 State under this section to pay the reasonable costs of administering the
			 bank.</text>
			</subsection>
      <subsection id="H8F0E71A08CBE4E04BBA2E0C24BFA1A23">
        <enum>(l)</enum>
        <header>Secretarial review</header>
        <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="2000" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of the Treasury</cato:entity-ref> shall review the financial condition of each infrastructure bank
			 established under this section and transmit to Congress a report on the
			 results of such review not later than 90 days after the completion of the
			 review.</text>
			</subsection>
      <subsection id="H0DA2ADC85BA144FABB10B2DBFAAA6B29">
        <enum>(m)</enum>
        <header>Authorization of appropriations</header>
        <text>
          <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="auth-auth-approp">
            <cato:property name="purpose">For grants to States for the initial capitalization of infrastructure banks</cato:property> there are authorized to
			 be appropriated <cato:funds-and-year amount="500000000" year="2015, 2016, 2017, 2018, 2019">$500,000,000 for fiscal year 2015 and for each of the 4
			 succeeding fiscal years</cato:funds-and-year>.</cato:entity>
        </text>
			</subsection>
    </section>
    <section id="H96B9879475A0469D8343F5EBAF44B821">
      <enum>3.</enum>
      <header>Definitions</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">For purposes of this Act:</text>
			<paragraph id="H7B42B34F54754DA68D8149D5681BFA20">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <header>Community learning center</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>community learning center</term> has the meaning given such term in <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965/s:4201/ss:b/p:1">section 4201(b)(1) of the Elementary and Secondary Education
			 Act of 1965</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7171">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/20/7171/b/1">20 U.S.C. 7171(b)(1)</cato:entity-ref>
          </external-xref>)</cato:entity>.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H453E08E71501427E846F2E1DEEAD94A5">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <header>Eligible charter school entity</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>eligible charter school entity</term> means—</text>
				<subparagraph id="HCCA5855DB24943998DE4B7EDB3E1F31A">
          <enum>(A)</enum>
          <text>a charter school (as defined in <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965/s:5210">section 5210 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965</cato:entity-ref>
			 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7221i">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/20/7221i">20 U.S.C. 7221i</cato:entity-ref>
            </external-xref>)</cato:entity>); or</text>
				</subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="HB239054340A741239F50BF99CFB3E708">
          <enum>(B)</enum>
          <text>a developer (as so defined) that has applied to an authorized public chartering agency (as so
			 defined) to operate a charter school.</text>
				</subparagraph>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H976CC41B434349BC84787CF9654DB757">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <header>Local educational agency</header>
				<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H7D57A0103EDB49E4A6E899A205EE8CEA">
          <enum>(A)</enum>
          <text>The term <term>local educational agency</term> means a public board of education or other public authority legally constituted within a State for
			 either administrative control or direction of, or to perform a service
			 function for, public elementary or secondary schools in a city, county,
			 township, school district, or other political subdivision of a State, or
			 for such combination of school districts or counties as are recognized in
			 a State as an administrative agency for its public elementary or secondary
			 schools.</text>
				</subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="H57285DF91DC84A34B22264A3F0ED587B" indent="up1">
          <enum>(B)</enum>
          <text>The term includes any other public institution or agency having administrative control and
			 direction of a public elementary or secondary school.</text>
				</subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="HF27557A1D0FA4ABE8CB171C244801D8F" indent="up1">
          <enum>(C)</enum>
          <text>The term includes an elementary or secondary school funded by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1450" entity-type="federal-body">Bureau of Indian Affairs</cato:entity-ref> but only
			 to the extent that such inclusion makes such school eligible for programs
			 for which specific eligibility is not provided to such school in another
			 provision of law and such school does not have a student population that
			 is smaller than the student population of the local educational agency
			 receiving assistance under this Act with the smallest student population,
			 except that such school shall not be subject to the jurisdiction of any
			 State educational agency other than the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1450" entity-type="federal-body">Bureau of Indian Affairs</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
				</subparagraph>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H516D5C3038264129B75E38AF6A7D1E8B">
        <enum>(4)</enum>
        <header>Outlying area</header>
        <text>The term <term>outlying area</term> means the Virgin Islands, Guam, American Samoa, the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands,
			 the Republic of the Marshall Islands, the Federated States of Micronesia,
			 and the Republic of Palau.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HB1F7D4E1EC354C46A8EC1A456F206356">
        <enum>(5)</enum>
        <header>Public library</header>
        <text>The term <term>public library</term> means a library that serves free of charge all residents of a community, district, or region, and
			 receives its financial support in whole or in part from public funds. Such
			 term also includes a research library, which, for the purposes of this
			 sentence, means a library that—</text>
				<subparagraph id="H46456A7434A5422D9B386EB61FD23CC6">
          <enum>(A)</enum>
          <text>makes its services available to the public free of charge;</text>
				</subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="H12DD014470044F429B68B0C628ECC8FE">
          <enum>(B)</enum>
          <text>has extensive collections of books, manuscripts, and other materials suitable for scholarly
			 research which are not available to the public through public libraries;</text>
				</subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="HA1BF9319643342AABE9A2BB421C2E8AC">
          <enum>(C)</enum>
          <text>engages in the dissemination of humanistic knowledge through services to readers, fellowships,
			 educational and cultural programs, publication of significant research,
			 and other activities; and</text>
				</subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="HDE5669AA61D3424581CC87F9755F17E9">
          <enum>(D)</enum>
          <text>is not an integral part of an institution of higher education.</text>
				</subparagraph>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HA8E15255976240BCB23C0F16C54AE599">
        <enum>(6)</enum>
        <header>State</header>
        <text>The term <term>State</term> means each of the 50 States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, and each
			 of the outlying areas.</text>
			</paragraph>
    </section>
  </legis-body>
</bill>
</doc>