<doc>
  <docmeta id="113hr4010ih">
    <bill congress="113" type="hr" number="4010" version="ih"/>
    <revision size="44983" annotations="0" status="complete" id="4" commit-time="2014-02-14T18:08:03Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113hr4010ih/4.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H6C0B683E1D0F412583605E6B2D9A0F55" public-private="public">
  <metadata>
<dublinCore>
<dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">113 HR 4010 IH: Autism Services and Workforce Acceleration Act of 2014</dc:title>
<dc:publisher xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">2014-02-06</dc:date>
<dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
    <congress>113th CONGRESS</congress>
    <session>2d Session</session>
    <legis-num>H. R. 4010</legis-num>
    <current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
    <action>
      <action-date date="20140206">February 6, 2014</action-date>
      <action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="C001090">Mr. Cartwright</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>
      </action-desc>
    </action>
    <legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
    <official-title>To provide for enhanced treatment, support, services, and research for individuals with autism spectrum disorders and their families.</official-title>
  </form>
  <legis-body id="HE4C24A32DBB54AC790BAFA53D7EACEC0" style="OLC">
    <section id="H439491A93DB446EAADA5FDD02B2B6699" section-type="section-one">
      <enum>1.</enum>
      <header>Short title; table of contents</header>
      <subsection id="HAB84BF57934247169E3E7182242E2605">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Short title</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote>
            <short-title>
              <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Autism Services and Workforce Acceleration Act of 2014" proposed="true">Autism Services and Workforce Acceleration Act of 2014</cato:entity-ref>
            </short-title>
          </quote>.</text>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="H4B9B43B2D4A04A05BCBCEB3B222C7126">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Table of contents</header>
        <text>The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text>
        <toc>
          <toc-entry idref="H439491A93DB446EAADA5FDD02B2B6699" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title; table of contents.</toc-entry>
          <toc-entry idref="HCF17E8484C1D49558978FA987FB2C404" level="section">Sec. 2. Findings.</toc-entry>
          <toc-entry idref="H1CFFFA6C5A9F4F52A1BD6955C6AE009B" level="section">Sec. 3. Parental rights rule of construction.</toc-entry>
          <toc-entry idref="H2EFAD9C6889C45C4BEBA077C8E89F290" level="section">Sec. 4. Definitions; technical amendment to the Public Health Service Act.</toc-entry>
          <toc-entry idref="HA29D4885B0AB48C69275F536D50A3832" level="section">Sec. 5. Autism Care Programs Demonstration Project.</toc-entry>
          <toc-entry idref="H8CA8D452E6EA4C7DBEA5B8261B4F880C" level="section">Sec. 6. Planning and demonstration grants for services for transitioning youth and adults.</toc-entry>
          <toc-entry idref="H777574B5F0EE46BF88903ED0E3C9E466" level="section">Sec. 7. Multimedia campaign.</toc-entry>
          <toc-entry idref="H37CCAB7E70274B46821B453EC99F9C5D" level="section">Sec. 8. National training initiatives on autism spectrum disorders.</toc-entry>
          <toc-entry idref="H07982AFFF8CB4760802269B52F22AEC7" level="section">Sec. 9. Authorization of appropriations.</toc-entry>
        </toc>
      </subsection>
    </section>
    <section id="HCF17E8484C1D49558978FA987FB2C404">
      <enum>2.</enum>
      <header>Findings</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">
        <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> makes the following findings:</text>
      <paragraph id="H6CA93DEB39324B20A9A05F7AC44DC1E2">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text>Autism (sometimes called <term>classical autism</term>) is the most common condition in a group of developmental disorders known as autism spectrum disorders.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H4C469BAD84E341929D3423A7E4AEE78E">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text>Autism spectrum disorders include autism as well as Asperger syndrome, Retts syndrome, childhood disintegrative disorder, and pervasive developmental disorder not otherwise specified (usually referred to as PDD–NOS), as well as other related developmental disorders.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HCDA704ABDA104216A90BD858F5673677">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <text>Individuals with autism spectrum disorders have the same rights as other individuals to exert control and choice over their own lives, to live independently, and to participate fully in, and contribute to, their communities and society through full integration and inclusion in the economic, political, social, cultural, and educational mainstream of society. Individuals with autism spectrum disorders have the right to a life with dignity and purpose.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H1F5A3F7A169246CBA2CAF6A7FBEAD687">
        <enum>(4)</enum>
        <text>While there is no uniform prevalence or severity of symptoms associated with autism spectrum disorders, the National Institutes of Health has determined that autism spectrum disorders are characterized by 3 distinctive behaviors: impaired social interaction, problems with verbal and nonverbal communication, and unusual, repetitive, or severely limited activities and interests.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HA8FE31E294064DDCA8253F089ED7F75E">
        <enum>(5)</enum>
        <text>Both children and adults with autism spectrum disorders can show difficulties in verbal and nonverbal communication, social interactions, and sensory processing. Individuals with autism spectrum disorders exhibit different symptoms or behaviors, which may range from mild to significant, and require varying degrees of support from friends, families, service providers, and communities.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H7DBC73297DB54F7D9DA19C124E905F0C">
        <enum>(6)</enum>
        <text>Individuals with autism spectrum disorders often need assistance in the areas of comprehensive early intervention, health, recreation, job training, employment, housing, transportation, and early, primary, and secondary education. Greater coordination and streamlining within the service delivery system will enable individuals with autism spectrum disorders and their families to access assistance from all sectors throughout an individual’s lifespan.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HC3C30C5AF1FB4F9986B5D5E287FB85B6">
        <enum>(7)</enum>
        <text>A 2009 report from the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7523">Centers for Disease Control and Prevention</cato:entity-ref> found that the prevalence of autism spectrum disorders is estimated to be 1 in 110 people in the United States.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HFDCA84CE0B944FA891041B688387506B">
        <enum>(8)</enum>
        <text>The Harvard School of Public Health reported that the cost of caring for and treating individuals with autism spectrum disorders in the United States is more than $35,000,000,000 annually (an estimated $3,200,000 over an individual’s lifetime).</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph commented="no" id="HC332FC03A9B6486DA9178E8CBDD3E50F">
        <enum>(9)</enum>
        <text>Although the overall incidence of autism is consistent around the globe, researchers with the Journal of Paediatrics and Child Health have found that males are 4 times more likely to develop an autism spectrum disorder than females. Autism spectrum disorders know no racial, ethnic, or social boundaries, nor differences in family income, lifestyle, or educational levels, and can affect any child.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H2CC373F51C6C490F8103523FDE051846">
        <enum>(10)</enum>
        <text>Individuals with autism spectrum disorders from low-income, rural, and minority communities often face significant obstacles to accurate diagnosis and necessary specialized services, supports, and education.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HCB71F0F4511E405D8A461FD2943CC739">
        <enum>(11)</enum>
        <text>There is strong consensus within the research community that intensive treatment as soon as possible following diagnosis not only can reduce the cost of lifelong care by two-thirds, but also yields the most positive life outcomes for children with autism spectrum disorders.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HBC6BB2133BF042C8A41F33E90745333C">
        <enum>(12)</enum>
        <text>Individuals with autism spectrum disorders and their families experience a wide range of medical issues. Few common standards exist for the diagnosis and management of many aspects of clinical care. Behavioral difficulties may be attributed to the overarching disorder rather than to the pain and discomfort of a medical condition, which may go undetected and untreated. The health care and other treatments available in different communities can vary widely. Many families, lacking access to comprehensive and coordinated health care, must fend for themselves to find the best health care, treatments, and services in a complex clinical world.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HECE889BA44B44569A7CDE16BEC2D0158">
        <enum>(13)</enum>
        <text>Effective health care, treatment, and services for individuals with autism spectrum disorders depends upon a continuous exchange among researchers and caregivers. Evidence-based and promising autism practices should move quickly into communities, allowing individuals with autism spectrum disorders and their families to benefit from the newest research and enabling researchers to learn from the life experiences of the people whom their work most directly affects.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HC289B2E685E3460BB6C138F934903831">
        <enum>(14)</enum>
        <text>There is a critical shortage of appropriately trained personnel across numerous important disciplines who can assess, diagnose, treat, and support children and adults with autism spectrum disorders and their families. Practicing professionals, as well as those in training to become professionals, need the most up-to-date practices informed by the most current research findings.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HEA7B9E6A0658489B848BA612C68FE01F">
        <enum>(15)</enum>
        <text>The appropriate goals of the Nation regarding individuals with autism spectrum disorder are the same as the appropriate goals of the Nation regarding individuals with disabilities in general, as established in the <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990">Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12101">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/42/12101/etseq">42 U.S.C. 12101 et seq</cato:entity-ref>.</external-xref>)</cato:entity>: to assure equality of opportunity, full participation, independent living, and economic self-sufficiency for such individuals.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H134BBEDFCAA54AE0B05B91DB3AE3E51B">
        <enum>(16)</enum>
        <text>Finally, individuals with autism spectrum disorders are often denied health care benefits solely because of their diagnosis, even though proven, effective treatments for autism spectrum disorders do exist.</text>
      </paragraph>
    </section>
    <section commented="no" id="H1CFFFA6C5A9F4F52A1BD6955C6AE009B">
      <enum>3.</enum>
      <header>Parental rights rule of construction</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this Act shall be construed to modify the legal rights of parents or legal guardians under Federal, State, or local law regarding the care of their children.</text>
    </section>
    <section id="H2EFAD9C6889C45C4BEBA077C8E89F290">
      <enum>4.</enum>
      <header>Definitions; technical amendment to the Public Health Service Act</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">
        <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
          <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Public Health Service Act/t:III/pt:R">Part R of title III of the Public Health Service Act</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/280i">
          <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/42/280i/etseq">42 U.S.C. 280i et seq</cato:entity-ref>.</external-xref>)</cato:entity> is amended—</text>
      <paragraph id="H15029C455BE145E8A440A2797B71F157">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by inserting after the header for <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Public Health Service Act/t:III/pt:R">part R</cato:entity-ref> the following:</text>
        <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H39269A4BBE6D4167A3709EB4733DA046" style="tax">
          <subpart id="H32562315E2F74B69B540C33AF28A7A27">
            <enum>1</enum>
            <header>Surveillance and Research Program; Education, Early Detection, and Intervention; and Reporting</header>
          </subpart>
          <after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block>
        </quoted-block>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H763E5F75E39D4CDC9E41B8367D155378">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text>in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Public Health Service Act/s:399AA/ss:d">section 399AA(d)</cato:entity-ref>, by striking <quote>part</quote> and inserting <quote>subpart</quote>; and</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H1A83DAC23AB445B5A0FFAF666621BD8C">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <text>by adding at the end the following:</text>
        <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H15078B00F3234FA0A756437EF9D70DFF" style="tax">
          <subpart id="H63C34C5F7D7D48258D2488B3E86A09FE">
            <enum>2</enum>
            <header>Care for people with autism spectrum disorders; public education</header>
            <section id="H3AC093A0CDF342F591C74FEC73ED17AB">
              <enum>399GG.</enum>
              <header>Definitions</header>
              <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Except as otherwise provided, in this subpart:</text>
              <paragraph id="H6D12222C03CA4B1BB9E64D17E9CE1BAC">
                <enum>(1)</enum>
                <header>Adult with autism spectrum disorder</header>
                <text>The term <term>adult with autism spectrum disorder</term> means an individual with an autism spectrum disorder who has attained 22 years of age.</text>
              </paragraph>
              <paragraph id="HE0A0D707356D4D3D8DA01E9855E03891">
                <enum>(2)</enum>
                <header>Affected individual</header>
                <text>The term <term>affected individual</term> means an individual with an autism spectrum disorder.</text>
              </paragraph>
              <paragraph id="HA7140116F24A4079AAE6485B3ECFD38B">
                <enum>(3)</enum>
                <header>Autism</header>
                <text>The term <term>autism</term> means an autism spectrum disorder or a related developmental disability.</text>
              </paragraph>
              <paragraph id="HBE69539A6C354513802962E71AE958F2">
                <enum>(4)</enum>
                <header>Autism care program</header>
                <text>In this subpart, the term <term>autism care program</term> means a program that is directed by a care coordinator who is an expert in autism spectrum disorder treatment and practice and provides an array of medical, psychological, behavioral, educational, and family services to individuals with autism and their families. Such a program shall—</text>
                <subparagraph id="HF45AF9C57A464C1CBA66373411B77893">
                  <enum>(A)</enum>
                  <text>incorporate the attributes of the care management model;</text>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="H4CFC28ADE38A4E2592D7FB22A8B09167">
                  <enum>(B)</enum>
                  <text>offer, through an array of services or through detailed referral and coordinated care arrangements, an autism management team of appropriate providers, including behavioral specialists, physicians, psychologists, social workers, family therapists, nurse practitioners, nurses, educators, and other appropriate personnel; and</text>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="HD110A46434FA4CFC8AAEA8C7BC399721">
                  <enum>(C)</enum>
                  <text>have the capability to achieve improvements in the management and coordination of care for targeted beneficiaries.</text>
                </subparagraph>
              </paragraph>
              <paragraph id="H9F72DC2C098A486F834EC576D07C44C4">
                <enum>(5)</enum>
                <header>Autism management team</header>
                <text>The term <term>autism management team</term> means a group of autism care providers, including behavioral specialists, physicians, psychologists, social workers, family therapists, nurse practitioners, nurses, educators, other appropriate personnel, and family members who work in a coordinated manner to treat individuals with autism spectrum disorders and their families. Such team shall determine the specific structure and operational model of its specific autism care program, taking into consideration cultural, regional, and geographical factors.</text>
              </paragraph>
              <paragraph id="H4900751951DF4EABB91EA0C205847EEC">
                <enum>(6)</enum>
                <header>Autism spectrum disorder</header>
                <text>The term <term>autism spectrum disorder</term> means a developmental disability that causes substantial impairments in the areas of social interaction, emotional regulation, communication, and the integration of higher-order cognitive processes and which may be characterized by the presence of unusual behaviors and interests. Such term includes autistic disorder, pervasive developmental disorder (not otherwise specified), Asperger syndrome, Retts disorder, childhood disintegrative disorder, and other related developmental disorders.</text>
              </paragraph>
              <paragraph id="HE95C9D165A36475BB4F591F0B0036D61">
                <enum>(7)</enum>
                <header>Care management model</header>
                <text>The term <term>care management model</term> means a model of care that with respect to autism—</text>
                <subparagraph id="HF7807154B592427FA39A07602D5ABE9C">
                  <enum>(A)</enum>
                  <text>is centered on the relationship between an individual with an autism spectrum disorder and his or her family and their personal autism care coordinator;</text>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="H67523030EDBA4C0388D82CAE03556528">
                  <enum>(B)</enum>
                  <text>provides services to individuals with autism spectrum disorders to improve the management and coordination of care provided to individuals and their families; and</text>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0C7AE0CE83E0409CB65A7A578AE7A19E">
                  <enum>(C)</enum>
                  <text>has established, where practicable, effective referral relationships between the autism care coordinator and the major medical, educational, and behavioral specialties and ancillary services in the region.</text>
                </subparagraph>
              </paragraph>
              <paragraph id="H9648FA155FCC491B8541146CA1512ABA">
                <enum>(8)</enum>
                <header>Child with autism spectrum disorder</header>
                <text>The term <term>child with autism spectrum disorder</term> means an individual with an autism spectrum disorder who has not attained 22 years of age.</text>
              </paragraph>
              <paragraph id="H1E2B92E09C7C4024914DC8A4E91FDCD5">
                <enum>(9)</enum>
                <header>Interventions</header>
                <text>The term <term>interventions</term> means the educational methods and positive behavioral support strategies designed to improve or ameliorate symptoms associated with autism spectrum disorders.</text>
              </paragraph>
              <paragraph id="H2CA363C6FEAF4037837B99C1530B34F7">
                <enum>(10)</enum>
                <header>Personal care coordinator</header>
                <text>The term <term>personal care coordinator</term> means a physician, nurse, nurse practitioner, psychologist, social worker, family therapist, educator, or other appropriate personnel (as determined by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref>) who has extensive expertise in treatment and services for individuals with autism spectrum disorders, who—</text>
                <subparagraph id="H0C9E9772BEB4404E95E90262859693A2">
                  <enum>(A)</enum>
                  <text>practices in an autism care program; and</text>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="H51AEB39FFED14429A0A4EBCD6A3123CF">
                  <enum>(B)</enum>
                  <text>has been trained to coordinate and manage comprehensive autism care for the whole person.</text>
                </subparagraph>
              </paragraph>
              <paragraph id="HCCD608CEDCB04682B040C82CED80B112">
                <enum>(11)</enum>
                <header>Project</header>
                <text>The term <term>project</term> means the autism care program demonstration project established under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Public Health Service Act/s:399GG–1" proposed="true">section 399GG–1</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
              </paragraph>
              <paragraph id="H40722FB2F2C34B269D475574F5AA8221">
                <enum>(12)</enum>
                <header>Services</header>
                <text>The term <term>services</term> means services to assist individuals with autism spectrum disorders to live more independently in their communities and to improve their quality of life.</text>
              </paragraph>
              <paragraph id="HBBE5879056D04623967773D728D64BA8">
                <enum>(13)</enum>
                <header>Treatments</header>
                <text>The term <term>treatments</term> means the health services, including mental health and behavioral therapy services, designed to improve or ameliorate symptoms associated with autism spectrum disorders.</text>
              </paragraph>
            </section>
          </subpart>
          <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
        </quoted-block>
      </paragraph>
    </section>
    <section id="HA29D4885B0AB48C69275F536D50A3832">
      <enum>5.</enum>
      <header>Autism Care Programs Demonstration Project</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">
        <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
          <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Public Health Service Act/t:III/pt:R">Part R of title III of the Public Health Service Act</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/280i">
          <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/42/280i">42 U.S.C. 280i</cato:entity-ref>
        </external-xref>)</cato:entity>, as amended by <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Public Health Service Act/s:4">section 4</cato:entity-ref>, is further amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
      <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFABA9884E5CE493A8A7E5F41F5EC07E1" style="tax">
        <section id="H08F68031D3E14F89969CE0C27B6D8D02">
          <enum>399GG–1.</enum>
          <header>Autism Care Programs demonstration project</header>
          <subsection id="H926D3CD0479845C4BCAFB61EA80234C3">
            <enum>(a)</enum>
            <header>In general</header>
            <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Autism Services and Workforce Acceleration Act of 2014" proposed="true">
                <short-title>Autism Services and Workforce Acceleration Act of 2014</short-title>
              </cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref>, acting through the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7526">Administrator of the Health Resources and Services Administration</cato:entity-ref>, shall establish a demonstration project for the implementation of an Autism Care Program (referred to in this section as the <term>Program</term>) to provide grants and other assistance to improve the effectiveness and efficiency in providing comprehensive care to individuals diagnosed with autism spectrum disorders and their families.</text>
          </subsection>
          <subsection id="H3A8F491F4A2B4C2581525FF50C977515">
            <enum>(b)</enum>
            <header>Goals</header>
            <text>The Program shall be designed—</text>
            <paragraph id="HADF38E7B3AE6483E83DFE09F42CE18C5">
              <enum>(1)</enum>
              <text>to increase—</text>
              <subparagraph id="HA53142DCEE5E4F5082C83928FE256389">
                <enum>(A)</enum>
                <text>comprehensive autism spectrum disorder care delivery;</text>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="H8D8F4AD310C545509226A9CAFEE56D01">
                <enum>(B)</enum>
                <text>access to appropriate health care services, especially wellness and prevention care, at times convenient for individuals;</text>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="HC059F065959A4503AFC1BC9C2C31D16F">
                <enum>(C)</enum>
                <text>satisfaction of individuals with autism spectrum disorders;</text>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="H3699DA39E421403CB42E65A63DB92516">
                <enum>(D)</enum>
                <text>communication among autism spectrum disorder health care providers, behaviorists, educators, specialists, hospitals, and other autism spectrum disorder care providers;</text>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="H3EB900CF819A42A587EA1656B3FDB9FE">
                <enum>(E)</enum>
                <text>academic progress of students with autism spectrum disorders;</text>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="H616BC6D7CC294F41B2FA89BAFC620F73">
                <enum>(F)</enum>
                <text>successful transition to postsecondary education, vocational or job training and placement, and comprehensive adult services for individuals with autism spectrum disorders, focusing in particular upon the transitional period for individuals between the ages of 18 and 25;</text>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="H90F3A852D3FE4E0C85040B29DEFEB568">
                <enum>(G)</enum>
                <text>the quality of health care services, taking into account nationally developed standards and measures;</text>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="HE5E23E04FB80448DA15839D31A96AAB3">
                <enum>(H)</enum>
                <text>development, review, and promulgation of common clinical standards and guidelines for medical care to individuals with autism spectrum disorders;</text>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="H130E676B77EE44F9A4370B65F6025199">
                <enum>(I)</enum>
                <text>development of clinical research projects to support clinical findings in a search for recommended practices; and</text>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="HB0124E865D6348E18AF2F60F6F1CBC25">
                <enum>(J)</enum>
                <text>the quality of life of individuals with autism spectrum disorders, including communication abilities, social skills, community integration, self-determination, and employment and other related services; and</text>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="HC12C85B67E594A988A9EF999FE46BECB">
              <enum>(2)</enum>
              <text>to decrease—</text>
              <subparagraph id="H66CCE0B2E978411B888B0573F3CA17E5">
                <enum>(A)</enum>
                <text>inappropriate emergency room utilization;</text>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="HBABF0A1CB180454EB95372B9C87EDD94">
                <enum>(B)</enum>
                <text>avoidable hospitalizations;</text>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="HA5ADECC8979342DA9DEFB9D273C1AF13">
                <enum>(C)</enum>
                <text>the duplication of health care services;</text>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="HC180F7B1D47C44029A089C415A9F7F92">
                <enum>(D)</enum>
                <text>the inconvenience of multiple provider locations;</text>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="H7B7AC26DDF1649EAA3004131B2B72522">
                <enum>(E)</enum>
                <text>health disparities and inequalities that individuals with autism spectrum disorders face; and</text>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="HFC078FFB22E748569738E389CB918B03">
                <enum>(F)</enum>
                <text>preventable and inappropriate involvement with the juvenile and criminal justice systems.</text>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection id="H6CE1267EB31A4B37AD9FD36BB622B31E">
            <enum>(c)</enum>
            <header>Eligible entities</header>
            <text>To be eligible to receive assistance under the Program, an entity shall—</text>
            <paragraph commented="no" id="HC5039C1FD9344B9D9E80179ADB4B50B1">
              <enum>(1)</enum>
              <text>be a State or a public or private nonprofit entity;</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="H2DF83E37449A4D459103EE58B54F45B8">
              <enum>(2)</enum>
              <text>coordinate activities with the applicable University Centers for Excellence in Developmental Disabilities, the Council on Developmental Disabilities, and the Protection and Advocacy System;</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="H0E1920279A464483BE329B44AC7BCC2E">
              <enum>(3)</enum>
              <text>demonstrate a capacity to provide services to individuals with developmental disabilities and autism spectrum disorder;</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="HCD1B8BC56B814E298B54D5D165B9F40E">
              <enum>(4)</enum>
              <text>agree to establish and implement treatments, interventions, and services that—</text>
              <subparagraph id="H719B39A624BD478E9F960BA0DF41D3C0">
                <enum>(A)</enum>
                <text>enable targeted beneficiaries to designate a personal care coordinator to be their source of first contact and to recommend comprehensive and coordinated care for the whole of the individual;</text>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="H308C8AB292E24C0E9941B0B4565F7CFF">
                <enum>(B)</enum>
                <text>provide for the establishment of a coordination of care committee that is composed of clinicians and practitioners trained in and working in autism spectrum disorder intervention;</text>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="H34E3B596A0E2497EA4BBC749A27E300C">
                <enum>(C)</enum>
                <text>establish a network of physicians, psychologists, family therapists, behavioral specialists, social workers, educators, and health centers that have volunteered to participate as consultants to patient-centered autism care programs to provide high-quality care, focusing on autism spectrum disorder care, at the appropriate times and places and in a cost-effective manner;</text>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="H7FA8F91E373C40D397C6E6D4311A702D">
                <enum>(D)</enum>
                <text>work in cooperation with hospitals, local public health departments, and the network of patient-centered autism care programs, to coordinate and provide health care;</text>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H53D9CE2531CD4C98AA022382865E26C6">
                <enum>(E)</enum>
                <text>utilize health information technology to facilitate the provision and coordination of health care by network participants; and</text>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H065FA619BC1643039DF5222A3AA8FBD4">
                <enum>(F)</enum>
                <text>collaborate with other entities to further the goals of the program, particularly by collaborating with entities that provide transitional adult services to individuals between the ages of 18 and 25 with autism spectrum disorder, to ensure successful transition of such individuals to adulthood; and</text>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H03CADB12D35547C2BD46C0592EA7E72C">
              <enum>(5)</enum>
              <text>submit to the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> an application, at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> may require, including—</text>
              <subparagraph id="H42CA2C6D7C184744B5D0F86A929F6826">
                <enum>(A)</enum>
                <text>a description of the treatments, interventions, or services that the eligible entity proposes to provide under the Program;</text>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="HD35871B209824CB7A71B2AD64F25F24F">
                <enum>(B)</enum>
                <text>a demonstration of the capacity of the eligible entity to provide or establish such treatments, interventions, and services within such entity;</text>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="H7A354674FB3047B19C075DA6EC650B28">
                <enum>(C)</enum>
                <text>a description of the treatments, interventions, or services that are available to individuals with autism in the State;</text>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="HA9A944E309E54754832A2176CFC7EB3E">
                <enum>(D)</enum>
                <text>a description of the gaps in services that exist in different geographic segments of the State;</text>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="H9C7C1E26C02F45E69F1021CC636E706D">
                <enum>(E)</enum>
                <text>a demonstration of the capacity of the eligible entity to monitor and evaluate the outcomes of the treatments, interventions, and services described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Public Health Service Act/s:399GG–1/ss:c/p:5/sp:A" proposed="true">subparagraph (A)</cato:entity-ref>;</text>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="HE2B93D92F2404F51B06A4999AEA04A0E">
                <enum>(F)</enum>
                <text>estimates of the number of individuals and families who will be served by the eligible entity under the Program, including an estimate of the number of such individuals and families in medically underserved areas;</text>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="HABDCBB3C99D94A858E352341D9CE34BC">
                <enum>(G)</enum>
                <text>a description of the ability of the eligible entity to enter into partnerships with community-based or nonprofit providers of treatments, interventions, and services, which may include providers that act as advocates for individuals with autism spectrum disorders and local governments that provide services for individuals with autism spectrum disorders at the community level;</text>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="HFC20E4CCA7D142579FBE7E4C6D71AA41">
                <enum>(H)</enum>
                <text>a description of the ways in which access to such treatments and services may be sustained following the Program period;</text>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="H3BBABF265CBF45969A14573B8FC0E5CC">
                <enum>(I)</enum>
                <text>a description of the ways in which the eligible entity plans to collaborate with other entities to develop and sustain an effective protocol for successful transition from children's services to adult services for individuals with autism spectrum disorder, particularly for individuals between the ages of 18 and 25; and</text>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="H18F7340A09FB4A3988257C047BA804E7">
                <enum>(J)</enum>
                <text>a description of the compliance of the eligible entity with the integration requirement provided under <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
                    <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990/s:302">section 302 of the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12182">
                    <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/42/12182">42 U.S.C. 12182</cato:entity-ref>
                  </external-xref>)</cato:entity>.</text>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection id="HBB2E34380EFE4D3090191FC6011CE293">
            <enum>(d)</enum>
            <header>Grants</header>
            <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall award 3-year grants to eligible entities whose applications are approved under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Public Health Service Act/s:399GG–1/ss:c" proposed="true">subsection (c)</cato:entity-ref>. Such grants shall be used to—</text>
            <paragraph id="HBE31F727FF16411D86CF8ECB5D65F558">
              <enum>(1)</enum>
              <text>carry out a program designed to meet the goals described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Public Health Service Act/s:399GG–1/ss:b" proposed="true">subsection (b)</cato:entity-ref> and the requirements described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Public Health Service Act/s:399GG–1/ss:c" proposed="true">subsection (c)</cato:entity-ref>; and</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="HA422440F4C1E44218B24FEDF7753F9D2">
              <enum>(2)</enum>
              <text>facilitate coordination with local communities to be better prepared and positioned to understand and meet the needs of the communities served by autism care programs.</text>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection id="H8D8CE698969E42FE9F48617042E3D8D5">
            <enum>(e)</enum>
            <header>Advisory councils</header>
            <paragraph id="H1AE214B9A8794EC9853CFADE55CF977E">
              <enum>(1)</enum>
              <header>In general</header>
              <text>Each recipient of a grant under this section shall establish an autism care program advisory council, which shall advise the autism care program regarding policies, priorities, and services.</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="H61BB20B9650F412C819ADFDEF9A495D7">
              <enum>(2)</enum>
              <header>Membership</header>
              <text>Each recipient of a grant shall appoint members of the recipient's advisory council, which shall include a variety of autism care program service providers, individuals from the public who are knowledgeable about autism spectrum disorders, individuals receiving services through the Program, and family members of such individuals. At least 60 percent of the membership shall be comprised of individuals who have received, or are receiving, services through the Program or who are family members of such individuals.</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="HC8E185E327B44F7D99CFCD7B78E329D9">
              <enum>(3)</enum>
              <header>Chairperson</header>
              <text>The recipient of a grant shall appoint a chairperson to the advisory council of the recipient's autism care program who shall be—</text>
              <subparagraph id="HA23FA1F572E44550B71E9B074F4B9196">
                <enum>(A)</enum>
                <text>an individual with autism spectrum disorder who has received, or is receiving, services through the Program; or</text>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="H071E7373140D49BBB227D336C58ED63C">
                <enum>(B)</enum>
                <text>a family member of such an individual.</text>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection id="HEFD0CD45EA9D405F9D3AA720A5BDDECA">
            <enum>(f)</enum>
            <header>Evaluation</header>
            <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall enter into a contract with an independent third-party organization with expertise in evaluation activities to conduct an evaluation and, not later than 180 days after the conclusion of the 3-year grant program under this section, submit a report to the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref>, which may include measures such as whether and to what degree the treatments, interventions, and services provided through the Program have resulted in improved health, educational, employment, and community integration outcomes for individuals with autism spectrum disorders, or other measures, as the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> determines appropriate.</text>
          </subsection>
          <subsection id="HA11D093AE13D432B96586D222336EE19">
            <enum>(g)</enum>
            <header>Administrative expenses</header>
            <text>Of the amounts appropriated to carry out this section, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall allocate not more than 7 percent for administrative expenses, including the expenses related to carrying out the evaluation described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Public Health Service Act/s:399GG–1/ss:f" proposed="true">subsection (f)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
          </subsection>
          <subsection id="HAB8A84A9005F441A8B3111C58B9271BF">
            <enum>(h)</enum>
            <header>Supplement not supplant</header>
            <text>Amounts provided to an entity under this section shall be used to supplement, not supplant, amounts otherwise expended for existing treatments, interventions, and services for individuals with autism spectrum disorders.</text>
          </subsection>
        </section>
        <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
      </quoted-block>
    </section>
    <section id="H8CA8D452E6EA4C7DBEA5B8261B4F880C">
      <enum>6.</enum>
      <header>Planning and demonstration grants for services for transitioning youth and adults</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">
        <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
          <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Public Health Service Act/t:III/pt:R">Part R of title III of the Public Health Service Act</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/280i">
          <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/42/280i">42 U.S.C. 280i</cato:entity-ref>
        </external-xref>)</cato:entity>, as amended by <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Public Health Service Act/s:5">section 5</cato:entity-ref>, is further amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
      <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBD46690245D84C05A83FA07F6F4A6263" style="tax">
        <section id="H14136300770444DBADAE0C26A11A42BB">
          <enum>399GG–2.</enum>
          <header>Planning and demonstration grants for services for transitioning youth and adults</header>
          <subsection id="H69263B7504BC4D7EBEA139F456AF24C2">
            <enum>(a)</enum>
            <header>In general</header>
            <paragraph id="H3250D9DEA33B48A59834A841C518B737">
              <enum>(1)</enum>
              <header>Establishment</header>
              <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall establish the grants described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Public Health Service Act/s:399GG–2/ss:a/p:2" proposed="true">paragraph (2)</cato:entity-ref> in order to enable selected eligible entities to provide appropriate services—</text>
              <subparagraph commented="no" id="H29F928B7F29E4FDD8B0C95B8BE6530A9">
                <enum>(A)</enum>
                <text>to youth with autism spectrum disorders who are transitioning from secondary education to careers or postsecondary education (referred to in this section as <term>transitioning youth</term>); and</text>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph commented="no" id="H13531F0887D94693BEBF2CEBD154838B">
                <enum>(B)</enum>
                <text>to adults with autism spectrum disorders, including individuals who are typically underserved, to enable such individuals to be as independent as possible.</text>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="HDD9AB8E668704ADD9ACD0FE25D7556FD">
              <enum>(2)</enum>
              <header>Grants</header>
              <text>The grants described in this paragraph are—</text>
              <subparagraph id="H9CBFE44A71134EF69D42AE1DE925C873">
                <enum>(A)</enum>
                <text>a one-time, single-year planning grant program for eligible entities; and</text>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="HC6BF4E38275A4EFC99D154EB45B599CF">
                <enum>(B)</enum>
                <text>a multiyear service provision demonstration grant program for selected eligible entities.</text>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection id="HB2B28937DD7943AA8DF5783BE2644A81">
            <enum>(b)</enum>
            <header>Purpose of grants</header>
            <text>Grants shall be awarded to eligible entities to provide all or part of the funding needed to carry out programs that focus on critical aspects of life for transitioning youth and adults with autism spectrum disorders, such as—</text>
            <paragraph id="HCC1D915253054C92B1C4DA9D611C24FA">
              <enum>(1)</enum>
              <text>postsecondary education, vocational training, self-advocacy skills, and employment;</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="H047E8700BD424C6BB24431B935D6B408">
              <enum>(2)</enum>
              <text>residential services and supports, housing, and transportation;</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="H7CC3370199034B019D98D2F4D8BE2105">
              <enum>(3)</enum>
              <text>nutrition, health and wellness, recreational and social activities; and</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="H327296F2854F4D3CAC93C6AAEC2E467D">
              <enum>(4)</enum>
              <text>personal safety and the needs of individuals with autism spectrum disorders who become involved with the criminal justice system.</text>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection id="H81442FC3FFC4479B84B78133DA01E3C5">
            <enum>(c)</enum>
            <header>Eligible entity</header>
            <text>An eligible entity desiring to receive a grant under this section shall be a State or other public or private nonprofit organization, including an autism care program.</text>
          </subsection>
          <subsection id="H9FC979C188EC4C28BDF961FCC00CCEBD">
            <enum>(d)</enum>
            <header>Planning grants</header>
            <paragraph id="H6559CA1A5FDC4850928B7097E9A5CA38">
              <enum>(1)</enum>
              <header>In general</header>
              <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall award one-time grants to eligible entities to support the planning and development of initiatives that will expand and enhance service delivery systems for transitioning youth and adults with autism spectrum disorders.</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="H159BC6248C9247E886151A5B733F287F">
              <enum>(2)</enum>
              <header>Application</header>
              <text>In order to receive such a grant, an eligible entity shall—</text>
              <subparagraph id="HCF7EEB786A834EF191649CFF2BE49983">
                <enum>(A)</enum>
                <text>submit an application at such time and containing such information as the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> may require; and</text>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="H7C0062D5D44A4FE3B750444DF40B4BF6">
                <enum>(B)</enum>
                <text>demonstrate the ability to carry out such planning grant in coordination with the State Developmental Disabilities Council and organizations representing or serving individuals with autism spectrum disorders and their families.</text>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection id="HD4175D1D86914EE69951FF6A8BD84BCA">
            <enum>(e)</enum>
            <header>Implementation grants</header>
            <paragraph id="H99777C4E435D4D4C8ED0FFE3C0EC416D">
              <enum>(1)</enum>
              <header>In general</header>
              <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall award grants to eligible entities that have received a planning grant under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Public Health Service Act/s:399GG–2/ss:d" proposed="true">subsection (d)</cato:entity-ref> to enable such entities to provide appropriate services to transitioning youth and adults with autism spectrum disorders.</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="H151CB8BAA8104DFFB2C5161E23E81A3E">
              <enum>(2)</enum>
              <header>Application</header>
              <text>In order to receive a grant under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Public Health Service Act/s:399GG–2/ss:e/p:1" proposed="true">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref>, the eligible entity shall submit an application at such time and containing such information as the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> may require, including—</text>
              <subparagraph id="H884619FCED294B1FA3B03B9647B9DC41">
                <enum>(A)</enum>
                <text>the services that the eligible entity proposes to provide and the expected outcomes for individuals with autism spectrum disorders who receive such services;</text>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="HDA521F21FA1E4760A4F33532AFC0A7D5">
                <enum>(B)</enum>
                <text>the number of individuals and families who will be served by such grant, including an estimate of the individuals and families in underserved areas who will be served by such grant;</text>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="H03C604ABA1D448ABB240482DAD3EBA65">
                <enum>(C)</enum>
                <text>the ways in which services will be coordinated among both public and nonprofit providers of services for transitioning youth and adults with disabilities, including community-based services;</text>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="HDDD6A11F3EDB4FAFA2C55F5C3C5E9D5A">
                <enum>(D)</enum>
                <text>where applicable, the process through which the eligible entity will distribute funds to a range of community-based or nonprofit providers of services, including local governments, and such entity's capacity to provide such services;</text>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="H95ECD6D0592644A1AEF2122C7C874589">
                <enum>(E)</enum>
                <text>the process through which the eligible entity will monitor and evaluate the outcome of activities funded through the grant, including the effect of the activities upon adults with autism spectrum disorders who receive such services;</text>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="HE9653FF46D3B4DB6B2F6645DC25B2D36">
                <enum>(F)</enum>
                <text>the plans of the eligible entity to coordinate and streamline transitions from youth to adult services;</text>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="HDCEA7EAEDCF3481495C3711C79022E27">
                <enum>(G)</enum>
                <text>the process by which the eligible entity will ensure compliance with the integration requirement provided under <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
                    <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Americans With Disabilities Act of 1990/s:302">section 302 of the Americans With Disabilities Act of 1990</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12182">
                    <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/42/12182">42 U.S.C. 12182</cato:entity-ref>
                  </external-xref>)</cato:entity>; and</text>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="H17BBC48A2B71424DA6415BA18C6DF9EC">
                <enum>(H)</enum>
                <text>a description of how such services may be sustained following the grant period.</text>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection id="H04DAE75AF2664B8BA87A9E93567C7A2C">
            <enum>(f)</enum>
            <header>Evaluation</header>
            <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall contract with a third-party organization with expertise in evaluation to evaluate such demonstration grant program and, not later than 180 days after the conclusion of the grant program under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Public Health Service Act/s:399GG–2/ss:e" proposed="true">subsection (e)</cato:entity-ref>, submit a report to the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref>. The evaluation and report may include an analysis of whether and to what extent the services provided through the grant program described in this section resulted in improved health, education, employment, and community integration outcomes for adults with autism spectrum disorders, or other measures, as the Secretary determines appropriate.</text>
          </subsection>
          <subsection id="H81054FFA21004C9DBE55113FFF0AD302">
            <enum>(g)</enum>
            <header>Administrative expenses</header>
            <text>Of the amounts appropriated to carry out this section, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall set aside not more than 7 percent for administrative expenses, including the expenses related to carrying out the evaluation described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Public Health Service Act/s:399GG–2/ss:f" proposed="true">subsection (f)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
          </subsection>
          <subsection id="H1580EC3172894D11B25D53F82012E807">
            <enum>(h)</enum>
            <header>Supplement, not supplant</header>
            <text>Demonstration grant funds provided under this section shall supplement, not supplant, existing treatments, interventions, and services for individuals with autism spectrum disorders.</text>
          </subsection>
        </section>
        <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
      </quoted-block>
    </section>
    <section id="H777574B5F0EE46BF88903ED0E3C9E466">
      <enum>7.</enum>
      <header>Multimedia campaign</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">
        <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
          <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Public Health Service Act/t:III/pt:R">Part R of title III of the Public Health Service Act</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/280i">
          <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/42/280i">42 U.S.C. 280i</cato:entity-ref>
        </external-xref>)</cato:entity>, as amended by <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Public Health Service Act/s:6">section 6</cato:entity-ref>, is further amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
      <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6449CA60900F4067B02936A3DA56D419" style="tax">
        <section id="HCD368044098E4648837C096A95918A65">
          <enum>399GG–3.</enum>
          <header>Multimedia campaign</header>
          <subsection id="HF72A9975940D4CAFB1014A61C9733FDC">
            <enum>(a)</enum>
            <header>In general</header>
            <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref>, in order to enhance existing awareness campaigns and provide for the implementation of new campaigns, shall award grants to public and nonprofit private entities for the purpose of carrying out multimedia campaigns to increase public education and awareness and reduce stigma concerning—</text>
            <paragraph id="H62440146C2D04C36806F7F8140EB539C">
              <enum>(1)</enum>
              <text>healthy developmental milestones for infants and children that may assist in the early identification of the signs and symptoms of autism spectrum disorders; and</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="HD2E0D25372134DF3AEEF646A04B34E5B">
              <enum>(2)</enum>
              <text>autism spectrum disorders through the lifespan and the challenges that individuals with autism spectrum disorders face, which may include transitioning into adulthood, securing appropriate job training or postsecondary education, securing and holding jobs, finding suitable housing, interacting with the correctional system, increasing independence, and attaining a good quality of life.</text>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection id="H29FFD68A6BB64539AA43BE3D3A3E2CBB">
            <enum>(b)</enum>
            <header>Eligibility</header>
            <text>To be eligible to receive a grant under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Public Health Service Act/s:399GG–3/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref>, an entity shall—</text>
            <paragraph id="HBCC4977841AB414C81AD0B0F9D470ADE">
              <enum>(1)</enum>
              <text>submit to the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> may require; and</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="HE418E553D3464644B17D69140D8DE4AE">
              <enum>(2)</enum>
              <text>provide assurance that the multimedia campaign implemented under such grant will provide information that is tailored to the intended audience, which may be a diverse public audience or a specific audience, such as health professionals, criminal justice professionals, or emergency response professionals.</text>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
        </section>
        <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
      </quoted-block>
    </section>
    <section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H37CCAB7E70274B46821B453EC99F9C5D">
      <enum>8.</enum>
      <header>National training initiatives on autism spectrum disorders</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">
        <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
          <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Public Health Service Act/t:III/pt:R">Part R of title III of the Public Health Service Act</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/280i">
          <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/42/280i">42 U.S.C. 280i</cato:entity-ref>
        </external-xref>)</cato:entity>, as amended by <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Public Health Service Act/s:7">section 7</cato:entity-ref>, is further amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
      <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6F9AEE6CB60E4CEFA12D8BFC45E79645" style="tax">
        <section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5726EADD67EA4AA99CAAFC65255D34D6">
          <enum>399GG–4.</enum>
          <header>National training initiatives on autism spectrum disorders</header>
          <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE0F40C6514FC40BE96AA3EFA108DE292">
            <enum>(a)</enum>
            <header>National training initiative supplemental grants</header>
            <paragraph id="H6D7F98C4EA5F4702B05C9E0B0EBF8DE2">
              <enum>(1)</enum>
              <header>In general</header>
              <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall award multiyear national training initiative supplemental grants to eligible entities so that such entities may provide training and technical assistance and to disseminate information, in order to enable such entities to address the unmet needs of individuals with autism spectrum disorders and their families.</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph commented="no" id="HEC674351618B43EAB8F4948C119732FB">
              <enum>(2)</enum>
              <header>Eligible entity</header>
              <text>To be eligible to receive assistance under this section an entity shall—</text>
              <subparagraph commented="no" id="H450D0B0F0C49408B91347DFCAF573150">
                <enum>(A)</enum>
                <text>be a public or private nonprofit entity, including University Centers for Excellence in Developmental Disabilities and other service, training, and academic entities; and</text>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph commented="no" id="H3C971ADBBA0847A698414979711C0F51">
                <enum>(B)</enum>
                <text>submit an application as described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Public Health Service Act/s:399GG–4/ss:a/p:3" proposed="true">paragraph (3)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="H146B56417DF94730914FDA27A33A7026">
              <enum>(3)</enum>
              <header>Requirements</header>
              <text>An eligible entity that desires to receive a grant under this paragraph shall submit to the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> an application containing such agreements and information as the Secretary may require, including agreements that the training program shall—</text>
              <subparagraph id="HA15E94C8E10441569F24F928B3621E35">
                <enum>(A)</enum>
                <text>provide training and technical assistance in evidence-based practices of effective interventions, services, treatments, and supports to children and adults on the autism spectrum and their families, and evaluate the implementation of such practices;</text>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="HBD59B63E18A44A79A11DE482BABEBDCF">
                <enum>(B)</enum>
                <text>provide trainees with an appropriate balance of interdisciplinary academic and community-based experiences;</text>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="HAA1495EAD280486C95E8B9D7B2906273">
                <enum>(C)</enum>
                <text>have a demonstrated capacity to include individuals with autism spectrum disorders, parents, and family members as part of the training program to ensure that a person and family-centered approach is used;</text>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="HBA2013D516FE47CF88628AC0B3954FB7">
                <enum>(D)</enum>
                <text>provide to the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref>, in the manner prescribed by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref>, data regarding the outcomes of the provision of training and technical assistance;</text>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="HC9818D724E58445190DCBFCC156F750D">
                <enum>(E)</enum>
                <text>demonstrate a capacity to share and disseminate materials and practices that are developed and evaluated to be effective in the provision of training and technical assistance; and</text>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="H222E0E60CA6544DF8719F87CE6D29CA9">
                <enum>(F)</enum>
                <text>provide assurances that training, technical assistance, and information dissemination performed under grants made pursuant to this paragraph shall be consistent with the goals established under already existing disability programs authorized under Federal law and conducted in coordination with other relevant State agencies and service providers.</text>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="H39A8A801EDDB43C8B811AF120796A765">
              <enum>(4)</enum>
              <header>Activities</header>
              <text>An entity that receives a grant under this section shall expand and develop interdisciplinary training and continuing education initiatives for health, allied health, and educational professionals by engaging in the following activities:</text>
              <subparagraph id="HB4DC0C6171E241A4A6588FAD0604E222">
                <enum>(A)</enum>
                <text>Promoting and engaging in training for health, allied health, and educational professionals to identify, diagnose, and develop interventions for individuals with, or at risk of developing, autism spectrum disorders.</text>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="HC6C086BF3DA6482DA982A7ECD6A3A669">
                <enum>(B)</enum>
                <text>Expanding the availability of training and dissemination of information regarding effective, lifelong interventions, educational services, and community supports.</text>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="HA558087778E24D7E868C83DCF29F11FB">
                <enum>(C)</enum>
                <text>Providing training and technical assistance in collaboration with relevant State, regional, or national agencies, institutions of higher education, and advocacy groups or community-based service providers, including health and allied health professionals, employment providers, direct support professionals, emergency first responder personnel, and law enforcement officials.</text>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="H2478439DB75C46EB98D4F1B9D59929C2">
                <enum>(D)</enum>
                <text>Developing mechanisms to provide training and technical assistance, including for-credit courses, intensive summer institutes, continuing education programs, distance-based programs, and Web-based information dissemination strategies.</text>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="HC22F46AE64AC499294B5956BA86AA891">
                <enum>(E)</enum>
                <text>Collecting data on the outcomes of training and technical assistance programs to meet statewide needs for the expansion of services to children with autism spectrum disorders and adults with autism spectrum disorders.</text>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection id="HB0F0F955C4A442269E2949F11392011E">
            <enum>(b)</enum>
            <header>Technical assistance</header>
            <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall reserve 2 percent of the appropriated funds to make a grant to a national organization with demonstrated capacity for providing training and technical assistance to the entities receiving grants under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Public Health Service Act/s:399GG–4/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref> to enable such entities to—</text>
            <paragraph id="HBC28B7693468488BAE91392B8C5BB39B">
              <enum>(1)</enum>
              <text>assist in national dissemination of specific information, including evidence-based and promising best practices, from interdisciplinary training programs, and when appropriate, other entities whose findings would inform the work performed by entities awarded grants;</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="HEEF152105C224DBC96BA4B05E10BC90D">
              <enum>(2)</enum>
              <text>compile and disseminate strategies and materials that prove to be effective in the provision of training and technical assistance so that the entire network can benefit from the models, materials, and practices developed in individual programs;</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="HC730FE9C146340F1842DB2745856DC6B">
              <enum>(3)</enum>
              <text>assist in the coordination of activities of grantees under this section;</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="H0D378859A38C476AAD6D271397240244">
              <enum>(4)</enum>
              <text>develop an Internet Web portal that will provide linkages to each of the individual training initiatives and provide access to training modules, promising training, and technical assistance practices and other materials developed by grantees;</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="HD91C5037D7084B31AFE91B2C401965B9">
              <enum>(5)</enum>
              <text>convene experts from multiple interdisciplinary training programs and individuals with autism spectrum disorders and their families to discuss and make recommendations with regard to training issues related to the assessment, diagnosis of, treatment, interventions and services for, children and adults with autism spectrum disorders; and</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="HFFD37222F0454D898F3DFE69C0C93DD7">
              <enum>(6)</enum>
              <text>undertake any other functions that the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> determines to be appropriate.</text>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection id="H337B74823D534B2989EADC188A2D0717">
            <enum>(c)</enum>
            <header>Supplement not supplant</header>
            <text>Amounts provided under this section shall be used to supplement, not supplant, amounts otherwise expended for existing network or organizational structures.</text>
          </subsection>
        </section>
        <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
      </quoted-block>
    </section>
    <section id="H07982AFFF8CB4760802269B52F22AEC7">
      <enum>9.</enum>
      <header>Authorization of appropriations</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">
        <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="auth-auth-approp">There are authorized to be appropriated for <cato:funds-and-year amount="indefinite" year="2015..2019">fiscal years 2015 through 2019 such sums as may be necessary</cato:funds-and-year> <cato:property name="purpose">to carry out <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Autism Services and Workforce Acceleration Act of 2014" proposed="true">this Act</cato:entity-ref>
          </cato:property>.</cato:entity>
      </text>
    </section>
  </legis-body>
</bill>
</doc>