<doc>
  <docmeta id="113hr5530ih">
    <bill congress="113" type="hr" number="5530" version="ih"/>
    <revision size="4920" annotations="0" status="complete" id="4" commit-time="2014-10-08T20:20:19Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113hr5530ih/4.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H8DDFFEEB80AE46EB9872B2FE243C06E3" public-private="public">
	<metadata>
<dublinCore>
<dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">113 HR 5530 IH: To require that hunting activities be a land use in all management plans for Federal land under the jurisdiction of the Secretary of the Interior or the Secretary of Agriculture to the extent that such use is not clearly incompatible with the purposes for which the Federal land is managed, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">2014-09-18</dc:date>
<dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>113th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>2d Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 5530</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20140918">September 18, 2014</action-date>
			<action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="B001262">Mr. Broun of Georgia</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Agriculture</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To require that hunting activities be a land use in all management plans for Federal land under the
			 jurisdiction of the Secretary of the Interior or the Secretary of
			 Agriculture to the extent that such use is not clearly incompatible with
			 the purposes for which the Federal land is managed, and for other
			 purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="HABFDD2067180435593D0EC961E11009C" style="OLC">
		<section id="H1C5EDB83410D470BBE1B4CF6C8D617B9" section-type="section-one">
      <enum>1.</enum>
      <header>Hunting on Federal land</header>
			<subsection id="HD0B726C56BA64CD8B8FFAD9D1C256444">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Purpose</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The purpose of this section is to require that hunting activities be a land use in all management
			 plans for Federal land to the extent that such use is not clearly
			 incompatible with the purposes for which the Federal land is managed.</text>
			</subsection>
      <subsection id="H6B9F990EE8534460AAF589EF6800878D">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Hunting Allowed Unless Incompatible</header>
        <text>When developing or considering approval of a management plan (or any amendment to such a management
			 plan) for Federal land, the head of the agency with jurisdiction over such
			 Federal land shall ensure that hunting activities are allowed as a use of
			 such Federal land to the extent that such use is not clearly incompatible
			 with the purposes for which the Federal land is managed.</text>
			</subsection>
      <subsection id="H4458149D54604973946BF9CBE58FB8C5">
        <enum>(c)</enum>
        <header>Prohibiting or Restricting Hunting</header>
				<paragraph id="H8BAAA793CBCC461B99260338C2A92C36">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>Reasons set forth in management plan</header>
          <text>If hunting activities are not allowed or are restricted on Federal land, the head of the agency
			 with jurisdiction over such Federal land shall set forth in the management
			 plan for that Federal land the specific reason that hunting activities are
			 not allowed or are restricted.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H2E847B84B50D4FB8A41768103E3A3617">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Restriction clarified</header>
          <text>For the purposes of this subsection—</text>
					<subparagraph id="H218FFCFC33BB4340B5DAE0C3D01C904E">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>allowing contract or quota thinning of wildlife shall not constitute allowing unrestricted hunting;
			 and</text>
					</subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H4E30A784A7BD485BAD5C95427C38EBE2">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>a fee charged by any entity related to hunting activities on Federal land that is in excess of that
			 needed to recoup costs of management of the Federal land shall be deemed
			 to be a restriction on hunting.</text>
					</subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="H6301D032A58D4D52988E5FFA51DFEED5">
        <enum>(d)</enum>
        <header>Fees</header>
        <text>Fees charged related to hunting activities on Federal land shall be—</text>
				<paragraph id="HBE46DD06D41446D6A5B788CA9EC1F206">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">retained by—</text>
					<subparagraph id="H49BD33BFA2D949728025D35C78C21FCF">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>the State or local authority tasked with managing the land to offset costs directly related to
			 management of hunting on the Federal land upon which hunting activities
			 related to the fee are conducted; or</text>
					</subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H7CC8F5B4EC87497EB957AA0C3CA6ACD6">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>in any case where a State or local authority described in subparagraph (A) does not exist, the head
			 of the agency with jurisdiction over such Federal land to offset costs
			 directly related to management of hunting on the Federal land upon which
			 hunting activities related to the fee are conducted; and</text>
					</subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H584024C458B04EF78E401BAF8F7B9018">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>limited to what the Secretary reasonably estimates to be necessary to offset costs directly related
			 to management of hunting on the Federal land upon which hunting activities
			 related to the fee are conducted.</text>
				</paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="HF8CFECFADADD4AC4B7ACF6A0E5E42264">
        <enum>(e)</enum>
        <header>Definitions</header>
        <text>In this section—</text>
				<paragraph id="HB4ECAA9A2E4149BF81D4A6320B5D9A65">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>the term <term>Federal land</term> means Federal land under the jurisdiction of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1400" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of the Interior</cato:entity-ref> (excluding lands held
			 in trust for an Indian or an Indian tribe) or the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1200" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of
			 Agriculture</cato:entity-ref>;</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H9FE9B468C69C4D468AF802D0E22B8697">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>the term <term>hunting</term> means hunting, trapping, netting, and fishing; and</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H9826BC13F631415C9FEBF33611FFFF49">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <text>the term <term>management plan</term> means a management plan, management contract, or other comprehensive plan or agreement for the
			 management or use of Federal land.</text>
				</paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="H144ACA4D754048CB8FA296672DDFD506">
        <enum>(f)</enum>
        <header>Applicability</header>
        <text>This section shall apply to all management plans developed, approved, or amended after the date of
			 the enactment of this section.</text>
			</subsection>
    </section>
  </legis-body>
</bill>
</doc>