<doc>
  <docmeta id="113hr1101ih">
    <bill congress="113" type="hr" number="1101" version="ih"/>
    <revision size="75577" annotations="0" id="8" commit-time="2013-04-22T16:52:28+00:00" committer="favila" doc="113hr1101ih/8.xml" status="complete">
      <description/>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H51A7DCB7F367414D8F9583CCAB78E7B1" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>113 HR 1101 IH: Homeowners and Taxpayers Protection Act of 2013</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2013-03-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>113th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 1101</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20130312">March 12, 2013</action-date>
			<action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="S001165">Mr. Sires</sponsor> introduced
			 the following bill; which was referred to the
			 <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial
			 Services</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on
			 <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Transportation and
			 Infrastructure</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by
			 the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within
			 the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To strengthen America’s financial infrastructure, by
		  requiring pre-funding for catastrophe losses using private insurance premium
		  dollars to better prepare and protect homeowners from natural catastrophes and
		  to protect taxpayers from massive bailouts, and to provide dedicated funding
		  from insurance premiums to improve catastrophe preparedness, loss prevention
		  and mitigation, and to improve the availability and affordability of private
		  market homeowners insurance coverage for catastrophic events, and for other
		  purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="HB2B6D08A3B0D40FA98D0681EB479298C" style="OLC">
		<section id="H7E33C2ECFA0A445B8696AE7A09B0E6EB" section-type="section-one">
      <enum>1.</enum>
      <header>Short title and table of
			 contents</header>
			<subsection id="HF77A6E4F2E9548A39CF9164CBB6B3E49">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Short
			 title</header>
        <text>This Act may be cited as the <quote>
            <short-title>Homeowners and Taxpayers Protection Act of
			 2013</short-title>
          </quote>.</text>
			</subsection>
      <subsection id="H9C958005F1FE4C64A416E270A0A8B2AC">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Table of
			 contents</header>
        <text>The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text>
				<toc container-level="legis-body-container" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded" lowest-level="section" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" regeneration="yes-regeneration">
					<toc-entry idref="H7E33C2ECFA0A445B8696AE7A09B0E6EB" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title and table of contents.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H8BADE189CAE548BA90889118EFF1600A" level="section">Sec. 2. Findings and purpose.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HFC4D14D042A645F4A6803DAE6E5F4026" level="section">Sec. 3. Definitions.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H57B6AA2C02FB4F8BAA49951712606921" level="title">Title I—TAXPAYER PROTECTION, PRE-FUNDED CATASTROPHE RECOVERY, AND
				MARKET STABILIZATION</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H527990DC90AE486BA5F88CF73DF590DF" level="section">Sec. 101. National Commission on Natural Catastrophe
				Preparation and Protection.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HA77E39C508E54093BB2F51E9643EB39F" level="section">Sec. 102. Pre-funded and privately financed catastrophe
				recovery program.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H313F381CF86946C29842739CF7A02E9E" level="section">Sec. 103. Post-catastrophe market stabilization program for
				liquidity loans.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H632093702D8D421D93C1C10B424B105E" level="section">Sec. 104. Termination.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HBBFC9E3692AE4B83B0D3B5CA61BD9A5E" level="title">Title II—CATASTROPHE READINESS, CITIZEN AND COMMUNITY
				PREPAREDNESS, AND MITIGATION</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HD432488F69CD4C2D9B912C9C498A935B" level="section">Sec. 201. National Readiness, Preparedness, and Mitigation
				Committee.</toc-entry>
				</toc>
			</subsection>
    </section>
    <section id="H8BADE189CAE548BA90889118EFF1600A">
      <enum>2.</enum>
      <header>Findings and
			 purpose</header>
			<subsection id="H2037BB4F0DF04892AF0C2851762FBFE3">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Findings</header>
        <text>The
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> finds the following:</text>
				<paragraph id="H6DA1D38A61414236A56A2C8CB06D2313">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>The economy of the
			 United States, the American taxpayers, and all homeowners need to be better
			 prepared for, and more protected from, major natural catastrophes.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H733CEC60BD564FE1BF7338D5F36FDA9F">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>Taking into
			 consideration the current economic and fiscal challenges facing the United
			 States, it is more important than ever to fortify our Nation’s financial
			 infrastructure to be fully prepared for major natural catastrophes and to
			 mitigate the risk of catastrophe as much as possible.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H8F5E39086B3842D9958F7CA4E908AFB7">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <text>When major
			 catastrophes hit, the Federal Government is called upon to provide significant
			 funding and services to support recovery.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H7C63823A40154E8C9612A5DBBAC67F02">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
          <text>The costs of
			 post-catastrophe Federal <quote>bailouts</quote> are borne by all taxpayers and
			 can create a disincentive to fully prepare for catastrophes.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HB1828BFA35254A22885242DC637FA43B">
          <enum>(5)</enum>
          <text>Historically, the
			 budget for Federal Government has assumed there will be no natural
			 catastrophes, and this lack of pre-funding for catastrophes contributed
			 substantially to annual budget deficits and growing national debt.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HC287B586347D4A6DA967BB363A1F4CA8">
          <enum>(6)</enum>
          <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Budget Control Act of 2011">Budget Control
			 Act of 2011</cato:entity-ref> ends an era of unbudgeted recovery assistance and authorizes a
			 fixed level of annual funding for catastrophes relief.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HAA1772456DD7434BA40C827984AC5187">
          <enum>(7)</enum>
          <text>The amount of
			 future catastrophe relief funding is capped at the average amount spent on
			 natural catastrophes during the previous 10 years with the high and low years
			 removed.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H4006302B7FF94004845A3E6C69CDDED2">
          <enum>(8)</enum>
          <text>By removing the
			 high and low years, the law now caps catastrophes spending at a level that is
			 less than 60 percent of the amount spent on catastrophe relief during the
			 previous 10 years.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HD2A9FA0644D44CB8AFE4ADB3DDF5CC4D">
          <enum>(9)</enum>
          <text>Responsibly
			 managing Government spending is a top congressional priority, especially in
			 light of the unprecedented fiscal challenges facing the Nation.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H86D3C89FF9E145CE8D98958666185C61">
          <enum>(10)</enum>
          <text>Natural
			 catastrophes will continue to occur, and the exposure to catastrophe risk is
			 growing. Scientists warn that future catastrophes will inevitably cause losses
			 far in excess of prior events, and these losses could exceed the limited
			 capacity in the private market to cover claims and remain viable to insure
			 properties after massive catastrophic events.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H36B23B3A15EA48D095DFCBFA0DFA7C11">
          <enum>(11)</enum>
          <text>In 2011, the
			 earthquake centered in Virginia that shook the East Coast and the extreme
			 weather and deadly super tornadoes that ripped across the country provided
			 powerful reminders that natural catastrophes can strike unexpectedly, severely
			 damaging areas not thought to be at high risk, and no region is immune from the
			 threat of natural catastrophe.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H0D7AB3365054436EA483404E05C5DCFA">
          <enum>(12)</enum>
          <text>In 2012, the
			 devastation caused by Superstorm Sandy demonstrated yet again the need for a
			 mechanism to ensure that privately funded monies will be available if needed
			 following mega-catastrophes.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H406CE3422D9C430F91E92288B95663CA">
          <enum>(13)</enum>
          <text>To successfully
			 transition to a more limited and targeted Federal role in post-event
			 catastrophe funding, communities must be better prepared for future
			 catastrophes, the risk of damage must be mitigated, and individuals must have
			 greater access to private market protection against catastrophe risk.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H4C98FCB7421B479285241EE7ED71BB4A">
          <enum>(14)</enum>
          <text>The private
			 insurance market alone does not have sufficient capacity to efficiently address
			 the timing risk presented by major natural catastrophes, and there is no
			 guarantee that the level of capacity that does exist will continue to be
			 available from one year to the next or that consumers have the resources to
			 adjust to significant price swings in the cost of the capital for available
			 capacity.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H73ABEF80EE5B476983F067AD701B1521">
          <enum>(15)</enum>
          <text>Disruptions in
			 insurance availability and affordability will continue to harm economic
			 activity in States exposed to major catastrophes and place significant burdens
			 on residents of these States.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HA66EBFAA9CE04D968B8E8664A74AAF84">
          <enum>(16)</enum>
          <text>Consumers in many
			 areas around the country cannot find homeowners insurance in the private
			 market, and affordability and availability challenges will grow dramatically
			 when future major catastrophes strike.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H329F5C585FF142A7B9F4702EB0562EFF">
          <enum>(17)</enum>
          <text>Hurricane
			 Katrina, Superstorm Sandy, and other recent catastrophes confirm that the
			 economic harm from natural catastrophes has a disproportionate impact upon the
			 poor and middle class because areas most frequently and adversely impacted by
			 catastrophic hurricanes have disproportionately high rates of poverty and
			 housing stock valued well below State averages.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H562E062101F346A29554C53F51613228">
          <enum>(18)</enum>
          <text>A new
			 public-private partnership approach to deal more effectively with major natural
			 catastrophes would more efficiently leverage the public sector and establish a
			 limited, less expensive, more focused role for government while also maximizing
			 the capabilities of the private sector.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HC5B698E49CE54B9BBE05F3564F1EC0CF">
          <enum>(19)</enum>
          <text>A privately
			 funded backstop can provide more protection at lower cost for consumers while
			 also strengthening America’s financial infrastructure to deal with natural
			 catastrophes by increasing capacity and providing more market stability after a
			 catastrophe.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HB7122C9AF25646CCABC91C1B6933AA1A">
          <enum>(20)</enum>
          <text>Cost savings can
			 lower premiums for consumers and be used to encourage better prevention and
			 mitigation in lieu of post-event bailouts.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HAA75B3E4452B4BD092D564164FDD2BB5">
          <enum>(21)</enum>
          <text>A financial
			 backstop can be structured to be fully funded to protect taxpayers from
			 bailouts and insurance policyholders from subsidies upon which the current
			 system relies.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H421C44AC1DB8439896D8AFE8F0A09E0E">
          <enum>(22)</enum>
          <text>A public-private
			 partnership model, with an appropriately structured backstop, can protect
			 against the timing risk presented by major natural catastrophes, spread risk
			 more broadly, and enable private direct insurers to underwrite and price
			 insurance for large-scale catastrophes more efficiently and with less risk of
			 insolvency or financial distress while making insurance more available and
			 affordable for consumers.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HB08DA5545CC34F86B336908495F9B475">
          <enum>(23)</enum>
          <text>A public-private
			 partnership model can be structured to include and encourage participation by
			 private market reinsurers.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H9123A694EFB744428D89F9AC2B9735F3">
          <enum>(24)</enum>
          <text>Incentives and
			 requirements can be created to improve prevention and mitigation measures at
			 the State and local levels, including strong building codes, effective
			 retrofits for existing homes, and sensible land use policies to prohibit
			 further development in environmentally sensitive areas that are highly exposed
			 to catastrophe.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H4E9DA63301D249D6908A3905D23C4D25">
          <enum>(25)</enum>
          <text>For the majority
			 of Americans, their home is their single biggest asset and protecting that
			 investment is important to the economic health of millions of Americans, to
			 social stability; and to the health of the banking system and broader
			 economy.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HF3C77544480F473FA8C843B2EDE79836">
          <enum>(26)</enum>
          <text>The financial
			 crisis of 2008 and recent fiscal challenges confirm the value of taking action
			 in advance to strengthen America’s financial infrastructure through a privately
			 funded backstop rather than waiting for a future crisis or collapse to take
			 emergency action in the form of bailouts.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HE8DC9CAA8B9844DF9D99DF1FEAFEF45C">
          <enum>(27)</enum>
          <text>It is in the best
			 interests of the Nation to take responsible action now to begin to build a
			 financial backstop that will help protect a recovering American economy and
			 mitigate the economic or financial shock that could result from a major
			 catastrophic event.</text>
				</paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="H7CD4CF8E392C43309AFBDA8F87B93DEE">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Purposes</header>
        <text>The
			 purposes of this Act are—</text>
				<paragraph id="H7BA388B8E55E40AE82265971E4B9B3C9">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>to better prepare
			 and protect homeowners and taxpayers from major natural catastrophe;</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H2E60A5EA19874C96B2C958DF11FDAD74">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>to establish a
			 fully funded program for catastrophe losses to strengthen the financial
			 infrastructure of the United States;</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HE49F058F13DC4C12AFFF8EB6E09ADD9B">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <text>to protect
			 taxpayers from bailouts and subsidies related to the financing of
			 post-catastrophe catastrophe relief;</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H6C68D1ECACB94265839CAE7868346894">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
          <text>to develop a
			 public-private partnership that maximizes and supplements private market
			 capacity, increases the spread of risk, and increases market stability;</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H61D8091835234A9AA54170562786833E">
          <enum>(5)</enum>
          <text>to reduce the size
			 of State government insurance exposure;</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H1791B9D9EAAA4BD798C5CBE72022E3CB">
          <enum>(6)</enum>
          <text>to make private
			 market homeowners insurance more available and affordable;</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H55C0C80C4418450F9BBF1F223429A2AB">
          <enum>(7)</enum>
          <text>to improve
			 emergency preparedness;</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H68D4E77D660B4863B0771CF7FE553767">
          <enum>(8)</enum>
          <text>to encourage
			 individuals and communities to adopt mitigation and prevention measures that
			 reduce losses from such catastrophes; and</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H9DD1CC080FD9496FA9D69D1A61BA0462">
          <enum>(9)</enum>
          <text>to fortify the
			 Nation’s capacity to assist in the financial recovery from major
			 catastrophes.</text>
				</paragraph>
      </subsection>
    </section>
    <section id="HFC4D14D042A645F4A6803DAE6E5F4026">
      <enum>3.</enum>
      <header>Definitions</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">For purposes of this Act, the following
			 definitions shall apply:</text>
			<paragraph id="HCC124D0DF5A04B1582CE4D9AE862E48F">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <header>Actuarially
			 sound</header>
        <text>The term <quote>actuarially sound</quote> means, with
			 respect to premiums, that premiums are determined according to principles of
			 actuarial science to be adequate, but not excessive, in the aggregate to pay
			 current and future obligations, including the expected annualized cost of all
			 claims, loss adjustment expenses, and all administrative costs.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H5D135AB6626642C48091C835891260D4">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <header>Covered
			 event</header>
        <text>The term <quote>covered event</quote> means the occurrence
			 of one or more of the events specified in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Homeowners and Taxpayers Protection Act of 2013/s:102/ss:c" proposed="true">section 102(c)</cato:entity-ref> that causes a loss or
			 series of losses.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H79DFD1B91AFE4FA58AF581C6E9B41ACC">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <header>Covered
			 state</header>
        <text>The term <quote>covered States</quote> means, with respect
			 to a State plan, a State covered by the plan.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H3132013F4DE349209041A48635D09278">
        <enum>(4)</enum>
        <header>Eligible state
			 plan</header>
        <text>The term <quote>eligible State plan</quote> means a State
			 plan or multi-State plan that meets the requirements of <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Homeowners and Taxpayers Protection Act of 2013/s:102/ss:d" proposed="true">section 102(d)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H0F09221189A446C4B6017C0F6D2053C8">
        <enum>(5)</enum>
        <header>Emergency
			 response providers</header>
        <text>The term <quote>emergency response
			 providers</quote> has the meaning given such term in <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Homeland Security Act of 2002/s:2">section 2 of the Homeland
			 Security Act of 2002</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/101">6 U.S.C. 101</external-xref>)</cato:entity>.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H8B0A32D3AB124D238A1E1966CCFA0D7C">
        <enum>(6)</enum>
        <header>Fund</header>
        <text>The
			 term <quote>Fund</quote> means the Catastrophe Preparedness Fund established
			 under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Homeowners and Taxpayers Protection Act of 2013/s:102/ss:g" proposed="true">section 102(g)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HA63A356C0C0643C08C31ED3C8D7D5B59">
        <enum>(7)</enum>
        <header>Insured
			 loss</header>
        <text>The term <quote>insured loss</quote> means any loss and
			 associated loss adjustment expense insured or reinsured by an eligible State
			 plan.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HE3FE72AA366E466C9C83B0EED1BF8967">
        <enum>(8)</enum>
        <header>Liquidity
			 loan</header>
        <text>The term <quote>liquidity loan</quote> means a loan to an
			 eligible State plan made under section 103.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HEE67E01FC4304E5FA96DE64388764328">
        <enum>(9)</enum>
        <header>Multi-state
			 plan</header>
        <text>The term <quote>multi-State plan</quote> means a State plan
			 described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Homeowners and Taxpayers Protection Act of 2013/s:3/p:13/sp:A/cl:ii" proposed="true">paragraph (13)(A)(ii) of this section</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H85FB94D98E2D463492B475AE2FCDDCE3">
        <enum>(10)</enum>
        <header>Qualified
			 entity</header>
        <text>The term <quote>qualified entity</quote> means a private
			 market reinsurer or other private sector entity that has satisfied the criteria
			 established by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> to be treated as a qualified entity for the
			 purposes of <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Homeowners and Taxpayers Protection Act of 2013/s:102/ss:e" proposed="true">section 102(e)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HB35C642A735D469EB61487417B3B8116">
        <enum>(11)</enum>
        <header>Secretary</header>
        <text>The
			 term <quote>Secretary</quote> means the Secretary of the Treasury except as
			 specifically provided otherwise.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H8110A45B82654A8DA71040CE9C6D5738">
        <enum>(12)</enum>
        <header>State</header>
        <text>The
			 term <quote>State</quote> includes the several States of the United States, the
			 District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, Guam, the Commonwealth
			 of the Northern Mariana Islands, the United States Virgin Islands, and American
			 Samoa, and any other territory or possession of the United States.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H4466D435B2D5499FA7C3624D431F20CE">
        <enum>(13)</enum>
        <header>State
			 plan</header>
        <text>The term <quote>State plan</quote> means a plan that—</text>
				<subparagraph id="H2995C27EDDDB47749D384EA6AF250669">
          <enum>(A)</enum>
          <text>is created or
			 administered by—</text>
					<clause id="H5FA1585755BE46A2902CCABDFDD908E4">
            <enum>(i)</enum>
            <text>a
			 single State; or</text>
					</clause>
          <clause id="HDF02A9B13BA748EF9735B1522901B503">
            <enum>(ii)</enum>
            <text>two
			 or more States; and</text>
					</clause>
        </subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="HE9527A5C9164401FB77A8EBED6F49057">
          <enum>(B)</enum>
          <text>provides insurance
			 or reinsurance protection to address natural catastrophe preparedness and
			 protection, and in the case of a plan described in subparagraph (A)(ii),
			 provides such protection as part of a program covering multiple States.</text>
				</subparagraph>
      </paragraph>
    </section>
    <title id="H57B6AA2C02FB4F8BAA49951712606921">
      <enum>I</enum>
      <header>TAXPAYER
			 PROTECTION, PRE-FUNDED CATASTROPHE RECOVERY, AND MARKET STABILIZATION</header>
			<section id="H527990DC90AE486BA5F88CF73DF590DF">
        <enum>101.</enum>
        <header>National
			 Commission on Natural Catastrophe Preparation and Protection</header>
				<subsection id="H256A2EAAA646491B95EF049101E28DEA">
          <enum>(a)</enum>
          <header>Establishment</header>
          <text>To
			 effectuate a stronger public-private partnership at the local, State, and
			 national levels regarding natural catastrophe preparation and protection, the
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary of the Treasury</cato:entity-ref>, in consultation with the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7000">Secretary of Homeland
			 Security</cato:entity-ref>, shall establish a commission to be known as the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="National Commission on Natural Catastrophe Preparation and Protection" proposed="true">National Commission
			 on Natural Catastrophe Preparation and Protection</cato:entity-ref> (in this title referred to as
			 the <quote>Commission</quote>).</text>
				</subsection>
        <subsection id="HF8D20BBD12244A89B1E2E8BC4CB39C87">
          <enum>(b)</enum>
          <header>Duties</header>
          <text>The
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="National Commission on Natural Catastrophe Preparation and Protection" proposed="true">Commission</cato:entity-ref> shall meet for the purpose of advising the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> regarding the
			 estimated loss costs associated with the contracts for reinsurance protection
			 made available under this title and carrying out the functions specified in
			 this Act, including—</text>
					<paragraph id="HD889FAC9914A4264B3BBA2E1A3C4A689">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <text>the development
			 and implementation of public education concerning the risks posed by natural
			 catastrophes;</text>
					</paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H390384440CA147A6B9B737415C456C76">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <text>the establishment
			 of a research priority for the development and implementation of prevention,
			 mitigation, recovery, and rebuilding strategies, that better prepare and
			 protect the United States from natural catastrophes;</text>
					</paragraph>
          <paragraph id="HF712CC797C6042338FC0986D752539F4">
            <enum>(3)</enum>
            <text>the establishment
			 of a process for members of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="National Commission on Natural Catastrophe Preparation and Protection" proposed="true">Commission</cato:entity-ref> to deploy following every major
			 catastrophe to inspect and evaluate the handling of such catastrophes;</text>
					</paragraph>
          <paragraph id="HC08CE1B25B5A428DBBBF38FA3BF3F2CF">
            <enum>(4)</enum>
            <text>conducting
			 continuous analysis of the effectiveness of this Act and recommending
			 improvements to the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> so that the costs of providing natural catastrophe
			 protection are decreased and so that the United States is better prepared;
			 and</text>
					</paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H0E625FB33F23476D9C997E0AA2A6B7E2">
            <enum>(5)</enum>
            <text>ensuring that the
			 programs under this title are operated in a financially prudent manner and on
			 an actuarially sound basis consistent with the provisions of this title and is
			 not dependent on subsidy from taxpayers or consumers in areas that do not
			 reside in areas that have a high-risk to natural catastrophe loss, including by
			 monitoring the expenditure of funds for administrative purposes to promote
			 efficiency and economy in the operation and administration of the program and
			 to minimize the cost for participating States.</text>
					</paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="H6414EBB8D19B429E911DCE12F4C66437">
          <enum>(c)</enum>
          <header>Members</header>
          <text>The
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="National Commission on Natural Catastrophe Preparation and Protection" proposed="true">Commission</cato:entity-ref> shall consist of 14 members, as follows:</text>
					<paragraph id="HFC80A459DD1946DAA314A62D0A5DEF62">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <header>Homeland
			 security member</header>
            <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7000">Secretary of Homeland Security</cato:entity-ref> or the
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-parent-id="7000">Secretary’s designee</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
					</paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H8B9B31A2ED5A45709746D1B9D5B96187">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <header>Appointed
			 members</header>
            <text>13 members appointed by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary of the Treasury</cato:entity-ref>,
			 who shall consist of—</text>
						<subparagraph id="HB65ECA47B10E415DABA83E20FFC3EECC">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Federal Insurance Office" entity-parent-id="2000">Director of
			 the Federal Insurance Office of the Department of the Treasury</cato:entity-ref>, or the
			 Director’s designee;</text>
						</subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H5F3AC2A7B74E41C4A88D9EEAAEF95AA4">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>a member of a
			 State legislature who can provide the perspective of State government;</text>
						</subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="HB791A0A9613349EAA84567F084FABC38">
              <enum>(C)</enum>
              <text>one individual who
			 is an actuary;</text>
						</subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="HA0724164698F45EC8CFCD7ED895DAFFB">
              <enum>(D)</enum>
              <text>one individual who
			 is employed in engineering;</text>
						</subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H73CD0BD6727F4E009B59D8A6CC101C47">
              <enum>(E)</enum>
              <text>one individual
			 representing the scientific community;</text>
						</subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="HECDAA0AEA2A140BFB7090336AE88D166">
              <enum>(F)</enum>
              <text>one individual
			 representing property and casualty insurers;</text>
						</subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H309BEF8E63A348E6B72D0F7B3AD6107C">
              <enum>(G)</enum>
              <text>one individual
			 representing reinsurers;</text>
						</subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H6E54B6B11697471C8BF026DA631C4C4A">
              <enum>(H)</enum>
              <text>one individual who
			 is a member or former member of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="National Association of Insurance Commission">National Association of Insurance
			 Commissioners</cato:entity-ref>;</text>
						</subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H48DCEC77877D466998AEEFF090E3D65F">
              <enum>(I)</enum>
              <text>two individuals
			 who are consumers, including one consumer who is a homeowner who resides in an
			 area with relatively high exposure to natural catastrophe risk and one consumer
			 who resides in an area with relatively low exposure to natural catastrophe
			 risk;</text>
						</subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H1091E1738DA64F76853BD39D13BB0872">
              <enum>(J)</enum>
              <text>one individual who
			 is an emergency response expert;</text>
						</subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H647349060A3D401E9B02B4258EC874FD">
              <enum>(K)</enum>
              <text>one individual
			 with expertise regarding capital markets; and</text>
						</subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="HB550B6C86FD24443AE67F24850CD3D22">
              <enum>(L)</enum>
              <text>one individual
			 representing the residential construction community.</text>
						</subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="H572D3B681BFC46E89997C75A5AEE6FA6">
          <enum>(d)</enum>
          <header>Treatment of
			 non-Federal members</header>
          <text>Each member of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="National Commission on Natural Catastrophe Preparation and Protection" proposed="true">Commission</cato:entity-ref> who is not
			 otherwise employed by the Federal Government shall be considered a special
			 Government employee for purposes of <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc/18/202, 208">sections 202 and 208 of title 18, United
			 States Code</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
				</subsection>
        <subsection id="H72E19EF193BE4E21BAD3B3FB68ECEC18">
          <enum>(e)</enum>
          <header>Experts and
			 consultants</header>
          <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="National Commission on Natural Catastrophe Preparation and Protection" proposed="true">Commission</cato:entity-ref> may procure temporary and intermittent
			 services from individuals or groups recognized as experts in the fields of
			 actuarial science, meteorology, seismology, vulcanology, geology, structural
			 engineering, wind engineering, seismic engineering and hydrology, emergency
			 response, and other fields, under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc/5/3109/b">
              <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/5/3109">section 3109(b)</external-xref> of title 5, United States
			 Code</cato:entity-ref>, but at rates not in excess of the daily equivalent of the annual rate of
			 basic pay payable for level V of the Executive Schedule, for each day during
			 which the individual procured is performing such services for the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="National Commission on Natural Catastrophe Preparation and Protection" proposed="true">Commission</cato:entity-ref>.
			 The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="National Commission on Natural Catastrophe Preparation and Protection" proposed="true">Commission</cato:entity-ref> may also procure, and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> encourages the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="National Commission on Natural Catastrophe Preparation and Protection" proposed="true">Commission</cato:entity-ref> to
			 procure, experts from universities, research centers, foundations, and other
			 appropriate organizations that could study, research, and develop methods and
			 mechanisms that could be utilized to strengthen structures to better withstand
			 the events covered by this Act.</text>
				</subsection>
        <subsection id="H093D810C56814BF3B7C1D14F0BBAC764">
          <enum>(f)</enum>
          <header>Compensation</header>
          <text>Each
			 member of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="National Commission on Natural Catastrophe Preparation and Protection" proposed="true">Commission</cato:entity-ref> who is not an officer or employee of the Federal
			 Government shall be compensated at a rate of basic pay payable for level V of
			 the Executive Schedule, for each day (including travel time) during which such
			 member is engaged in the performance of the duties of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="National Commission on Natural Catastrophe Preparation and Protection" proposed="true">Commission</cato:entity-ref>. All
			 members of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="National Commission on Natural Catastrophe Preparation and Protection" proposed="true">Commission</cato:entity-ref> who are officers or employees of the United States
			 shall serve without compensation in addition to that received for their
			 services as officers or employees of the United States.</text>
				</subsection>
        <subsection id="H8D6233D9B1744F2897AC646FB256A394">
          <enum>(g)</enum>
          <header>Obtaining
			 data</header>
					<paragraph id="HCA47C80AB4A64A90963C294A3A010FA1">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <header>Authority</header>
            <text>The
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="National Commission on Natural Catastrophe Preparation and Protection" proposed="true">Commission</cato:entity-ref> and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> may solicit loss and exposure data and such other
			 information that they deem necessary to carry out their responsibilities under
			 this Act from eligible State plans, other governmental agencies, and bodies and
			 organizations that act as statistical agents for the insurance industry. The
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="National Commission on Natural Catastrophe Preparation and Protection" proposed="true">Commission</cato:entity-ref> and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall take such actions as are necessary to ensure
			 that confidential or proprietary information is disclosed only to authorized
			 individuals working for the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="National Commission on Natural Catastrophe Preparation and Protection" proposed="true">Commission</cato:entity-ref> or the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
					</paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H940FD4B2B96C49CC9B7B00ABC145A82F">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <header>Confidentiality</header>
						<subparagraph id="H1C131D3275B5494FB9270F830C158E9F">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <header>In
			 general</header>
              <text>Information obtained by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="National Commission on Natural Catastrophe Preparation and Protection" proposed="true">Commission</cato:entity-ref> and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary</cato:entity-ref>
			 pursuant to this Act with reference to which a request for confidential
			 treatment is made by the person furnishing such information—</text>
							<clause id="H76793E47A0504191B3D579185C5FCEC5">
                <enum>(i)</enum>
                <text>shall be exempt
			 from disclosure under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/5/552">section 552</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code; and</text>
							</clause>
              <clause id="HE9BDCBCF18DD4810AB0F8ECE4FA51DC4">
                <enum>(ii)</enum>
                <text>shall not be
			 published or disclosed.</text>
							</clause>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H7B0230B51D4A4628989E958D8188B1FC">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <header>Exception</header>
              <text>
                <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Homeowners and Taxpayers Protection Act of 2013/s:101/ss:g/p:2/sp:A" proposed="true">Subparagraph
			 (A)</cato:entity-ref> shall not apply with respect to the publication or disclosure of any data
			 aggregated in a manner that ensures protection of the identity of the person
			 furnishing such data.</text>
						</subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="H38BB40D12089460B8D2A28581E7AD1DE">
          <enum>(h)</enum>
          <header>Authorization of
			 appropriations</header>
          <text>
            <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="auth-auth-approp">There is authorized to be appropriated—</cato:entity>
          </text>
					<paragraph id="H5644A995C2264B5CBC66F860BC5D2ABE">
            <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="auth-auth-approp">
              <enum>(1)</enum>
            <text>
                <cato:funds-and-year amount="10000000" year="2013">$10,000,000 for
			 fiscal year 2013</cato:funds-and-year> <cato:property name="purpose">for the initial expenses in establishing the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" value="National Commission on Natural Catastrophe Preparation and Protection" proposed="true">Commission</cato:entity-ref> and
			 the initial activities of the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" value="National Commission on Natural Catastrophe Preparation and Protection" proposed="true">Commission</cato:entity-ref> during such fiscal year that cannot
			 timely be covered by amounts that are deposited in the Fund pursuant to <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Homeowners and Taxpayers Protection Act of 2013/s:102/ss:e/p:5/sp:D" proposed="true">section
			 102(e)(5)(D)</cato:entity-ref>
                </cato:property>; and</text>
            </cato:entity>
					</paragraph>
          <paragraph id="HF2FA80040D3444EC966C68D560E9AD2D">
            <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="auth-auth-approp">
              <enum>(2)</enum>
            <text>for <cato:funds-and-year amount="indefinite" year="2014,..">fiscal year
			 2014 and each fiscal year thereafter, such sums as may be necessary</cato:funds-and-year> <cato:property name="purpose">to carry
			 out the activities of the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" value="National Commission on Natural Catastrophe Preparation and Protection" proposed="true">Commission</cato:entity-ref> during each such fiscal year that cannot
			 timely be covered by amounts that are deposited in the Fund pursuant to <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Homeowners and Taxpayers Protection Act of 2013/s:102/ss:e/p:5/sp:D" proposed="true">section
			 102(e)(5)(D)</cato:entity-ref>
                </cato:property>.</text>
            </cato:entity>
					</paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="HE910FC4B1C3940C1A9FF7697CE493D4C">
          <enum>(i)</enum>
          <header>Termination</header>
          <text>The
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="National Commission on Natural Catastrophe Preparation and Protection" proposed="true">Commission</cato:entity-ref> shall terminate upon the date specified in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Homeowners and Taxpayers Protection Act of 2013/s:104/ss:c" proposed="true">section 104(c)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
				</subsection>
      </section>
      <section id="HA77E39C508E54093BB2F51E9643EB39F">
        <enum>102.</enum>
        <header>Pre-funded and
			 privately financed catastrophe recovery program</header>
				<subsection id="H16747C6FF8C9472EAB1D4A4D40198542">
          <enum>(a)</enum>
          <header>Program
			 authority</header>
					<paragraph id="HF0B736082EFB40A19A65E4977AC5D983">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <header>In
			 general</header>
            <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary of the Treasury</cato:entity-ref>, in consultation with the
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7000">Secretary of Homeland Security</cato:entity-ref>, shall carry out a program under this section
			 that utilizes premiums from eligible State plans to provide additional capacity
			 and stability in the homeowners insurance market and improve the availability
			 and affordability of homeowners protection coverage to pre-fund future natural
			 catastrophe recovery by making available for purchase, only by eligible State
			 plans, contracts for reinsurance coverage under this section.</text>
					</paragraph>
          <paragraph id="HD0B108F9137B49B3AE0C9B39D76A1CEF">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <header>Purpose</header>
            <text>The
			 program shall make available privately funded reinsurance coverage under this
			 section—</text>
						<subparagraph id="HA301BCD8FC024A7494D718E9A5E1AD18">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>to diversify and
			 spread risk more efficiently and leverage the economies of pooling reinsurance
			 arrangements from different geographical areas of the country covering the
			 events specified in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Homeowners and Taxpayers Protection Act of 2013/s:102/ss:c" proposed="true">subsection (c)</cato:entity-ref>;</text>
						</subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H34333DBEFAC74C9BAABC4A98D4E0CA90">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>to generate
			 additional capacity and provide stability to the homeowners insurance market by
			 encouraging States to develop or expand plans that address current market
			 challenges and assist homeowners in securing needed protection;</text>
						</subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="HF7828CADAB48476D8C30963A3D563F3E">
              <enum>(C)</enum>
              <text>to improve the
			 availability and affordability of homeowners insurance for the purpose of
			 privately financing post-catastrophe recovery by facilitating the pooling and
			 spreading the risk of catastrophic financial losses from natural
			 catastrophes;</text>
						</subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H462BEBB81F3948FC8ABB55D846031B7B">
              <enum>(D)</enum>
              <text>to improve the
			 solvency, capacity, and stability of homeowners insurance markets, supplement
			 private market reinsurance, and increase the spread of risk;</text>
						</subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H6A3AFA7E531F4310AF0A9FE3D195D4B0">
              <enum>(E)</enum>
              <text>to encourage the
			 development and implementation of mitigation, prevention, recovery, and
			 rebuilding strategies to reduce future catastrophe losses; and</text>
						</subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H75D14E23A1B64F4FB6DBDC389CBE5477">
              <enum>(F)</enum>
              <text>to recommend
			 methods to continuously improve the way the United States prepares for, reacts
			 to, and responds to catastrophes, including improvements to the Catastrophe
			 Preparedness Fund established under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Homeowners and Taxpayers Protection Act of 2013/s:102/ss:g" proposed="true">section 102(g)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
						</subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H6C1C99CD638249158029FCE941CB7733">
            <enum>(3)</enum>
            <header>Contract
			 principles</header>
            <text>Under the program under this section, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary</cato:entity-ref>
			 shall offer reinsurance coverage through contracts with eligible State plans,
			 which contracts shall—</text>
						<subparagraph id="H7F6F23048AAE43E8AAB0624762727CDD">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>be priced on an
			 actuarially sound basis as specified in this section; and</text>
						</subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H1A16DDC8750B41809CC11550EE14E514">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>provide coverage
			 based solely on insured losses within the State or States participating in the
			 eligible State plan purchasing the contract.</text>
						</subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="HB6CB5198C9894C50A60A10E435BCFC45">
          <enum>(b)</enum>
          <header>Qualified lines
			 of coverage</header>
          <text>Each contract for reinsurance coverage made available
			 under this section shall provide coverage for insured property losses covered
			 under primary insurance contracts to homeowners, mobile home owners, renters,
			 and condominium owners for covered events. Nothing in this Act shall be
			 interpreted to expand the terms, conditions, or scope of coverage or events
			 covered under insurance policies issued by insurers or eligible State
			 plans.</text>
				</subsection>
        <subsection id="H75DBFE9825DD433BBD8B514CA4AB2892">
          <enum>(c)</enum>
          <header>Covered
			 events</header>
					<paragraph id="H5174745BCB524F258A9AE72004FD8514">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <header>In
			 general</header>
            <text>Each contract for reinsurance coverage made available
			 under this section shall cover losses insured or reinsured by the eligible
			 State plan purchasing the contract that are proximately caused by—</text>
						<subparagraph id="HA9C0FB4290964285A3EFA633C49564D1">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>earthquakes;</text>
						</subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H7C8999273D8A4ABFAC96A680C39077F8">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>events ensuing
			 from earthquakes, including fire and tsunami-related flood;</text>
						</subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="HD0DD9532219D4550853D581B5EFC902B">
              <enum>(C)</enum>
              <text>catastrophic
			 wildfires unrelated to earthquakes;</text>
						</subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H79D55622AF9843BB84ADEC82511B34EF">
              <enum>(D)</enum>
              <text>tropical cyclones
			 having maximum sustained winds of at least 74 miles per hour, including
			 hurricanes and typhoons;</text>
						</subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H311EA33EC69045C7AFC44BC822557780">
              <enum>(E)</enum>
              <text>tornadoes;</text>
						</subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="HB3F594E840CE45D0A19DECFDD17A7DF5">
              <enum>(F)</enum>
              <text>volcanic
			 eruptions;</text>
						</subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H43C4A2950EB749BB91D7B89E6D1CAAA8">
              <enum>(G)</enum>
              <text>catastrophic
			 winter storms; and</text>
						</subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="HAD3918D3734A4777A6CABE94438CF92B">
              <enum>(H)</enum>
              <text>any other natural
			 catastrophe insured or reinsured under the eligible State plan purchasing the
			 contract.</text>
						</subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H977864C32F6A4A3FB1599C120AB4DECD">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <header>Definitions</header>
            <text>The
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall, by regulation, define the natural catastrophe events
			 identified under this subsection.</text>
					</paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="H8239374813734B5C81D390F7BF4244AA">
          <enum>(d)</enum>
          <header>Eligible state
			 plans</header>
          <text>A State plan shall be an eligible State plan for purposes
			 of this section only if the State plan meets all of the following
			 requirements:</text>
					<paragraph id="HDA717D8CC43A4B108FD2E8C3E8140374">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <header>Program
			 design</header>
            <text>The entity for the covered State or States that is
			 authorized to make such determinations certifies to the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> that the
			 State plan is a program, established by the covered State or States, that
			 provides—</text>
						<subparagraph id="HD40A7F0332824D88BFCC3B4CFA2D07BA">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>insurance coverage
			 for insured property losses covered under primary insurance contracts for
			 residential property located in any covered State; or</text>
						</subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="HD584FE01B42A4B02B7C93D5D549CF380">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>reinsurance
			 coverage that is designed to improve availability or affordability, or both, in
			 the private insurance markets that offers coverage for insured property losses
			 covered under primary insurance contracts for residential property located in
			 any covered State.</text>
						</subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="HF24859FBF20746DBAA548DFB2B227E87">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <header>Operation</header>
            <text>The
			 entity for the covered State or States that is authorized to make such
			 determinations certifies to the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> that the State plan complies with the
			 following requirements:</text>
						<subparagraph id="H923CC1361C8D4ED3BA989A52C199DF08">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <header>Establishment;
			 governing body</header>
              <text>The State plan shall be established by the covered
			 State or States and a majority of the members of the governing body of the
			 State plan shall be public officials or appointed by public officials.</text>
						</subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H0CD1C5BD00DC4552BA5F606016AB1766">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <header>Repayment</header>
              <text>If
			 any covered State has at any time appropriated amounts from the fund of the
			 State plan for any purpose other than payments made in connection with the
			 activities authorized under the State plan, the State shall have repaid such
			 amounts to the State fund, together with interest on such amounts.</text>
						</subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H859A300C4563478DAC613C8AA435C1B0">
              <enum>(C)</enum>
              <header>Nondiscrimination
			 in coverage</header>
              <text>Insurance or reinsurance coverage, as applicable,
			 provided under the eligible State plan shall be made available on a
			 nondiscriminatory basis to all qualifying residents of any covered
			 State.</text>
						</subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H0FCDC2EC3A6C448C892DB19EBB1DDB0A">
              <enum>(D)</enum>
              <header>Prohibition of
			 cross-subsidization</header>
              <text>The State plan may not, except for charges or
			 assessments related to post-event financing or bonding, involve
			 cross-subsidization between any separate property and casualty lines covered
			 under the plan.</text>
						</subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="HE9D8C9E988C44FC5A4CA6535F53B0D66">
              <enum>(E)</enum>
              <header>Reinsurance
			 premiums</header>
              <text>In the case of State plans providing reinsurance
			 coverage, the plan or the law in effect in each covered State shall require
			 that to the extent that reinsurance coverage made available under the program
			 under this section results in cost savings in providing insurance coverage for
			 risks in such State, such cost savings be reflected in premium rates charged to
			 consumers for such coverage.</text>
						</subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H6BEBB6D63D904CD5BF65C10CF4713A51">
              <enum>(F)</enum>
              <header>Termination</header>
              <text>The
			 State plan shall include provisions that authorize the entity for the covered
			 State or States that is authorized to make such a determination to terminate
			 the State plan or, in the case of a multi-State plan, membership in such Plan,
			 if such entity determines that the State plan is no longer necessary to ensure
			 the availability or affordability of residential property insurance for all
			 residents of any covered State.</text>
						</subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H780FDC3A0CB942C694CB38EA90E02ECE">
              <enum>(G)</enum>
              <header>Actuarial
			 soundness</header>
              <text>The State plan shall have actuarially sound
			 rates.</text>
						</subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H8E651A4DCB584369B7CCB7A1AC592721">
            <enum>(3)</enum>
            <header>Treatment of
			 earnings</header>
            <text>The entity for the covered State or States that is
			 authorized to make such determinations certifies to the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> that the
			 State plan does not provide for redistribution of any part of any net profits
			 under the State plan to any insurer that participates in the State plan.</text>
					</paragraph>
          <paragraph id="HD4245D71D45C45609D0FF7C72BA2394B">
            <enum>(4)</enum>
            <header>Support for
			 mitigation and prevention</header>
						<subparagraph id="H5FEA33B21625404FAC2529387C13536C">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <header>Requirements</header>
              <text>Except
			 as provided in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Homeowners and Taxpayers Protection Act of 2013/s:102/ss:d/p:4/sp:B" proposed="true">subparagraph (B)</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> determines that, for any year
			 for which the coverage is in effect, the provision of reinsurance coverage
			 under the program under this section to the State plan supports mitigation and
			 prevention of risk associated with covered events and that the State plan meets
			 all of the following requirements:</text>
							<clause id="H596B539498554AF58933EC45ED311DF0">
                <enum>(i)</enum>
                <header>Building
			 codes</header>
                <text>Each covered State has in effect, or appropriate local
			 governments within each covered State have in effect, and enforce building
			 codes and standards that offer risk responsive resistance to earthquakes or
			 high winds.</text>
							</clause>
              <clause id="H9C7C36C81FDF4B4EAE9683D3338AD374">
                <enum>(ii)</enum>
                <header>Mitigation</header>
                <text>Each
			 covered State has taken actions to mitigate losses caused by natural
			 catastrophes.</text>
							</clause>
              <clause id="HE7B635ADC0854851A24BEBDACDC668CF">
                <enum>(iii)</enum>
                <header>Prohibition of
			 price gouging</header>
                <text>Each covered State has in effect laws or
			 regulations sufficient to prohibit price gouging, during the term of
			 reinsurance coverage provided under the program under this section for the
			 State plan in any catastrophe area located within the covered State.</text>
							</clause>
              <clause id="H0C8A937358564C08AE7D26D18B7393B0">
                <enum>(iv)</enum>
                <header>Homeowners
			 insurance rates</header>
                <text>For any covered State that has in effect laws
			 that require insurers providing homeowners insurance to file their rates for
			 review or regulatory approval, the covered State has confirmed that homeowners
			 insurance rates associated with catastrophe coverage for covered events are
			 actuarially sound.</text>
							</clause>
              <clause id="HF9125E5BCDA2450C9C7C4C18B46819A5">
                <enum>(v)</enum>
                <header>Land use and
			 zoning plans</header>
                <text>Each covered State, to the extent feasible, shall
			 encourage State and local government units to develop, comprehensive land use
			 and zoning plans that are designed to limit additional natural hazard exposure
			 and promote natural hazard mitigation.</text>
							</clause>
              <clause id="H8DCA56F65C394164B08B66DA4520AA9D">
                <enum>(vi)</enum>
                <header>Emergency
			 preparedness actions</header>
                <text>Each covered State, in consultation and
			 cooperation with localities in the State, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7022">Administrator of the Federal
			 Emergency Management Agency</cato:entity-ref>, and other appropriate agencies and organizations,
			 shall have taken actions to continuously improve emergency preparedness.</text>
							</clause>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H29AA0FC400294AC4BEC636AE0C926FC7">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <header>Transition
			 period</header>
              <text>To provide sufficient time for adoption of the provisions
			 of this subsection and to support implementation of prevention and mitigation
			 measures set forth in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Homeowners and Taxpayers Protection Act of 2013/s:102/ss:d/p:4/sp:A" proposed="true">subparagraph (A) of this paragraph</cato:entity-ref>, during the 5-year
			 period that begins on the date of the enactment of this Act, a State plan shall
			 not be precluded from qualifying as an eligible State plan because the
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> is unable to make any of the determinations required under
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Homeowners and Taxpayers Protection Act of 2013/s:102/ss:d/p:4/sp:A" proposed="true">subparagraph (A)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
						</subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="HBD842C81B2294AA7B1D605BD5AEA0D93">
          <enum>(e)</enum>
          <header>Terms of
			 reinsurance contracts</header>
          <text>Each contract for reinsurance coverage
			 under this section shall be subject to the following terms and
			 conditions:</text>
					<paragraph id="H3F0B332DDB244B1C9699F4A037578024">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <header>Maturity</header>
            <text>The
			 contract shall have a minimum term of 1 year or such longer duration as the
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> may determine.</text>
					</paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H8F09053B5B60401A924ADF6563FD2B9A">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <header>Payment
			 condition</header>
            <text>The contract shall authorize claims payments only for
			 eligible losses to the eligible State plan purchasing the coverage.</text>
					</paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H7C96412D1F374643BE715E9BB771ABC6">
            <enum>(3)</enum>
            <header>Retained losses
			 requirement</header>
            <text>For each covered event, the contract shall not
			 reimburse any losses until the total incurred covered losses exceeds the
			 applicable attachment point established pursuant to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Homeowners and Taxpayers Protection Act of 2013/s:102/ss:f/p:2" proposed="true">subsection (f)(2)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
					</paragraph>
          <paragraph id="HB484A79B102E458895BF20750DC4B5C4">
            <enum>(4)</enum>
            <header>Multiple
			 events</header>
            <text>The contract shall cover any eligible losses from one or
			 more covered events that may occur during the term of the contract and shall
			 provide that if multiple events occur, the retained losses requirement under
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Homeowners and Taxpayers Protection Act of 2013/s:102/ss:f" proposed="true">paragraph (f)</cato:entity-ref> shall apply in the aggregate and not separately to each
			 individual event.</text>
					</paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H94E8BCC3D4DA4A57878D0C8759A1D272">
            <enum>(5)</enum>
            <header>Pricing</header>
            <text>The
			 price of reinsurance coverage under the contract shall be an amount established
			 by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> as follows:</text>
						<subparagraph id="HFE1DD011EA944FD9B31E8A0768BC5EC6">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <header>Recommendations</header>
              <text>The
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall take into consideration the recommendations of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="National Commission on Natural Catastrophe Preparation and Protection" proposed="true">Commission</cato:entity-ref>
			 in establishing the price, but the price may not be less than the amount
			 recommended by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="National Commission on Natural Catastrophe Preparation and Protection" proposed="true">Commission</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
						</subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H0D631E5C06EB4492B261F41BDEBF20E9">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <header>Fairness to
			 taxpayers</header>
              <text>The price shall be established at an actuarially sound
			 level that protects taxpayers from liability and takes into consideration
			 models that estimate losses from covered events.</text>
						</subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="HFF445C2C38FA4726AB3AD5B612A4733D">
              <enum>(C)</enum>
              <header>Self-sufficiency</header>
              <text>The
			 rates for reinsurance coverage for an eligible State plan shall be established
			 at an actuarially sound level that produces expected premiums sufficient to
			 pay—</text>
							<clause id="H66B9B001338B43F195E72018D9D0B757">
                <enum>(i)</enum>
                <text>the
			 expected annualized cost of all claims;</text>
							</clause>
              <clause id="H4445D61C5F884525B7A67CDAF318BFAF">
                <enum>(ii)</enum>
                <text>loss adjustment
			 expenses;</text>
							</clause>
              <clause id="H6922468AD0AA4C0FA80F7E13468AE978">
                <enum>(iii)</enum>
                <text>the cost of
			 funding emergency preparedness and mitigation efforts; and</text>
							</clause>
              <clause id="HE14C21466C9B4E59854C14BADA75A551">
                <enum>(iv)</enum>
                <text>the
			 costs of operating the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="National Commission on Natural Catastrophe Preparation and Protection" proposed="true">Commission</cato:entity-ref> and all administrative costs of reinsurance
			 coverage offered under this subsection.</text>
							</clause>
              <continuation-text continuation-text-level="subparagraph">The
			 expected annualized cost of all claims shall be comparable to amounts being
			 included in the price for similar layers of coverage in the private sector,
			 taking into account the savings associated with the funding mechanisms and the
			 non-profit and tax-exempt status of the Fund.</continuation-text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="HB3D37D47E2F443E5B1F6D7A6EE954FAB">
              <enum>(D)</enum>
              <header>Offset</header>
              <text>The
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall ensure, to the maximum extent practicable, that in each fiscal
			 year an amount equal to any amount appropriated pursuant to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Homeowners and Taxpayers Protection Act of 2013/s:101/ss:h" proposed="true">section 101(h)</cato:entity-ref> for
			 such fiscal year is obtained from purchasers of reinsurance coverage under this
			 section by incorporating the costs described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Homeowners and Taxpayers Protection Act of 2013/s:102/ss:e/p:5/sp:C/cl:iv" proposed="true">subparagraph (C)(iv)</cato:entity-ref> of this
			 paragraph into the pricing of the contracts for such coverage.</text>
						</subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H401720906C41453FAFD4A812BD82F777">
            <enum>(6)</enum>
            <header>Taxpayer
			 protection, rapid cash build-up, and post-event pricing adjustments</header>
						<subparagraph id="H2FC538615BE442278183E4BEB63C2BCA">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <header>First 5
			 years</header>
              <text>Notwithstanding any other provision of this section, during
			 the first five years of the program under this section, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall
			 increase the price that is charged for reinsurance coverage provided under the
			 program under this section by at least five percent, or such higher amount as
			 the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> deems, above the actuarially sound price calculated under
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Homeowners and Taxpayers Protection Act of 2013/s:102/ss:e/p:5" proposed="true">paragraph (5)</cato:entity-ref>, to facilitate and accelerate the accumulation of reserves and to
			 support the creation of the readiness, preparedness, and mitigation grant
			 program under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Homeowners and Taxpayers Protection Act of 2013/s:201" proposed="true">section 201</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
						</subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="HEEA403605D7E4CDD8C6CDE78C58E8838">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <header>Post-event</header>
              <text>Notwithstanding
			 any other provision of this section, after any covered event triggering any
			 payment under a contract for reinsurance coverage that requires the Fund to
			 issue obligations under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Homeowners and Taxpayers Protection Act of 2013/s:102/ss:g/p:4" proposed="true">subsection (g)(4)</cato:entity-ref> to make such payment and to provide
			 additional taxpayer protection and ensure that the program under this section
			 is fully funded on an ongoing basis, the Secretary shall require the inclusion
			 of an additional amount in the price that is charged for reinsurance coverage
			 provided under the program equal to at least five percent of the actuarially
			 sound price calculated under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Homeowners and Taxpayers Protection Act of 2013/s:102/ss:g/p:5" proposed="true">paragraph (5)</cato:entity-ref> to ensure that the program collects
			 all revenue necessary—</text>
							<clause id="H3E4ABD0A29E64766985271809E1C4ED8">
                <enum>(i)</enum>
                <text>to
			 provide the reinsurance coverage authorized under this section;</text>
							</clause>
              <clause id="H3BCF9A93A929426684BEBDB48A7EACEA">
                <enum>(ii)</enum>
                <text>to
			 administer the program under this section, and</text>
							</clause>
              <clause id="HCA17B0F199894B859B9ABD24BCC9AE26">
                <enum>(iii)</enum>
                <text>to
			 account for any losses paid with funds acquired from obligations issued under
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Homeowners and Taxpayers Protection Act of 2013/s:102/ss:g/p:4" proposed="true">subsection (g)(4)</cato:entity-ref> during a period having a duration not longer than five years,
			 if feasible.</text>
							</clause>
              <continuation-text continuation-text-level="subparagraph">Any such
			 obligations issued under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Homeowners and Taxpayers Protection Act of 2013/s:102/ss:g/p:4" proposed="true">subsection (g)(4)</cato:entity-ref> shall be repaid in full from the
			 surcharges assessed under this paragraph.</continuation-text>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="HF327AA8690CD4D84A77192A07D0C37D4">
            <enum>(7)</enum>
            <header>Information</header>
            <text>The
			 contract shall contain a condition providing that the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="National Commission on Natural Catastrophe Preparation and Protection" proposed="true">Commission</cato:entity-ref> may require
			 the eligible State plan that is covered under the contract to submit to the
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="National Commission on Natural Catastrophe Preparation and Protection" proposed="true">Commission</cato:entity-ref> all information regarding the eligible State plan relevant to the
			 duties of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="National Commission on Natural Catastrophe Preparation and Protection" proposed="true">Commission</cato:entity-ref>, as determined by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
					</paragraph>
          <paragraph id="HC21D2CD163004781A46DB2E3D5C261E0">
            <enum>(8)</enum>
            <header>Additional
			 contract option</header>
            <text>The contract shall provide that the purchaser of
			 the contract may, during the term of such original contract, purchase
			 additional contracts from among those offered by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> at the beginning
			 of the term, subject to the limitations under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Homeowners and Taxpayers Protection Act of 2013/s:102/ss:f" proposed="true">subsection (f)</cato:entity-ref>, at the prices at
			 which such contracts were offered at the beginning of the term, prorated based
			 upon the remaining term as determined by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary</cato:entity-ref>. Such additional
			 contracts shall provide coverage beginning on a date 15 days after the date of
			 purchase, but shall not provide coverage for losses for an event that has
			 already occurred. Eligible State plans may arrange for prospective contracts
			 for planning purposes and to enhance stability and predictability in managing
			 risk and accounting for costs associated with risk transfer.</text>
					</paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H4F7D6D7A1E614DEC95A5949800347550">
            <enum>(9)</enum>
            <header>Other
			 terms</header>
            <text>The contract shall contain such other terms as the
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> considers necessary to carry out this Act and to ensure the long-term
			 financial integrity of the program under this section. The contract shall also
			 specify how payouts shall be administered if multiple events occur that affect
			 more than one eligible State plan.</text>
					</paragraph>
          <paragraph id="HE78AF1493BCD44ACB8C7A6D246879A33">
            <enum>(10)</enum>
            <header>Encouragement
			 for private sector to participate</header>
						<subparagraph id="H50E1B81B599C4758AB61F2C029CCDA3C">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <header>Establishment of
			 competitive procedure</header>
              <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> encourages private market
			 reinsurers and other private sector entities to participate in the program
			 under this section. Accordingly, the Secretary shall establish, by regulation,
			 a competitive procedure under this paragraph that provides qualified entities
			 an opportunity, on a basis consistent with the contract cycle established under
			 this section by the Secretary, to offer to provide, in lieu of reinsurance
			 coverage under this section, reinsurance coverage that is substantially similar
			 to coverage otherwise made available under this section.</text>
						</subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H3F2440FEA4744D6B90EE2582F055CC5D">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <header>Competitive
			 procedure</header>
              <text>Under the procedure established under this
			 paragraph—</text>
							<clause id="H549B37D484C04256A5D8A2CDB02EB7DA">
                <enum>(i)</enum>
                <text>the
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall establish criteria for private insurers, reinsurers, and
			 capital market companies, and consortia of such entities to be treated as
			 qualified entities for purposes of this paragraph, which criteria shall require
			 such an entity to have at all times capital sufficient to satisfy the terms of
			 the reinsurance contracts and shall include such other industry and credit
			 rating standards as the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> considers appropriate;</text>
							</clause>
              <clause id="HD784183F86EA431C8353826BCFE5A8C8">
                <enum>(ii)</enum>
                <text>not
			 less than 30 days before the beginning of each contract cycle during which any
			 reinsurance coverage under this section is to be made available, the Secretary
			 may request proposals and shall publish in the Federal Register the rates and
			 terms for contracts for coverage under this section that are to be made
			 available during such contract cycle;</text>
							</clause>
              <clause id="H923EE9551F804EAD9EBEF537F8FDE55B">
                <enum>(iii)</enum>
                <text>the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary</cato:entity-ref>
			 shall provide qualified entities a period of not less than 10 days (which shall
			 terminate not less than 20 days before the beginning of the contract cycle) to
			 submit to the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> a written expression of interest in providing
			 reinsurance coverage in lieu of the coverage otherwise to be made available
			 under this section;</text>
							</clause>
              <clause id="HC48A854DEDB44E6EA0A1DA3EEA27F2F5">
                <enum>(iv)</enum>
                <text>the
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall provide any qualified entity submitting an expression of
			 interest during the period referred to in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Homeowners and Taxpayers Protection Act of 2013/s:102/ss:e/p:10/sp:B/cl:iii" proposed="true">clause (iii)</cato:entity-ref> a period of not less
			 than 20 days (which shall terminate before the beginning of the contract cycle)
			 to submit to the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> an offer to provide, in lieu of the reinsurance
			 coverage otherwise to be made available under this section, coverage that is
			 substantially similar to such coverage;</text>
							</clause>
              <clause id="HDC2446D0B8934830BCE3BBF47F6FC0BD">
                <enum>(v)</enum>
                <text>if
			 the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> determines that an offer submitted during the period referred to
			 in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Homeowners and Taxpayers Protection Act of 2013/s:102/ss:e/p:10/sp:B/cl:iii" proposed="true">clause (iii)</cato:entity-ref> is a bona fide offer to provide reinsurance coverage during the
			 contract cycle at rates and terms that are substantially similar to the rates
			 and terms for reinsurance coverage otherwise to be provided under this section
			 by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall accept the offer (if still outstanding)
			 and, notwithstanding any other provision of this Act, provide for such entity
			 to make reinsurance coverage available in accordance with the offer; and</text>
							</clause>
              <clause id="H7EA6F0323CDD4C9983F11898FF3A841E">
                <enum>(vi)</enum>
                <text>if
			 the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> accepts an offer pursuant to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Homeowners and Taxpayers Protection Act of 2013/s:102/ss:e/p:10/sp:B/cl:v" proposed="true">clause (v)</cato:entity-ref> to make reinsurance
			 coverage available, notwithstanding any other provision of this Act, the
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall reduce, to an equivalent extent, the amount of reinsurance
			 coverage available under this section during the contract cycle to which the
			 offer relates, unless and until the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> determines that the entity is not
			 complying with the terms of the accepted offer.</text>
							</clause>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H6E6928580F1A4414BB4BAEE098E86842">
            <enum>(11)</enum>
            <header>Participation
			 by multi-state plans</header>
            <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> hereby explicitly encourages
			 States to create and maintain catastrophe funds for their States or with other
			 States, and nothing in this Act may be interpreted to prohibit or discourage
			 the creation of multi-State plans, or the participation by such plans in the
			 program established pursuant to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Homeowners and Taxpayers Protection Act of 2013/s:102/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref>. The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall, by
			 regulation, provide for the application of the provisions of this Act to
			 multi-State catastrophe insurance and reinsurance plans. The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="National Commission on Natural Catastrophe Preparation and Protection" proposed="true">Commission</cato:entity-ref> shall
			 develop a process to evaluate and encourage the creation of regional programs
			 and approaches to advance the purposes of this Act through the establishment of
			 multi-State plans.</text>
					</paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="HCB4A4970634446C4B424674A4AAE969C">
          <enum>(f)</enum>
          <header>Treatment of
			 insured losses and maximum federal liability</header>
					<paragraph id="H4CA3C031B12C43DDB7606E33BD4E6169">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <header>Available levels
			 of retained losses</header>
            <text>In making reinsurance coverage available under
			 this section, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall make available for purchase contracts for
			 such coverage that require the sustainment of retained losses from covered
			 events (as required under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Homeowners and Taxpayers Protection Act of 2013/s:102/ss:e/p:3" proposed="true">subsection (e)(3)</cato:entity-ref> for payment of eligible losses) in
			 various amounts, as the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary</cato:entity-ref>, in consultation with the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="National Commission on Natural Catastrophe Preparation and Protection" proposed="true">Commission</cato:entity-ref>,
			 determines appropriate and subject to the requirements under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Homeowners and Taxpayers Protection Act of 2013/s:102/ss:f/p:2" proposed="true">paragraph
			 (2)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
					</paragraph>
          <paragraph id="HA854B168961643FB829D8CAA3E6F648A">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <header>Standard
			 attachment point</header>
						<subparagraph id="H0F3D95F8106244AE9574F011F2C3ED7C">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <header>Establishment</header>
              <text>The
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary</cato:entity-ref>, in consultation with the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="National Commission on Natural Catastrophe Preparation and Protection" proposed="true">Commission</cato:entity-ref>, shall establish a standard
			 attachment point at which coverage is provided to eligible State plans for all
			 contracts.</text>
						</subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H53D028021E1444EB9F74FEDEDD0C650B">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <header>Considerations</header>
              <text>In
			 setting a standard attachment point, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="National Commission on Natural Catastrophe Preparation and Protection" proposed="true">Commission</cato:entity-ref> shall
			 take into consideration—</text>
							<clause id="HB1032A1951C64D0BB309AFABC6A1AF49">
                <enum>(i)</enum>
                <text>how
			 many and which eligible State plans are seeking contracts for reinsurance
			 coverage under this section;</text>
							</clause>
              <clause id="H824C4EE9BDFD472A8409740F2C2FC9A2">
                <enum>(ii)</enum>
                <text>the
			 capital and surplus positions of the eligible State plans;</text>
							</clause>
              <clause id="H6AECCA44A5204B73922A500F153B5644">
                <enum>(iii)</enum>
                <text>the coverage
			 preferences of eligible State plans;</text>
							</clause>
              <clause id="HD2BDEAB92B8349AD9D20FFDFA0AEB5DE">
                <enum>(iv)</enum>
                <text>the
			 availability and price of reinsurance in the private market;</text>
							</clause>
              <clause id="HEE0D7D3E86604EAFAA89C95E4B7E8E47">
                <enum>(v)</enum>
                <text>that
			 pooling reinsurance from different geographic locations and covering different
			 events is more efficient than stand-alone programs;</text>
							</clause>
              <clause id="H9CC3D7E4280D424F8A9E985E486417ED">
                <enum>(vi)</enum>
                <text>affordability of
			 homeowners insurance; and</text>
							</clause>
              <clause id="H33606C7C6B9C400AACC536643AF714A5">
                <enum>(vii)</enum>
                <text>other factors
			 deemed appropriate to operating a long-term national reinsurance backstop
			 program.</text>
							</clause>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H097F22D7BDF245CB918B6CC1AA607720">
              <enum>(C)</enum>
              <header>Use</header>
              <text>The
			 standard attachment point established pursuant to this paragraph shall be used
			 in establishing reinsurance contracts for each eligible State plan, unless the
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary</cato:entity-ref>, in consultation with the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="National Commission on Natural Catastrophe Preparation and Protection" proposed="true">Commission</cato:entity-ref>, determines that market
			 conditions or the financial position of an eligible State plan warrants a lower
			 attachment point in a contract for such eligible State plan in a given
			 year.</text>
						</subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H59F4B3F5039B41F4A023125D022E453F">
              <enum>(D)</enum>
              <header>Lower attachment
			 points</header>
              <text>If a reinsurance contract is contemplated for an eligible
			 State plan having an attachment point lower than the standard attachment point,
			 the cost of such contract shall include or otherwise take into account the
			 additional costs associated with such additional layer of protection.</text>
						</subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="HE6439C80D90C423AB71E1AA24890E770">
            <enum>(3)</enum>
            <header>Minimum level of
			 retained losses</header>
            <text>For each covered event, the minimum level of
			 retained losses shall be the amount of cash available to the eligible State
			 plan to pay covered losses.</text>
					</paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H28B8C2C8528949BB9E6442978103C10C">
            <enum>(4)</enum>
            <header>Ceiling coverage
			 level</header>
            <text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law and subject to
			 any limitations in future appropriations Acts, the aggregate potential
			 liability for payment of claims under all contracts for reinsurance coverage
			 sold under this title to any single eligible State plan during a 12-month
			 period shall not exceed the difference between—</text>
						<subparagraph id="H8B15E22FD80A453A92F8DFBAC5066B74">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>the amount equal
			 to the covered loss projected to be incurred once every 600 years from a single
			 event by the eligible State plan; and</text>
						</subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="HD7ED47900C594D5FACEBD4F2B3DBF6D3">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>the amount equal
			 to the cash available in the eligible State plan to pay covered losses.</text>
						</subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="H9A2957AF70864158B329F46E5179FBFF">
          <enum>(g)</enum>
          <header>Catastrophe
			 preparedness fund for pre-Funding preparedness and recovery</header>
					<paragraph id="HADC49EB279454369A790DB17976B313B">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <header>Establishment</header>
            <text>There
			 is established within the Treasury of the United States a fund to be known as
			 the <quote>Catastrophe Preparedness Fund</quote>.</text>
					</paragraph>
          <paragraph id="HCB63A55875B7476D85248A53F5D42F73">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <header>Credits</header>
            <text>The
			 Fund shall be credited with—</text>
						<subparagraph id="H10A7F49E2BBE45169488BE2B58CD73E5">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>amounts received
			 from the sale of contracts for reinsurance coverage under this section;</text>
						</subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H6BA3820C61C24BED8221BF77AD4FADB9">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>any amounts
			 borrowed under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Homeowners and Taxpayers Protection Act of 2013/s:102/ss:g/p:4" proposed="true">paragraph (4)</cato:entity-ref>;</text>
						</subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="HA6318718D38D419395BB2B5B9AABB0D4">
              <enum>(C)</enum>
              <text>any amounts earned
			 on investments of the Fund pursuant to paragraph (5); and</text>
						</subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H91EB53D77C3D4280822367EE72AA74BB">
              <enum>(D)</enum>
              <text>such other amounts
			 as may be credited to the Fund.</text>
						</subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H6310B46C8BFB40F692AC3A312A703A5C">
            <enum>(3)</enum>
            <header>Uses</header>
            <text>Amounts
			 in the Fund shall be available to the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> only for the following
			 purposes:</text>
						<subparagraph id="HBA3696C2A94C404B9F153CEB9D674636">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <header>Contract
			 payments</header>
              <text>For payments to covered purchasers under contracts for
			 reinsurance coverage under this section for eligible losses under such
			 contracts.</text>
						</subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H49128718A275454DB765E145E5D4C5BE">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <header>Commission
			 costs</header>
              <text>For the operating costs of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="National Commission on Natural Catastrophe Preparation and Protection" proposed="true">Commission</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
						</subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="HB840DA6973E54D9B806E0146018C90AF">
              <enum>(C)</enum>
              <header>Administrative
			 expenses</header>
              <text>For the administrative expenses incurred by the
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> in carrying out the reinsurance program under this Act.</text>
						</subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H6E80D25245894B44B201419A308535E4">
              <enum>(D)</enum>
              <header>Cost of national
			 readiness, preparedness, and mitigation committee</header>
              <text>For the
			 operating costs of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="National Readiness, Preparedness, and Mitigation Committee" proposed="true">National Readiness, Preparedness, and Mitigation
			 Committee</cato:entity-ref> established under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Homeowners and Taxpayers Protection Act of 2013/s:201" proposed="true">section 201</cato:entity-ref> and for disbursements under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Homeowners and Taxpayers Protection Act of 2013/s:201/ss:f/p:2" proposed="true">section
			 201(f)(2)</cato:entity-ref> for catastrophe readiness, preparedness, prevention, and
			 mitigation.</text>
						</subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H0595F70550544636AE2BA0D248DCC3B9">
              <enum>(E)</enum>
              <header>Termination</header>
              <text>Upon
			 termination under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Homeowners and Taxpayers Protection Act of 2013/s:104" proposed="true">section 104</cato:entity-ref>, as provided in such section.</text>
						</subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="HD224A9BFC74245D390AA8817F737AC73">
            <enum>(4)</enum>
            <header>Liquidity</header>
						<subparagraph id="H1F0549E616024E5B9B01EDC5911F433C">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <header>Authority</header>
              <text>To
			 the extent that the amounts in the Fund are insufficient to pay claims and
			 expenses under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Homeowners and Taxpayers Protection Act of 2013/s:102/ss:g/p:3" proposed="true">paragraph (3)</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> may issue such obligations of the
			 Fund as may be necessary to cover the insufficiency and shall purchase any such
			 obligations issued.</text>
						</subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H043B9FA9488F4429B5A50BE11A490889">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <header>Public debt
			 transaction</header>
              <text>For the purpose of purchasing any such obligations,
			 the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> may use as a public debt transaction the proceeds from the sale
			 of any securities issued under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/31/31">chapter 31</external-xref> of title 31, United States Code, and
			 the purposes for which securities are issued under such chapter are hereby
			 extended to include any purchase by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> of such obligations under
			 this paragraph.</text>
						</subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H2CC9EC77F3C349FE9D800B923232B0F6">
              <enum>(C)</enum>
              <header>Characteristics
			 of obligations</header>
              <text>Obligations issued under this paragraph shall be
			 in such forms and denominations, bear such maturities, bear interest at such
			 rate and be subject to such other terms and conditions as the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall
			 determine.</text>
						</subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H136EDDFDB96B4AC79E452CCFAE1A70B1">
              <enum>(D)</enum>
              <header>Treatment</header>
              <text>All
			 redemptions, purchases, and sales by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> of obligations under this
			 paragraph shall be treated as public debt transactions of the United
			 States.</text>
						</subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H231ABAF5C3994E36A4950857D94864E0">
              <enum>(E)</enum>
              <header>Repayment</header>
              <text>Any
			 obligations issued under this paragraph shall be repaid, including interest,
			 from the Fund and shall be recouped from surcharges under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Homeowners and Taxpayers Protection Act of 2013/s:102/ss:e/p:6/sp:B" proposed="true">subsection (e)(6)(B)</cato:entity-ref>
			 on premiums for reinsurance coverage provided under this section.</text>
						</subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H6B98C4C1B6574BA0BC74F1E7DCA17B60">
            <enum>(5)</enum>
            <header>Investment</header>
            <text>The
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall invest accumulated amounts in the Fund as the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary</cato:entity-ref>
			 considers advisable in obligations issued or guaranteed by the United
			 States.</text>
					</paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H7B9809AF48F543EAAA53FE39C8455533">
            <enum>(6)</enum>
            <header>Prohibition on
			 federal appropriations</header>
            <text>Except for amounts made available pursuant
			 to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Homeowners and Taxpayers Protection Act of 2013/s:102/ss:g/p:4/sp:A" proposed="true">paragraph (4)(A)</cato:entity-ref> of this subsection and <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Homeowners and Taxpayers Protection Act of 2013/s:101/ss:h" proposed="true">section 101(h)</cato:entity-ref>, no Federal funds
			 shall be authorized or appropriated for the Fund or for carrying out the
			 reinsurance liquidity protection program under this section.</text>
					</paragraph>
        </subsection>
      </section>
      <section id="H313F381CF86946C29842739CF7A02E9E">
        <enum>103.</enum>
        <header>Post-catastrophe
			 market stabilization program for liquidity loans</header>
				<subsection id="HC01F8E11D1834F7C869B6BFFB48C217B">
          <enum>(a)</enum>
          <header>Purposes</header>
          <text>The
			 purposes of this section are to establish a program—</text>
					<paragraph id="H6F90D186968746A3AE4F6112789B8E95">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <text>to expedite the
			 payment of claims under State catastrophe insurance programs and better assist
			 the financial recovery from significant natural catastrophes by authorizing the
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> to issue loans for such purposes; and</text>
					</paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H6B8F4C2353794C2BBEB19468138BD290">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <text>to promote the
			 availability of private capital to provide liquidity and capacity to State
			 catastrophe insurance programs and to augment the efforts of such
			 programs.</text>
					</paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="H44BB45637A9F49F191E1E95323F4A6C0">
          <enum>(b)</enum>
          <header>Liquidity
			 loans</header>
          <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> may make liquidity loans under this section
			 to State plans for the purposes of this section, and shall have the powers and
			 authorities necessary to make such loans, subject to the requirements of this
			 section.</text>
				</subsection>
        <subsection id="H8D68714042CD400E97225FE252C4DD29">
          <enum>(c)</enum>
          <header>Conditions for
			 loan eligibility</header>
          <text>A loan under this section may be made to a State
			 plan only if—</text>
					<paragraph id="H6C9EB77F98994294B381E0A67D9830A1">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <text>the plan has a
			 capital liquidity shortage, in accordance with regulations that the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary</cato:entity-ref>
			 shall establish, such that the obligations of the plan resulting from a covered
			 event exceed the amount of cash available to the plan to pay covered
			 losses;</text>
					</paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H02114D0BFB47431FBE88390FA51BAEB9">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <text>the plan cannot
			 access capital in the private market at a cost lower and for similar duration
			 than that provided under a loan under this section, as determined by the
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary</cato:entity-ref>; and</text>
					</paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H55C03B214F844007A1426FFE7016FA2D">
            <enum>(3)</enum>
            <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H337E8DD0F8864720AA915E363CD3587D">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>the plan is an eligible
			 State plan; and</text>
						</subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="HB5E0C78F207242D6BC2E961DD2235611" indent="up1">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>the loan complies with the
			 requirements under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Homeowners and Taxpayers Protection Act of 2013/s:103/ss:e" proposed="true">subsection (e)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
						</subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <continuation-text continuation-text-level="subsection">The
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> may not require an eligible State plan to purchase reinsurance
			 coverage made available under the program under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Homeowners and Taxpayers Protection Act of 2013/s:102" proposed="true">section 102</cato:entity-ref> to be eligible for
			 a liquidity loan under this section.</continuation-text>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="H61F495CB17A242858B782BF52A016064">
          <enum>(d)</enum>
          <header>States with
			 eligible state plans</header>
					<paragraph id="HA8368E86D04E44FEA37FBECF8931489D">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <header>Contracts</header>
            <text>The
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> may enter into contracts with eligible State plans to carry out the
			 purposes of this section by providing for liquidity loans for such plans, as
			 the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> may deem appropriate.</text>
					</paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H52F735CAB5734151B3C03E4C391261B2">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <header>Eligible state
			 plan pre-certification</header>
            <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall establish procedures
			 and standards for State plans to apply to the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> at any time for
			 pre-certification (and recertification) as eligible State plans, which
			 procedures and standards shall provide as follows:</text>
						<subparagraph id="HEE49ED6E8AAC44709C75F13C2295F2A8">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary</cato:entity-ref>
			 shall administer the pre-certification (and recertification) of State plans as
			 eligible State plans.</text>
						</subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H20153007BA7C419AB3FEE12D006645C7">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>State plans that
			 are pre-certified as eligible State plans may enter into contracts described in
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Homeowners and Taxpayers Protection Act of 2013/s:103/ss:d/p:1" proposed="true">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
						</subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H8AFF6AF0DA714F6D8F847778D0DB88DF">
            <enum>(3)</enum>
            <header>Interest
			 rate</header>
            <text>Subject to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Homeowners and Taxpayers Protection Act of 2013/s:103/ss:h" proposed="true">subsection (h)</cato:entity-ref>, a liquidity loan made under this
			 section to an eligible State plan shall bear interest at an annual rate to be
			 established by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary</cato:entity-ref>, in consultation with the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="National Commission on Natural Catastrophe Preparation and Protection" proposed="true">Commission</cato:entity-ref>, which shall
			 be equal to the rate of interest on State and local government series
			 securities have the same duration as the liquidity loan outstanding as of the
			 date the loan is made.</text>
					</paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H5E10151095074F52BA6EDC6E69C13070">
            <enum>(4)</enum>
            <header>Mandatory
			 assistance for eligible state plans</header>
            <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall, upon the
			 request of an eligible State plan and subject to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Homeowners and Taxpayers Protection Act of 2013/s:103/ss:c/p:1" proposed="true">paragraphs (1)</cato:entity-ref> and <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Homeowners and Taxpayers Protection Act of 2013/s:103/ss:c/p:2" proposed="true">(2) of
			 subsection (c)</cato:entity-ref>, make a loan for such plan in the amount requested by such plan
			 (subject to the limitations under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Homeowners and Taxpayers Protection Act of 2013/s:103/ss:f" proposed="true">subsection (f)</cato:entity-ref>).</text>
					</paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="HC3C9E47596D84512BB260F88306559EC">
          <enum>(e)</enum>
          <header>States without
			 eligible state plans</header>
					<paragraph id="HFCA3BAE1116340D2BA9397BD3B5C0730">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <header>Authority</header>
            <text>Subject
			 to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Homeowners and Taxpayers Protection Act of 2013/s:103/ss:c" proposed="true">subsection (c)</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> may make a liquidity loan under this section
			 to a State plan that is not an eligible State plan, but only if the Secretary
			 determines that—</text>
						<subparagraph id="H22F1F5FBA63D41FB800C77DAF7A09F3A">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>the loan is
			 necessary to avoid a capital shortfall; and</text>
						</subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H64764A57A5E7401E855F7E405EAED1F4">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>the provisions
			 providing for repayment of the loan are comparable in providing protection to
			 taxpayers as provisions providing for repayment of liquidity loans under this
			 section by eligible State plans.</text>
						</subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H422360226FF6482FBDA8355BC1894994">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <header>Interest
			 rate</header>
            <text>Subject to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Homeowners and Taxpayers Protection Act of 2013/s:103/ss:h" proposed="true">subsection (h)</cato:entity-ref>, a liquidity loan made under this
			 section to a State plan that is not an eligible State plan shall bear interest
			 at an annual rate that exceeds the rate required under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Homeowners and Taxpayers Protection Act of 2013/s:103/ss:d/p:3" proposed="true">subsection (d)(3)</cato:entity-ref> for a
			 loan made to an eligible State plan. Such rate shall be determined in
			 accordance with a schedule of interest rates, which shall be established by the
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> and shall provide lower rates for loans to State plans that comply
			 with more of the requirements for eligible State plans under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Homeowners and Taxpayers Protection Act of 2013/s:102/ss:d" proposed="true">section 102(d)</cato:entity-ref> and
			 higher rates for loans to State plans that comply with fewer of such
			 requirements.</text>
					</paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="HF164D563F2BA4F5980B1459A9F833831">
          <enum>(f)</enum>
          <header>Amount</header>
          <text>The
			 principal amount of a liquidity loan under this subsection may not exceed the
			 difference between the applicable attachment point as determined by the
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Homeowners and Taxpayers Protection Act of 2013/s:102/ss:f/p:2" proposed="true">section 102(f)(2)</cato:entity-ref> and the amount of funds the eligible State plan
			 had to pay losses at the time of the covered event for which the loan is
			 made.</text>
				</subsection>
        <subsection id="HF3DF1803C8B748E4B56402C703DCF177">
          <enum>(g)</enum>
          <header>Use</header>
          <text>Amounts
			 from a liquidity loan under this section may be used only to pay losses covered
			 by the State plan to which the loan is made.</text>
				</subsection>
        <subsection id="HDE4A5AA668674E1E83FCB3E3B3539556">
          <enum>(h)</enum>
          <header>Exception to
			 interest rate limitation</header>
          <text>In the case of liquidity loan under this
			 section made pursuant to a large covered event that occurs early in the
			 existence of a State plan, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> may charge an interest rate for the
			 loan that allows the State plan to repay the loan and interest without causing
			 significant increases in the cost of insurance for covered events in the
			 covered State or States.</text>
				</subsection>
        <subsection id="HFC12F20DFD0C4F679F843B2E5C6793FC">
          <enum>(i)</enum>
          <header>Premiums under
			 state plan</header>
					<paragraph id="H814CCE90A4B8441083BF4AA1E534CE62">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <header>Determination of
			 actuarially sound premiums</header>
            <text>In making a request for a liquidity
			 loan under this section, a State plan shall determine, and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary</cato:entity-ref>, in
			 consultation with the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="National Commission on Natural Catastrophe Preparation and Protection" proposed="true">Commission</cato:entity-ref>, shall approve, a premium amount for the
			 coverage layer under the State plan for which the liquidity loan is sought that
			 is actuarially sound.</text>
					</paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H866A3E5F38454703B6EB7CEB965832C5">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <header>Chargeable
			 premiums</header>
            <text>Unless otherwise provided by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary</cato:entity-ref>, a State plan
			 shall charge, for the coverage layer under the State plan for which the
			 liquidity loan is made an annual premium, for coverage during the period that
			 begins upon the making of the liquidity loan and ends upon full repayment of
			 the loan, in an amount that is not less than 150 percent of the actuarially
			 sound premium determined pursuant to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Homeowners and Taxpayers Protection Act of 2013/s:103/ss:i/p:1" proposed="true">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
					</paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="H2A7EB3D8F5FE472089D34888517FCDCB">
          <enum>(j)</enum>
          <header>Repayment of
			 loans</header>
					<paragraph id="HEA6B4F3684AC4A4DB16ADD40B370DB08">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <header>In
			 general</header>
            <text>Any liquidity loan made under this section to a State
			 plan shall be repaid solely through premiums charged by such plan in accordance
			 with <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Homeowners and Taxpayers Protection Act of 2013/s:103/ss:i/p:2" proposed="true">subsection (i)(2)</cato:entity-ref>, unless alternative arrangements have been made pursuant
			 to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Homeowners and Taxpayers Protection Act of 2013/s:103/ss:i/p:3" proposed="true">paragraph (3)</cato:entity-ref>. The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary</cato:entity-ref>, in consultation with the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="National Commission on Natural Catastrophe Preparation and Protection" proposed="true">Commission</cato:entity-ref>, shall
			 determine the expected duration of each loan and monitor repayment of such
			 loans.</text>
					</paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H9DE0A96A37B24D15A6D51824FE982A65">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <header>Amount of
			 payment</header>
            <text>To repay a liquidity loan under this section, the State
			 plan shall pay to the Fund, from all amounts collected for the coverage layer
			 referred to in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Homeowners and Taxpayers Protection Act of 2013/s:103/ss:i/p:2" proposed="true">subsection (i)(2)</cato:entity-ref> during the period referred to in such
			 subsection, an amount equal to a minimum of 100 percent of the actuarially
			 sound premium determined under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Homeowners and Taxpayers Protection Act of 2013/s:103/ss:j/p:1" proposed="true">subsection (j)(1)</cato:entity-ref> for such coverage layer, and
			 shall retain the remainder of such amount collected to build reserves for
			 future events, or such other amount or percentage of such amounts as the
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary</cato:entity-ref>, in consultation with the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="National Commission on Natural Catastrophe Preparation and Protection" proposed="true">Commission</cato:entity-ref> and State plans, determines is
			 appropriate.</text>
					</paragraph>
          <paragraph id="HC29C5CEBD8914D628E244970742A9991">
            <enum>(3)</enum>
            <header>Other
			 options</header>
            <text>A State plan may petition the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> for other
			 repayment terms, including repayment from sources such as dedicated State sales
			 taxes or other means, and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> may, in consultation with the
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="National Commission on Natural Catastrophe Preparation and Protection" proposed="true">Commission</cato:entity-ref>, agree to such other terms.</text>
					</paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="HB76C8CACE19B44B4ADB0FBD22676B678">
          <enum>(k)</enum>
          <header>Regulations</header>
          <text>The
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall issue any regulations necessary to carry out the program under
			 this section.</text>
				</subsection>
      </section>
      <section id="H632093702D8D421D93C1C10B424B105E">
        <enum>104.</enum>
        <header>Termination</header>
				<subsection id="HC9BC7310E9C34F9EAAFEFAA063CAC56A">
          <enum>(a)</enum>
          <header>In
			 general</header>
          <text>Except as provided in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Homeowners and Taxpayers Protection Act of 2013/s:104/ss:b" proposed="true">subsection (b)</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> may
			 not—</text>
					<paragraph id="H93876F60F4964C7EA0BB4E84F694EE94">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <text>provide any new
			 reinsurance coverage under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Homeowners and Taxpayers Protection Act of 2013/s:102" proposed="true">section 102</cato:entity-ref> that covers any period after the
			 expiration of the 20-year period beginning on the date of the enactment of this
			 Act; or</text>
					</paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H3A09E30E976140959EE6D35D91F49B49">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <text>make any new
			 liquidity loan under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Homeowners and Taxpayers Protection Act of 2013/s:103" proposed="true">section 103</cato:entity-ref> having a term to maturity that concludes after
			 the expiration of such 20-year period.</text>
					</paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="HB56F546C33134DE5B9068223E8334509">
          <enum>(b)</enum>
          <header>Extension</header>
          <text>If
			 upon the expiration of the period under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Homeowners and Taxpayers Protection Act of 2013/s:104/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref> the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary</cato:entity-ref>, in
			 consultation with the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="National Commission on Natural Catastrophe Preparation and Protection" proposed="true">Commission</cato:entity-ref>, determines that continuation of the program
			 for reinsurance coverage under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Homeowners and Taxpayers Protection Act of 2013/s:102" proposed="true">section 102</cato:entity-ref> or for liquidity loans under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Homeowners and Taxpayers Protection Act of 2013/s:103" proposed="true">section
			 103</cato:entity-ref> is necessary or appropriate to carry out the purposes this Act because of
			 insufficient growth of capacity in the private homeowners insurance market, the
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall continue to make such coverage and loans available and
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Homeowners and Taxpayers Protection Act of 2013/s:104/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref> shall be applied by substituting <quote>25-year period</quote>
			 for <quote>20-year period</quote> each place such term appears.</text>
				</subsection>
        <subsection id="HD5C72111187F44D4BBEB9720E1D8F646">
          <enum>(c)</enum>
          <header>Repeal</header>
          <text>Effective
			 upon the first date that reinsurance coverage under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Homeowners and Taxpayers Protection Act of 2013/s:102" proposed="true">section 102</cato:entity-ref> is no longer
			 available or in force and that liquidity loans under section 103 are no longer
			 available or outstanding, pursuant to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Homeowners and Taxpayers Protection Act of 2013/s:104/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref> or <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Homeowners and Taxpayers Protection Act of 2013/s:104/ss:b" proposed="true">(b)</cato:entity-ref>, this Act (except
			 for this section) is repealed.</text>
				</subsection>
        <subsection id="H88384ABD057F46D393C5D0131D0BFD35">
          <enum>(d)</enum>
          <header>Deficit
			 reduction</header>
          <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall pay into the General Fund of the
			 Treasury any amounts remaining in the Fund upon the repeal of this Act under
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Homeowners and Taxpayers Protection Act of 2013/s:104/ss:c" proposed="true">subsection (c)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
				</subsection>
      </section>
    </title>
    <title id="HBBFC9E3692AE4B83B0D3B5CA61BD9A5E">
      <enum>II</enum>
      <header>CATASTROPHE
			 READINESS, CITIZEN AND COMMUNITY PREPAREDNESS, AND MITIGATION</header>
			<section id="HD432488F69CD4C2D9B912C9C498A935B">
        <enum>201.</enum>
        <header>National
			 Readiness, Preparedness, and Mitigation Committee</header>
				<subsection id="HECEE1CC3AD084D9E8D6302DAE4983537">
          <enum>(a)</enum>
          <header>Establishment</header>
          <text>There
			 is established a <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="National Readiness, Preparedness, and Mitigation Committee" proposed="true">National Readiness, Preparedness and Mitigation Committee</cato:entity-ref> (in
			 this section referred to as the <quote>Committee</quote>).</text>
				</subsection>
        <subsection id="HAC87A13917704209843C2242643B7007">
          <enum>(b)</enum>
          <header>Members</header>
          <text>The
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="National Readiness, Preparedness, and Mitigation Committee" proposed="true">Committee</cato:entity-ref> shall consist of 9 members appointed by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="8600">Secretary of Housing and
			 Urban Development</cato:entity-ref> or the Secretary’s designee, as follows:</text>
					<paragraph id="H73038EA8C0B147F79BD9C1062F338D6D">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <text>Three individuals
			 from nationally recognized organizations representing State or local
			 catastrophe response providers or catastrophe management professionals.</text>
					</paragraph>
          <paragraph id="HFE5A9F129CFA46CEAF03669CCD729440">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <text>Three individuals
			 representing nationally recognized non-profits active in catastrophe
			 preparedness and response.</text>
					</paragraph>
          <paragraph id="HDD41009F4D93429D991221CDAEDEFE72">
            <enum>(3)</enum>
            <text>Three individuals
			 representing nationally recognized organizations with expertise in contingency
			 planning, residential construction, building code development and
			 implementation, and land use policy.</text>
					</paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="H86C331CD28D744DB9F46B64B841AF8EF">
          <enum>(c)</enum>
          <header>Terms</header>
					<paragraph id="HD4C5626E69204604912F0A7044E9A40E">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <header>In
			 general</header>
            <text>Except as provided in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Homeowners and Taxpayers Protection Act of 2013/s:201/ss:c/p:2" proposed="true">paragraphs (2)</cato:entity-ref> and <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Homeowners and Taxpayers Protection Act of 2013/s:201/ss:c/p:3" proposed="true">(3)</cato:entity-ref>, each member
			 of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="National Readiness, Preparedness, and Mitigation Committee" proposed="true">Committee</cato:entity-ref> shall be appointed for a term of 3 years.</text>
					</paragraph>
          <paragraph id="HA8FD016D15B94B819A71BAA213C7617A">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <header>Initial
			 members</header>
            <text>Of the members initially appointed to the
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="National Readiness, Preparedness, and Mitigation Committee" proposed="true">Committee</cato:entity-ref>—</text>
						<subparagraph id="HAB3703369DC447ABA62884526ADE4F0A">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>one member
			 appointed under each of <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Homeowners and Taxpayers Protection Act of 2013/s:201/ss:b/p:1" proposed="true">paragraphs (1)</cato:entity-ref>, <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Homeowners and Taxpayers Protection Act of 2013/s:201/ss:b/p:2" proposed="true">(2)</cato:entity-ref>, and <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Homeowners and Taxpayers Protection Act of 2013/s:201/ss:b/p:3" proposed="true">(3) of subsection (b)</cato:entity-ref> shall be
			 appointed for a term of 1 year;</text>
						</subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="HB8ABFC0AEA2E47BB8763DC5FD273D4EC">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>one member
			 appointed under each of <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Homeowners and Taxpayers Protection Act of 2013/s:201/ss:b/p:1" proposed="true">paragraphs (1)</cato:entity-ref>, <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Homeowners and Taxpayers Protection Act of 2013/s:201/ss:b/p:2" proposed="true">(2)</cato:entity-ref>, and <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Homeowners and Taxpayers Protection Act of 2013/s:201/ss:b/p:3" proposed="true">(3) of subsection (b)</cato:entity-ref> shall be
			 appointed for a term of 2 years; and</text>
						</subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H9BBBE98F96FD484A88A4957A95832B4A">
              <enum>(C)</enum>
              <text>one member
			 appointed under each of <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Homeowners and Taxpayers Protection Act of 2013/s:201/ss:b/p:1" proposed="true">paragraphs (1)</cato:entity-ref>, <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Homeowners and Taxpayers Protection Act of 2013/s:201/ss:b/p:2" proposed="true">(2)</cato:entity-ref>, and <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Homeowners and Taxpayers Protection Act of 2013/s:201/ss:b/p:3" proposed="true">(3) of subsection (b)</cato:entity-ref> shall be
			 appointed for a term of 3 years.</text>
						</subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H72DE4D6409234227B6A09BB5EA012DCB">
            <enum>(3)</enum>
            <header>Vacancies</header>
            <text>A
			 member appointed to fill an unexpired term shall serve the remainder of that
			 term.</text>
					</paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H5A2D8331FAAE4638A080B5516C8482A1">
            <enum>(4)</enum>
            <header>Termination</header>
            <text>In
			 the event that the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="National Readiness, Preparedness, and Mitigation Committee" proposed="true">Committee</cato:entity-ref> terminates, all appointments shall
			 terminate.</text>
					</paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="H8151F3EDC65B402FBA2DCBEB2B7C5758">
          <enum>(d)</enum>
          <header>Prohibition of
			 compensation; reimbursement</header>
          <text>Members of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="National Readiness, Preparedness, and Mitigation Committee" proposed="true">Committee</cato:entity-ref> shall
			 receive no compensation by reason of their service on the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="National Readiness, Preparedness, and Mitigation Committee" proposed="true">Committee</cato:entity-ref>, but shall
			 be reimbursed as provided by rules and by-laws established by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="National Commission on Natural Catastrophe Preparation and Protection" proposed="true">National
			 Commission on Natural Catastrophe Preparation and Protection</cato:entity-ref> established under
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Homeowners and Taxpayers Protection Act of 2013/s:101" proposed="true">section 101</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
				</subsection>
        <subsection id="HFC9EFE81094D4766A3119806120DBABC">
          <enum>(e)</enum>
          <header>Duties</header>
          <text>The
			 members of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="National Readiness, Preparedness, and Mitigation Committee" proposed="true">Committee</cato:entity-ref> shall administer the program under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Homeowners and Taxpayers Protection Act of 2013/s:201/ss:f" proposed="true">subsection (f)</cato:entity-ref> and
			 conduct oversight of the program and activities under such program.</text>
				</subsection>
        <subsection id="H51FEAED1E9D5474E867642860FFB841E">
          <enum>(f)</enum>
          <header>Readiness,
			 preparedness, and mitigation grant program</header>
					<paragraph id="HBF58AC5F10A44162B9AD35898D26B4A9">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <header>Allocation of
			 amount</header>
            <text>Beginning upon the expiration of the 12-month period that
			 begins on the date of the enactment of this Act, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall ensure
			 that, to the extent provided in appropriation Acts, approximately 35 percent of
			 the annual net investment income of the Fund under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Homeowners and Taxpayers Protection Act of 2013/s:102/ss:g" proposed="true">sec. 102(g)</cato:entity-ref>, but not less
			 than $15,000,000, and not more than 20 percent of the premium charged for
			 reinsurance coverage under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Homeowners and Taxpayers Protection Act of 2013/s:102" proposed="true">section 102</cato:entity-ref> in any given year, shall be used for
			 grants to States, units of local government, nonprofit organizations, and other
			 appropriate public and private entities to develop, enhance, or maintain
			 programs and initiatives to improve and maintain catastrophe response, citizen
			 preparedness and protection, and prevention and mitigation of losses from
			 natural catastrophes.</text>
					</paragraph>
          <paragraph id="HA00138A7829F4CD7B175C827B2662487">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <header>Program
			 elements</header>
            <text>The amounts made available under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Homeowners and Taxpayers Protection Act of 2013/s:201/ss:f/p:1" proposed="true">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref> shall be
			 allocated for each of the following purposes in equal amounts:</text>
						<subparagraph id="H2B9A7252DE4F43EE87F1E724971ADF0D">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <header>Catastrophe
			 response readiness</header>
              <text>For catastrophe response readiness programs,
			 which shall include national initiatives that develop, enhance, or maintain the
			 capacity of a public safety agency or other organization to be better prepared,
			 equipped, and trained to respond to natural catastrophes.</text>
						</subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H00649DD36B8B4B7CA2649CC885C0316F">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <header>Citizen and
			 community preparedness</header>
              <text>For citizen and community preparedness,
			 which shall include programs and initiatives, such as those offered by the
			 American Red Cross, to improve education and training to ensure that citizens
			 and organizations in their community are better prepared for natural
			 catastrophes.</text>
						</subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H3049DF14A6B84C3EA4B344B1726EAB46">
              <enum>(C)</enum>
              <header>Prevention and
			 mitigation</header>
              <text>For prevention and mitigation of loss from natural
			 catastrophes, which shall include methods to reduce loss of life and property,
			 including appropriate measures to—</text>
							<clause id="HFC84B8D927714776BD091DD42E184FF8">
                <enum>(i)</enum>
                <text>encourage
			 awareness of the risk factors and what steps can be taken to eliminate or
			 reduce them;</text>
							</clause>
              <clause id="HF6A80C94FC0A4C3BA68E26651AEE13B1">
                <enum>(ii)</enum>
                <text>identify location
			 of risks, by giving careful consideration to the natural risks for the location
			 of the property and providing that information to the builder, developer and
			 homeowner; and</text>
							</clause>
              <clause id="H81144CC3F6FF4075AA8684E34AF06C59">
                <enum>(iii)</enum>
                <text>provide for
			 construction relative to the risk and hazards, including—</text>
								<subclause id="H540C2625B3B54B88B2BAAFE9C8E48869">
                  <enum>(I)</enum>
                  <text>establishment and
			 adoption of State, or locally mandated building codes, as amended by the
			 governing body;</text>
								</subclause>
                <subclause id="HE9AB077A61524E38BD699211CB734DE8">
                  <enum>(II)</enum>
                  <text>adequate
			 enforcement of the building codes; and</text>
								</subclause>
                <subclause id="HE1FECB404AAD487DA89534ED19127CBD">
                  <enum>(III)</enum>
                  <text>focusing on
			 prevention and mitigation for existing homes, with an emphasis on how
			 structures can be retrofitted cost-effectively to make them compliant with
			 building codes.</text>
								</subclause>
              </clause>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="H79EF95BDC9404171B738373D8B2FD821">
          <enum>(g)</enum>
          <header>Continuous
			 improvement, coordination and integration</header>
          <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="National Commission on Natural Catastrophe Preparation and Protection" proposed="true">National Commission
			 on Natural Catastrophe Preparation and Protection</cato:entity-ref> established under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Homeowners and Taxpayers Protection Act of 2013/s:101" proposed="true">section 101</cato:entity-ref>
			 shall work with eligible State plans and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="National Readiness, Preparedness, and Mitigation Committee" proposed="true">Committee</cato:entity-ref> to continuously improve,
			 coordinate, and integrate catastrophe readiness, citizen and community
			 preparedness, and loss prevention and mitigation at the local, State, regional,
			 and national levels.</text>
				</subsection>
      </section>
    </title>
  </legis-body>
</bill>
</doc>