<doc>
  <docmeta id="113hres366eh">
    <bill congress="113" type="hres" number="366" version="eh"/>
    <revision size="2734" annotations="0" status="complete" id="5" commit-time="2013-10-17T21:52:20Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113hres366eh/5.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <resolution xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" dms-id="Hf9d1be2d-495d-4fa5-8c4f-f156c74f3e0c" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Engrossed-in-House" key="H" stage-count="1"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>113 HRES 366 EH: Providing for consideration of the Senate amendment to the joint resolution (H.J. Res. 59) making continuing appropriations for fiscal year 2014, and for other purposes, and providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 3210) making continuing appropriations for military pay in the event of a Government shutdown.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2013-09-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="no">IV</distribution-code> 
<congress display="no">113th CONGRESS</congress>
<session display="no">1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. RES. 366</legis-num> 
<current-chamber display="yes">In the House of Representatives, U. S.,</current-chamber>
<action>
<action-date date="20130928">September 28, 2013</action-date>
</action> 
<legis-type display="yes">RESOLUTION</legis-type>
<official-title display="no">Providing for consideration of the Senate amendment to the joint resolution (H.J. Res. 59) making continuing appropriations for fiscal year 2014, and for other purposes, and providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 3210) making continuing appropriations for military pay in the event of a Government shutdown.</official-title>
</form>
<resolution-body style="traditional" id="H565e8da1-f9e0-4c7a-aa05-2b5baf92ffb3">
<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H8a9f9f3c-037b-458d-8556-8efa5914ea08">
      <text>That upon adoption of this resolution it shall be in order to take from the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" value="Speaker of the House of Representatives" entity-parent-id="0050">Speaker's</cato:entity-ref> table the joint resolution (<cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="113 HJRES 59" proposed="true">H.J. Res. 59</cato:entity-ref>) making continuing appropriations for fiscal year 2014, and for other purposes, with the Senate amendment thereto, and to consider in the House, without intervention of any point of order, a motion offered by the chair of the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="committee" entity-id="HAP00">Committee on Appropriations</cato:entity-ref> or his designee that the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0050">House</cato:entity-ref> concur in the Senate amendment with each of the two amendments printed in the report of the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="committee" entity-id="HRU00">Committee on Rules</cato:entity-ref> accompanying this resolution. The Senate amendment and the motion shall be considered as read. The motion shall be debatable for one hour equally divided and controlled by the chair and ranking minority member of the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="committee" entity-id="HAP00">Committee on Appropriations</cato:entity-ref>. The previous question shall be considered as ordered on the motion to its adoption without intervening motion or demand for division of the question except that the question of adoption of the motion shall be divided between the two House amendments. </text>
    </section>
<section id="H8DC4110BA9A84EB8AA9F288F655B966D">
      <enum>2.</enum>
      <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon adoption of this resolution it shall be in order to consider in the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0050">House</cato:entity-ref> the bill (<cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="113 HR 3210" proposed="true">H.R. 3210</cato:entity-ref>) making continuing appropriations for military pay in the event of a Government shutdown. All points of order against consideration of the bill are waived. The bill shall be considered as read. All points of order against provisions in the bill are waived. The previous question shall be considered as ordered on the bill and on any amendment thereto to final passage without intervening motion except: (1) 40 minutes of debate equally divided and controlled by the chair and ranking minority member of the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="committee" entity-id="HAP00">Committee on Appropriations</cato:entity-ref>; and (2) one motion to recommit.</text>
    </section>
</resolution-body>
<attestation>
    <attestation-group>
      <attestor display="no">Karen L. Haas,</attestor>
      <role>Clerk.</role>
    </attestation-group>
  </attestation>
</resolution>
</doc>