<doc>
  <docmeta id="113hres326ih">
    <bill congress="113" type="hres" number="326" version="ih"/>
    <revision size="3410" annotations="0" status="complete" id="3" commit-time="2013-08-25T20:05:04Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113hres326ih/3.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <resolution xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" dms-id="H52C939874AA748709A7D62749E22DEB8" key="H" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print">
	<metadata>
<dublinCore>
<title>113 HRES 326 IH: Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives that any immigration reform proposal adopted by Congress should not legalize, grant amnesty for, or confer any other legal status condoning the otherwise unlawful entry or presence in the United States of any individual.</title>
<publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</publisher>
<date>2013-08-02</date>
<format>text/xml</format>
<language>EN</language>
<rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">113th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session display="yes">1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. RES. 326</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20130802">August 2, 2013</action-date>
			<action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="B001262">Mr. Broun of Georgia</sponsor>
			 submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the
			 <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the
			 Judiciary</committee-name>
      </action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">Expressing the sense of the House of
		  Representatives that any immigration reform proposal adopted by Congress should
		  not legalize, grant amnesty for, or confer any other legal status condoning the
		  otherwise unlawful entry or presence in the United States of any
		  individual.</official-title>
	</form>
	<preamble>
		<whereas>
      <text>Whereas on November 6, 1986, the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Immigration Reform and Control Act of 1986">Immigration Reform and
			 Control Act</cato:entity-ref> (IRCA) of 1986 was signed into law;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas between 1987 and 1988, nearly 2,700,000 illegal
			 immigrants received legal status under the 1986 <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Immigration Reform and Control Act of 1986">IRCA</cato:entity-ref> amnesty before being
			 granted lawful permanent residence by 1992;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Immigration Reform and Control Act of 1986">IRCA</cato:entity-ref> was touted by its sponsors as the
			 <quote>three-legged stool</quote> approach to immigration reform incorporating
			 improved border security and employment enforcement, a H–2A temporary worker
			 program, and legal status for certain eligible groups;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Immigration Reform and Control Act of 1986">IRCA</cato:entity-ref> contained provisions to inhibit future
			 illegal immigration by penalizing employers who knowingly hire an unauthorized
			 immigrant;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas despite these penalties, a policy brief by the
			 Migration Policy Institute dated August 2005 showed that over 90 percent of
			 unauthorized males in the United States were employed;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Immigration Reform and Control Act of 1986">IRCA</cato:entity-ref> included language to increase Border
			 Personnel by 50 percent;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas then-Immigration and Naturalization Service (INS)
			 Commissioner Alan C. Nelson announced the law’s initial success in a 1989 House
			 Judiciary Committee hearing, citing the shrinking number of apprehensions at
			 the border, as signal <quote>to demonstrate that the law is working and
			 employer sanctions are having the intended effect of reducing illegal
			 immigration</quote>;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas illegal immigration actually increased in volume
			 and frequency by 1989, with 1,700,000 to 2,500,000 unauthorized immigrants
			 crossing into the United States from Mexico that year;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the number of illegal aliens grew to 3,400,000 by
			 the early 1990s, and by 1997 the approximate unauthorized population totaled
			 more than 5,000,000, the same number of illegal immigrants as before the 1986
			 law took effect; and</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas an estimated 11,500,000 million illegal aliens
			 currently reside in the United States: Now, therefore, be it</text>
		</whereas>
  </preamble>
	<resolution-body id="H99B89D4D93104724B855B7E915870F44" style="traditional">
		<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H09769645233244CCA7B905D4EA26E4F5" section-type="undesignated-section">
      <enum/>
      <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That it is the sense of the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0050">House of
			 Representatives</cato:entity-ref> that any immigration reform proposal adopted by <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> should
			 not legalize, grant amnesty for, or confer any other legal status condoning the
			 otherwise unlawful entry or presence in the United States of any individual.</text>
		</section>
  </resolution-body>
</resolution>
</doc>