<doc>
  <docmeta id="113hr5316ih">
    <bill congress="113" type="hr" number="5316" version="ih"/>
    <revision size="47553" annotations="0" status="complete" id="4" commit-time="2014-08-27T16:45:45Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113hr5316ih/4.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" key="H"> 
<metadata>
<dublinCore>
<dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">113 HR 5316 IH: Safely Exacting Cautious Useful Rules for Immigration This Year (SECURITY) Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">2014-07-31</dc:date>
<dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>113th CONGRESS</congress> <session> 2d Session</session> 
<legis-num>H. R. 5316</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20140731">July 31, 2014</action-date> 
<action-desc>
        <cosponsor name-id="S000937">Mr. Stockman</cosponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the<committee-name committee-id="HJU00"> Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the <committee-name committee-id="HHM00"> Committees on Homeland Security</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HWM00"> Ways and Means</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HAS00"> Armed Services</committee-name>, and<committee-name committee-id="HFA00"> Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc> 
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To secure the border between the United States and Mexico.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="HC78BCB947A4348F0BDCF551293F9A4D0"> 
<section id="S1" section-type="section-one">
      <enum>1.</enum>
      <header>Short title</header> <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote>
          <short-title>
            <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Safely Exacting Cautious Useful Rules for Immigration This Year (SECURITY) Act" proposed="true">Safely Exacting Cautious Useful Rules for Immigration This Year (SECURITY) Act</cato:entity-ref>
          </short-title>
        </quote>.</text>
    </section> 
<section id="H0B6F02F846F84CD19A055DA4E41503A1">
      <enum>2.</enum>
      <header>Findings and declaration of policy</header> 
<subsection id="H955990694BEC4DB09EB8893964C16CD5">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <text>The Congress finds that:</text> 
<paragraph id="H2BA4B27E00B143EB9198DEEC20072EC7">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>An estimated 11,800,000 aliens reside in the United States in contravention of Federal immigration law.</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDFBAE52BDBA043B1B91922212818BF0A">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>The construction of a double-layered fence along the entire Southern Border reduces illegal immigration, decreases cross-border smuggling, and enables the effective deployment of manpower, as demonstrated by the San Diego sector where a fence was built in 2004.</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB579217271E445F1A9EE153C31829D79">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <text>Aliens, such as the El Salvadoran national and MS–13 gang members Kevin Fabricio Claros Cantarero and Julio Martinez, have attempted to use applications for asylum in order to reside in the United States.</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H47746948652F4A36BD9F0EB0ACD78999">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
          <text>The closing of <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="7014" entity-type="federal-body">Border Patrol</cato:entity-ref> stations, such as in June 2011, and failure to deploy the National Guard to assist the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="7014" entity-type="federal-body">Border Patrol</cato:entity-ref>, such as during the border crisis of June 2014, impaired the ability of law enforcement to secure the border.</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF7CE15820292461FBEFB125D5A1312FC">
          <enum>(5)</enum>
          <text>The backlog of immigration cases, in which 87 percent of cases where <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="7012" entity-type="federal-body">ICE</cato:entity-ref> filed Notices to Appear between 2009 to 2014 are still pending in 2014, could be addressed if Congress knew the number of judges needed in immigration courts.</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBB1DB00A58174E198B024BE1E2A91C57">
          <enum>(6)</enum>
          <text>Illegal aliens, despite being ineligible, received $4.2 billion in additional child tax credits from the United States Treasury in 2010 by applying with an individual taxpayer identification number. </text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6C23D8648FDC49668FD7067994497947">
          <enum>(7)</enum>
          <text>Aliens have been applying for and receiving public benefits from Federal, State, and local governments in substantially burdensome levels, such as $791.6 million covered by California taxpayers in 2013.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="HCE424EEBFF6B45F1A748263C398E3820">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <text>The Congress further finds and declares that it serves a compelling government interest of the United States to—</text> 
<paragraph id="HE96EBAED33CC4D09A87DEA8C7DAC89CA">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>establish and regularly evaluate the security at United States borders using the same metric;</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2BF265CF79C947DD812C9A706CED2353">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>construct a double-layered fence along the entire Southern Border of the United States;</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB193FF1B22544033BBC507A18071F98A">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <text>provide adequate manpower for enforcement of immigration laws, sufficient judges to address the backlog in immigration courts, and the appropriate number of beds and facilities to meet immigration detention needs; </text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB352CED754594FB880B3BCC83FA356EC">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
          <text>end the release of dangerous criminal aliens and the likelihood of foreign gang members using refugee and asylee status to reside in the United States; and</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0B7AA69C17E24F5882FC2E8B263F6C72">
          <enum>(5)</enum>
          <text>remove incentives for illegal immigration provided by the availability of public benefits.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
    </section> 
<section id="HA0ABBC057A564BB899997A45C5FD5C14">
      <enum>3.</enum>
      <header>Achieving and maintaining operational control of the border</header> 
<subsection id="HE3696CA80DD845068C853FD3DC4B57CF">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Plan</header>
        <text>Not later than 180 days of the date of enactment of this Act, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="7000" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of Homeland Security</cato:entity-ref> shall develop and submit to the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="HHM00" entity-type="committee">Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives</cato:entity-ref> and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="SSGA00" entity-type="committee">Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate</cato:entity-ref> a plan to achieve and maintain operational control of the entire international land and maritime borders of the United States. The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7000">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall begin implementing the plan immediately following its submission.</text>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="H0F012E968BDE4916A4C0597EE976CB47">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Definition of operational control of the border</header>
        <text>For purposes of this Act, the term <quote>operational control</quote> means the prevention of all unlawful entries into the United States, including entries by terrorists, other unlawful aliens, instruments of terrorism, narcotics, and other contraband. Any changes to the definition of <quote>operational control</quote> as defined in this Act must be approved by <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="H10CF5107D16A4D7090E9E49FFA8400BB">
        <enum>(c)</enum>
        <header>Report and certification</header> 
<paragraph id="H6E5EE60322E349EEA78F35C582752D81">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>Not later than one year after the date of enactment of this Act and annually thereafter, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7000">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall submit to the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="HHM00" entity-type="committee">Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives</cato:entity-ref> and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="SSGA00" entity-type="committee">Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate</cato:entity-ref> a report on the progress made toward achieving and maintaining operational control of the entire international land and maritime borders of the United States. Such report shall contain an analysis of the reason why, if any, operational control has not been achieved or maintained, and steps the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7000">Department</cato:entity-ref> will take to meet its goal of operational control.</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H233AFE8420684978863E02A4B81ECA4D">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>Within 30 days of receiving the report, the respective committees in subsection (1) must certify whether operational control has been met.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="HC011FC1CD30C48678039063D909AA5FE">
        <enum>(d)</enum>
        <header>Failure To achieve operational control</header>
        <text>If the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="7000" entity-type="federal-body">Department of Homeland Security</cato:entity-ref> fails to achieve or maintain operational control, then twenty-five percent of the Department’s <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="7051" entity-type="federal-body">Under Secretary for Management</cato:entity-ref>’s budget will be cut and redistributed to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="7014" entity-type="federal-body">Customs and Border Protection</cato:entity-ref> to go toward surveillance and interdiction activities.</text>
      </subsection>
    </section> 
<section id="HE0BF62DD38D44F8298F7094215365576">
      <enum>4.</enum>
      <header>Construction and completion of reinforced double-layered fencing along the southern border</header> 
<subsection id="H9D6DE82EFB7A4492BD48787E8E3AA7FF">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <text>
          <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Consolidated Appropriations Act of 2008/d:E/s:564">Section 564 of division E of the Consolidated Appropriations Act of 2008</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/110/161">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="public-law" value="public-law/110/161">Public Law 110–161</cato:entity-ref>
          </external-xref>)</cato:entity> is hereby repealed.</text>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="H5A8230F654AD4534B23A8A6864BA9B45">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Plan</header>
        <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="7000" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of Homeland Security</cato:entity-ref> shall establish a plan to construct double-layered reinforced fencing as required under section 3 of the Secure Fence Act of 2006 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/109/367">
            <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="public-law" value="public-law/109/367">Public Law 109–367</cato:entity-ref>
          </external-xref>). Such plan must be submitted by the Secretary within 180 days of enactment of this Act to the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="HHM00" entity-type="committee">Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives</cato:entity-ref> and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="SSGA00" entity-type="committee">Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate</cato:entity-ref>. The plan shall include annual deadlines to complete a proportion of the total construction of the fence, with the entirety of the fence to be completed no later than 10 years from the date of the submission of the plan.</text>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="H0C26546D1E3F4BFEA1F26BD6C531B4B1">
        <enum>(c)</enum>
        <header>Report</header>
        <text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="7000" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of Homeland Security</cato:entity-ref> shall submit a report on the progress of the fence to the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="HHM00" entity-type="committee">Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives</cato:entity-ref> and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="SSGA00" entity-type="committee">Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate</cato:entity-ref>. The report shall include whether planned objectives have been achieved by the Secretary’s proposed deadline, and detailed reasons why such deadline, if any, has not been met.</text>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="HA8D3965137D3406AB1F475CACCE55F5D">
        <enum>(d)</enum>
        <text>If the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="7000" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of Homeland Security</cato:entity-ref> does not submit a plan or fencing progress reports as required by subsections (b) and (c) of this section, the budget of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="7000" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of Homeland Security</cato:entity-ref> shall be reduced by twenty-five percent and redistributed to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="7014" entity-type="federal-body">Customs and Border Protection</cato:entity-ref> operations along the border where the fence has not yet been constructed.</text>
      </subsection>
    </section> 
<section id="HA6D8EDD7E5354D759BCF5E4C125F42D7">
      <enum>5.</enum>
      <header>Use of national guard to support department of homeland security border control activities</header> 
<subsection id="H696D109371BC41C2990D4AD978CB5196">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Deployment</header>
        <text>In addition to the members of the National Guard deployed along the Southern Border as of the date of the enactment of this Act, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="9700" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of Defense</cato:entity-ref> shall provide for the deployment of not less than an additional 10,000 members of the National Guard to be made available to border State Governors along the Southern Border until the date on which the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="7000" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of Homeland Security</cato:entity-ref> certifies that the Federal Government has achieved operational control of the Southern Border as defined in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Safely Exacting Cautious Useful Rules for Immigration This Year (SECURITY) Act/s:2" proposed="true">section 2 of this Act</cato:entity-ref>.</text> 
<paragraph id="HAD875719667140A0998745A0995692A4">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>Additional deployments</header>
          <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="9700" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of Defense</cato:entity-ref> may exceed the number specified in this section at the request of a Governor of a State along the Southern Border if operational control of the Southern Border has not been achieved.</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6A5A6CE714EC4694A7B27774E275B315">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Deployment authorities</header>
          <text>Members of the National Guard required to be deployed under this section may be deployed under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc/32/502/f">
              <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/32/502">section 502(f)</external-xref> of title 32, United States Code</cato:entity-ref>, pursuant to a State border control activities plan approved under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc/32/112a">section 112a of such title</cato:entity-ref>, as added by this section, or pursuant to the order of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="9700" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of Defense</cato:entity-ref> under any other provision of law.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="H126B9393E443490CB9B22D33BBA838C4">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Exemption from end strengths and other limitations</header>
        <text>Members of the National Guard deployed pursuant to this section shall not be included in the calculation to determine compliance with—</text> 
<paragraph id="HE84C776A5EBB4FCDADBD0CC42F07CE80">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>limits on end strength; or</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7F9B485957AB41359CC5AF26BD620246">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>limits on the number of National Guard personnel that may be placed on active duty for operational support.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="HA24580C649E143B7BFE837F0943474FA">
        <enum>(c)</enum>
        <header>Federal assistance for state border control activities plans</header>
        <text>
          <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc/32">Title 32, United States Code</cato:entity-ref>, is amended by adding after <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc/32/115">section 115</cato:entity-ref>, <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc/32/116">section 116</cato:entity-ref>:</text> 
<quoted-block style="USC" id="H782BC9E9833F444AA68D2D1C55C73663" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<section id="H71BE640C14934CC9B01F7A4081796B14">
            <enum>116.</enum>
            <header>Assisting <enum-in-header>S</enum-in-header>tates in securing the border</header> 
<subsection id="HB6BB4573F3C74D9DAD85ADA0801D148B">
              <enum>(a)</enum>
              <header>Funding assistance</header>
              <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="9700" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of Defense</cato:entity-ref> shall provide funds to the Governor of a State who submits to the Secretary a State border control activities plan satisfying the requirements of subsection (c). Such funds shall be used for the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H3704295743634A70A0FFD0161409B3D6">
                <enum>(1)</enum>
                <text>The pay, allowances, clothing, subsistence, gratuities, travel, and related expenses, as authorized by State law, of personnel of the National Guard of that State used, while not in Federal service, for the purpose of border control activities.</text>
              </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9A420259CAF041CAB9716616BF5A22F5">
                <enum>(2)</enum>
                <text>The operation and maintenance of the equipment and facilities of the National Guard of that State used for the purpose of border control activities.</text>
              </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HED98D4AE802E4F859C438F67EFD73495">
                <enum>(3)</enum>
                <text>The procurement of services and equipment, and the leasing of equipment, for the National Guard of that State used for the purpose of border control activities. However, the use of such funds for the procurement of equipment may not exceed $10,000 per item, unless approval for procurement of equipment in excess of that amount is granted in advance by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="9700" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of Defense</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
              </paragraph>
            </subsection> 
<subsection id="H5AC5B99B030C48D0A501B7D2EE7855B4">
              <enum>(b)</enum>
              <header>Use of personnel performing full-Time National Guard duty</header> 
<paragraph id="H74FF10D593EC4A1997955A81DE62B5F7">
                <enum>(1)</enum>
                <text>Under regulations prescribed by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="9700" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of Defense</cato:entity-ref>, personnel of the National Guard of a State may, in accordance with the State border control activities plan referred to in subsection (c), be ordered to perform full-time National Guard duty under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc/32/502/f">section 502(f) of this title</cato:entity-ref> for the purpose of carrying out border control activities.</text>
              </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8CC852F205324B5DA3D305BA6E5AA3BD">
                <enum>(2)</enum>
                <text>A member of the National Guard serving full-time National Guard duty under orders authorized under paragraph (1) shall participate in the training required under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc/32/502/a">section 502(a) of this title</cato:entity-ref> in addition to the duty performed for the purpose authorized under that paragraph. The pay, allowances, and other benefits of the member while participating in the training shall be the same as those to which the member is entitled while performing duty for the purpose of carrying out border control activities. The member is not entitled to additional pay, allowances, or other benefits for participation in training required under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc/32/502/a/1">section 502(a)(1) of this title</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
              </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6A5703002D97467490E313AB53A46008">
                <enum>(3)</enum>
                <text>Appropriations available for the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="9700" entity-type="federal-body">Department of Defense</cato:entity-ref> for homeland defense may be used for paying costs associated with a member’s participation in training described in this section. Appropriations available for paying those costs shall be available for making the reimbursements.</text>
              </paragraph>
            </subsection> 
<subsection id="H3B7ADB716F3D49F0831BADB33198313E">
              <enum>(c)</enum>
              <text>To ensure that the use of units and personnel of the National Guard of a State pursuant to a State border control activities plan does not degrade the training and readiness of such units and personnel, the following requirements shall apply in determining the border control activities that units and personnel of the National Guard of a State may perform:</text> 
<paragraph id="HA5C5331917DD4853ABE64BEEE7C0FBCF">
                <enum>(1)</enum>
                <text>The performance of the activities may not adversely affect the quality of that training or otherwise interfere with the ability of a member or unit of the National Guard to perform the military functions of the member or unit.</text>
              </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9AEAA1E749924A618B22B51690B7B370">
                <enum>(2)</enum>
                <text>National Guard personnel will not degrade their military skills as a result of performing the activities.</text>
              </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF3D280D4388A4F178B3EF1D9DED4848C">
                <enum>(3)</enum>
                <text>The performance of the activities will not result in a significant increase in the cost of training.</text>
              </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H44D731A4EA81495BA1356037ECFF2F42">
                <enum>(4)</enum>
                <text>In the case of border control activities performed by a unit organized to serve as a unit, the activities will support valid unit training requirements.</text>
              </paragraph>
            </subsection> 
<subsection id="H3839683068E54C558B6E34C8EDAB14ED">
              <enum>(d)</enum>
              <header>Plan requirements</header>
              <text>A State border control activities plan shall—</text> 
<paragraph id="HDFF463202FD8416298E09AAD47768715">
                <enum>(1)</enum>
                <text>specify how personnel of the National Guard of that State are to be used in border control activities in support of the mission of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="7014" entity-type="federal-body">United States Customs and Border Protection of the Department of Homeland Security</cato:entity-ref>;</text>
              </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBBC80C34F85B4EEA8EAD92416D30C7AF">
                <enum>(2)</enum>
                <text>certify that those operations are to be conducted at a time when the personnel involved are not in Federal service;</text>
              </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFC5F41C6DA7E431A99E6570082686373">
                <enum>(3)</enum>
                <text>certify that participation by National Guard personnel in those operations is service in addition to training required under section 502 of this title;</text>
              </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4CF6B1998E46448682621BBAA5824563">
                <enum>(4)</enum>
                <text>certify that any engineer-type activities (as defined by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="9700" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of Defense</cato:entity-ref>) under the plan will be performed only by units and members of the National Guard;</text>
              </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7B26EADD21284158AEAA6B66BF1183F9">
                <enum>(5)</enum>
                <text>include a certification by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1500" entity-type="federal-body">Attorney General</cato:entity-ref> of the State (or, in the case of a State with no position of <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1500" entity-type="federal-body">Attorney General</cato:entity-ref>, a civilian official of the State equivalent to a State attorney general) that the use of the National Guard of the State for the activities proposed under the plan is authorized by, and is consistent with, State law; and</text>
              </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCEB6A4E42A714AD1A1987E63A828F138">
                <enum>(6)</enum>
                <text>certify that the Governor of the State or a civilian law enforcement official of the State designated by the Governor has determined that any activities included in the plan that are carried out in conjunction with Federal law enforcement agencies serve a State law enforcement purpose.</text>
              </paragraph>
            </subsection> 
<subsection id="H6D38CACA383143038CF34FEE00AF04AB">
              <enum>(e)</enum>
              <header>Examination of plan</header>
              <text>Before funds are provided to the Governor of a State under this section and before members of the National Guard of that State are ordered to full-time National Guard duty as authorized in subsection (b), the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="9700" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of Defense</cato:entity-ref> shall, in consultation with the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="7000" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of Homeland Security</cato:entity-ref>, examine the adequacy of the plan submitted by the Governor under subsection (c). The plan as approved by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="9700" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of Defense</cato:entity-ref> may provide for the use of personnel and equipment of the National Guard of that State to assist <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="7014" entity-type="federal-body">United States Customs and Border Protection</cato:entity-ref> in the transportation of aliens who have violated a Federal immigration law.</text>
            </subsection> 
<subsection id="HA269F2A989A74D05BFC6A967F6F0895E">
              <enum>(f)</enum>
              <header>Annual report</header>
              <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="9700" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of Defense</cato:entity-ref> shall submit to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> within 180 days an annual report regarding assistance provided and activities carried out under this section during the preceding fiscal year. The report shall include the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H93D00B0F9CB34D01986A7C75F1C27ACE">
                <enum>(1)</enum>
                <text>The number of members of the National Guard deployed along the border.</text>
              </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H34788965BB954C7EBA3A035163F37A98">
                <enum>(2)</enum>
                <text>A description of the border control activities conducted by the National Guard along the border.</text>
              </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB09976E68829419A91EC1A2B1DA401D1">
                <enum>(3)</enum>
                <text>An accounting of the amount of funds provided to each State.</text>
              </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H94598634C7D54557A1FFD29B9CF6B8B4">
                <enum>(4)</enum>
                <text>A description of the effect on military training and readiness of using units and personnel of the National Guard to perform activities under the State border control activities plans.</text>
              </paragraph>
            </subsection> 
<subsection id="HB4DC8EEAF1234E9E97A9E8F30E63C0A4">
              <enum>(g)</enum>
              <header>Statutory construction</header>
              <text>Nothing in this section shall be construed as a limitation on the authority of any unit of the National Guard of a State, when such unit is not in Federal service, to perform law enforcement functions authorized to be performed by the National Guard by the laws of the State concerned.</text>
            </subsection> 
<subsection id="HDC88F9E9D0394D85B0DA2F9909D083F6">
              <enum>(h)</enum>
              <header>Border control activities defined</header>
              <text>The term <quote>border control activities</quote>, with respect to the National Guard of a State, means the use of National Guard personnel in border control activities authorized by the law of the State and requested by the Governor of the State in support of the mission of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="7014" entity-type="federal-body">United States Customs and Border Protection of the Department of Homeland Security</cato:entity-ref>, including activities as follows:</text> 
<paragraph id="H5903113D5F824570B5EE4BA48844CEC8">
                <enum>(1)</enum>
                <text>Armed vehicle and foot patrols along the international border between the United States and Mexico.</text>
              </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2E3DADBEAFEC47D583F7AF27D00A3B87">
                <enum>(2)</enum>
                <text>Interdiction of a vehicle, vessel, aircraft or other similar activity.</text>
              </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H07243FCF85ED422092C68E75883AF5B8">
                <enum>(3)</enum>
                <text>Search, seizure, and detention of suspects.</text>
              </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF1CC6FBCBBED4D99AB91342C70C74A1E">
                <enum>(4)</enum>
                <text>Construction of roads, fences, and vehicle barriers.</text>
              </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1F6608780B3B43F5B4AE11EACF39345D">
                <enum>(5)</enum>
                <text>Search and rescue operations.</text>
              </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H969FBC8C06DA46C7AC203ABD88E1E0B3">
                <enum>(6)</enum>
                <text>Intelligence gathering, surveillance, and reconnaissance.</text>
              </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H25F07013E303470FBBC1DB3D7959373A">
                <enum>(7)</enum>
                <text>Aviation support.</text> </paragraph>
            </subsection>
          </section>
          <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
        </quoted-block>
      </subsection>
    </section> 
<section id="H251C31A153F4485E972E775E82A862A5">
      <enum>6.</enum>
      <header>Keeping criminal aliens off of the streets</header> 
<subsection id="H8B403AABB2DC42CDB763EA962FB57FE4">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Detention, release, and removal of aliens ordered removed</header> 
<paragraph id="H869BC0DE426D4AA6BDCE63B43E2132DB">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>In <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Immigration and Nationality Act/s:241/ss:a/p:1/sp:A">section 241(a)(1)(A) of the Immigration and Nationality Act</cato:entity-ref>, strike <quote>
              Attorney General
            </quote> and insert <quote>
              <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="7000" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of Homeland Security</cato:entity-ref>
            </quote>.</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8CE2499488E348798A5C80B9EE3CB01B">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>In <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Immigration and Nationality Act/s:241/ss:a/p:1/sp:B">section 241(a)(1)(B) of the Immigration and Nationality Act</cato:entity-ref>, strike <quote>following:</quote> and insert <quote>following, if the alien is in the custody of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7000">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> on the date in question, and if the alien is not yet in the custody of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7000">Secretary</cato:entity-ref>, then the removal period will start on the day the alien is taken into custody of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7000">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> after the latest of the following:</quote>.</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4EA0F8E54DFC40558063C20B0E57DBC2">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <text>Strike <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Immigration and Nationality Act/s:241/ss:a/p:1/sp:C">section 241(a)(1)(C) of the Immigration and Nationality Act</cato:entity-ref>, and replace with:</text> 
<quoted-block id="HA685D4FDC03447DF9D3CEFFAED01D4E5" style="OLC"> 
<subparagraph id="HCFB97A40DB814ABAACEBC52586E3AD60">
              <enum>(C)</enum>
              <header>Suspension of period</header>
              <text>The removal period shall be extended beyond a period of 90 days and the alien may remain in detention during such extended period if:</text> 
<clause id="HF19CF2EF282045CF89CB195EBA468377">
                <enum>(i)</enum>
                <text>The alien fails or refuses to make timely application in good faith for travel or other documents necessary to the alien’s departure or conspires or acts to prevent the alien’s removal subject to an order of removal, or in any other way fails or refuses to fully cooperate with the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="7000" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of Homeland Security</cato:entity-ref>’s efforts to carry out the removal order.</text>
              </clause> 
<clause id="H9C2EB64E50C34CEDAA7734C637FC49C5">
                <enum>(ii)</enum>
                <text>Any court, immigration judge or the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1500" entity-type="federal-body">Board of Immigration Appeals</cato:entity-ref> orders a stay of the alien’s removal.</text>
              </clause> 
<clause id="H4CB81A826EBF425C8D3D94DA74631FC9">
                <enum>(iii)</enum>
                <text>Another agency takes custody of the alien.</text>
              </clause>
            </subparagraph>
            <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
          </quoted-block>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H933849EC934E47F0B256A63783A44669">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
          <text>In <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Immigration and Nationality Act/s:241/ss:a/p:1/sp:2">section 241(a)(1)(2) of the Immigration and Nationality Act</cato:entity-ref>, strike <quote>
              Attorney General
            </quote> each time it appears and replace with <quote>
              <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="7000" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of Homeland Security</cato:entity-ref>
            </quote>.</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H84DA958ED0A0450C9339A52C2F914A98">
          <enum>(5)</enum>
          <text>Strike <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Immigration and Nationality Act/s:241/ss:a/p:3">section 241(a)(3) of the Immigration and Nationality Act</cato:entity-ref> and replace with:</text> 
<quoted-block id="H96CA47376CA34161ACE47C9DB36FBF0F" style="OLC"> 
<paragraph id="H45FF6CE4EA6B4EDC8F9D3AE5B638F535">
              <enum/>
              <header>Supervision after 90-day period</header>
              <text>If the alien does not leave or is not removed within the removal period, or is not detained pursuant to paragraph (8) of this subsection, the alien pending removal shall be subject to supervision under regulations prescribed by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="7000" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of Homeland Security</cato:entity-ref>. The regulations shall include provisions:</text> 
<subparagraph id="HD54D9DFB518D4A1B892C6596E268A0BD">
                <enum>(A)</enum>
                <text>Requiring the alien—</text> 
<clause id="H84ACB9791EFB418E9D5C15C59F43BDEF">
                  <enum>(i)</enum>
                  <text>to appear before an immigration officer monthly for identification, and to be eligible for placement in detention again if an appearance is missed;</text>
                </clause> 
<clause id="HAA76BF8B934147598E4FEEE4A9B81FEF">
                  <enum>(ii)</enum>
                  <text>to give information under oath about the alien’s nationality, circumstances, habits, associations, and activities, and other information the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="7000" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of Homeland Security</cato:entity-ref> considers appropriate; and</text>
                </clause> 
<clause id="H0AA379396B4D4422AEE78C2A540BC1A5">
                  <enum>(iii)</enum>
                  <text>to obey reasonable restrictions on the alien’s conduct or activities that the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="7000" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of Homeland Security</cato:entity-ref> prescribes for the alien through regulations.</text>
                </clause>
              </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H23941F5BEDE744F5A23CDB533FD5EAAE">
                <enum>(B)</enum>
                <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="7000" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of Homeland Security</cato:entity-ref> must ensure—</text> 
<clause id="H6C7579CBB86C4141AABB4C9892D24402">
                  <enum>(i)</enum>
                  <text>that the alien’s whereabouts are continually monitored electronically to prevent the alien absconding;</text>
                </clause> 
<clause id="H98FBF454BB7147E4AF1262B4648B65C6">
                  <enum>(ii)</enum>
                  <text>that local law enforcement are notified upon the alien’s settlement in a community of the alien’s arrival and known criminal history; and</text>
                </clause> 
<clause id="H3410588094604234A65309A3E0E7D508">
                  <enum>(iii)</enum>
                  <text>that any other reasonable precautions in light of the alien’s circumstances of release are taken for the protection of the community, at the Federal Government’s expense.</text>
                </clause>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
          </quoted-block>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6DAE771125A24FF48E86C5035CEDE9A0">
          <enum>(6)</enum>
          <text>In <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Immigration and Nationality Act/s:241/ss:a/p:4">section 241(a)(4) of the Immigration and Nationality Act</cato:entity-ref>, strike <quote>
              <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1500" entity-type="federal-body">Attorney General</cato:entity-ref>
            </quote> each time it appears and replace with <quote>
              <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="7000" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of Homeland Security</cato:entity-ref>
            </quote>.</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB85D8B8CE7EF4E4495D78F622CD4BC77">
          <enum>(7)</enum>
          <text>In <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Immigration and Nationality Act/s:241/ss:a/p:6">section 241(a)(6) of the Immigration and Nationality Act</cato:entity-ref>, insert following <quote>comply with the order of removal</quote>, <quote>, in accordance with the procedures in paragraph (8)</quote>.</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HEF580315AD1E4DE6AE6299C05F7D77CC">
          <enum>(8)</enum>
          <text>Insert after paragraph (7):</text> 
<quoted-block id="HB6336C4C063A413DB7E37DACA6D8AA8C" style="OLC"> 
<paragraph id="HE71F56764721483A8225CF5869A86296">
              <enum>(8)</enum>
              <header>Detention of aliens from countries refusing repatriation</header>
              <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="7000" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of Homeland Security</cato:entity-ref> shall establish an administrative review process through the rulemaking process, available only to those aliens who are not otherwise subject to mandatory detention, to determine whether and how to release those aliens who have received a final order of removal, and have made all reasonable efforts to comply, including fully cooperating with the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="7000" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of Homeland Security</cato:entity-ref>, but the United States has been unable to return to the alien’s country of origin.</text> 
<subparagraph id="H56DFB3E40C314CC1A556E39ABDF03EDF">
                <enum>(A)</enum>
                <text>The Secretary will have the authority to detain the alien for 90 days beyond the removal period even if this review process is not instituted.</text>
              </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HECC72674CC8A454783474E6F8FA4BA30">
                <enum>(B)</enum>
                <text>At the end of the removal period, the Secretary shall indicate in writing if the review process should be initiated.</text>
              </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H542748AC936A4495945639452C7FC249">
                <enum>(C)</enum>
                <text>The first hearing to determine whether the alien should be released shall be held within 90 days after the Secretary indicates the review process shall be initiated.</text>
              </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC0845DF063A34BC1AA76D96C1A9858CB">
                <enum>(D)</enum>
                <text>Both the Secretary and the alien shall be able to present evidence during this review process.</text>
              </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2931E359CDE248619A10E2931F111044">
                <enum>(E)</enum>
                <text>There will be further hearings every 180 days to determine whether the alien should remain in detention or, if released, be again detained, until the alien is removed from the United States or otherwise leaves the country.</text>
              </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H4EDC456C320F4E22BE2C9467FA66221C">
                <enum>(F)</enum>
                <text>During the review process, the alien may continue to be detained, or, if released, shall be detained again, if evidence is presented at the first or subsequent hearing that—</text> 
<clause id="H367D737A1FE94EEBA0711E8662502348">
                  <enum>(i)</enum>
                  <text>there is still any significant likelihood the alien may be removed,</text>
                </clause> 
<clause id="HE5F15C839397498BA4F846E2D2D4D2D1">
                  <enum>(ii)</enum>
                  <text>the alien has a highly contagious disease that poses a threat to public safety,</text>
                </clause> 
<clause id="HF0DF0DF8B1DF42F3BB60BD2FEBE863DB">
                  <enum>(iii)</enum>
                  <text>the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1900" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref> says release would have adverse foreign policy consequences,</text>
                </clause> 
<clause id="HA481946D2E9341C8B77F3F1F4C37D95D">
                  <enum>(iv)</enum>
                  <text>there is reason to believe based on classified information that releasing the alien would threaten the security of the United States,</text>
                </clause> 
<clause id="HB2E92A763EF74EA79307F52D9820A18C">
                  <enum>(v)</enum>
                  <text>the release of the alien would threaten the safety of the community or any individual,</text>
                </clause> 
<clause id="H3DA98663A07D446686CD9B1DC41CDC21">
                  <enum>(vi)</enum>
                  <text>conditions of release cannot be expected to ensure the safety of the community,</text>
                </clause> 
<clause id="HC6325F331F56470780A1CC4B12078F13">
                  <enum>(vii)</enum>
                  <text>the alien has committed any aggravated felonies as defined in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Immigration and Nationality Act/s:101/ss:a/p:43/sp:A">section 101(a)(43)(A)</cato:entity-ref> of this Act, or a crime of violence as defined in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/18">
                      <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc/16/18">16 U.S.C. 18</cato:entity-ref>
                    </external-xref>, or</text>
                </clause> 
<clause id="HD1D1DB6B6A074419A61AB65E9A04D9B9">
                  <enum>(viii)</enum>
                  <text>because of a mental condition the alien is likely to commit a crime of violence or threaten the safety of himself or any other person.</text>
                </clause>
              </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H1F69F8BBB7D14407A629AB8AED64375B">
                <enum>(G)</enum>
                <text>The review will allow one administrative appeal of the outcome of the hearing. After the alien has exhausted his administrative remedies, review of the outcome will only be available through habeas corpus proceedings under the U.S. District Court for the District of Columbia.</text>
              </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF7F2B04EAB8F4A968BCE52E864B3F551">
                <enum>(H)</enum>
                <text>If the review determines that the alien should be released, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="7000" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of Homeland Security</cato:entity-ref> shall provide notice to the chief law enforcement officers of the State and local jurisdiction in which the alien is released of the identity of the alien and the circumstances which under which he or she was not able to be removed or detained, and will describe what sanctions, if any, have been applied to the alien’s country, if the alien has not been removed because that country has refused to accept the alien.</text>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
          </quoted-block>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="H9163055B80914C5EBF16CF63B9B872E6">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <text>Strike <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Immigration and Nationality Act/s:243/ss:d">section 243(d) of the Immigration and Nationality Act</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1253">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/8/1253/d">8 U.S.C. 1253(d)</cato:entity-ref>
          </external-xref>)</cato:entity> and replace with the following:</text> 
<quoted-block id="H1931736F3D184ECE8D64E022751F8482" style="OLC"> 
<subsection id="HF7258609967F407F8A9233FFCFECE654">
            <enum>(d)</enum>
            <header>Sanctions on countries which deny or delay accepting aliens</header> 
<paragraph id="HACF825381069487B975FC3C85749BD52">
              <enum>(1)</enum>
              <header>Countries refusing or unreasonably delaying repatriation</header>
              <text>If a country for more than 60 days after receiving a request from an official of the United States who is authorized to make such a request refuses to accept an alien who is a citizen, national, subject, or resident, that country will be considered to be refusing or unreasonably delaying repatriation.</text>
            </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3E81F64509E947509F60FFCB10DDE315">
              <enum>(2)</enum>
              <header>Report</header> 
<subparagraph id="H57C0F48E607C4A69A3FA350A2E89B3C5">
                <enum>(A)</enum>
                <text>Within 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="7000" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of Homeland Security</cato:entity-ref> shall prepare, publish publicly to the Department of Homeland Security Website, and submit to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> a report listing for each month the following:</text> 
<clause id="HD81D837A51814BB8BA2E345DCE992C2C">
                  <enum>(i)</enum>
                  <text>The number of aliens without lawful status or presence released from the custody of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="7000" entity-type="federal-body">Department of Homeland Security</cato:entity-ref> with criminal convictions or arrests, including a list of the crimes for which each alien was convicted or arrested, the reason for the release from custody, and the detention status of each alien.</text>
                </clause> 
<clause id="H38A2FDAEC3DE473D8384130A2B581D00">
                  <enum>(ii)</enum>
                  <text>The number of aliens without lawful status or presence that come from a country, which, in the previous six months, refused or unreasonably delaying repatriating its citizens, nationals, subjects, or residents, and will include the total number of aliens from each country that has refused or delayed repatriation, the detention status of each of these aliens, and the criminal record of each of these aliens.</text>
                </clause>
              </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB1FC75F2FC0943AAAEDCC69D68166E06">
                <enum>(B)</enum>
                <text>Following the first report, the Secretary shall submit subsequent reports annually. If the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="7000" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of Homeland Security</cato:entity-ref> misses the deadline for submitting one of these reports by more than 90 days, any American citizen has a cause of action in the United States District Court against the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7000">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> to compel the Secretary to publish the late report.</text>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9EC6B4BEC3FD423B88B65AAB7D032234">
              <enum>(3)</enum>
              <header>Visas</header>
              <text>Not later than 60 days after the first report has been submitted, and for each report thereafter, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1900" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref> may not issue a visa to any citizen, national, subject, or resident of a country listed in the report. This subsection will apply to the country until a report pursuant to subsection (2) of this section is submitted to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7000">Congress</cato:entity-ref> or the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="7000" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of Homeland Security</cato:entity-ref> otherwise certifies that the country no longer meets the requirements to be listed in the report, and the country has issued appropriate travel documents to and accepted every alien listed in a report that they have refused. If the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1900" entity-type="federal-body">State Department</cato:entity-ref> should issue a visa to a citizen, national, subject, or resident when it is not legal to do so under this section, that visa shall be null and void under law. If a <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1900" entity-type="federal-body">State Department</cato:entity-ref> issues a visa when it is not legal to do so under this section, employees of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1900" entity-type="federal-body">State Department</cato:entity-ref> shall no longer be eligible for bonuses or salary increases until it has revoked all such unlawful visas and stopped issuing such visas.</text>
            </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBFD7623E58EA43C292BDF27F28F1DDCB">
              <enum>(4)</enum>
              <header>Trade</header>
              <text>If a country listed in the report has any favored or preferred status in a trade agreement with the United States, the country will lose that status. This sanction will apply to the country until another report is submitted to Congress or the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="7000" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of Homeland Security</cato:entity-ref> otherwise certifies that the country no longer meets the requirements to be listed in the report, and the country has issued appropriate travel documents to and accepted every alien listed in a report that they have refused.</text>
            </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H600B7467743F49019C241BAC9A444A86">
              <enum>(5)</enum>
              <header>Foreign aid</header>
              <text>If a country listed in the report receives any money from the United States in foreign aid, the United States will discontinue all such aid. This sanction will apply to the country until another report is submitted to Congress or the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="7000" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of Homeland Security</cato:entity-ref> otherwise certifies that the country no longer meets the requirements to be listed in the report, and the country has issued appropriate travel documents to and accepted every alien listed in a report that they have refused.</text>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
        </quoted-block>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="H3E24F6E1A8C64C8BA8220466F1E873DF">
        <enum>(c)</enum>
        <header>Severability</header>
        <text>If any of the provisions of this Act is held to be invalid for any reason, the remainder of the Act shall not be affected by such holding.</text>
      </subsection>
    </section> 
<section id="H8C873C5BC2184AC8AE8FA2F06D81BD8E">
      <enum>7.</enum>
      <header>Grounds of inadmissibility and deportability for alien gang members</header> 
<subsection id="H47E77ACE1FEC499195F2F01A2EBC4468">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Definition of gang member</header>
        <text>
          <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Immigration and Nationality Act/s:101/ss:a">Section 101(a) of the Immigration and Nationality Act</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/8/1101/a">8 U.S.C. 1101(a)</cato:entity-ref>
          </external-xref>)</cato:entity> is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block id="H65BE676EFBCA4F1293623981A0EA10D4" style="OLC"> 
<paragraph id="HC62D427E150C4FDEA1005690371ABACE">
            <enum>(53)</enum> 
<subparagraph id="HD3E2A10F5DD74FD897CB5F24EBB40536" display-inline="yes-display-inline" indent="subparagraph">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>The term <quote>criminal gang</quote> means an ongoing group, club, organization, or association of 5 or more persons that has as one of its primary purposes the commission of 1 or more of the following criminal offenses and the members of which engage, or have engaged within the past 5 years, in a continuing series of such offenses, or that has been designated as a criminal gang by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="7000" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of Homeland Security</cato:entity-ref>, in consultation with the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1500" entity-type="federal-body">Attorney General</cato:entity-ref>, as meeting these criteria. The offenses described, whether in violation of Federal or State law or foreign law and regardless of whether the offenses occurred before, on, or after the date of the enactment of this paragraph, are the following:</text> 
<clause id="H92BEAC84BCBB4DD69BD6D6264D424096" indent="subparagraph">
                <enum>(i)</enum>
                <text>A <quote>felony drug offense</quote> (as defined in <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
                    <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Controlled Substances Act/s:102">section 102 of the Controlled Substances Act</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/802">
                    <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/21/802">21 U.S.C. 802</cato:entity-ref>
                  </external-xref>)</cato:entity>).</text>
              </clause> 
<clause id="H74EBF591809346109F97DFB8D7EF335D" indent="subparagraph">
                <enum>(ii)</enum>
                <text>An offense under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Immigration and Nationality Act/s:274">section 274</cato:entity-ref> (related to bringing in and harboring certain aliens), <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Immigration and Nationality Act/s:277">section 277</cato:entity-ref> (relating to aiding or assisting certain aliens to enter the United States), or <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Immigration and Nationality Act/s:278">section 278</cato:entity-ref> (relating to importation of alien for immoral purpose).</text>
              </clause> 
<clause id="H649D6FF7F7EC471BA778440F90755E6C" indent="subparagraph">
                <enum>(iii)</enum>
                <text>A crime of violence (as defined in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc/18/16">
                    <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/18/16">section 16</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code</cato:entity-ref>).</text>
              </clause> 
<clause id="H895370D89AC14A718C1584798C712A40" indent="subparagraph">
                <enum>(iv)</enum>
                <text>A crime involving obstruction of justice, tampering with or retaliating against a witness, victim, or informant, or burglary.</text>
              </clause> 
<clause id="H9CB0F8CCC7AA4391B4DE048FF2E46BE6" indent="subparagraph">
                <enum>(v)</enum>
                <text>Any conduct punishable under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc/18/1028">sections <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/18/1028">1028</external-xref>
                  </cato:entity-ref> and <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc/18/1029">
                    <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/18/1029">1029</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code</cato:entity-ref> (relating to fraud and related activity in connection with identification documents or access devices), <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc/18/1581..1594">sections 1581 through 1594 of such title</cato:entity-ref> (relating to peonage, slavery and trafficking in persons), <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc/18/1952">section 1952 of such title</cato:entity-ref> (relating to interstate and foreign travel or transportation in aid of racketeering enterprises), <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc/18/1956">section 1956 of such title</cato:entity-ref> (relating to the laundering of monetary instruments), <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc/18/1957">section 1957 of such title</cato:entity-ref> (relating to engaging in monetary transactions in property derived from specified unlawful activity), or <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc/18/2312..2315">sections 2312 through 2315 of such title</cato:entity-ref> (relating to interstate transportation of stolen motor vehicles or stolen property).</text>
              </clause> 
<clause id="H159A624460C24D24BA4D4999D6998203" indent="subparagraph">
                <enum>(vi)</enum>
                <text>A conspiracy to commit an offense described in clauses (i) through (v).</text>
              </clause>
            </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H827E1D70EB86412781F73940C379036E" indent="paragraph">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law (including any effective date), the term applies regardless of whether the conduct occurred before, on, or after the date of enactment of this paragraph.</text>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
        </quoted-block>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="HED18F9670E8E407CBA94E7268178AF8D">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Inadmissibility</header>
        <text>
          <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Immigration and Nationality Act/s:212/ss:a/p:2">Section 212(a)(2) of such Act</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1182">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/8/1182/a/2">8 U.S.C. 1182(a)(2)</cato:entity-ref>
          </external-xref>)</cato:entity>, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block id="H18C2B839FED74B7898261332DF9F0069" style="OLC"> 
<subparagraph id="H8ACD6BC9ECE6478CBF0563AC47F00183">
            <enum>(J)</enum>
            <header>Aliens associated with criminal gangs</header>
            <text>Any alien is inadmissible who a consular officer, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="7000" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of Homeland Security</cato:entity-ref>, or the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1500" entity-type="federal-body">Attorney General</cato:entity-ref> knows or has reason to believe—</text> 
<clause id="H60398E247680430BBD9F8D3B5F797C70">
              <enum>(i)</enum>
              <text>to be or to have been a member of a criminal gang (as defined in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Immigration and Nationality Act/s:101/ss:a/p:53" proposed="true">section 101(a)(53)</cato:entity-ref>); or</text>
            </clause> 
<clause id="HECB680E639534876B4E79F72FD3366B4">
              <enum>(ii)</enum>
              <text>to have participated in the activities of a criminal gang (as defined in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Immigration and Nationality Act/s:101/ss:a/p:53" proposed="true">section 101(a)(53)</cato:entity-ref>), knowing or having reason to know that such activities will promote, further, aid, or support the illegal activity of the criminal gang.</text>
            </clause>
          </subparagraph>
          <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
        </quoted-block>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="H4D79C1B4DCF842D091FB6B4A861EAA12">
        <enum>(c)</enum>
        <header>Deportability</header>
        <text>
          <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Immigration and Nationality Act/s:237/ss:a/p:2">Section 237(a)(2) of the Immigration and Nationality Act</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1227">
            <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc/8/1227/a/2">8 U.S.C. 1227(a)(2)</cato:entity-ref>
          </external-xref>), is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block id="H0534AD4162F44E3C87B0CB9939DA8A4D" style="OLC"> 
<subparagraph id="HDDBFA74FD812428CB519AAD2750BEEE0">
            <enum>(G)</enum>
            <header>Aliens associated with criminal gangs</header>
            <text>Any alien is deportable who the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="7000" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of Homeland Security</cato:entity-ref> or the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1500" entity-type="federal-body">Attorney General</cato:entity-ref> knows or has reason to believe—</text> 
<clause id="H260F81AF63C140C9A1ED312A3C91AA29">
              <enum>(i)</enum>
              <text>is or has been a member of a criminal gang (as defined in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Immigration and Nationality Act/s:101/ss:a/p:53" proposed="true">section 101(a)(53)</cato:entity-ref>); or</text>
            </clause> 
<clause id="HC6444F94758E4DAF93DC9B11AD96120B">
              <enum>(ii)</enum>
              <text>has participated in the activities of a criminal gang (as so defined), knowing or having reason to know that such activities will promote, further, aid, or support the illegal activity of the criminal gang.</text>
            </clause>
          </subparagraph>
          <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
        </quoted-block>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="HE6FC980AE3854147986C1E3A5CC50BAD">
        <enum>(d)</enum>
        <header>Designation</header> 
<paragraph id="HDFD79EDE3E6046C4A68301966568028D">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>In general</header>
          <text>The <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Immigration and Nationality Act">Immigration and Nationality Act</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1182">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/8/1182">8 U.S.C. 1182</cato:entity-ref>
            </external-xref>)</cato:entity> is amended by inserting after <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Immigration and Nationality Act/s:219">section 219</cato:entity-ref> the following:</text> 
<quoted-block id="H623BD701C7A346DB9468F217C28739DB" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HA5CD9DF4C3784CA3AE67D1143130B31C">
              <enum>220.</enum>
              <header>Designation of Criminal Street Gang</header> 
<subsection id="H7AD06EF04FB546478607619509ABC130">
                <enum>(a)</enum>
                <header>Designation</header>
                <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="7000" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of Homeland Security</cato:entity-ref>, in consultation with the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1500" entity-type="federal-body">Attorney General</cato:entity-ref> and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1900" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref>, may designate a group or association as a criminal street gang if its conduct is described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Immigration and Nationality Act/s:101/ss:a/p:53" proposed="true">section 101(a)(53)</cato:entity-ref> or if the group or association conduct poses a significant risk that threatens the security and the public safety, national security, homeland security, foreign policy, or economy of the United States.</text>
              </subsection> 
<subsection id="HD90BED7C7BDB41728AFFF78F4C58A4AF">
                <enum>(b)</enum>
                <header>Effective date</header>
                <text>Designations under subsection (a) shall remain in effect until the designation is revoked after consultation between the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="7000" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of Homeland Security</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1500" entity-type="federal-body">Attorney General</cato:entity-ref>, and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1900" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref> or is terminated in accordance with Federal law. The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7000">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall notify the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="committee" entity-id="SSJU00">Senate Judiciary Committee</cato:entity-ref> and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="committee" entity-id="HJU00">House Judiciary Committee</cato:entity-ref> of any revocation of designation at least 30 days before the revocation takes effect.</text>
              </subsection>
            </section>
            <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
          </quoted-block>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA01038CB14854C548A0FD46E63EA4D76">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Clerical amendment</header>
          <text>The table of contents for such Act is amended by inserting after the item relating to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Immigration and Nationality Act/s:219">section 219</cato:entity-ref> the following:</text> 
<toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> 
<toc-entry level="section">
              <quote>Sec. 220. Designation of criminal street gang.</quote>.</toc-entry>
          </toc> 
<quoted-block id="H1672DA16A4844F738BAE0F33F8E1A5BE" style="OLC"> <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
          </quoted-block>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="HAA7A69E7C30F4BD78382016D0956937B">
        <enum>(e)</enum>
        <header>Mandatory detention</header> 
<paragraph id="H7D11C964979748FB846180720CE4C112">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>In general</header>
          <text>
            <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Immigration and Nationality Act/s:236/ss:c/p:1/sp:D">Section 236(c)(1)(D) of the Immigration and Nationality Act</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1226">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/8/1226/c/1/D">8 U.S.C. 1226(c)(1)(D)</cato:entity-ref>
            </external-xref>)</cato:entity> is amended—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H1869A871AEB0425C8E1DE8BF400D064B">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>by inserting <quote>or <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Immigration and Nationality Act/s:212/ss:a/p:2/sp:J" proposed="true">212(a)(2)(J)</cato:entity-ref>,</quote> after <quote>212(a)(3)(B)</quote>; and</text>
          </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2BD699F42078404084031240BE2545FF">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>by inserting <quote>or <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Immigration and Nationality Act/s:237/ss:c/p:1/sp:G" proposed="true">237(a)(2)(G)</cato:entity-ref>,</quote> before <quote>237(a)(4)(B)</quote>.</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6EDC8B55B5034E988D1566FBDA8365C7">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Annual report</header>
          <text>Not later than 180 days after the end of each fiscal year, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="7000" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of Homeland Security</cato:entity-ref>, after consultation with the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1500" entity-type="federal-body">Department of Justice</cato:entity-ref>, shall submit a report to the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="HJU00" entity-type="committee">Committees on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives</cato:entity-ref> and of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="committee" entity-id="SSJU00">Senate</cato:entity-ref> on the number of aliens detained under the amendments made by paragraph (1).</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="HA849FA6B0AE84F3F901B277C514A1C91">
        <enum>(f)</enum>
        <header>Asylum claims based on gang affiliation</header> 
<paragraph id="H362359BDDD1B49CDBF4E442EFF823B92">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>Inapplicability of restriction on removal to certain countries</header>
          <text>
            <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Immigration and Nationality Act/s:241/ss:b/p:3/sp:B">Section 241(b)(3)(B) of the Immigration and Nationality Act</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1251">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/8/1251/b/3/B">8 U.S.C. 1251(b)(3)(B)</cato:entity-ref>
            </external-xref>)</cato:entity> is amended, in the matter preceding clause (i), by inserting <quote>who is described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Immigration and Nationality Act/s:212/ss:a/p:2/sp:J/cl:i" proposed="true">section 212(a)(2)(J)(i)</cato:entity-ref> or <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Immigration and Nationality Act/s:237/ss:a/p:2/sp:G/cl:i" proposed="true">section 237(a)(2)(G)(i)</cato:entity-ref> or who is</quote> following <quote>to an alien</quote>.</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA9649351BB4F4D41AF4AAD1D5D19C004">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Ineligibility for asylum</header>
          <text>
            <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Immigration and Nationality Act/s:208/ss:b/p:2/sp:A">Section 208(b)(2)(A) of such Act</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1158">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/8/1158/b/2/A">8 U.S.C. 1158(b)(2)(A)</cato:entity-ref>
            </external-xref>)</cato:entity> is amended—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HC59C220850D64F5F954089E87EC69475">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>in clause (v), by striking <quote>or</quote> at the end;</text>
          </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HDD7FADA1AA2E4E33A3DD1099A8A616F6">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>by redesignating clause (vi) as clause (vii); and</text>
          </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H187FC408BF34492A885D6C8BB6F14B95">
            <enum>(C)</enum>
            <text>by inserting after clause (v) the following:</text> 
<quoted-block id="H3E14ED45C5C04D15851A77BF75F8B98E" style="OLC"> 
<clause id="H638E4253095F419BBAA923E8EE7D0C32">
                <enum>(vi)</enum>
                <text>the alien is described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Immigration and Nationality Act/s:212/ss:a/p:2/sp:J/cl:i" proposed="true">section 212(a)(2)(J)(i)</cato:entity-ref> or <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Immigration and Nationality Act/s:237/ss:a/p:2/sp:G/cl:i" proposed="true">section 237(a)(2)(G)(i)</cato:entity-ref> (relating to participation in criminal street gangs); or</text>
              </clause>
              <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
            </quoted-block>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="H52C00BA0F66041DD978DDDB2601BA2EA">
        <enum>(g)</enum>
        <header>Temporary protected status</header>
        <text>
          <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Immigration and Nationality Act/s:244">Section 244 of such Act</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1254a">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/8/1254a">8 U.S.C. 1254a</cato:entity-ref>
          </external-xref>)</cato:entity> is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="HD0007AEB54614B20A2A2AEC7AE9226E6">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>by striking <quote>
              <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1500" entity-type="federal-body">Attorney General</cato:entity-ref>
            </quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>
              <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="7000" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of Homeland Security</cato:entity-ref>
            </quote>;</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE29D2619E0C546208940BF36097B7ECA">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>in subparagraph (c)(2)(B), by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block id="H692D37D7B90E4461B93E9C22F8D72982" style="OLC"> 
<clause id="H69991EEC55A34978853ABD01B84A2F97">
              <enum>(iii)</enum>
              <text>the alien is, or at any time after admission has been, a member of a criminal gang (as defined in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Immigration and Nationality Act/s:101/ss:a/p:53" proposed="true">section 101(a)(53)</cato:entity-ref>).</text>
            </clause>
            <after-quoted-block>; and </after-quoted-block>
          </quoted-block>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H92024CB6C59B411A97071F3434B57097">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <text>in subsection (d)—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H8522C4C9B2D64D43A16F0F2DB0D0FBD1">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>by striking paragraph (3) and redesignating paragraph (4) as paragraph (3); and</text>
          </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE918AB6760E14A1DA53A6298AFDA54FD">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>in paragraph (3), as redesignated, by adding at the end the following: <quote>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="7000" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of Homeland Security</cato:entity-ref> may detain an alien provided temporary protected status under this section whenever appropriate under any other provision of law.</quote>.</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="HD71ED72BE29940C49E37BFC7A2EB3843">
        <enum>(h)</enum>
        <header>Effective date</header>
        <text>The amendments made by this section shall take effect on the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
      </subsection>
    </section> 
<section id="H29B909E083DA47968D2FF782EC3237DA">
      <enum>8.</enum>
      <header>Additional judges</header> 
<subsection id="HA3DCD8152FDD4686A88F5122C910E10D">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Evaluation</header>
        <text>Not later than 30 days after the enactment of this Act, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1500" entity-type="federal-body">Attorney General</cato:entity-ref>, in consultation with the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="7000" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of Homeland Security</cato:entity-ref>, shall submit to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> a report indicating the number, if any, of additional immigration judges that are needed to process the backlog of removal cases.</text>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="H5DDCC46A258E4950B586C6BDA65CC4B7">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Reporting</header>
        <text>Following the initial report, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1500" entity-type="federal-body">Attorney General</cato:entity-ref>, in consultation with the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="7000" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of Homeland Security</cato:entity-ref>, shall thereafter submit a report annually to the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="committee" entity-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary in the Senate</cato:entity-ref> and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="committee" entity-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary in the House</cato:entity-ref>, indicating the number of immigration judges needed for the following fiscal year.</text>
      </subsection>
    </section> 
<section id="H4F81059AF057443BA7F266B4FF5D3027">
      <enum>9.</enum>
      <header>Additional detention space</header> 
<subsection id="HB3BA8DCC374E4B6DBA61F1E9B6D255F3">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Additional detention space needed To house unlawful entrants</header>
        <text>Not later than 30 days of enactment, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="7000" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of Homeland Security</cato:entity-ref> shall submit to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> a request for additional beds and detention space needed to hold criminal aliens and aliens without lawful presence or lawful status.</text>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="HFAA356B18C1742EAA25C6E0ABF0686CE">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Reporting</header>
        <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="7000" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of Homeland Security</cato:entity-ref> shall submit to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> annually a report indicating the number, if any, of additional detention beds and detention space needed to hold criminal aliens and aliens without lawful presence or lawful status.</text>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="HDA57E94B8B244B44A8818ED8D0070C44">
        <enum>(c)</enum>
        <header>Funding</header>
        <text>Such requests are hereby authorized to be funded.</text>
      </subsection>
    </section> 
<section id="H6E292C21156C4856BE5BB84977666FB7">
      <enum>10.</enum>
      <header>Offsets</header> 
<subsection id="HA1D04B685ED34841B2AD77B372DFA072">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Closing the additional child tax credit loophole</header> 
<paragraph id="H61ACA953B0784137A82475C704C84582">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>In general</header>
          <text>
            <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:24/ss:e">Subsection (e) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/24">section 24</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986</cato:entity-ref> is amended by striking <quote>under this section to a taxpayer</quote> and all that follows and inserting </text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H3F8519AEC4334C1B944F37BBCF3720DA" display-inline="yes-display-inline">
            <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">under this section to any taxpayer unless—</text>
<subparagraph id="HC8E2163E02044CB8A0FF96674D38A6C1">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>such taxpayer includes the taxpayer’s valid identification number (as defined in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:6428/ss:h/p:2">section 6428(h)(2)</cato:entity-ref>) on the return of tax for the taxable year, and</text>
            </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H46A17C371BC24B0F8C47165728FEB892">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>with respect to any qualifying child, the taxpayer includes the name and taxpayer identification number of such qualifying child on such return of tax.</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
          </quoted-block>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBB0DBC94AE7D4077A1AD6264E9B3A206">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Effective date</header>
          <text>The amendment made by this section shall apply to the first full taxable year and all subsequent years following the date of enactment of this Act.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="HFE8EC7EE52974CFE9D414EAC5C13C832">
        <enum>(b)</enum> <header>
          Section 1641 of title 8 of the United States Code is amended by adding</header> 
<paragraph id="HEDD02DC72E804D52BA3A276F51F025D3">
          <enum>(1)</enum> <header>Limitation on benefits for previously unlawful aliens</header>
<quoted-block id="H4C170EF5F61A4E208E1400971C1E7ABA" style="OLC"> 
<subsection id="H7A634015128A4BCD9E98DC2FA75BA7F9">
              <enum>(d)</enum>
              <header>Limitation on benefits for previously unlawful aliens</header>
              <text>Any alien in violation of <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Immigration and Nationality Act/s:212/ss:a/p:6">section 212(a)(6)</cato:entity-ref> or <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Immigration and Nationality Act/s:212/ss:a/p:7">section 212(a)(7) of the Immigration and Nationality Act</cato:entity-ref> who gains lawful status pursuant to an Act of Congress, or lawful status or lawful presence pursuant to an order or policy directive by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1100" entity-type="federal-body">Executive Branch</cato:entity-ref>, is hereby not qualified for public benefits under this section.</text>
            </subsection>
            <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
          </quoted-block>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H56152D48890C4C6BACD15EEE2B6DA27B">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Effective date</header>
          <text>This provision shall be effective upon enactment of this Act.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="H2A3E4F06041B44B3B4DA8BE18388ECD6">
        <enum>(c)</enum>
        <header>Foreign remittance tax</header> 
<paragraph id="HE2C7147BB5A949C5AFA601A8ECDEA78E">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>In general</header>
          <text>
            <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="public-law" value="public-law/111/203/s:1073">Section 1073 of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/203">
              Public Law 111–203
            </external-xref> i</cato:entity-ref>s amended by adding:</text> 
<quoted-block id="HB0D61D4C240E4F748B026B14D584C833" style="OLC"> 
<subsection id="H0E2F3E568E4B4CCF89141E9D120576DC">
              <enum/>
              <header>Taxation of Remittances</header>
              <text display-inline="yes-display-inline"> All monetary remittances sent from senders in the United States to recipients in any of the top ten remittance recipient nations shall be taxed at the rate of ten percent (10%) of the transmitted amount, provided however that the transmitters shall not be required to provide to the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="2050" entity-type="federal-body">Internal Revenue Service</cato:entity-ref> information with respect to each individual transmission. The top ten remittance recipients are defined as those ten nations with the greatest money transfers from the United States, from reported data required in <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/203">
                  <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="public-law" value="public-law/111/203">Public Law 111–203</cato:entity-ref>
                </external-xref>. </text>
            </subsection>
            <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
          </quoted-block>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H868E13D1633C48409729E6961544B548">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Effective date</header>
          <text>This provision shall be effective upon enactment of this Act.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
    </section> 
<section id="H60D6CE26A25440B582EEED4C1764E836">
      <enum>11.</enum>
      <header>Limitation on deferred action for childhood arrivals; restrictions on employment authorization for aliens not in lawful status</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">No agency or instrumentality of the Federal Government may use Federal funding or resources—</text> 
<paragraph id="H8930EE4C556D4BA88EECA242FCED91E7">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text>to consider or adjudicate any new or previously denied application of any alien requesting consideration of deferred action for childhood arrivals, as authorized by Executive memorandum on August 15, 2012; or</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE0707E1B5B444F94ADC8D5358C5C4B6F">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text>to authorize any alien to work in the United States if such alien—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H9465CAFE6B8F40A1A969F0DEB1C340B8">
          <enum>(A)</enum>
          <text>was not lawfully admitted into the United States in compliance with the <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Immigration and Nationality Act">Immigration and Nationality Act</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/8/1101/etseq">8 U.S.C. 1101 et seq.</cato:entity-ref>
            </external-xref>)</cato:entity>; and</text>
        </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9D17E944BBC1430193B0F45CF31625B1">
          <enum>(B)</enum>
          <text>is not in lawful status in the United States on the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
        </subparagraph>
      </paragraph>
    </section> 
</legis-body> 
</bill>
</doc>