<doc>
  <docmeta id="113hr324eh">
    <bill congress="113" type="hr" number="324" version="eh"/>
    <revision size="6906" annotations="0" status="complete" id="6" commit-time="2013-09-11T01:27:59Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113hr324eh/6.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <bill bill-stage="Engrossed-in-House" dms-id="H95D830FC42B742499F52678E5807D4B9" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc" stage-count="1"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>113 HR 324 EH: To grant the Congressional Gold Medal, collectively, to the First Special Service Force, in recognition of its superior service during World War II.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date/>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="no">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>113th CONGRESS</congress> <session>1st Session</session> 
<legis-num>H. R. 324</legis-num> 
<current-chamber display="no">IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type> 
<official-title display="yes">To grant the Congressional Gold Medal, collectively, to the First Special Service Force, in recognition of its superior service during World War II.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H899C34DCE4324FAE9C432739295C4D7A" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H3A5F41948630455DAAE4FD82692C90CC" section-type="section-one">
      <enum>1.</enum>
      <header>Findings</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">
        <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> finds the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H0CA2FF4C5B4D4505BD60E56910C3A728">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The First Special Service Force (the <quote>Force</quote>), a military unit composed of volunteers from the United States and Canada, was activated in July 1942 at Fort Harrison near Helena, Montana.</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0117DA0576B84A64922C4C50263DE855">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text>The Force was initially intended to target military and industrial installations that were supporting the German war effort, including important hydroelectric plants, which would severely limit the production of strategic materials used by the Axis powers.</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBE34334A435C473FAC41C70349F6ACD0">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <text>From July 1942 through June 1943, volunteers of the Force trained in hazardous, arctic conditions in the mountains of western Montana, and in the waterways of Camp Bradford, Virginia.</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8FE3BDE7E931433D81B4BFFF6CA15A6D">
        <enum>(4)</enum>
        <text>The combat echelon of the Force totaled 1,800 soldiers, half from the United States and half from Canada.</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HAA55B3B3E0F745E58E5C8F9DB7A984C1">
        <enum>(5)</enum>
        <text>The Force also contained a service battalion, composed of 800 members from the United States, that provided important support for the combat troops.</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC87FDFD3716E437AB5FDAF714D5D59CB">
        <enum>(6)</enum>
        <text>A special bond developed between the Canadian and United States soldiers, who were not segregated by country, although the commander of the Force was a United States colonel.</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H31AEB51FE0DD499C917A7CAE921253AA">
        <enum>(7)</enum>
        <text>The Force was the only unit formed during World War II that consisted of troops from Canada and the United States.</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB4B93BA2E1EB44FD8077897AD672DBBF">
        <enum>(8)</enum>
        <text>In October 1943, the Force went to Italy, where it fought in battles south of Cassino, including Monte La Difensa and Monte Majo, two mountain peaks that were a critical anchor of the German defense line.</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCBF34B562F1F4B28A8720C8FD775C8AD">
        <enum>(9)</enum>
        <text>During the night of December 3, 1943, the Force ascended to the top of the precipitous face of Monte La Difensa, where the Force suffered heavy casualties and overcame fierce resistance to overtake the German line.</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H80D32EE7A9EB4F5FA37F195764C52127">
        <enum>(10)</enum>
        <text>After the battle for La Difensa, the Force continued to fight tough battles at high altitudes, in rugged terrain, and in severe weather.</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7F4C1E9F1B10454DB1B7F1AC90FB6D1E">
        <enum>(11)</enum>
        <text>After battles on the strongly defended Italian peaks of Sammucro, Vischiataro, and Remetanea, the size of the Force had been reduced from 1,800 soldiers to fewer than 500.</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2BD4D995BF5A401D8483641D63DF5CE3">
        <enum>(12)</enum>
        <text>For 4 months in 1944, the Force engaged in raids and aggressive patrols at the Anzio Beachhead.</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1A28C147833149888141C0632CD178E8">
        <enum>(13)</enum>
        <text>On June 4, 1944, members of the Force were among the first Allied troops to liberate Rome.</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8F7A964D7A7549DA826B071220341777">
        <enum>(14)</enum>
        <text>After liberating Rome, the Force moved to southern Italy and prepared to assist in the liberation of France.</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA076DB272D374C449F4C136DB55E9FA4">
        <enum>(15)</enum>
        <text>During the early morning of August 15, 1944, members of the Force made silent landings on Les Iles D'Hyeres, small islands in the Mediterranean Sea along the southern coast of France.</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3EE7B79A12D64E028BA2891E7DFE0323">
        <enum>(16)</enum>
        <text>The Force faced a sustained and withering assault from the German garrisons as the Force progressed from the islands to the Franco-Italian border.</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4D87E33F3B9941D98959F96AEC121D37">
        <enum>(17)</enum>
        <text>After the Allied forces secured the Franco-Italian border, the United States Army ordered the disbandment of the Force on December 5, 1944, in Nice, France.</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5ABA579B935449869580F375570BB7C3">
        <enum>(18)</enum>
        <text>During 251 days of combat, the Force suffered 2,314 casualties, or 134 percent of its authorized strength, captured thousands of prisoners, won 5 United States campaign stars and 8 Canadian battle honors, and never failed a mission.</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCEE8F931588E43B38A1FFA90A2BCCBF0">
        <enum>(19)</enum>
        <text>The United States is forever indebted to the acts of bravery and selflessness of the troops of the Force, who risked their lives for the cause of freedom.</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H693AC6D214224E29B4242CBD8344CFB2">
        <enum>(20)</enum>
        <text>The efforts of the Force along the seas and skies of Europe were critical in repelling the advance of Nazi Germany and liberating numerous communities in France and Italy.</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HECB02EF8569C456FADCFB56C3F744DB4">
        <enum>(21)</enum>
        <text>The bond between the members of the Force from the United States and those from Canada has endured over the decades, as the members meet every year for a reunion, alternating between the United States and Canada.</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H149A45FF2110465384BB98C49B6736ED">
        <enum>(22)</enum>
        <text>The traditions and honors exhibited by the Force are carried on by 2 outstanding active units of 2 great democracies, the Special Forces of the United States and the Canadian Special Operations Regiment.</text>
      </paragraph>
    </section> 
<section id="HEF3C0C59B67E409AAB9650B0C22C932A">
      <enum>2.</enum>
      <header>Congressional gold medal</header> 
<subsection id="H145396346DD048279242D490E12D453D">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Award authorized</header>
        <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Speaker of the House of Representatives" entity-parent-id="0050">Speaker of the House of Representatives</cato:entity-ref> and the
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="President pro tempore of the Senate" entity-parent-id="0010">President pro tempore of the Senate</cato:entity-ref> shall make appropriate arrangements for the
			 award, on behalf of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref>, of a gold medal of appropriate design to the
			 First Special Service Force, collectively, in recognition of their dedicated
			 service during World War II.</text>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="H109614971B0C4915B4EC2B46BCE6FB3A">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Design and striking</header>
        <text>For the purposes of the award referred to in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="113 HR 324/s:2/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection
			 (a)</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary of the Treasury</cato:entity-ref> (in this Act referred to as the
			 <term>Secretary</term>) shall strike the gold medal with suitable emblems,
			 devices, and inscriptions, to be determined by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="H850C67849D52479191B9045EF076A2EC">
        <enum>(c)</enum>
        <header>Award of medal</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Following the award of
			 the gold medal in honor of the First Special Service Force under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="113 HR 324/s:2/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection
			 (a)</cato:entity-ref>, the medal shall be given to the First Special Service Force Association in
			 Helena, Montana, where it shall be available for display or temporary loan to
			 be displayed elsewhere, particularly at other appropriate locations associated
			 with the First Special Service Force, including Fort William Henry Harrison in
			 Helena, Montana.</text>
      </subsection>
    </section> 
<section id="H8A6A1AC39DD04A01A19B1EECA554CEC3">
      <enum>3.</enum>
      <header>Duplicate medals</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> may strike and sell duplicates in bronze of the gold medal struck under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="113 HR 324/s:2" proposed="true">section 2</cato:entity-ref>, at a price sufficient to cover the costs of the medal, including labor, materials, dies, use of machinery, and overhead expenses, and amounts received from the sale of such duplicates shall be deposited in the United States Mint Public Enterprise Fund.</text>
    </section> 
<section id="H0C91E0B527454FC5BA676CCC979C1534">
      <enum>4.</enum>
      <header>National medals</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Medals struck pursuant to this Act are national medals for purposes of <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc-chapter/31/51">
          <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/31/51">chapter 51</external-xref> of title 31, United States Code</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
    </section> 
</legis-body> <attestation>
    <attestation-group>
      <attestation-date date="20130521" chamber="House">Passed the House of Representatives May 21, 2013.</attestation-date>
      <attestor display="no">Karen L. Haas,</attestor>
      <role>Clerk.</role>
    </attestation-group>
  </attestation>
<endorsement display="yes"/>
</bill>
</doc>