<doc>
  <docmeta id="113hr3216ih">
    <bill congress="113" type="hr" number="3216" version="ih"/>
    <revision size="2862" annotations="0" status="complete" id="5" commit-time="2013-10-07T20:42:46Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113hr3216ih/5.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HDBB7A3494FEA4F63B4F2F41C60B48EED" public-private="public">
  <metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>113 HR 3216 IH: To ensure that members of the Armed Forces and Federal law enforcement officers continue to receive their pay and allowances despite a shutdown of the Federal Government or in the event that the debt of the United States Government reaches the statutory limit.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2013-09-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
    <congress>113th CONGRESS</congress>
    <session>1st Session</session>
    <legis-num>H. R. 3216</legis-num>
    <current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
    <action>
      <action-date date="20130928">September 28, 2013</action-date>
      <action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="K000220">Mr. Kingston</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="G000552">Mr. Gohmert</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Armed Services</committee-name> and <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
    </action>
    <legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
    <official-title>To ensure that members of the Armed Forces and Federal law enforcement officers continue to receive their pay and allowances despite a shutdown of the Federal Government or in the event that the debt of the United States Government reaches the statutory limit.</official-title>
  </form>
  <legis-body id="H4150C04727F545B69D6DD1B82764B159" style="OLC">
    <section id="HC00EF24EFAD444588B68822D6BB9FA30" section-type="section-one">
      <enum>1.</enum>
      <header>Payment of pay and allowances for members of the Armed Forces and Federal law enforcement officers during Federal Government shutdown or despite reaching statutory debt limit</header>
      <subsection id="HFD3B2D78852C470CA56DBDCDDA45FD24">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Continuation during a federal government shutdown</header>
        <text>During any funding gap during fiscal year 2014 when interim or full-year appropriations for the following activities have not been enacted, from amounts in the general fund of the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary of the Treasury</cato:entity-ref> shall transfer to the head of the appropriate Executive agency such amounts as are necessary to continue such activities:</text>
        <paragraph id="H095C84DC3BAD4DA3B646A944DF303560">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The payment of pay and allowances for members of the Armed Forces (including reserve components thereof) on active duty.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HF7F25B775C0C49DE93453127AC20167B">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The payment of salaries and benefits for sworn Federal law enforcement officers.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="H441C2D1DB7CD45E9872D5C670BBB7309">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Continuation despite reaching statutory debt limit</header>
        <text>In the event that the debt of the United States Government reaches the statutory limit as defined in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc/31/3101">
            <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/31/3101">section 3101</external-xref> of title 31, United States Code</cato:entity-ref>, the following shall take equal priority over all other obligations incurred by the United States Government:</text>
        <paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1BAE7295558B445097BEDA09907915BC">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The payment of pay and allowances for members of the Armed Forces (including reserve components thereof) on active duty.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HF786C07EE368441D9A5C7AFB5DAFEAF9">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The payment of salaries and benefits for sworn Federal law enforcement officers.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
    </section>
  </legis-body>
</bill>
</doc>