<doc>
  <docmeta id="113hr3597ih">
    <bill congress="113" type="hr" number="3597" version="ih"/>
    <revision size="4450" annotations="0" status="complete" id="3" commit-time="2013-12-05T22:13:34Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113hr3597ih/3.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HEDBF0BF1BACC421D9DA97F54FD1574B4" public-private="public">
  <metadata>
<dublinCore>
<dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">113 HR 3597 IH: Safety, Efficiency, and Accountability in Transportation Projects Through Public Inspection Act of 2013</dc:title>
<dc:publisher xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">2013-11-21</dc:date>
<dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
    <congress>113th CONGRESS</congress>
    <session>1st Session</session>
    <legis-num>H. R. 3597</legis-num>
    <current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
    <action>
      <action-date date="20131121">November 21, 2013</action-date>
      <action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="E000290">Ms. Edwards</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>
      </action-desc>
    </action>
    <legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
    <official-title>To require public employees to perform the inspection of State and local surface transportation projects, and related essential public functions, to ensure public safety, the cost-effective use of transportation funding, and timely project delivery.</official-title>
  </form>
  <legis-body id="HF36457C4324743F4AD6AA1F49F65FF14" style="OLC">
    <section id="H42E0F9959CB94F67B7F8994CCB620860" section-type="section-one">
      <enum>1.</enum>
      <header>Short title</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote>
          <short-title>Safety, Efficiency, and Accountability in Transportation Projects Through Public Inspection Act of 2013</short-title>
        </quote>.</text>
    </section>
    <section id="HC80F51D4B7034E68A05B513022F72521">
      <enum>2.</enum>
      <header>Findings</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">
        <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> finds the following:</text>
      <paragraph id="H56F24829AC8A4EB09DDBFBA6D49C2C00">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text>Public inspectors serve as the eyes, ears, and voice of the public on State and local surface transportation projects and help ensure that construction and seismic standards are met, that projects meet safety requirements, and that the materials used will stand the test of time.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H507ACA5FE5794ECB92F9608138B15877">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text>Public inspectors on State and local surface transportation projects ensure that tax-paying motorists get what they pay for and public safety and the public interest are considered first and foremost.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H139FD0BCDE8A4C5CB6E2632303CC47D4">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <text>Outsourcing public inspection functions on State and local surface transportation projects eliminates a representative of the public from the construction site and puts a private company in charge of inspecting the work of the private construction company, creating multiple conflicts of interest.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H266E9A281DFB4CF7AEC1D49B6AE9F8AF">
        <enum>(4)</enum>
        <text>A private inspector’s primary obligation and responsibility is not to the public, but to the success and profitability of the inspector’s company. Because the private construction company whose work they are inspecting on one project may be a business partner on a future project, private inspectors are likely to feel pressure from the private contractor to take steps that ensure larger profits for both firms.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HC810C8629BB34C69851ED0EF6C264F51">
        <enum>(5)</enum>
        <text>These conflicts of interest may lead private inspectors to cut corners and overlook problems that threaten public safety, increase costs, and delay projects.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H07EC06A26AD64D01B2328707F11F88BE">
        <enum>(6)</enum>
        <text>Across the United States, transportation agencies have outsourced public inspection functions with disastrous results. Examples of the dangers of outsourcing include the following: Boston’s Big Dig (where a concrete slab from a tunnel ceiling fell and killed a woman), the Los Angeles Redline subway (Hollywood Boulevard collapsed), and the Connecticut I–84 project (hundreds of drains that lead nowhere).</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H306A79B3B5CD48B38C301D061F517E7A">
        <enum>(7)</enum>
        <text>Commuters and taxpayers are best served by requiring public inspection on State and local surface transportation projects to protect public safety, use transportation revenues cost effectively, and deliver projects on time.</text>
      </paragraph>
    </section>
    <section id="H0340C4E0B7F44029B54082984AE89753">
      <enum>3.</enum>
      <header>Public inspection</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Public employees shall carry out the construction inspection functions for all surface transportation projects receiving Federal funding.</text>
    </section>
    <section id="H73625449710F412EB5FB6114E11EE231">
      <enum>4.</enum>
      <header>Definitions</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act, the following definitions apply:</text>
      <paragraph id="H85BBAD3A25384BA5BAD328386C14D496">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <header>Construction inspection functions</header>
        <text>The term <term>construction inspection functions</term> means construction engineering, contract administration, quality control inspection, materials testing, and resident engineer and assistant resident engineer functions.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H2CBEE0F39F1E4168B6BDED341FF04E27">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <header>Public employee</header>
        <text>The term <term>public employee</term> means an employee of a Federal, State, or local government.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H6367F06516BD46A29DC44C824649BE26">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <header>Surface transportation project</header>
        <text>The term <term>surface transportation project</term> means a project receiving assistance under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc/23">title 23, United States Code</cato:entity-ref>, a capital project (as defined in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc/49/5302">
            <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/49/5302">section 5302</external-xref> of title 49, United States Code</cato:entity-ref>), and any other project related to surface transportation that the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="6900">Secretary of Transportation</cato:entity-ref> determines appropriate.</text>
      </paragraph>
    </section>
  </legis-body>
</bill>
</doc>