<doc>
  <docmeta id="113hres129ih">
    <bill congress="113" type="hres" number="129" version="ih"/>
    <revision size="3120" annotations="0" id="3" commit-time="2013-04-13T23:23:14+00:00" committer="favila" doc="113hres129ih/3.xml" status="complete">
      <description/>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <resolution xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" dms-id="H79598F6BCA6E4C6AB5FE8F62AAFDB480" key="H" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>113 HRES 129 IH: Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives that the Congress should not pass any legislation that would tax or confiscate personal savings accounts, including retirement accounts such as Individual Retirement Accounts (IRAs) and 401k plans, certificates of deposit (CDs), or other personal savings to provide financial relief for private businesses.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2013-03-19</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">113th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session display="yes">1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. RES. 129</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20130319">March 19, 2013</action-date>
			<action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="L000576">Mr. Long</sponsor> submitted
			 the following resolution; which was referred to the
			 <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and
			 Means</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on
			 <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Financial Services</committee-name>, for a
			 period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for
			 consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the
			 committee concerned</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">Expressing the sense of the House of
		  Representatives that the Congress should not pass any legislation that would
		  tax or confiscate personal savings accounts, including retirement accounts such
		  as Individual Retirement Accounts (IRAs) and 401k plans, certificates of
		  deposit (CDs), or other personal savings to provide financial relief for
		  private businesses.</official-title>
	</form>
	<preamble>
		<whereas>
      <text>Whereas the personal savings and retirement accounts of
			 the American public are the personal property of their owners;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas personal savings and retirement accounts are used
			 by millions of Americans to fund their retirement, their children’s education,
			 their purchase of a family home, and other uses according to their pursuit of
			 happiness;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the United States Government should not abuse its
			 power by substituting political priorities for the personal economic choices of
			 millions of individual Americans;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas previous attempts to use taxpayer money to provide
			 financial relief to troubled industries has failed to produce economic recovery
			 and has undermined the American system of economic freedom; and</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the American system of economic freedom has given
			 millions of ordinary people the opportunity to pursue economic success and
			 their American dream: Now, therefore, be it</text>
		</whereas>
  </preamble>
	<resolution-body id="H8030ED533D8F44C69A2553AD770BFA17" style="traditional">
		<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H7BD86ECC9271406C89B254BCEF32B8EA" section-type="undesignated-section">
      <enum/>
      <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That it is the sense of the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0050">House of
			 Representatives</cato:entity-ref> that the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> should—</text>
			<paragraph id="HC869429B67C64B28AA2098A58DAA5C22">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text>refrain from
			 considering or adopting any legislation that would tax or confiscate any or all
			 personal savings held by the American people, including retirement accounts
			 such as Individual Retirement Accounts (IRAs) and 401k plans, certificates of
			 deposit (CDs), or other personal savings and assets; and</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H1DBC972F76454EF8B43F5A7B1A1D1C39">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text>refrain from
			 considering or adopting any legislation to provide financial relief to a
			 private business or general sector of the American economy at taxpayer
			 expense.</text>
			</paragraph>
    </section>
  </resolution-body>
</resolution>
</doc>