<doc>
  <docmeta id="113hr5491ih">
    <bill congress="113" type="hr" number="5491" version="ih"/>
    <revision size="6296" annotations="0" status="complete" id="4" commit-time="2014-10-08T20:27:07Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113hr5491ih/4.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H21773E069E1C40428BD8A1252445C3F0" public-private="public">
	<metadata>
<dublinCore>
<dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">113 HR 5491 IH: United States-Caribbean Partnership Act of 2014</dc:title>
<dc:publisher xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">2014-09-16</dc:date>
<dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>113th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>2d Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 5491</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20140916">September 16, 2014</action-date>
			<action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="E000179">Mr. Engel</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name>
      </action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To establish United States embassies with consular services in the five countries in the Caribbean
			 with which the United States has diplomatic relations but no permanent
			 diplomatic presence: Antigua and Barbuda, Dominica, St. Kitts and Nevis,
			 St. Lucia, and St. Vincent and the Grenadines.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="HAECBE20151964E4E8062F64F5BCD5B3A" style="OLC">
		<section id="H5899CDBB26B148ADA2D542C3CDA743E1" section-type="section-one">
      <enum>1.</enum>
      <header>Short title</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote>
          <short-title>
            <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="United States-Caribbean Partnership Act of 2014" proposed="true">United States-Caribbean Partnership Act of 2014</cato:entity-ref>
          </short-title>
        </quote>.</text>
		</section>
    <section id="H0E339D2D900C423FBADC38C3EF5E0F75">
      <enum>2.</enum>
      <header>Definition</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act, the term <quote>appropriate congressional committees</quote> means the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="HFA00" entity-type="committee">Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives</cato:entity-ref> and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="SSFR00" entity-type="committee">Committee on
			 Foreign Relations of the Senate</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
		</section>
    <section id="HE57686C19129499C97D8F62487E30E80">
      <enum>3.</enum>
      <header>Findings</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text>
			<paragraph id="H3086B432FE2A4826B17DDA9A626454DF">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text>While often overlooked, the countries of the Caribbean are important United States partners.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HAE4D8E4615794B26ADDB62A5B9FA11A2">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text>United States-Caribbean cooperation on commerce, security, and energy must be deepened.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H8CFF5DD6A86A4E1495941D4649310A08">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <text>The countries of the Caribbean are key voting members of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="19AS" entity-type="federal-body">Organization of American States</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H7B9E1677ED044BABB578311DDE9A8020">
        <enum>(4)</enum>
        <text>There are five countries in the Caribbean with which the United States has diplomatic relations,
			 but within which the United States does not have a permanent diplomatic
			 presence. Those countries are Antigua and Barbuda, Dominica, St. Kitts and
			 Nevis, St. Lucia, and St. Vincent and the Grenadines.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HFB47CFFF8E0F416BB4BC869AA026D036">
        <enum>(5)</enum>
        <text>Diplomatic relations with these five countries are conducted through the United States Embassy in
			 Bridgetown, Barbados.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H99D80C6BB47E42AE9D93107FBA1F30E4">
        <enum>(6)</enum>
        <text>Due to the lack of presence of United States diplomats in these five countries, citizens of these
			 five countries are required to travel to Barbados for all consular
			 services.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HD80864B9FB0B462FA41C0E56F0D0B046">
        <enum>(7)</enum>
        <text>Due to the lack of presence of United States diplomats in these five countries, in order to meet
			 with local officials, civil society representatives, private sector
			 leaders, United States citizens or others, embassy officials must fly from
			 Barbados to these countries on what are often expensive, sometimes
			 infrequent flights and remain overnight in what are often expensive hotel
			 rooms.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HB3F363CB5B9445FDA18F94B81F1F78DB">
        <enum>(8)</enum>
        <text>Due to the lack of presence of United States diplomats in these five countries, United States
			 citizens living in and visiting these five countries do not have full
			 consular services, and in the event of a consular emergency, air traffic
			 could be shut off to any of these islands, in effect stranding United
			 States citizens without full in-country consular services.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H6D65D807ECC74F98B7159D57881CBAE6">
        <enum>(9)</enum>
        <text>Due to the lack of presence of United States diplomats in these five countries, key events,
			 meetings, ceremonies, and other opportunities are often not attended by
			 United States officials as they are in other countries where there is a
			 permanent diplomatic presence.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H56C2A2CDB31D4D8794F117B742191C8A">
        <enum>(10)</enum>
        <text>Due to the lack of presence of United States diplomats in these five countries, it is more
			 difficult for United States diplomats to establish close working
			 relationships with local officials, civil society representatives, and
			 others.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H7B3A58294A784362B056FEA58712CD1D">
        <enum>(11)</enum>
        <text>Due to the lack of presence of United States diplomats in these five countries, United States
			 official diplomatic interaction with these countries, including delivery
			 of demarches and other diplomatic messages, which the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1900" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref>
			 sometimes requires embassy officials to personally deliver, particularly
			 if of a confidential nature, is often relegated to telephone, facsimile,
			 or email, dramatically reducing the ability of the United States to engage
			 host governments in substantive dialogue.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HA2EFE8F95DF64D76A940AF2A82CED69E">
        <enum>(12)</enum>
        <text>Due to the lack of presence of United States diplomats in these five countries, it is more
			 difficult for the United States to conduct public diplomacy in these five
			 countries.</text>
			</paragraph>
    </section>
    <section id="H52BD6F2184444CF4BCDAF2DC9EC7C3A6">
      <enum>4.</enum>
      <header>Establishment of United States embassies with consular services in Antigua and Barbuda, Dominica,
			 St. Kitts and Nevis, St. Lucia, and St. Vincent and the Grenadines</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than five years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1900" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref> shall
			 establish United States embassies with consular services in Antigua and
			 Barbuda, Dominica, St. Kitts and Nevis, St. Lucia, and St. Vincent and the
			 Grenadines to—</text>
			<paragraph id="H655000F7FD4244ABAD4D7D34F63871EA">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text>provide consular services to citizens of these countries and United States citizens living in or
			 traveling to these countries; and</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H7AE5A6FBDE49415797911E830E5FBD04">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text>engage in direct diplomacy with appropriate government counterparts in these countries.</text>
			</paragraph>
    </section>
    <section id="H96A9063CAA0F4288BE78CA0A6000B5B1">
      <enum>5.</enum>
      <header>Report</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act and annually thereafter until
			 the requirements under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="United States-Caribbean Partnership Act of 2014/s:4" proposed="true">section 4</cato:entity-ref> have been satisfied, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1900" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of
			 State</cato:entity-ref> shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on
			 the progress made toward carrying out such section.</text>
		</section>
    <section id="HB3FABAB793EA43F49EC9EBF02C3F0AD2">
      <enum>6.</enum>
      <header>Exception for delay</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1900" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref> may delay for up to one year the carrying out of <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="United States-Caribbean Partnership Act of 2014/s:4" proposed="true">section 4</cato:entity-ref> if the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Secretary</cato:entity-ref>
			 determines that more time is needed to carry out such section and submits
			 to the appropriate congressional committees a report explaining the reason
			 for such delay.</text>
		</section>
    <section id="H368B27E3556C4AD981A1235F0A4A38EC">
      <enum>7.</enum>
      <header>Limitation on additional funding</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">To carry out this Act, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1900" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref> may use only amounts that are available from the
			 Embassy Security, Construction, and Maintenance account and the Diplomatic
			 and Consular Programs account of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1900" entity-type="federal-body">Department of State</cato:entity-ref> for such purpose.</text>
		</section>
  </legis-body>
</bill>
</doc>