<doc>
  <docmeta id="113hres256eh">
    <bill congress="113" type="hres" number="256" version="eh"/>
    <revision size="4035" annotations="0" status="complete" id="3" commit-time="2013-08-05T18:01:59Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113hres256eh/3.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <resolution xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" dms-id="Hd8361c0c-f2f5-4c59-a2c5-1f849ebf7bdf" key="H" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Engrossed-in-House" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" stage-count="1"> 
<metadata>
<dublinCore>
<title>113 HRES 256 EH: Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 1960) to authorize appropriations for fiscal year 2014 for military activities of the Department of Defense and for military construction, to prescribe military personnel strengths for such fiscal year, and for other purposes; and providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 1256) to direct the Securities and Exchange Commission and the Commodity Futures Trading Commission to jointly adopt rules setting forth the application to cross-border swaps transactions of certain provisions relating to swaps that were enacted as part of the Dodd-Frank Wall Street Reform and Consumer Protection Act.</title>
<publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</publisher>
<date>2013-06-12</date>
<format>text/xml</format>
<language>EN</language>
<rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="no">IV</distribution-code> 
<congress display="no">113th CONGRESS</congress> 
<session display="no">1st Session</session> 
<legis-num>H. RES. 256</legis-num> 
<current-chamber display="yes">In the House of Representatives, U. S.,</current-chamber>
<action>
<action-date date="20130612">June 12, 2013</action-date>
</action> 
<legis-type display="yes">RESOLUTION</legis-type> 
<official-title display="no">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 1960) to authorize appropriations for fiscal year 2014 for military activities of the Department of Defense and for military construction, to prescribe military personnel strengths for such fiscal year, and for other purposes; and providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 1256) to direct the Securities and Exchange Commission and the Commodity Futures Trading Commission to jointly adopt rules setting forth the application to cross-border swaps transactions of certain provisions relating to swaps that were enacted as part of the Dodd-Frank Wall Street Reform and Consumer Protection Act.</official-title> 
</form> 
<resolution-body id="H28c0ec93-2a32-4b93-a4c7-9c59b6385e1a" style="traditional"> 
<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H7abb3d97-3c8e-4176-8644-362aa4fd553d" section-type="undesignated-section">
      <enum/>
      <text>That at any time after the adoption of this resolution the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" value="Speaker of the House of Representatives" entity-parent-id="0050">Speaker</cato:entity-ref> may, pursuant to clause 2(b) of rule XVIII, declare the House resolved into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for consideration of the bill (<cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="113 HR 1960" proposed="true">H.R. 1960</cato:entity-ref>) to authorize appropriations for fiscal year 2014 for military activities of the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="9700">Department of Defense</cato:entity-ref> and for military construction, to prescribe military personnel strengths for such fiscal year, and for other purposes. The first reading of the bill shall be dispensed with. All points of order against consideration of the bill are waived. General debate shall be confined to the bill and shall not exceed one hour equally divided and controlled by the chair and ranking minority member of the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="committee" entity-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</cato:entity-ref>. After general debate, the Committee of the Whole shall rise without motion. No further consideration of the bill shall be in order except pursuant to a subsequent order of the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0050">House</cato:entity-ref>.</text> </section>
<section id="H27AEB9167A99428C8A1ACB1DB65A9DBD">
      <enum>2.</enum>
      <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon the adoption of this resolution it shall be in order to consider in the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0050">House</cato:entity-ref> the bill (<cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="113 HR 1256" proposed="true">H.R. 1256</cato:entity-ref>) to direct the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="5000">Securities and Exchange Commission</cato:entity-ref> and the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="9507">Commodity Futures Trading Commission</cato:entity-ref> to jointly adopt rules setting forth the application to cross-border swaps transactions of certain provisions relating to swaps that were enacted as part of the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Dodd-Frank Wall Street Reform and Consumer Protection Act">Dodd-Frank Wall Street Reform and Consumer Protection Act</cato:entity-ref>. All points of order against consideration of the bill are waived. The amendments recommended by the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="committee" entity-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</cato:entity-ref> now printed in the bill shall be considered as adopted. The bill, as amended, shall be considered as read. All points of order against provisions in the bill, as amended, are waived. The previous question shall be considered as ordered on the bill, as amended, and on any amendment thereto to final passage without intervening motion except: (1) one hour of debate, with 40 minutes equally divided and controlled by the chair and ranking minority member of the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="committee" entity-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</cato:entity-ref> and 20 minutes equally divided and controlled by the chair and ranking minority member of the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="committee" entity-id="HAG00">Committee on Agriculture</cato:entity-ref>; and (2) one motion to recommit with or without instructions.</text> </section>
<section id="HD87E9B83A0324B1A987CACE122209BA6">
      <enum>3.</enum>
      <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The chair of the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="committee" entity-id="HAG00">Committee on Agriculture</cato:entity-ref> is authorized, on behalf of the committee, to file a supplemental report to accompany <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="113 HR 1947" proposed="true">H.R. 1947</cato:entity-ref>.</text> </section>
</resolution-body> 
<attestation>
    <attestation-group>
      <attestor display="no">Karen L. Haas,</attestor>
      <role>Clerk.</role>
    </attestation-group>
  </attestation>
</resolution>
</doc>