<doc>
  <docmeta id="113hr4706ih">
    <bill congress="113" type="hr" number="4706" version="ih"/>
    <revision size="21128" annotations="0" status="complete" id="4" commit-time="2014-06-03T16:47:04Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113hr4706ih/4.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H1AEF63D802364DA1AF93E6AEA5F41D56" public-private="public">
	<metadata>
<dublinCore>
<dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">113 HR 4706 IH: Healthy Kids Outdoors Act of 2014</dc:title>
<dc:publisher xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">2014-05-21</dc:date>
<dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>113th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>2d Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 4706</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20140521">May 21, 2014</action-date>
			<action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="K000188">Mr. Kind</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="C001078">Mr. Connolly</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="P000523">Mr. Price of North Carolina</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To authorize the Secretary of the Interior to carry out programs and activities that connect
			 Americans, especially children, youth, and families, with the outdoors.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H7CC5924C0B474403B355BA82E1E51CAD" style="OLC">
		<section id="H956AEC8F3E8D4B0FB423EEB3E1A61E7B" section-type="section-one">
      <enum>1.</enum>
      <header>Short title</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote>
          <short-title>
            <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Healthy Kids Outdoors Act of 2014" proposed="true">Healthy Kids Outdoors Act of 2014</cato:entity-ref>
          </short-title>
        </quote>.</text>
		</section>
    <section id="H858B502997FE437F8ACF9A8FC818A9EA">
      <enum>2.</enum>
      <header>Findings</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds as follows:</text>
			<paragraph id="H352718ECE9404C89BF3002ED418C42EE">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text>Children today are spending less time outdoors than any generation in human history, as evidenced
			 by studies that show children enjoy half as much time outdoors today as
			 they did just 20 years ago, while spending more than 7<fraction>½</fraction> hours every day in front of electronic media.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H763134EBC28C4D499BAAEAB65F2FF3E6">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The health of our children is at risk as evidenced by the growing obesity crisis where, in the past
			 30 years, childhood obesity has more than doubled in children and
			 quadrupled in adolescents, costing the economy of the United States
			 billions of dollars each year.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HA7399F03914D41D396ED6C4F16849C18">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <text>Our military readiness is declining as nearly 1 in 4 applicants to the military is rejected for
			 being overweight or obese, which is the most common reason for medical
			 disqualification.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HB8B249B234014C69BAA684D8B7067C7A">
        <enum>(4)</enum>
        <text>Research has shown that military children and families are facing increased stress and mental
			 strain and challenges due to multiple, extended deployments. Military
			 family service organizations have developed programs that connect military
			 children and families with positive, meaningful outdoor experiences that
			 benefit mental and physical health, but they lack sufficient resources to
			 meet increasing demand.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HE49000B018294CBEA138D83F4520943D">
        <enum>(5)</enum>
        <text>In addition to the negative economic impact of childhood obesity, the outdoor retail industry, many
			 local tourist destinations or <quote>gateway communities</quote>, and State fish and wildlife agencies rely on revenue generated when individuals spend time
			 outdoors to create jobs in local communities.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H4ED5A167182C47BCBBCC995120586ECB">
        <enum>(6)</enum>
        <text>Over the past several years, urbanization, changing land use patterns, increasing road traffic, and
			 inadequate solutions to addressing these challenges in the built
			 environment have combined to make it more difficult for many Americans to
			 walk or bike to schools, parks, and play areas or experience the natural
			 environment in general.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H10827DABE46E4CB59330E369B3857E61">
        <enum>(7)</enum>
        <text>Spending time in green spaces outside the home, including public lands, parks, play areas, and
			 garden, can increase concentration, inhibition of initial impulses, and
			 self-discipline and has been shown to reduce stress and mental fatigue. In
			 one study, children who were exposed to greener environments in a public
			 housing area demonstrated less aggression, violence, and stress.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HB32EE07E0AEB46449905B35EDC19A486">
        <enum>(8)</enum>
        <text>Visitation to our Nation’s public lands has declined or remained flat in recent years, and yet,
			 connecting with nature and the great outdoors in our communities is
			 critical to fostering the next generation of outdoor enthusiasts who will
			 visit, appreciate, and become stewards of our Nation’s public lands.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HD7A3FCBEFE7C4EDF9B6E64C113039155">
        <enum>(9)</enum>
        <text>Spending time outdoors in nature is beneficial to our children’s physical, mental, and emotional
			 health and has been proven to decrease symptoms of attention deficit and
			 hyperactivity disorder, stimulate brain development, improve motor skills,
			 result in better sleep, reduce stress, increase creativity, improve mood,
			 and reduce children’s risk of developing myopia.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H0B8A670F76384AC49A3206C27208F01B">
        <enum>(10)</enum>
        <text>Children who spend time playing outside are more likely to take risks, seek out adventure, develop
			 self-confidence, and respect the value of nature. A direct childhood
			 experience with nature before the age of 11 promotes a long-term
			 connection to nature.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H06E41DD77F7244A3A4B19B3C00D90428">
        <enum>(11)</enum>
        <text>Conservation education and outdoor recreation experiences such as camping, hiking, boating,
			 hunting, fishing, archery, recreational shooting, wildlife watching, and
			 others are critical to engaging young people in the outdoors.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HD08308D05E4549FE90EED0625641F18B">
        <enum>(12)</enum>
        <text>As children become more disconnected from the natural world, the hunting and angling conservation
			 legacy of America is at risk.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H62F842E36D1A4CFABFF4DB305E999A9D">
        <enum>(13)</enum>
        <text>Hunters and anglers play a critical role in reconnecting young people with nature, protecting our
			 natural resources, and fostering a lifelong understanding of the value of
			 conserving the natural world.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H7F56C68813014746BA58816BFB2458FE">
        <enum>(14)</enum>
        <text>Research demonstrates that hunters who become engaged in hunting as children are among the most
			 active and interested hunters as adults. The vast majority of hunters
			 report they were introduced to hunting between the ages of 10 and 12, and
			 the overwhelming majority of children are introduced to hunting by an
			 adult.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HD9157EC06F424FF3889641505341DE81">
        <enum>(15)</enum>
        <text>Parks and recreation, youth-serving, service-learning, conservation, health, education, and
			 built-environment organizations, facilities, and personnel provide
			 critical resources and infrastructure for connecting children and families
			 with nature.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H388087EE6A6541FE8FF7BE1823F3BCC6">
        <enum>(16)</enum>
        <text>It takes many dedicated men and women to work to preserve, protect, enhance, and restore America’s
			 natural resources, and with an aging workforce in the natural resource
			 professions, it is critical for the next generation to have an
			 appreciation for nature and be ready to take over these responsibilities.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H8AF3537AFE304EF491030EBC332152E4">
        <enum>(17)</enum>
        <text>Place-based service-learning opportunities use our lands and waters as the context for learning by
			 engaging students in the process of exploration, action, and reflection.
			 Physical activity outdoors connected with meaningful community service to
			 solve real-world problems, such as removing invasive plants or removing
			 trash from a streambed, strengthens communities by engaging youth as
			 citizen stewards.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H1C2F72B12C9A4854AF09AC51C2E4CB8E">
        <enum>(18)</enum>
        <text>States nationwide and their community based partners have some notable programs that connect
			 children and families with nature; however, most States lack sufficient
			 resources and a comprehensive strategy to effectively engage State
			 agencies across multiple fields.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HB20B167D3282479EA2541D6A66B0DDC7">
        <enum>(19)</enum>
        <text>States need to engage in cross-sector agency and nonprofit collaboration that involves public
			 health and wellness, parks and recreation, transportation and city
			 planning, and other sectors focused on connecting children and families
			 with the outdoors to increase coordination and effective implementation of
			 the policy tools and programs that a State can bring to bear to provide
			 outdoor opportunities for children and families.</text>
			</paragraph>
    </section>
    <section id="HEC826EF3493B427999D184565098CFCA">
      <enum>3.</enum>
      <header>Definitions</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text>
			<paragraph id="H070BD7DF4AF24A88B56794E8BF432F04">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <header>Eligible entity</header>
        <text>The term <term>eligible entity</term> means—</text>
				<subparagraph id="H4AB8D43CB15F481A81370E49E2DF1E03">
          <enum>(A)</enum>
          <text>a State; or</text>
				</subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="H924FC1A063DA4B188ADC4DCE506F61BF">
          <enum>(B)</enum>
          <text>a consortium from one State that may include such State and municipalities, entities of local or
			 tribal governments, parks and recreation departments or districts, school
			 districts, institutions of higher education, or nonprofit organizations.</text>
				</subparagraph>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H771FD1E52B964EB490ECA8F5DAB1F12C">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <header>Local partners</header>
        <text>The term <term>local partners</term> means a municipality, entity of local or tribal government, parks and recreation departments or
			 districts, Indian tribe, school district, institution of higher education,
			 nonprofit organization, or a consortium of local partners.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HAED1C0AF8364416A9DBAA316EE594BEC">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <header>Secretary</header>
        <text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1400" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of the Interior</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H192ED22C50B841F38B6065C40BDA8D91">
        <enum>(4)</enum>
        <header>State</header>
        <text>The term <term>State</term> means any of the several States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the
			 United States Virgin Islands, Guam, American Samoa, the Commonwealth of
			 the Northern Mariana Islands, any other territory or possession of the
			 United States, or any Indian tribe.</text>
			</paragraph>
    </section>
    <section id="H66416FC06EEB4F0287B2D9CC961AC5DB">
      <enum>4.</enum>
      <header>Cooperative agreements for development or implementation of healthy kids outdoors State strategies</header>
			<subsection id="H8A0D5EEAF640462DBA2366579FBF8CFB">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>In general</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1400">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> is authorized to issue one cooperative agreement per State to eligible entities to
			 develop, implement, and update a 5-year State strategy, to be known as a <quote>Healthy Kids Outdoors State Strategy</quote>, designed to encourage Americans, especially children, youth, and families, to be physically
			 active outdoors.</text>
			</subsection>
      <subsection id="HD546171C572A451C89455F190464386A">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Submission and approval of strategies</header>
				<paragraph id="HF3FDFF5E802A4006B5304E4608711C82">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>Applications</header>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An application for a cooperative agreement under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Healthy Kids Outdoors Act of 2014/s:4/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref> shall—</text>
					<subparagraph id="H8CE0832C650A450B89BDA6FB71DE6C49">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">be submitted not later than 120 days after the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1400">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> publishes guidelines under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Healthy Kids Outdoors Act of 2014/s:4/ss:f/p:1" proposed="true">subsection
			 (f)(1)</cato:entity-ref>; and</text>
					</subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H3AAE9F1190E24CA58A12EF199E16DF61">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">include a Healthy Kids Outdoors State Strategy meeting the requirements of <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Healthy Kids Outdoors Act of 2014/s:4/ss:c" proposed="true">subsection (c)</cato:entity-ref> or a
			 proposal for development and submission of such a strategy.</text>
					</subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HBA6824AC8BAF4D0B9F64B355F6E32A14">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Approval of strategy; peer review</header>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after submission of a Healthy Kids Outdoors State Strategy, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1400">Secretary</cato:entity-ref>
			 shall, through a peer review process, approve or recommend changes to the
			 strategy.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HD0DD982E9C374831B84801EE0F7262AA">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <header>Strategy update</header>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An eligible entity receiving funds under this section shall update its Healthy Kids Outdoors State
			 Strategy at least once every 5 years. Continued funding under this section
			 shall be contingent upon submission of such updated strategies and reports
			 that document impact evaluation methods consistent with the guidelines in
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Healthy Kids Outdoors Act of 2014/s:4/ss:f/p:1" proposed="true">subsection (f)(1)</cato:entity-ref> and lessons learned from implementing the strategy.</text>
				</paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="H5952776642BA454CB22742F0A1A29549">
        <enum>(c)</enum>
        <header>Comprehensive strategy requirements</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Healthy Kids Outdoors State Strategy under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Healthy Kids Outdoors Act of 2014/s:4/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref> shall include—</text>
				<paragraph id="HF6377BF873134427A6308A1973C28794">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a description of how the eligible entity will encourage Americans, especially children, youth, and
			 families, to be physically active in the outdoors through State, local,
			 and tribal—</text>
					<subparagraph id="H14FB92E583DE4629B88948F11D114C98">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">public health systems;</text>
					</subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H7E44730AACEA4F51B47F15B50F8926D7">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">public parks and recreation systems;</text>
					</subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H176C0655B186425C9BCF7D9982286EB6">
            <enum>(C)</enum>
            <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">public transportation and city planning systems; and</text>
					</subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="HAAAE8089B8D9413A914E701F367F08C0">
            <enum>(D)</enum>
            <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">other public systems that connect Americans, especially children, youth, and families, to the
			 outdoors;</text>
					</subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HB9D9AE5C785E47E98C5A10C5F53F2CAE">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a description of how the eligible entity will partner with nongovernmental organizations,
			 especially those that serve children, youth, and families, including those
			 serving military families and tribal agencies;</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H7CDD7930A0F6461B96D9FDBD00BD9440">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a description of how State agencies will collaborate with each other to implement the strategy;</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HF29542D81A33404F81396E42D11769DC">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a description of how funding will be spent through local planning and implementation subgrants
			 under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Healthy Kids Outdoors Act of 2014/s:4/ss:d" proposed="true">subsection (d)</cato:entity-ref>;</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HA3A4A9A6A6A54A7BA5363D946AB29976">
          <enum>(5)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a description of how the eligible entity will evaluate the effectiveness of, and measure the impact
			 of, the strategy, including an estimate of the costs associated with such
			 evaluation;</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HBB69488E81EF49D08C4BC97C5FB53689">
          <enum>(6)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a description of how the eligible entity will provide opportunities for public involvement in
			 developing and implementing the strategy;</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H830633DA241B4AF8BCB87D12A389178F">
          <enum>(7)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a description of how the strategy will increase visitation to Federal public lands within the
			 State; and</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H188F1505E8D5490FA2C7294B28242413">
          <enum>(8)</enum>
          <text>a description of how the eligible entity will leverage private funds to expand opportunities and
			 further implement the strategy.</text>
				</paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="H3D5FAE7EE7AB42E88DB8CDE3B004AD1C">
        <enum>(d)</enum>
        <header>Local planning and implementation</header>
				<paragraph id="H383B10E0BDEF41CF9F9C1183C3905E0D">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>In general</header>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A Healthy Kids Outdoors State Strategy shall provide for subgrants by the cooperative agreement
			 recipient under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Healthy Kids Outdoors Act of 2014/s:4/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref> to local partners to implement the strategy
			 through one or more of the program activities described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Healthy Kids Outdoors Act of 2014/s:4/ss:d/p:2" proposed="true">paragraph (2)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H1EBCA59FFF5F46D2A5E2E3822ABFF4AD">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Program activities</header>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Program activities may include—</text>
					<subparagraph id="H76CEF459256F4DEC981FF7463D825B1B">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">implementing outdoor recreation and youth mentoring programs that provide opportunities to
			 experience the outdoors, be physically active, and teach skills for
			 lifelong participation in outdoor activities, including fishing, hunting,
			 recreational shooting, archery, hiking, camping, outdoor play in natural
			 environments, and wildlife watching;</text>
					</subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H9A2206A88ABD4456B74DD62154F59A2B">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">implementing programs that connect communities with safe parks, green spaces, and outdoor
			 recreation areas through affordable public transportation and trail
			 systems that encourage walking, biking, and increased physical activity
			 outdoors;</text>
					</subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H944DF3729EB2481AAB6537AC269F136F">
            <enum>(C)</enum>
            <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">implementing school-based programs that use outdoor learning environments, such as wildlife
			 habitats or gardens, and programs that use service learning to restore
			 natural areas and maintain recreational assets; and</text>
					</subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H9185543BE01748018A5A38B80EAE29AA">
            <enum>(D)</enum>
            <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">implementing education programs for parents and caregivers about the health benefits of active time
			 outdoors to fight obesity and increase the quality of life for Americans,
			 especially children, youth, and families.</text>
					</subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="HBE908DA5D0FB46C9B6B36083923BFDAE">
        <enum>(e)</enum>
        <header>Priority</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In making cooperative agreements under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Healthy Kids Outdoors Act of 2014/s:4/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref> and subgrants under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Healthy Kids Outdoors Act of 2014/s:4/ss:d/p:1" proposed="true">subsection (d)(1)</cato:entity-ref>, the
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1400">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> and the recipient under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Healthy Kids Outdoors Act of 2014/s:4/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref>, respectively, shall give
			 preference to entities that serve individuals who have limited
			 opportunities to experience nature, including those who are
			 socioeconomically disadvantaged or have a disability or suffer
			 disproportionately from physical and mental health stressors.</text>
			</subsection>
      <subsection id="HB685681EDDE94705871CB2EAC103B04F">
        <enum>(f)</enum>
        <header>Guidelines</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, and after notice and
			 opportunity for public comment, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1400">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall publish in the Federal
			 Register guidelines on the implementation of this Act, including
			 guidelines for—</text>
				<paragraph id="HF48C5C46EAD3407B9FDB673B0569A3C3">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">developing and submitting strategies and evaluation methods under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Healthy Kids Outdoors Act of 2014/s:4/ss:b" proposed="true">subsection (b)</cato:entity-ref>; and</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H684EAEF2C1C048478023AFC67C6A87C8">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">technical assistance and dissemination of best practices under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Healthy Kids Outdoors Act of 2014/s:7" proposed="true">section 7</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
				</paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="H70BEA954E4C4408C88E811977595A19C">
        <enum>(g)</enum>
        <header>Reporting</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 2 years after the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1400">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> approves the Healthy Kids Outdoors State Strategy of an
			 eligible entity receiving funds under this section, and every year
			 thereafter, the eligible entity shall submit to the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1400">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> a report on
			 the implementation of the strategy based on the entity’s evaluation and
			 assessment of meeting the goals specified in the strategy.</text>
			</subsection>
      <subsection id="H2C40E803CC8D4E12A3DD3367714EE3ED">
        <enum>(h)</enum>
        <header>Allocation of funds</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An eligible entity receiving funding under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Healthy Kids Outdoors Act of 2014/s:4/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref> for a fiscal year—</text>
				<paragraph id="HEB8B0FECF1564238B8792326C303F4A9">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">may use not more than 5 percent of the funding for administrative expenses; and</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HBBFA9F8734AA4696A40D56F4797276F2">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall use at least 95 percent of the funding for subgrants to local partners under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Healthy Kids Outdoors Act of 2014/s:4/ss:d" proposed="true">subsection (d)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
				</paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="H9F8DF8B8E6884FCDA8095B502AD996B4">
        <enum>(i)</enum>
        <header>Match</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An eligible entity receiving funding under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Healthy Kids Outdoors Act of 2014/s:4/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref> for a fiscal year shall provide a
			 25-percent match through in-kind contributions or cash.</text>
			</subsection>
    </section>
    <section id="HA9E619E2C0F54403BD5E9A4766424F00">
      <enum>5.</enum>
      <header>National strategy for encouraging Americans to be active outdoors</header>
			<subsection id="HC7B7DD652FB9409BBFEE2A4BF3B06ED4">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>In general</header>
        <text>Not later than September 30, 2015, the President, in cooperation with appropriate Federal
			 departments and agencies, shall develop and issue a national strategy for
			 encouraging Americans, especially children, youth, and families, to be
			 physically active outdoors. Such a strategy shall include—</text>
				<paragraph id="HF9683D72CB174976947CC09CABA31835">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>identification of barriers to Americans, especially children, youth, and families, spending healthy
			 time outdoors and specific policy solutions to address those barriers;</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H1F78A10E91C94C36A25CF1F34FCCEA89">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>identification of opportunities for partnerships with Federal, State, tribal, and local partners;</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HC4628D3037A84BB3A624D24CE74EEFA8">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <text>coordination of efforts among Federal departments and agencies to address the impacts of Americans,
			 especially children, youth, and families, spending less active time
			 outdoors on—</text>
					<subparagraph id="H7899BC941D9B4E90870EAED8A40AFB4F">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>public health, including childhood obesity, attention deficit disorders and stress;</text>
					</subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="HBADE959B97E8444B8A6646674A275A55">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>the future of conservation in the United States; and</text>
					</subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H5C616015ECFC4D7BAF0BA1F43AB020D5">
            <enum>(C)</enum>
            <text>the economy;</text>
					</subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H074A1F7AEE5841958F37D4BFBF52F2BA">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
          <text>identification of ongoing research needs to document the health, conservation, economic, and other
			 outcomes of implementing the national strategy and State strategies;</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HD6A7C563D9C94F35B1DA3C2F7E90459D">
          <enum>(5)</enum>
          <text>coordination and alignment with Healthy Kids Outdoors State Strategies; and</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H517F1B5A4C3C4EC4ABAD72EFB929CC55">
          <enum>(6)</enum>
          <text>an action plan for implementing the strategy at the Federal level.</text>
				</paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="H0EBD0E281EFF4CB1978CB4DCEE91D2BF">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Strategy development</header>
				<paragraph id="H852C6A3F938C4FA1AB2892870BC700E4">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>Public participation</header>
          <text>Throughout the process of developing the national strategy under subsection (a), the President may
			 use, incorporate, or otherwise consider existing Federal plans and
			 strategies that, in whole or in part, contribute to connecting Americans,
			 especially children, youth, and families, with the outdoors and shall
			 provide for public participation, including a national summit of
			 participants with demonstrated expertise in encouraging individuals to be
			 physically active outdoors in nature.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H1095BB082A95416BBA456ADB0E03FD95">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Updating the national strategy</header>
          <text>The President shall update the national strategy not less than 5 years after the date the first
			 national strategy is issued under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Healthy Kids Outdoors Act of 2014/s:4/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref>, and every 5 years
			 thereafter. In updating the strategy, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> shall incorporate
			 results of the evaluation under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Healthy Kids Outdoors Act of 2014/s:6" proposed="true">section 6</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
				</paragraph>
      </subsection>
    </section>
    <section id="HB74426E812B24C9F8825B759EAAED1A8">
      <enum>6.</enum>
      <header>National evaluation of health impacts</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1400">Secretary</cato:entity-ref>, in coordination with the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="7500" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of Health and Human Services</cato:entity-ref>, shall—</text>
			<paragraph id="H3E3608C24A7E4575B5C3FD7FA52571D2">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text>develop recommendations for appropriate evaluation measures and criteria for a study of national
			 significance on the health impacts of the strategies under this Act; and</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HA8DB4970548D4B07851D63B8DFAD24E4">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text>carry out such a study.</text>
			</paragraph>
    </section>
    <section id="H87D66D54607543B8B391617793646076">
      <enum>7.</enum>
      <header>Technical assistance and best practices</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1400">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall—</text>
			<paragraph id="H9D7EBE9BC1B04D4CA314BD1F876272EA">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide technical assistance to grantees under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Healthy Kids Outdoors Act of 2014/s:4" proposed="true">section 4</cato:entity-ref> through cooperative agreements with
			 national organizations with a proven track record of encouraging
			 Americans, especially children, youth, and families, to be physically
			 active outdoors; and</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HBEB9D803DD834D4ABF53571D13586911">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">disseminate best practices that emerge from strategies funded under this Act.</text>
			</paragraph>
    </section>
    <section id="HAC2860C9338342C4B49C2A32BFB07F34">
      <enum>8.</enum>
      <header>Authorization of appropriations</header>
			<subsection id="HAF724BB517A84A28A30D40C0B9EAA397">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>In general</header>
        <text>There are authorized to be appropriated to the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1400">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> to carry out this Act—</text>
				<paragraph id="HFBB7BBE6EDF5401482EA913079836AE5">
          <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="auth-auth-approp">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>
              <cato:funds-and-year amount="1000000" year="2015">$1,000,000 for fiscal year 2015</cato:funds-and-year>;</text>
          </cato:entity>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H5308578F866D466DA53598FA25780A58">
          <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="auth-auth-approp">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>
              <cato:funds-and-year amount="2000000" year="2016">$2,000,000 for fiscal year 2016</cato:funds-and-year>; and</text>
          </cato:entity>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H16A7D7B22C0D43B4BB806688322008C3">
          <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="auth-auth-approp">
            <enum>(3)</enum>
          <text>
              <cato:funds-and-year amount="3000000" year="2017">$3,000,000 for fiscal year 2017</cato:funds-and-year>.</text>
          </cato:entity>
				</paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="H9A6CAD6A0D994DFFB1DF637874F78B8C">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Limitation</header>
        <text>Of the amounts made available to carry out this Act for a fiscal year, not more than 5 percent may
			 be made available for carrying out <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Healthy Kids Outdoors Act of 2014/s:7" proposed="true">section 7</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
			</subsection>
      <subsection id="HC387C32030CE4B40A4D82E2D2B364031">
        <enum>(c)</enum>
        <header>Supplement, not supplant</header>
        <text>Funds made available under this Act shall be used to supplement, and not supplant, any other
			 Federal, State, or local funds available for activities that encourage
			 Americans, especially children, youth, and families to be physically
			 active outdoors.</text>
			</subsection>
    </section>
  </legis-body>
</bill>
</doc>