<doc>
  <docmeta id="113hr761eh">
    <bill congress="113" type="hr" number="761" version="eh"/>
    <revision size="14377" annotations="0" status="complete" id="4" commit-time="2014-01-17T21:44:22Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113hr761eh/4.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <bill bill-stage="Engrossed-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HC500A2BE3C7F4A03B7402A721A3E8300" public-private="public" stage-count="1"> 
<metadata>
<dublinCore>
<dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">113 HR 761 EH: National Strategic and Critical Minerals Production Act of 2013</dc:title>
<dc:publisher xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"/>
<dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="no">IB</distribution-code> 
<congress display="yes">113th CONGRESS</congress> <session display="yes">1st Session</session> 
<legis-num>H. R. 761</legis-num> 
<current-chamber display="no">IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type> 
<official-title display="yes">To require the Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Agriculture to more efficiently develop domestic sources of the minerals and mineral materials of strategic and critical importance to United States economic and national security and manufacturing competitiveness.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="HF8995E728E7E4390AF03BAE947C3685C" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HFCA8F956AEBA44DB8F294B9F6F9F1BB3" section-type="section-one">
      <enum>1.</enum>
      <header>Short title</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote>
          <short-title>National Strategic and Critical Minerals Production Act of 2013</short-title>
        </quote>.</text> </section> 
<section id="H269CC742266845FE899DF94EAFA209D8">
      <enum>2.</enum>
      <header>Findings</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">
        <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> finds the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H5EF3878F610645248DC1A2B5AB61DBDA">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text>The industrialization of China and India has driven demand for nonfuel mineral commodities, sparking a period of resource nationalism exemplified by China’s reduction in exports of rare-earth elements necessary for telecommunications, military technologies, healthcare technologies, and conventional and renewable energy technologies.</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H18F97FA2105947F384653B6572F7A94C">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text>The availability of minerals and mineral materials are essential for economic growth, national security, technological innovation, and the manufacturing and agricultural supply chain.</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H183358613FE54899BAD205F09F571343">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <text>The exploration, production, processing, use, and recycling of minerals contribute significantly to the economic well-being, security and general welfare of the Nation.</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB67679F108BF402D877875DE85FF27CC">
        <enum>(4)</enum>
        <text>The United States has vast mineral resources, but is becoming increasingly dependent upon foreign sources of these mineral materials, as demonstrated by the following:</text> 
<subparagraph id="HDDAC8C80A37345A3938994C970F9506C">
          <enum>(A)</enum>
          <text>Twenty-five years ago the United States was dependent on foreign sources for 30 nonfuel mineral materials, 6 of which the United States imported 100 percent of the Nation’s requirements, and for another 16 commodities the United States imported more than 60 percent of the Nation’s needs.</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC377EBF291D4421287CF0907B19298BD">
          <enum>(B)</enum>
          <text>By 2011 the United States import dependence for nonfuel mineral materials had more than doubled from 30 to 67 commodities, 19 of which the United States imported 100 percent of the Nation’s requirements, and for another 24 commodities, imported more than 50 percent of the Nation’s needs.</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD250009B4FC64F738039A42FBA6D3441">
          <enum>(C)</enum>
          <text>The United States share of worldwide mineral exploration dollars was 8 percent in 2011, down from 19 percent in the early 1990s.</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC8F7AC568A4D4D0A98144388D1309A8D">
          <enum>(D)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the 2012 Ranking of Countries for Mining Investment, out of 25 major mining countries, the United States ranked last with Papua New Guinea in permitting delays, and towards the bottom regarding government take and social issues affecting mining.</text> </subparagraph>
      </paragraph>
    </section> 
<section id="H7D715DBDE2E54FBDBF4E715381FABF53">
      <enum>3.</enum>
      <header>Definitions</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> 
<paragraph id="H2C23A55D54A64B41970161796C53485E">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <header>Strategic and critical minerals</header>
        <text>The term <term>strategic and critical minerals</term> means minerals that are necessary—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H51C540BBB68B46089D23061FFF226602">
          <enum>(A)</enum>
          <text>for national defense and national security requirements;</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H72E0F0E70DF04C32A30AC57CCB43FFFC">
          <enum>(B)</enum>
          <text>for the Nation’s energy infrastructure, including pipelines, refining capacity, electrical power generation and transmission, and renewable energy production;</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H029A67A46EA6478FA56241347FDDCAB8">
          <enum>(C)</enum>
          <text>to support domestic manufacturing, agriculture, housing, telecommunications, healthcare, and transportation infrastructure; or</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC6C0EF70211844FDAEFD803BA6423835">
          <enum>(D)</enum>
          <text>for the Nation’s economic security and balance of trade.</text> </subparagraph>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H02851D162DF14B4AA704FFF0171A08F7">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <header>Agency</header>
        <text>The term <term>agency</term> means any agency, department, or other unit of Federal, State, local, or tribal government, or Alaska Native Corporation.</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA04EF5520AA74B8FB246D11B01F9EE7D">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <header>mineral exploration or mine permit</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>mineral exploration or mine permit</term> includes plans of operation issued by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1422">Bureau of Land Management</cato:entity-ref> and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="12C2">Forest Service</cato:entity-ref> pursuant to 43 CFR 3809 and 36 CFR 228A or the authorities listed in 43 CFR 3503.13, respectively.</text> </paragraph>
    </section> 
<title id="H8BF5710B45A943068776B1E1D9DE13A2">
      <enum>I</enum>
      <header>Development of Domestic Sources of Strategic and Critical Minerals</header> 
<section id="H75F125656CEF4E6690E41A46F8721251">
        <enum>101.</enum>
        <header>Improving development of strategic and critical minerals</header>
        <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Domestic mines that will provide strategic and critical minerals shall be considered an <term>infrastructure project</term> as described in Presidential Order <term>Improving Performance of Federal Permitting and Review of Infrastructure Projects</term> dated March 22, 2012.</text> </section> 
<section id="HADDD0850A9654E68A61C1E7E3914D2E0">
        <enum>102.</enum>
        <header>Responsibilities of the lead agency</header> 
<subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7F9A7BEA66724EE5A9D05743F1CA5B33">
          <enum>(a)</enum>
          <header>In general</header>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The lead agency with responsibility for issuing a mineral exploration or mine permit shall appoint a project lead who shall coordinate and consult with cooperating agencies and any other agency involved in the permitting process, project proponents and contractors to ensure that agencies minimize delays, set and adhere to timelines and schedules for completion of the permitting process, set clear permitting goals and track progress against those goals.</text> </subsection> 
<subsection id="H1548F7A4D57D437DBD0AEF701895255D">
          <enum>(b)</enum>
          <header>Determination under NEPA</header>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To the extent that the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="National Environmental Policy Act of 1969">National Environmental Policy Act of 1969</cato:entity-ref> applies to any mineral exploration or mine permit, the lead agency with responsibility for issuing a mineral exploration or mine permit shall determine that the action to approve the exploration or mine permit does not constitute a major Federal action significantly affecting the quality of the human environment within the meaning of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="National Environmental Policy Act of 1969">National Environmental Policy Act of 1969</cato:entity-ref> if the procedural and substantive safeguards of the permitting process alone, any applicable State permitting process alone, or a combination of the two processes together provide an adequate mechanism to ensure that environmental factors are taken into account.</text> </subsection> 
<subsection id="HBA6D6B7DEA204ABCBE519FD2FBE9F54F">
          <enum>(c)</enum>
          <header>coordination on permitting process</header>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The lead agency with responsibility for issuing a mineral exploration or mine permit shall enhance government coordination for the permitting process by avoiding duplicative reviews, minimizing paperwork and engaging other agencies and stakeholders early in the process. The lead agency shall consider the following best practices:</text> 
<paragraph id="H094B093C782B4BD8991F852544AA21F1">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Deferring to and relying upon baseline data, analyses and reviews performed by State agencies with jurisdiction over the proposed project.</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7A1049DDBEC4468D9E5A8088B1ECFA63">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Conducting any consultations or reviews concurrently rather than sequentially to the extent practicable and when such concurrent review will expedite rather than delay a decision.</text> </paragraph>
        </subsection> 
<subsection id="HF96A00105EB941AEB7D8C9858F3DDD1E">
          <enum>(d)</enum>
          <header>Schedule for permitting process</header>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">At the request of a project proponent, the lead agency, cooperating agencies and any other agencies involved with the mineral exploration or mine permitting process shall enter into an agreement with the project proponent that sets time limits for each part of the permitting process including the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H07621C7726BF47DB9F4A57EADF1745E4">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The decision on whether to prepare a document required under the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="National Environmental Policy Act of 1969">National Environmental Policy Act of 1969</cato:entity-ref>.</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC54AA02252A745D0A611F57D14749E35">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A determination of the scope of any document required under the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="National Environmental Policy Act of 1969">National Environmental Policy Act of 1969</cato:entity-ref>.</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H871C90AF9742491899851E76B4E64B17">
            <enum>(3)</enum>
            <text>The scope of and schedule for the baseline studies required to prepare a document required under the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="National Environmental Policy Act of 1969">National Environmental Policy Act of 1969</cato:entity-ref>.</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7007EB7595034ECD967054C5FC9F2D03">
            <enum>(4)</enum>
            <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Preparation of any draft document required under the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="National Environmental Policy Act of 1969">National Environmental Policy Act of 1969</cato:entity-ref>.</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4E36D948078D4D68B69E4FAB58210AC6">
            <enum>(5)</enum>
            <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Preparation of a final document required under the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="National Environmental Policy Act of 1969">National Environmental Policy Act of 1969</cato:entity-ref>.</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H34A4C669B0D24CA28DEC08F596BD1A4C">
            <enum>(6)</enum>
            <text>Consultations required under applicable laws.</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC5F57573C6A34180AF9586DA0816BC4A">
            <enum>(7)</enum>
            <text>Submission and review of any comments required under applicable law.</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HAC17189968944BDE84E521A432AC6656">
            <enum>(8)</enum>
            <text>Publication of any public notices required under applicable law.</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HEA8B9F86DD154A3AA6965CFEDF5D2085">
            <enum>(9)</enum>
            <text>A final or any interim decisions.</text> </paragraph>
        </subsection> 
<subsection id="HE0672B5FCC324D33AB3261BFBBCD4C68">
          <enum>(e)</enum>
          <header>Time limit for permitting process</header>
          <text>In no case should the total review process described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="National Strategic and Critical Minerals Production Act of 2013/s:102/ss:d" proposed="true">subsection (d)</cato:entity-ref> exceed 30 months unless agreed to by the signatories of the agreement.</text> </subsection> 
<subsection id="HD208D6FB0FB441FDB8B4B3D16214C07D">
          <enum>(f)</enum>
          <header>Limitation on addressing public comments</header>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The lead agency is not required to address agency or public comments that were not submitted during any public comment periods or consultation periods provided during the permitting process or as otherwise required by law.</text> </subsection> 
<subsection id="H953F9367CCF3486C8BF5D4EFBBFF4B30">
          <enum>(g)</enum>
          <header>Financial assurance</header>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The lead agency will determine the amount of financial assurance for reclamation of a mineral exploration or mining site, which must cover the estimated cost if the lead agency were to contract with a third party to reclaim the operations according to the reclamation plan, including construction and maintenance costs for any treatment facilities necessary to meet Federal, State or tribal environmental standards.</text> </subsection> 
<subsection id="HB100BC7065FC4B1C96243858C5A2EC77">
          <enum>(h)</enum>
          <header>Application to existing permit applications</header>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This section shall apply with respect to a mineral exploration or mine permit for which an application was submitted before the date of the enactment of this Act if the applicant for the permit submits a written request to the lead agency for the permit. The lead agency shall begin implementing this section with respect to such application within 30 days after receiving such written request.</text> </subsection> 
<subsection id="H0D580E96910C445198B75397693BE353">
          <enum>(i)</enum>
          <header>Strategic and critical minerals within National Forests</header>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to strategic and critical minerals within a federally administered unit of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="National Forest System" entity-parent-id="12C2">National Forest System</cato:entity-ref>, the lead agency shall—</text> 
<paragraph id="H2057E3E0CF6B4CD0B756EABE5F5D8D42">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">exempt all areas of identified mineral resources in Land Use Designations, other than Non-Development Land Use Designations, in existence as of the date of the enactment of this Act from the procedures detailed at and all rules promulgated under part 294 of title 36, Code for Federal Regulations;</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2AB353C541234DD891183C8528EE2D67">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">apply such exemption to all additional routes and areas that the lead agency finds necessary to facilitate the construction, operation, maintenance, and restoration of the areas of identified mineral resources described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="National Strategic and Critical Minerals Production Act of 2013/s:102/ss:i/p:1" proposed="true">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref>; and</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H75EF9EEE2942444FA3982F5746BC993C">
            <enum>(3)</enum>
            <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">continue to apply such exemptions after approval of the Minerals Plan of Operations for the unit of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="National Forest System" entity-parent-id="12C2">National Forest System</cato:entity-ref>.</text> </paragraph>
        </subsection>
      </section> 
<section commented="no" id="H966B4E1E73254C02A8CC596CCD780EFF">
        <enum>103.</enum>
        <header>Conservation of the resource</header>
        <text display-inline="no-display-inline">In evaluating and issuing any mineral exploration or mine permit, the priority of the lead agency shall be to maximize the development of the mineral resource, while mitigating environmental impacts, so that more of the mineral resource can be brought to the market place.</text> </section> 
<section id="H1A06894511D64EEFAE161A9DE8AC62CF">
        <enum>104.</enum>
        <header>Federal register process for mineral exploration and mining projects</header> 
<subsection id="HF6693E5496E049B2BF649B855A7A730B">
          <enum>(a)</enum>
          <header>Preparation of Federal Notices for Mineral Exploration and Mine Development Projects</header>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The preparation of Federal Register notices required by law associated with the issuance of a mineral exploration or mine permit shall be delegated to the organization level within the agency responsible for issuing the mineral exploration or mine permit. All Federal Register notices regarding official document availability, announcements of meetings, or notices of intent to undertake an action shall be originated and transmitted to the Federal Register from the office where documents are held, meetings are held, or the activity is initiated.</text> </subsection> 
<subsection id="H8FCB851695F546E192DE699403185AF0">
          <enum>(b)</enum>
          <header>Departmental Review of Federal Register Notices for Mineral Exploration and Mining Projects</header>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Absent any extraordinary circumstance or except as otherwise required by any Act of Congress, each Federal Register notice described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="National Strategic and Critical Minerals Production Act of 2013/s:104/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref> shall undergo any required reviews within the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1400">Department of the Interior</cato:entity-ref> or the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1200">Department of Agriculture</cato:entity-ref> and be published in its final form in the Federal Register no later than 30 days after its initial preparation.</text> </subsection>
      </section>
    </title> 
<title id="H1BE893004FD746DDBF4E37868FA1C83B">
      <enum>II</enum>
      <header>Judicial review of agency actions relating to Exploration and Mine Permits</header> 
<section id="HF2D0EDA194D6452F9437489AC8B2BF63">
        <enum>201.</enum>
        <header>Definitions for title</header>
        <text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this title the term <term>covered civil action</term> means a civil action against the Federal Government containing a claim under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc/5/702">
            <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/5/702">section 702</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code</cato:entity-ref>, regarding agency action affecting a mineral exploration or mine permit.</text> </section> 
<section id="H60594D8B186341E9867E936BFBE877CE">
        <enum>202.</enum>
        <header>Timely filings</header>
        <text display-inline="no-display-inline">A covered civil action is barred unless filed no later than the end of the 60-day period beginning on the date of the final Federal agency action to which it relates.</text> </section> 
<section id="HFBB635B08AD34F34BDC8F6A013782B63">
        <enum>203.</enum>
        <header>Right to intervene</header>
        <text display-inline="no-display-inline">The holder of any mineral exploration or mine permit may intervene as of right in any covered civil action by a person affecting rights or obligations of the permit holder under the permit.</text> </section> 
<section id="HB2581AD34E8840B288C5EA098BEF459C">
        <enum>204.</enum>
        <header>Expedition in hearing and determining the action</header>
        <text display-inline="no-display-inline">The court shall endeavor to hear and determine any covered civil action as expeditiously as possible.</text> </section> 
<section id="HB8C66CCFF658433489B0B5936296747C">
        <enum>205.</enum>
        <header>Limitation on prospective relief</header>
        <text display-inline="no-display-inline">In a covered civil action, the court shall not grant or approve any prospective relief unless the court finds that such relief is narrowly drawn, extends no further than necessary to correct the violation of a legal requirement, and is the least intrusive means necessary to correct that violation.</text> </section> 
<section id="H0894BDD26889400AA40F52BC0AC01792">
        <enum>206.</enum>
        <header>Limitation on attorneys’ fees</header>
        <text display-inline="no-display-inline">
          <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/5/504">Sections 504 of title 5, United States Code</cato:entity-ref>, and <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/28/2412">2412 of title 28, United States Code</cato:entity-ref> (together commonly called the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Equal Access to Justice Act">Equal Access to Justice Act</cato:entity-ref>)</cato:entity> do not apply to a covered civil action, nor shall any party in such a covered civil action receive payment from the Federal Government for their attorneys’ fees, expenses, and other court costs.</text> </section>
    </title> 
<title id="H07435C1AE83D465BB611F57431CE9668">
      <enum>III</enum>
      <header>Miscellaneous Provisions</header> 
<section id="H466EC1179722482CA1938DC177ABAE68">
        <enum>301.</enum>
        <header>Secretarial order not affected</header>
        <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this Act shall be construed as to affect any aspect of Secretarial Order 3324, issued by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1400">Secretary of the Interior</cato:entity-ref> on December 3, 2012, with respect to potash and oil and gas operators.</text>
      </section>
    </title> 
</legis-body> <attestation>
    <attestation-group>
      <attestation-date date="20130918" chamber="House">Passed the House of Representatives September 18, 2013.</attestation-date>
      <attestor display="no">Karen L. Haas,</attestor>
      <role>Clerk.</role>
    </attestation-group>
  </attestation> 
<endorsement display="yes"/> 
</bill>
</doc>