<doc>
  <docmeta id="113hr5523ih">
    <bill congress="113" type="hr" number="5523" version="ih"/>
    <revision size="5320" annotations="0" status="complete" id="4" commit-time="2014-10-08T20:06:54Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113hr5523ih/4.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H3AB30776E2944D56A9ADB45E460B12B2" public-private="public">
	<metadata>
<dublinCore>
<dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">113 HR 5523 IH: Employee Benefits Protection Act of 2014</dc:title>
<dc:publisher xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">2014-09-17</dc:date>
<dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>113th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>2d Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 5523</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20140917">September 17, 2014</action-date>
			<action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="S000480">Ms. Slaughter</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="J000255">Mr. Jones</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and the Workforce</committee-name>
      </action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To amend the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 and the National Labor Relations Act
			 to protect the health benefits of retirees, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H54DCCDC2DB1043D2A256E432A6D33BC2" style="OLC">
		<section id="HA690135EE904482C816D6B8E9DDB07CF" section-type="section-one">
      <enum>1.</enum>
      <header>Short title</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote>
          <short-title>
            <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Employee Benefits Protection Act of 2014" proposed="true">Employee Benefits Protection Act of 2014</cato:entity-ref>
          </short-title>
        </quote>.</text>
		</section>
    <section id="HBCE219673AE14F85B273AA6B7AAB0E9F">
      <enum>2.</enum>
      <header>Notification of extent to which health benefits can be modified or terminated</header>
			<subsection id="H211026550F8648AFA5AD55149FF38ACF">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Inclusion in summary plan description</header>
        <text>
          <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974/s:102/ss:b">Section 102(b) of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/1022">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/29/1022">29 U.S.C. 1022</cato:entity-ref>
          </external-xref>)</cato:entity> is amended
			 by inserting <quote>; in the case of a group health plan (as so defined), whether the provisions of the plan permit the
			 plan sponsor or any employer participating in the plan to unilaterally
			 modify or terminate the benefits under the plan with respect to employees,
			 retired employees, and beneficiaries, and when and to what extent benefits
			 under the plan are fully vested with respect to employees, retired
			 employees, and beneficiaries</quote> after <quote>the name and address of such issuer</quote>.</text>
			</subsection>
      <subsection id="HBC48A1276EC148A08F16B24E70C2B8B9">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Presumption that retired employee health benefits cannot be modified or terminated</header>
        <text>
          <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974/s:502">Section 502 of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/1132">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/29/1132">29 U.S.C. 1132</cato:entity-ref>
          </external-xref>)</cato:entity> is amended by
			 adding at the end the following new subsection:</text>
				<quoted-block act-name="" id="HE17B41666DC940A296A8E6ECBCFFDB9E" style="OLC">
					<subsection id="H8859DA6F024B48BA81706FFE1F4FFF8E">
            <enum>(n)</enum>
            <text>In the case of a suit brought under this title by a participant or beneficiary relating to benefits
			 of a retired employee or the dependents of a retired employee under a
			 group health plan (as defined in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974/s:733/ss:a/p:1">section 733(a)(1)</cato:entity-ref>), the presumption for
			 purposes of such suit shall be that as of the date an employee retires or
			 completes 20 years of service with the employer, benefits available under
			 the plan during retirement of the employee are fully vested and cannot be
			 modified or terminated for the life of the employee or, if longer, the
			 life of the employee's spouse. This presumption can be overcome only upon
			 a showing, by clear and convincing evidence, that the terms of the group
			 health plan allow for a modification or termination of benefits available
			 under the plan and that the employee, prior to becoming a participant in
			 the plan, was made aware, in clear and unambiguous terms, that the plan
			 allowed for such modification or termination of benefits.</text>
          </subsection>
          <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
        </quoted-block>
			</subsection>
    </section>
    <section id="H639734E4CDB64AB7BE21655844F3D5FC">
      <enum>3.</enum>
      <header>Protection of retirees under certain collectively bargained agreements</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">
        <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
          <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="National Labor Relations Act/s:8">Section 8 of the National Labor Relations Act</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/158">
          <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/29/158">29 U.S.C. 158</cato:entity-ref>
        </external-xref>)</cato:entity> is amended by adding at the end the
			 following:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H75BBC3C89D0249B493E941A035569B13" style="OLC">
				<subsection id="HA8915170E7874E808480A8A6221A29F2">
          <enum>(h)</enum>
          <text>It shall be an unfair labor practice for any labor organization and any employer to enter into any
			 contract or agreement, express or implied, whereby the organization and
			 employer agree to modify the terms of any previous agreement in a manner
			 that would result in a reduction or termination of retiree health
			 insurance benefits provided to an employee or a dependent of an employee
			 under the previous agreement, if such modification of the terms of the
			 previous agreement occurs after the date on which the employee retires.</text>
        </subsection>
        <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
      </quoted-block>
		</section>
    <section id="H210E242FAA3F488FA0D9E2F388709D24">
      <enum>4.</enum>
      <header>Comptroller General report</header>
			<subsection id="H5235E8DA84344050B18DEB0847EF952C">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>In general</header>
        <text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="0500" entity-type="federal-body">Comptroller General of the
			 United States</cato:entity-ref> shall submit to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> a report on the strategies that
			 corporations use to avoid obligations to pay promised employee and retiree
			 benefits.</text>
			</subsection>
      <subsection id="H5F249B8952BA413E86DBD4CFB3312139">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Contents</header>
        <text>The report under subsection (a) shall include a discussion of—</text>
				<paragraph id="H9F49B72348C24DD89E992E5FB6FB6A8E">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>the use of spin-offs, mergers, subsidiaries, bankruptcies, asset sales, and other strategies to
			 avoid obligations to pay promised employee and retiree benefits;</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H2A447B61B72F4C7F807644B58EF7DA0B">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>the impact of such avoidance on the financial, physical, and mental well-being of employees and
			 retirees;</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H29C0B11F66934EFF925FF63B2EDA7B2E">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <text>the impact on Federal and State budgets when employers terminate or reduce the benefits of
			 employees and retirees, including the costs that are incurred when
			 employees and retirees seek assistance from Federal and State government
			 programs and services as a result of the termination or reduction of their
			 employment-related benefits; and</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H5AA9B9140D684F7595D55D0E519A0C2F">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
          <text>recommendations to prevent corporations from evading contractual obligations to pay employee and
			 retiree benefits.</text>
				</paragraph>
      </subsection>
    </section>
  </legis-body>
</bill>
</doc>