<doc>
  <docmeta id="113hres400ih">
    <bill congress="113" type="hres" number="400" version="ih"/>
    <revision size="2800" annotations="0" status="complete" id="3" commit-time="2013-11-13T18:08:29Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113hres400ih/3.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <resolution xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" dms-id="HFC83FD27B7834E2A93E1D9CE5603E766" key="H" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print">
  <metadata>
<dublinCore>
<dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">113 HRES 400 IH: Honoring the life and work of Commander M. Scott Carpenter, the second American to orbit the Earth.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">2013-10-30</dc:date>
<dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code>
    <congress display="yes">113th CONGRESS</congress>
    <session display="yes">1st Session</session>
    <legis-num>H. RES. 400</legis-num>
    <current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
    <action display="yes">
      <action-date date="20131030">October 30, 2013</action-date>
      <action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="P000593">Mr. Perlmutter</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="P000598">Mr. Polis</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Committee on Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name>
      </action-desc>
    </action>
    <legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
    <official-title display="yes">Honoring the life and work of Commander M. Scott Carpenter, the second American to orbit the Earth.</official-title>
  </form>
  <preamble>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas Commander M. Scott Carpenter was 1 of the original 7 astronauts of the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="8000">National Aeronautics and Space Administration’s</cato:entity-ref> Project Mercury;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas, in 1962, Mr. Carpenter, aboard the spacecraft Aurora 7, was the second American to orbit the Earth and was able to overcome extreme technical difficulties during the mission by manually piloting the spacecraft to a safe re-entry;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas, in 1965, Mr. Carpenter spent 30 days living and working on the ocean floor as an aquanaut aboard the Sealab II;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas Mr. Carpenter was the fourth American to go into space;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas Malcolm Scott Carpenter was born on May 1, 1925, in Boulder, Colorado, and was also a resident of New York City for a time;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas Mr. Carpenter became a naval aviation cadet in 1943, serving his country for the duration of World War II, after which he entered the University of Colorado in 1946, received a Navy commission in 1949, and earned his wings of gold in 1951;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas Mr. Carpenter flew patrol planes during the Korean war, trained as a test pilot at Naval Air Station Patuxent River, Maryland, and was chosen in April 1959 among 7 military test pilots to be a Mercury astronaut, helping to carry out President John F. Kennedy’s goal of putting a man on the Moon; and</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas Mr. Carpenter is survived by his wife, Patricia Barrett Carpenter; his sons Jay, Matthew, Nicholas, and Zachary; his daughters Kristen Stoever and Candace Carpenter; 1 granddaughter; 3 stepchildren; and 5 step-grandchildren: Now, therefore, be it</text>
    </whereas>
  </preamble>
  <resolution-body id="H52DA10D27EE8408B876A58B141AEFFEF" style="traditional">
    <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H7DFC0666CF244906AC62DC2F63FD87A2" section-type="undesignated-section">
      <enum/>
      <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0050">House of Representatives</cato:entity-ref>—</text>
      <paragraph id="HB6F74FF366CA486EAA1E72F7253CF927">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">honors Commander M. Scott Carpenter for his brave work, unrelenting passion for space exploration, and encouragement in sending future students into the fields of aeronautics, astronautics, and undersea exploration; and</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HA8181D25CA09448DAE3C3DE0D8658DFD">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text>acknowledges Mr. Carpenter as a dynamic pioneer of modern exploration.</text>
      </paragraph>
    </section>
  </resolution-body>
</resolution>
</doc>