<doc>
  <docmeta id="113hr3323ih">
    <bill congress="113" type="hr" number="3323" version="ih"/>
    <revision size="99552" annotations="0" status="complete" id="8" commit-time="2013-11-05T21:21:25Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113hr3323ih/8.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H300ABBF6CC304041AB094999B1570268" public-private="public">
  <metadata>
<dublinCore>
<dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">113 HR 3323 IH: Children in Families First Act of 2013</dc:title>
<dc:publisher xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">2013-10-23</dc:date>
<dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
    <congress>113th CONGRESS</congress>
    <session>1st Session</session>
    <legis-num>H. R. 3323</legis-num>
    <current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
    <action>
      <action-date date="20131023">October 23, 2013</action-date>
      <action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="G000377">Ms. Granger</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="B001256">Mrs. Bachmann</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001273">Mrs. Black</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000600">Mr. Diaz-Balart</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000448">Mr. Franks of Arizona</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000168">Mr. Olson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000244">Mr. Sensenbrenner</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001270">Ms. Bass</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001278">Ms. Bonamici</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000126">Ms. Eddie Bernice Johnson of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001259">Mr. Braley of Iowa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001284">Mrs. Brooks of Indiana</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C000754">Mr. Cooper</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000399">Mr. Doggett</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="I000057">Mr. Israel</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000032">Ms. Jackson Lee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000559">Mr. Langevin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001191">Mr. Murphy of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001165">Mr. Sires</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="T000472">Mr. Takano</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Judiciary</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
    </action>
    <legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
    <official-title>To realign structures and reallocate resources in the Federal Government, in keeping with the core American belief that families are the best protection for children and the bedrock of any society, to bolster United States diplomacy and assistance targeted at ensuring that every child can grow up in a permanent, safe, nurturing, and loving family, and to strengthen intercountry adoption to the United States and around the world and ensure that it becomes a viable and fully developed option for providing families for children in need, and for other purposes.</official-title>
  </form>
  <legis-body id="H0A14742132A34C6DB916C9AEE6D0C5CE" style="OLC">
    <section id="H7E07AB1F590C430DB07FB73FF0E6F54D" section-type="section-one">
      <enum>1.</enum>
      <header>Short title; table of contents</header>
      <subsection id="HF1E102BA19EB450C9DAA9B7A5FF4DB93">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Short title</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote>
            <short-title>Children in Families First Act of 2013</short-title>
          </quote>.</text>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="H79E9F24C9FF24D5B8FCE0C7BEE4ED23E">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Table of contents</header>
        <text>The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text>
        <toc container-level="legis-body-container" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded" lowest-level="section" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" regeneration="yes-regeneration">
          <toc-entry idref="H7E07AB1F590C430DB07FB73FF0E6F54D" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title; table of contents.</toc-entry>
          <toc-entry idref="HA822AAD05FCD4672910C61B134C1266C" level="section">Sec. 2. Findings; purposes.</toc-entry>
          <toc-entry idref="HC1FBD396BEBA4BCF8E5A8F74C6CF8406" level="section">Sec. 3. Definitions.</toc-entry>
          <toc-entry idref="H5DA6CA21E17040598154605BC0F745EB" level="title">Title I—Realignment of certain international child welfare responsibilities and functions</toc-entry>
          <toc-entry idref="H8B13F5FA33DA40F5994030DB510CE2BA" level="section">Sec. 101. Establishment of Bureau of Vulnerable Children and Family Security in the Department of State.</toc-entry>
          <toc-entry idref="H2626308BD57C4D5791A66D05AE68047D" level="section">Sec. 102. Responsibilities of U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services for accreditation of adoption service providers.</toc-entry>
          <toc-entry idref="HCEEBEF6491464CEB8C43306B136BF294" level="section">Sec. 103. Transfer of functions and savings provisions.</toc-entry>
          <toc-entry idref="H618D629A810149C4BFE4381F9C573295" level="section">Sec. 104. Responsibilities of U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services for adoption-related case processing.</toc-entry>
          <toc-entry idref="H79306F4C5E74482DBE5E8DDC13A5E3C4" level="title">Title II—Annual reporting</toc-entry>
          <toc-entry idref="H9D7101E2D201448E85EE29BF6E513D9E" level="section">Sec. 201. Annual report on children living without families.</toc-entry>
          <toc-entry idref="H8179F3B451314614BBFDE9F613F81FCD" level="section">Sec. 202. Country reports regarding severe forms of trafficking.</toc-entry>
          <toc-entry idref="HCB464E65BAB046BBA24A94BA6A574E55" level="title">Title III—Promotion of a comprehensive approach for children in adversity</toc-entry>
          <toc-entry idref="HE08FF54C8FBB4CB685E2FBEF057E3687" level="section">Sec. 301. Establishment of a USAID Center for Excellence for Children in Adversity.</toc-entry>
          <toc-entry idref="HC03C66B2B1A94E4B8586716350785D05" level="title">Title IV—Funding and effective dates</toc-entry>
          <toc-entry idref="H8CED157AC2834B8C959B3A90CC8A8F44" level="section">Sec. 401. Funding.</toc-entry>
          <toc-entry idref="H528147D69C184495BEB3E57C4C1F4E7B" level="section">Sec. 402. Effective dates.</toc-entry>
        </toc>
      </subsection>
    </section>
    <section id="HA822AAD05FCD4672910C61B134C1266C">
      <enum>2.</enum>
      <header>Findings; purposes</header>
      <subsection id="HF1E829BD5B7E4753BE0C2E43F8DA8965">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Findings</header>
        <text>
          <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> makes the following findings:</text>
        <paragraph id="H216970B20A4249568C8755F03077BF3E">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>The people of the United States recognize and believe that children must grow up in permanent, safe, and nurturing families in order to develop and thrive.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H1C4E09BD8D494DFC82AB156B2BB2EBE5">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>Science now proves conclusively that children suffer immediate, lasting, and in many cases irreversible damage from time spent living in institutions or outside of families, including reduced brain activity, reduced IQ, smaller brain size, and inability to form emotional bonds with others.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HB49F7D8006D649DCB3BBC83ADFA91475">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <text>Governments in other countries seek models that promote the placement of children who are living outside family care in permanent, safe, and nurturing families, rather than in foster care or institutions, but many governments lack the resources or infrastructure to adequately address this need.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H2B78922DB9D34A4B8C3DE513F1334855">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
          <text>Despite the good efforts of countless governments and nongovernmental organizations, millions of children remain uncounted and outside of the protection, nurturing care, permanence, safety, and love of a family. Without the care of a family, these children are forced to live on the streets, in institutions, in paid foster care, in child-headed households, in group homes, or as household servants.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HC7580C36243A4B859818ACF92315E9E2">
          <enum>(5)</enum>
          <text>No reliable data currently exists to define and document the number and needs of children in the world currently living without families, but available evidence demonstrates that there are millions of children in this situation needing immediate help.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H2FF92EB81D644C008BAC096D62DE8793">
          <enum>(6)</enum>
          <text>The December 2012 Action Plan for Children in Adversity commits the United States Government to achieving a world in which all children grow up within protective family care and free from deprivation, exploitation, and danger. To effectively and efficiently accomplish this goal, it is necessary to realign the United States Government’s current operational system for assisting orphans and vulnerable children, and processing intercountry adoptions.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H0923FE38BA144242BDF5779814851E8F">
          <enum>(7)</enum>
          <text>All options for providing appropriate, protective, and permanent family care to children living without families must be considered concurrently and permanent solutions must be put in place as quickly as possible. Solutions include family preservation and reunification, kinship care, guardianship, domestic and intercountry adoption, and other culturally acceptable forms of care that will result in appropriate, protective, and permanent family care. Preference should be given to options that optimize child best interests, which generally means options which provide children with fully protected legal status and parents with full legal status as parents, including full parental rights and responsibilities. The principle of subsidiarity, which gives preference to in-country solutions, should be implemented within the context of a concurrent planning strategy, exploring in- and out-of-country options simultaneously. If an in-country placement serving the child’s best interest and providing appropriate, protective, and permanent care is not quickly available, and such an international home is available, the child should be placed in that international home without delay.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H0220B31426B34F1F8B43A416173FD76A">
          <enum>(8)</enum>
          <text>Significant resources are already dedicated to international assistance for orphans and vulnerable children, and a relatively small portion of these resources can be reallocated to achieve more timely, effective, nurturing, and permanent familial solutions for children living without families, resulting in fewer children worldwide living in institutions or on the streets, more families preserved or reunified, and increased domestic and international adoptions.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="H3A295B4805B54491969F36DB2F3CA5E6">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Purposes</header>
        <text>The purposes of this Act are—</text>
        <paragraph id="H74567D52448F4192B1A851D5BAC660F7">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>to support the core American value that families are the bedrock of any society;</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H92A8886519CE4236A6DBFD5DB6E12B3F">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>to protect the fundamental human right of all children to grow up within the loving care of permanent, safe, and nurturing families;</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HDAD0270D1BF848EDBEFD40EB1D71131B">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <text>to address a critical gap in United States foreign policy implementation by adjusting the Federal Government’s international policy and operational structures so that seeking permanent families for children living without families receives more prominence, focus, and resources (through the reallocation of existing personnel and resources);</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HEB45AD54CD484531BB1318015F6E7EBA">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
          <text>to harness the diplomatic and operational power of the United States Government in the international sphere by helping to identify and implement timely, permanent, safe, and nurturing familial solutions for children living without families, including refugee or stateless children;</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H8D147C94B5B2429186B055F0A7C80CAD">
          <enum>(5)</enum>
          <text>to ensure that intercountry adoption by United States citizens becomes a viable and fully developed option for creating permanent families for children who need them;</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H9A69C60C482B4EBDBF3B39DB7922B00A">
          <enum>(6)</enum>
          <text>to protect against abuses of children, birth families, and adoptive parents involved in intercountry adoptions, and to ensure that such adoptions are in the individual child’s best interests; and</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HB408856A9FEC43C1B7E8FDE434A582DB">
          <enum>(7)</enum>
          <text>to harmonize and strengthen existing intercountry adoption processes under United States law—</text>
          <subparagraph id="HCCAA732EB62845D8BC60F0BB006D8443">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>by ensuring that the same set of procedures and criteria govern suitability and eligibility determinations for prospective adoptive parents seeking to complete intercountry adoptions, whether or not the child is from a foreign state that is a party to the Hague Adoption Convention; and</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="HB702B4012C7F42D196CB3F4815F5D1A9">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>by aligning the definitions of eligible child for Convention adoptions and non-Convention adoptions to the maximum extent possible.</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
    </section>
    <section id="HC1FBD396BEBA4BCF8E5A8F74C6CF8406">
      <enum>3.</enum>
      <header>Definitions</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text>
      <paragraph id="H4F1D937F8867416B83FAFAFD6DCD8633">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <header>Action plan for children in adversity</header>
        <text>The term <term>Action Plan for Children in Adversity</term> means the policy document entitled <term>United States Government Action Plan on Children in Adversity: A Framework for International Assistance: 2012–2017</term>, released on December 19, 2012.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H022C87C36F9E4F5999222C03FF2060F0">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <header>Appropriate, protective, and permanent family care</header>
        <text>The term <term>appropriate, protective, and permanent family care</term> means a nurturing, lifelong, commitment to a child by an adult, or adults with parental roles and responsibilities that—</text>
        <subparagraph id="HDEDB435B4E7B485F83E5A970C248259C">
          <enum>(A)</enum>
          <text>provides physical and emotional support;</text>
        </subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="HF40AD62AA2484CC299162C86B13801EE">
          <enum>(B)</enum>
          <text>provides the child with a sense of belonging; and</text>
        </subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="H92B4C5E7AC7B437A8D7F127A806645DA">
          <enum>(C)</enum>
          <text>generally involves full legal recognition of the child’s status as child of the parents and of the parents’ rights and responsibilities regarding the child.</text>
        </subparagraph>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H29070AA1F7F54E50BAD7E4A8B8BCCFE7">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <header>Central authority</header>
        <text>The term <term>central authority</term> has the meaning given the term in <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000/s:3">section 3 of the Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/14902">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/42/14902">42 U.S.C. 14902</cato:entity-ref>
            </external-xref>)</cato:entity>.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H64EF9A4A8D9A46EB871073F35647F287">
        <enum>(4)</enum>
        <header>Children in adversity</header>
        <text>The term <term>children in adversity</term> means children living inside or outside of family care who are deprived, excluded, vulnerable, or at risk for violence, abuse, exploitation, or neglect.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H78BD896ABAAF4AF4B0FC84C90CD83248">
        <enum>(5)</enum>
        <header>Convention adoption</header>
        <text>The term <term>Convention adoption</term> has the meaning given the term in <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000/s:3">section 3 of the Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/14902">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/42/14902">42 U.S.C. 14902</cato:entity-ref>
            </external-xref>)</cato:entity>.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HF2D4B72E9508443AB00DB1B84F0A4F83">
        <enum>(6)</enum>
        <header>Convention country</header>
        <text>The term <term>Convention country</term> has the meaning given the term in <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000/s:3">section 3 of the Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/14902">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/42/14902">42 U.S.C. 14902</cato:entity-ref>
            </external-xref>)</cato:entity> and for which the Hague Adoption Convention has entered into force.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H1FB3480174E54C91947DBFE0ED7D5AD0">
        <enum>(7)</enum>
        <header>Guardianship</header>
        <text>The term <term>guardianship</term> means a permanent legal relationship between an adult and a child, whereby the adult is lawfully invested with the power, and charged with the duty, of taking care of the child. While some forms of guardianship are not truly permanent, the form of guardianship referred to and supported under this Act is permanent guardianship. A Kefala order issued by a country that follows traditional Islamic law does not qualify as an adoption under United States law, but may be a form of guardianship in some circumstances.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H8BD77733FEFD41548BCADAEDF3E1E1FF">
        <enum>(8)</enum>
        <header>Habitual residence determination</header>
        <text>The term <term>habitual residence determination</term> means a factual determination of where a prospective adoptive parent (or parents) resides and where the child resides for purposes of an intercountry adoption case.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H2172BB4D4A204131BE9F146498E34CD8">
        <enum>(9)</enum>
        <header>Hague adoption convention</header>
        <text>The term <term>Hague Adoption Convention</term> means the Convention of Protection of Children and Cooperation in Respect of Intercountry Adoption, concluded at The Hague May 29, 1993.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HD7D42361E88A4C03868DC58BD5714D24">
        <enum>(10)</enum>
        <header>Kinship care</header>
        <text>The term <term>kinship care</term> means the full time care, nurturing, and protection of children by relatives, members of their tribes or clans, godparents, stepparents, or any adult who has a kinship bond with a child, so long as those persons have the capacity and commitment to function as true parents for the child on a permanent basis. It does not include paid kinship foster care.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HD2AD4858E8314C50BF9367B97E134C83">
        <enum>(11)</enum>
        <header>Non-convention adoption</header>
        <text>The term <term>non-Convention adoption</term> means—</text>
        <subparagraph id="HF284E801A3B048F689E6F939E32574CF">
          <enum>(A)</enum>
          <text>an adoption by United States parents of a child from a non-Convention country in accordance with <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Immigration and Nationality Act/s:101/ss:b/p:1/sp:F">subparagraph (F) of section 101(b)(1) of the Immigration and Nationality Act</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/8/1101/b/1">8 U.S.C. 1101(b)(1)</cato:entity-ref>
              </external-xref>)</cato:entity>;</text>
        </subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="H554FE339B74D464EBBD53882AB95BE5B">
          <enum>(B)</enum>
          <text>an adoption by United States parents of a child under the laws of the child’s country of origin (generally when the parents are living in the child’s country of origin and therefore able legally to complete a domestic adoption); or</text>
        </subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="H307565C5B6A44FC0A459ACFDDBFF6FE9">
          <enum>(C)</enum>
          <text>in certain circumstances (generally with respect to relative adoptions or adoptions by dual national parents), an adoption by United States parents of a child from a Convention country if that country allows legal and valid adoptions to take place outside the scope of the Convention.</text>
        </subparagraph>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H028B951AFC714394A07B42625E1BB70E">
        <enum>(12)</enum>
        <header>Non-convention country</header>
        <text>The term <term>non-Convention country</term> means a country in which the Hague Adoption Convention has not entered into force, regardless of whether or not that country has signed the Convention.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HD044FFB925F7435F8B0F651CAFC7C97C">
        <enum>(13)</enum>
        <header>Unparented children</header>
        <text>The term <term>unparented children</term> means children lacking the legal, permanent, safe, and nurturing care of a parental figure or figures, either inside their country of origin, in the country of their habitual residence, or elsewhere, regardless of their lawful or unlawful immigration status in their current country of residence.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H20B0EE128D6C4217BDEB0D62A32BE8C6">
        <enum>(14)</enum>
        <header>Vulnerable children</header>
        <text>The term <term>vulnerable children</term>, consistent with the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7200">United States Agency for International Development's</cato:entity-ref> definition, means children and youth who are under 18 years whose safety, well-being, growth, and development are at significant risk due to inadequate care, protection, or access to essential services.</text>
      </paragraph>
    </section>
    <title id="H5DA6CA21E17040598154605BC0F745EB">
      <enum>I</enum>
      <header>Realignment of certain international child welfare responsibilities and functions</header>
      <section id="H8B13F5FA33DA40F5994030DB510CE2BA">
        <enum>101.</enum>
        <header>Establishment of Bureau of Vulnerable Children and Family Security in the Department of State</header>
        <subsection id="HC122AE0959D34A52A62AD34AA3A12A6C">
          <enum>(a)</enum>
          <header>Establishment</header>
          <text>There is established within the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Department of State</cato:entity-ref> the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Bureau of Vulnerable Children and Family Security" entity-parent-id="1900" proposed="true">Bureau of Vulnerable Children and Family Security</cato:entity-ref> (referred to in this Act as the <term>VCFS</term>), which shall be located in the Secretariat for Civilian Security, Democracy and Human Rights and shall promote and support the following activities:</text>
          <paragraph id="H0E0E8A06646E43169A389B2CAF4F92CE">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <text>The development and implementation in foreign countries of child welfare laws, regulations, policies, best practices, and procedures in keeping with the goals articulated in the Action Plan for Children in Adversity, including—</text>
            <subparagraph id="H006D0D02CCF040C5ACD773193471CA86">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>the sound development of children through the integration of health, nutrition, and family support;</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="HB94AA093F2724068812200E1DF44A127">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>supporting and enabling families to care for children through family preservation, reunification, and support of kinship care, guardianship, and domestic and intercountry adoption; and</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H0082763C7EF14FEDA094D6272FF7ECAB">
              <enum>(C)</enum>
              <text>facilitating the efforts of national governments and partners to prevent, respond to, and protect children from violence, exploitation, abuse, and neglect.</text>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="HFCB24D74AE0449EAB35B7005584D4BB3">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <text>Addressing the gap in United States Government diplomacy, policy, and operations with respect to promoting appropriate, protective, and permanent family care for children living without families by establishing within the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Bureau of Vulnerable Children and Family Security" entity-parent-id="1900" proposed="true">VCFS</cato:entity-ref> a Senior Coordinator for Permanence, who—</text>
            <subparagraph id="H6578BF98FF9F4C8AB5F9CDB62170107F">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>shall occupy at least a Deputy Assistant Secretary-level position in the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Bureau of Vulnerable Children and Family Security" entity-parent-id="1900" proposed="true">VCFS</cato:entity-ref>; and</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="HE501FD12603D46F5996500BA8115636B">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>shall lead the development and implementation of policies that will ensure the timely provision of appropriate, protective, and permanent family care for children living without families, including refugee and stateless children, through the full continuum of permanence solutions, including family preservation and reunification, kinship care, guardianship, and domestic and intercountry adoption.</text>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="HE084A5FC86E9449BB24F10F818BEF828">
          <enum>(b)</enum>
          <header>Assistant Secretary</header>
          <paragraph id="HF02C7FE3AF3B41438865DF9F61983017">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <header>Appointment</header>
            <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Bureau of Vulnerable Children and Family Security" entity-parent-id="1900" proposed="true">VCFS</cato:entity-ref> shall be headed by an <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Bureau of Vulnerable Children and Family Security" entity-parent-id="1900" proposed="true">Assistant Secretary</cato:entity-ref>, who shall be appointed by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> by and with the consent of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0010">Senate</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="HC5112E803B744A30801DBA028D1725B9">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <header>Qualifications</header>
            <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Bureau of Vulnerable Children and Family Security" entity-parent-id="1900" proposed="true">Assistant Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall—</text>
            <subparagraph id="HB14F98051C7A4DAC8D555CAE2310C539">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>have experience in the development of policies and systems and the implementation of programs that promote the goals of the Action Plan for Children in Adversity;</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="HA7C21B57737A4581B18861904982FFC6">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>be knowledgeable of international child welfare, family permanence, and family creation through domestic and intercountry adoption; and</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H5C0C3F1B7CF64A80A246611FAC27CFB1">
              <enum>(C)</enum>
              <text>be committed to developing an integrated United States Government approach to international child welfare that places equal emphasis on—</text>
              <clause id="HF786AD952CC148CB9FF9C6460332D8D2">
                <enum>(i)</enum>
                <text>early childhood survival and development;</text>
              </clause>
              <clause id="H2136D9DC6F1F478E850264EA2E4BAF05">
                <enum>(ii)</enum>
                <text>family permanence; and</text>
              </clause>
              <clause id="HCA3830AD37CC4393923A1378782CA297">
                <enum>(iii)</enum>
                <text>protection from abuse and exploitation.</text>
              </clause>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="HBB22F950A4F4461DA0A92FB314FA4D99">
            <enum>(3)</enum>
            <header>Authority</header>
            <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Bureau of Vulnerable Children and Family Security" entity-parent-id="1900" proposed="true">Assistant Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall report to the Under Secretary for Civilian Security, Democracy and Human Rights.</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H2B0612D3D7ED4A30B820B9E0066BF981">
            <enum>(4)</enum>
            <header>Increase in authorized assistant secretary positions</header>
            <subparagraph id="HFB28DA730425416483248DE51A76ACE2">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <header>Amendment to State Department Basic Authorities Act of 1956</header>
              <text>
                <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
                  <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="State Department Basic Authorities Act of 1956/s:1/ss:c/p:1">Section 1(c)(1) of the State Department Basic Authorities Act of 1956</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2651a">
                    <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/22/2651a/c/1">22 U.S.C. 2651a(c)(1)</cato:entity-ref>
                  </external-xref>)</cato:entity> is amended by striking <quote>
                  <short-title>not more than 24 Assistant Secretaries</short-title>
                </quote> and inserting <quote>
                  <short-title>not more than 25 Assistant Secretaries</short-title>
                </quote>.</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H4EA8559F291B4E1FB86CEF77ACBDBAD7">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <header>Amendment to title 5, United States Code</header>
              <text>
                <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc/5/5315">
                  <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/5/5315">Section 5315</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code</cato:entity-ref>, is amended by striking <quote>
                  <short-title>Assistant Secretaries of State (24)</short-title>
                </quote> and inserting <quote>
                  <short-title>Assistant Secretaries of State (25)</short-title>
                </quote>.</text>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="H433B3E611E4549139EAF32354D506D3D">
          <enum>(c)</enum>
          <header>Functions</header>
          <paragraph id="H7F9958D075394AC19BB4850435286CC0">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <header>Advisory</header>
            <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Bureau of Vulnerable Children and Family Security" entity-parent-id="1900" proposed="true">Assistant Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall serve as a primary advisor to the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref> and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> in all matters related to vulnerable children and family security in foreign countries.</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="HF6F0F20EECA04CBBAFC085CA563FA3D9">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <header>Diplomatic representation</header>
            <text>Subject to the direction of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref>, and in consultation and coordination with the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Senior Coordinator for Children in Adversity" entity-parent-id="7200">Senior Coordinator for Children in Adversity of the United States Agency for International Development</cato:entity-ref>, and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7000">Secretary of Homeland Security</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Bureau of Vulnerable Children and Family Security" entity-parent-id="1900" proposed="true">Assistant Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall represent the United States in matters relevant to international child welfare, family preservation and reunification, and provision of permanent, safe parental care through kinship, domestic and intercountry adoption in—</text>
            <subparagraph id="H7C52C651511F4527B74AEF4795E3EE42">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>contacts with foreign governments, nongovernmental organizations, intergovernmental agencies, and specialized agencies of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="19UN">United Nations</cato:entity-ref> and other international organizations of which the United States is a member;</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="HDF4CA74FAFD84203BA2546ECACB2AAF1">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>multilateral conferences and meetings relevant to family preservation, reunification, and creating appropriate, protective, and permanent care for unparented children; and</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H3229AB0E428C4D02A09490E835552E6E">
              <enum>(C)</enum>
              <text>fulfillment of the diplomatic responsibilities designated to the central authority under <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
                  <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000/t:I">title I of the Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/14911">
                    <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/42/14911/etseq">42 U.S.C. 14911 et seq.</cato:entity-ref>
                  </external-xref>)</cato:entity>, as amended by this Act.</text>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="HC391E890A3554813AF6D96B79CBFDFDA">
            <enum>(3)</enum>
            <header>Policy development with respect to permanence for unparented children</header>
            <subparagraph id="HE64F602D6A1A4F54BDAF2319C9EE5138">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <header>In general</header>
              <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Bureau of Vulnerable Children and Family Security" entity-parent-id="1900" proposed="true">Assistant Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall—</text>
              <clause id="H6AACDD53C3A04CD4A74826EC429693AF">
                <enum>(i)</enum>
                <text>develop and advocate for policies and practices to ensure that children in foreign countries who are living without families find appropriate, protective, and permanent family care which is in the best interest of each child;</text>
              </clause>
              <clause id="H85A32C9291104B14AA06F515E9A95D6C">
                <enum>(ii)</enum>
                <text>give consideration to family preservation and reunification, kinship care, guardianship, and domestic and intercountry adoption; and</text>
              </clause>
              <clause id="H53D719DE5C124472936CDF1961B001F4">
                <enum>(iii)</enum>
                <text>seek to develop and implement policies that lead to the use of all options for providing appropriate, protective, and permanent family care to children living without families as quickly as possible.</text>
              </clause>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="HC7BAC56AD0BD48C28299CB13819D7512">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <header>Best interest determination</header>
              <text>In carrying out <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Children in Families First Act of 2013/s:101/ss:c/p:3/sp:A" proposed="true">subparagraph (A)</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Bureau of Vulnerable Children and Family Security" entity-parent-id="1900" proposed="true">Assistant Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall give preference to options that optimize the best interests of children, including options which provide children with fully protected legal status as children and parents with full legal status as parents, including full parental rights and responsibilities.</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="HD92FBAFB32CF4255A14B76F3C9021CAA">
              <enum>(C)</enum>
              <header>Subsidiarity</header>
              <text>The principle of subsidiarity, which gives preference to in-country solutions, should be implemented within the context of a concurrent planning strategy, exploring in- and out-of-country options simultaneously. If an in-country placement serving the child’s best interests and providing appropriate, protective, and permanent care is not quickly available, and such an international home is available, the child should be placed in that international home without delay.</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H2B27A33513AC41EEB56AD7F9EBFECC6C">
              <enum>(D)</enum>
              <header>Best practices</header>
              <text>In developing policies and programs under this Act, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Bureau of Vulnerable Children and Family Security" entity-parent-id="1900" proposed="true">Assistant Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall identify and utilize evidence-based programs and best practices in family preservation and reunification and provision of permanent parental care through guardianship, kinship care, and domestic and intercountry adoption as derived from a wide variety of domestic, foreign, and global policies and practices.</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H15210E4621F04B81A26D99DA662AC0BD">
              <enum>(E)</enum>
              <header>Technical assistance</header>
              <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Bureau of Vulnerable Children and Family Security" entity-parent-id="1900" proposed="true">Assistant Secretary</cato:entity-ref>, in consultation with other appropriate Federal agencies, shall provide technical assistance to governments of foreign countries to help build their child welfare capacities and to strengthen appropriate family preservation and reunification and the provision of appropriate, protective, and permanent family care through kinship care, guardianship, and domestic and intercountry adoption, including assistance with—</text>
              <clause id="H814A9E2D32C04124BE257446A6175279">
                <enum>(i)</enum>
                <text>the drafting, disseminating, and implementing of legislation;</text>
              </clause>
              <clause id="H27A2B411D54D4B1D9DFEC1B8031F6BB7">
                <enum>(ii)</enum>
                <text>the development of implementing systems and procedures;</text>
              </clause>
              <clause id="HCAB49DCC0E9943ED97673914CDC81ADF">
                <enum>(iii)</enum>
                <text>the establishment of public, private, and faith- and community-based partnerships;</text>
              </clause>
              <clause id="H047BD2C4D98A4DE68828CFDAFD76141E">
                <enum>(iv)</enum>
                <text>the development of workforce training for governmental and nongovernmental staff; and</text>
              </clause>
              <clause id="HF5F17E30C8BA4132AC2B46199194C637">
                <enum>(v)</enum>
                <text>infrastructure development and data collection techniques necessary to identify and document the number and needs of children living without appropriate, protective, and permanent family care.</text>
              </clause>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="HC324B40F69804E33BBCECF1ACA3110CF">
            <enum>(4)</enum>
            <header>Responsibilities with respect to intercountry adoption</header>
            <subparagraph id="H8F083F62C59142A588D904C47B35B35B">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <header>In general</header>
              <text>The VCFS, in coordination with other offices of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Department of State</cato:entity-ref> and <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7003">U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services</cato:entity-ref>, shall have lead responsibility for representing the United States Government in discussions, negotiations, and diplomatic contacts pertaining to intercountry adoptions.</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H859854BB632F457FBB8C5CCA924A1D78">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <header>Central authority responsibility under the intercountry adoption act of 2000</header>
              <text>
                <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
                  <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000/s:101/ss:b/p:2">Section 101(b)(2) of the Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/14911">
                    <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/42/14911/b/2">42 U.S.C. 14911(b)(2)</cato:entity-ref>
                  </external-xref>)</cato:entity> is amended by striking <quote>
                  <short-title>Office of Children's Issues</short-title>
                </quote> and inserting <quote>
                  <short-title>
                    <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Bureau of Vulnerable Children and Family Security" entity-parent-id="1900" proposed="true">Bureau of Vulnerable Children and Family Security</cato:entity-ref>
                  </short-title>
                </quote>.</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="HC783E76A5B6045EC92C7B2E56D874050">
              <enum>(C)</enum>
              <header>Determinations of Hague adoption convention compliance</header>
              <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Bureau of Vulnerable Children and Family Security" entity-parent-id="1900" proposed="true">VCFS</cato:entity-ref>, in consultation with other offices of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Department of State</cato:entity-ref>, and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7000">Department of Homeland Security</cato:entity-ref>, shall have lead responsibility for determining whether a Convention partner country has met its obligations under the Hague Adoption Convention and is eligible to participate in intercountry adoptions in accordance with United States law. Such determinations shall be documented in writing, based on standardized criteria, and available for public review and comment.</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H1EF1DB1C0B774CBA8237FD1B95BEA454">
              <enum>(D)</enum>
              <header>Negotiation of bilateral agreements</header>
              <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Bureau of Vulnerable Children and Family Security" entity-parent-id="1900" proposed="true">VCFS</cato:entity-ref>, in consultation with the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7000">Secretary of Homeland Security</cato:entity-ref>, shall have lead responsibility for the negotiation of bilateral agreements with other countries pertaining to intercountry adoption and in conformity with the provisions of the Hague Adoption Convention when the other country is a Convention partner.</text>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H4A11970093894371BEAD97578CB796C1">
            <enum>(5)</enum>
            <header>Policy coordination</header>
            <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Bureau of Vulnerable Children and Family Security" entity-parent-id="1900" proposed="true">Assistant Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall coordinate with the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7000">Secretary of Homeland Security</cato:entity-ref> and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7200">Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development</cato:entity-ref> to maintain consistency in United States foreign and domestic policy and operations with respect to children living outside family care in foreign countries, particularly those living without families.</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="HDF38E245092D43559A890570F4C41DCC">
            <enum>(6)</enum>
            <header>Information coordination</header>
            <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Bureau of Vulnerable Children and Family Security" entity-parent-id="1900" proposed="true">Assistant Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall transmit—</text>
            <subparagraph id="H41C8C84F54914B029F3E6614A34959A0">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>any intercountry adoption related case information received from the Central Authority of another Convention country to the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7000">Secretary of Homeland Security</cato:entity-ref>; and</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H9DC9D8F2F9A84C8498A2906C61130971">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>any intercountry adoption related case information that the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7000">Secretary of Homeland Security</cato:entity-ref> requests to the Central Authority of another Convention country.</text>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
      </section>
      <section id="H2626308BD57C4D5791A66D05AE68047D">
        <enum>102.</enum>
        <header>Responsibilities of U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services for accreditation of adoption service providers</header>
        <subsection id="H9576DB8851C2440F97BA62E8EEBA1235">
          <enum>(a)</enum>
          <header>General responsibilities under the Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000</header>
          <paragraph id="HF72454737DAF45618DF824D7029DDF17">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <header>In general</header>
            <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000">Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/106/279">
                  <cato:entity-ref entity-type="public-law" value="public-law/106/279">Public Law 106–279</cato:entity-ref>
                </external-xref>; <cato:entity-ref entity-type="statute-at-large" value="statute-at-large/114/825">114 Stat. 825</cato:entity-ref>)</cato:entity> is amended by inserting after <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000/s:103">section 103</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/14913">
                  <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/42/14913">42 U.S.C. 14913</cato:entity-ref>
                </external-xref>)</cato:entity> the following:</text>
            <quoted-block act-name="" id="HF3D904D2FBEC40C5A97486AEB405542F" style="OLC">
              <section id="HAA96A9935F1C4125A77D72635CE32734">
                <enum>103A.</enum>
                <header>Responsibilities of the Department of Homeland Security</header>
                <subsection id="HA586F6A40A2E4492A6D344C5F3483284">
                  <enum>(a)</enum>
                  <header>Accreditation and approval responsibilities</header>
                  <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7000">Secretary of Homeland Security</cato:entity-ref>, working through the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7003">Director of U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services</cato:entity-ref>, shall carry out the functions prescribed by the Convention with respect to the accreditation of agencies and the approval of persons to provide adoption services in the United States in cases subject to the Convention as provided in title II. Such functions may not be delegated to any other Federal agency.</text>
                </subsection>
                <subsection id="HAFA91E9AEBFD40219C1C25D83B27EA2C">
                  <enum>(b)</enum>
                  <header>Investigations</header>
                  <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7000">Secretary of Homeland Security</cato:entity-ref> shall be responsible for managing and overseeing investigations related to the operation and services of adoption service providers, whether directly or indirectly.</text>
                </subsection>
                <subsection id="HC767CC1A9A924C1CB317933498DB02AE">
                  <enum>(c)</enum>
                  <header>Liaison with foreign governments on post-Placement reports and certain adoption cases</header>
                  <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7000">Secretary of Homeland Security</cato:entity-ref> shall serve as the liaison with foreign governments with respect to queries about required post-placement reports and about specific intercountry adoption cases once the adopted children are living in the United States, including queries about the status of adopted children who are living in the United States in cases involving allegations of abuse, neglect, abandonment, or death.</text>
                </subsection>
              </section>
              <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
            </quoted-block>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H08FB11556E0945B293A8D14C1D2735AB">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <header>Clerical amendment</header>
            <text>
              <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000/s:1">Section 1 of such Act</cato:entity-ref> is amended by inserting after the item relating to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000/s:103">section 103</cato:entity-ref> the following:</text>
            <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF19E3883405F41EC8B7E329D3D64AE63" style="OLC">
              <toc>
                <toc-entry bold="off" level="section">Sec. 103A. Responsibilities of the Department of Homeland Security.</toc-entry>
              </toc>
              <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
            </quoted-block>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H59185C99C3B54DC1BFBCF23623CF2C22">
            <enum>(3)</enum>
            <header>Conforming amendments</header>
            <text>
              <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000/s:102">Section 102 of such Act</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/14912">
                  <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/42/14912">42 U.S.C. 14912</cato:entity-ref>
                </external-xref>)</cato:entity> is amended—</text>
            <subparagraph id="H9997BD29BE164F07B81A1629BEA7CC7B">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000/s:102/ss:a">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref>, by striking <quote>
                  <short-title>The Secretary</short-title>
                </quote> and inserting <quote>
                  <short-title>Except as provided for under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000/s:103A">section 103A</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7000">Secretary</cato:entity-ref>
                  </short-title>
                </quote>;</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H896E10814838475795593A28CA8CDE32">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000/s:102/ss:b">subsection (b)</cato:entity-ref>, by inserting <quote>
                  <short-title>, in coordination with the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7000">Secretary of Homeland Security</cato:entity-ref>,</short-title>
                </quote> after <quote>
                  <short-title>The Secretary</short-title>
                </quote>;</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="HD8BCB876528C41D7A895C3E3A2B16B39">
              <enum>(C)</enum>
              <text>by striking <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000/s:102/ss:c">subsection (c)</cato:entity-ref>;</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H87916E52851648C6B2E64133D5E15AC5">
              <enum>(D)</enum>
              <text>by redesignating <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000/s:102/ss:d, f">subsections (d) and (f)</cato:entity-ref> as <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000/s:102/ss:c, d" proposed="true">subsections (c) and (d)</cato:entity-ref>, respectively; and</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H5E6F192C7F12445EBE12335238FAE6F5">
              <enum>(E)</enum>
              <text>by striking <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000/s:102/ss:e">subsection (e)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="H997BA8D180134C41B47BF69AEA2DCCC8">
          <enum>(b)</enum>
          <header>Accreditation responsibilities under the Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000</header>
          <paragraph id="H26A850FD04D445EB8CDA9E4129ACE52D">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <header>Designation of accrediting agencies</header>
            <text>
              <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000/s:202">Section 202 of the Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/14922">
                  <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/42/14922">42 U.S.C. 14922</cato:entity-ref>
                </external-xref>)</cato:entity> is amended by inserting <quote>
                <short-title>
                  <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7000">of Homeland Security</cato:entity-ref>
                </short-title>
              </quote> after <quote>
                <short-title>Secretary</short-title>
              </quote> each place it appears.</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="HAEA0D19A0E634E3DAC837CE93F5E4210">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <header>Standards and procedures for providing accreditation or approval</header>
            <text>
              <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000/s:203">Section 203 of the Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/14923">
                  <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/42/14923">42 U.S.C. 14923</cato:entity-ref>
                </external-xref>)</cato:entity> is amended by inserting <quote>
                <short-title>
                  <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7000">of Homeland Security</cato:entity-ref>
                </short-title>
              </quote> after <quote>
                <short-title>Secretary</short-title>
              </quote> each place it appears in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000/s:203/ss:a">subsections (a)</cato:entity-ref> and <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000/s:203/ss:b">(b)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H0263748C7B584BE485061A662D362102">
            <enum>(3)</enum>
            <header>Oversight of accreditation and approval</header>
            <text>
              <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000/s:204">Section 204 of the Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/14924">
                  <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/42/14924">42 U.S.C. 14924</cato:entity-ref>
                </external-xref>)</cato:entity> is amended—</text>
            <subparagraph id="H7F3A05A3E23A4FFE91FBF320BBD48398">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>by inserting <quote>
                  <short-title>
                    <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7000">of Homeland Security</cato:entity-ref>
                  </short-title>
                </quote> after <quote>
                  <short-title>Secretary</short-title>
                </quote> each place it appears; and</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H1A7BBA25F253441CBF9F9B4D4ECB04EA">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000/s:204/ss:c">subsection (c)</cato:entity-ref>—</text>
              <clause id="HC2E230E9214546399A5C31DD1133BD56">
                <enum>(i)</enum>
                <text>in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000/s:204/ss:c/p:1">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref>, by amending the paragraph heading to read as follows:</text>
                <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H11DF75CABADE4078A62ED6644362A602" style="OLC">
                  <paragraph id="H040F1B12BB4A4E05A06F89257AF63424">
                    <enum>(4)</enum>
                    <header>Authority of the secretary of homeland security</header>
                  </paragraph>
                  <after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block>
                </quoted-block>
              </clause>
              <clause id="HEF943D1FB8D24F259E3EFFF2862B488D">
                <enum>(ii)</enum>
                <text>in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000/s:204/ss:c/p:2">paragraph (2)</cato:entity-ref>, by striking <quote>
                    <short-title>Secretary's debarment order</short-title>
                  </quote> and inserting <quote>
                    <short-title>debarment order of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7000">Secretary of Homeland Security</cato:entity-ref>
                    </short-title>
                  </quote>.</text>
              </clause>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H57337303E01F4A628B665FC8FE1767F4">
            <enum>(4)</enum>
            <header>Administrative provisions</header>
            <subparagraph id="H9D04BB140E764ACAA70511776CC914D1">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <header>Access to convention records</header>
              <text>
                <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
                  <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000/s:401/ss:b">Section 401(b) of the Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/14941">
                    <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/42/14941/b">42 U.S.C. 14941(b)</cato:entity-ref>
                  </external-xref>)</cato:entity> is amended—</text>
              <clause id="H2E024FEBFD5E445694F95ABF46203DB1">
                <enum>(i)</enum>
                <text>in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000/s:401/ss:b/p:1">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref>, by inserting <quote>
                    <short-title>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7003">Director of U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services</cato:entity-ref>,</short-title>
                  </quote> after <quote>
                    <short-title>Secretary</short-title>
                  </quote>; and</text>
              </clause>
              <clause id="HF2846B1425094CF5B34A13179B6DC70D">
                <enum>(ii)</enum>
                <text>in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000/s:401/ss:b/p:2">paragraph (2)</cato:entity-ref>, by inserting <quote>
                    <short-title>the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7003">Director of U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services</cato:entity-ref>,</short-title>
                  </quote> after <quote>
                    <short-title>Secretary,</short-title>
                  </quote>.</text>
              </clause>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="HE828939518AF47419451C37DD77E9BE6">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <header>Assessment of fees</header>
              <text>
                <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
                  <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000/s:403/ss:b">Section 403(b) of the Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/14943">
                    <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/42/14943/b">42 U.S.C. 14943(b)</cato:entity-ref>
                  </external-xref>)</cato:entity> is amended—</text>
              <clause id="H6917D5AA939F4FAABF96926A139902C5">
                <enum>(i)</enum>
                <text>in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000/s:403/ss:b/p:1">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref>—</text>
                <subclause id="HF69CF5F5422744528C20B2B9075E5BBE">
                  <enum>(I)</enum>
                  <text>by inserting <quote>
                      <short-title>or the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7003">Director of U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services</cato:entity-ref>
                      </short-title>
                    </quote> after <quote>
                      <short-title>Secretary</short-title>
                    </quote>; and</text>
                </subclause>
                <subclause id="HAA42B0D4396A41A68F64315DD9202CB7">
                  <enum>(II)</enum>
                  <text>by inserting <quote>
                      <short-title>or <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7003">U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services</cato:entity-ref>, respectively,</short-title>
                    </quote> after <quote>
                      <short-title>Department of State</short-title>
                    </quote>; and</text>
                </subclause>
              </clause>
              <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H686B8EAACB904E6DB183F1ADFCECC7E9">
                <enum>(ii)</enum>
                <text>in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000/s:403/ss:b/p:2">paragraph (2)</cato:entity-ref>, by inserting <quote>
                    <short-title>or <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7003">U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services</cato:entity-ref> appropriation, as the case may be,</short-title>
                  </quote> after <quote>
                    <short-title>Department of State appropriation</short-title>
                  </quote>.</text>
              </clause>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="H315E8DC29643485EA1825CC7CC29ED62">
          <enum>(c)</enum>
          <header>Intercountry adoption functions of U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services</header>
          <paragraph id="HE58CE1B9C319433DB8C39A722EBCAA20">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <header>Definitions</header>
            <text>In this subsection and in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Children in Families First Act of 2013/s:103" proposed="true">section 103</cato:entity-ref>:</text>
            <subparagraph id="H4544E016CEA14C489E70A44CF98D37C3">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <header>Adoption service</header>
              <text>The term <term>adoption service</term> has the meaning given the term in <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
                  <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000/s:3">section 3 of the Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/14902">
                    <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/42/14902">42 U.S.C. 14902</cato:entity-ref>
                  </external-xref>)</cato:entity>.</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="HE513B5C7A8574CDAA777787E0CC52F9B">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <header>Associate director</header>
              <text>The term <term>Associate Director</term> means the Associate Director of the Directorate.</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H7FD8EDE4C2C149D58943706DCB7C82E8">
              <enum>(C)</enum>
              <header>Directorate</header>
              <text>Except as otherwise provided in this subsection, the term <term>Directorate</term> means the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Field Operations Directorate" entity-parent-id="7003">Field Operations Directorate of U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="HB62634E6CFB240AF981A6794865A14B6">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <header>Intercountry adoption functions</header>
            <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Field Operations Directorate" entity-parent-id="7003">Associate Director</cato:entity-ref> shall carry out—</text>
            <subparagraph id="H3958B276E9DA4EE685C0F8CC1DB0DD2F">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>the functions described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000/s:103A/ss:a">section 103A(a) of the Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000</cato:entity-ref>, relating to accreditation of agencies and approval of persons to provide adoption services;</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H15E8E183344944EC8ADD4C40F6207BE3">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>the functions described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000/s:103A/ss:b">section 103A(b) of such Act</cato:entity-ref>, relating to management and oversight of investigations related to the operation of such providers; and</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="HF7A0EACE4E57436F9D5B0A0F0EE203B9">
              <enum>(C)</enum>
              <text>the functions described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000/s:103A/ss:c">section 103A(c) of such Act</cato:entity-ref>, relating to liaison responsibilities regarding post-placement reports and certain adoption cases.</text>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H8D4F2280CE8E49B5AA64E453B28F26B9">
            <enum>(3)</enum>
            <header>Informational responsibilities</header>
            <subparagraph id="HBF5CAD94B1904BE7AE04955E6B328F5F">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <header>Database on adoption service providers</header>
              <clause id="H3745F1A08CF74C5681700314236859C9">
                <enum>(i)</enum>
                <header>In general</header>
                <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Field Operations Directorate" entity-parent-id="7003">Associate Director</cato:entity-ref> shall establish and operate, in conjunction with the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref>, a publicly accessible database of adoption service providers.</text>
              </clause>
              <clause id="HB2434947E4A14ACEB4E98E9517E29C2A">
                <enum>(ii)</enum>
                <header>Agreement</header>
                <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Field Operations Directorate" entity-parent-id="7003">Associate Director</cato:entity-ref>, the Director, and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref> shall enter into an agreement under which the Director and the Secretary shall provide, for the database, data on intercountry adoption cases relating to adoption service providers.</text>
              </clause>
              <clause id="HDDA504AC627546EFADF3C6922904D7E3">
                <enum>(iii)</enum>
                <header>Contents</header>
                <text>The database shall include, with respect to each accredited agency and approved person, who is an adoption service provider individually, and to the aggregate of all adoption service providers—</text>
                <subclause id="H7C56BFF76EBE42A4ABA66EAD24064535">
                  <enum>(I)</enum>
                  <text>information identifying such a provider;</text>
                </subclause>
                <subclause id="H2A26429B778D44DB9CAE6A9202257323">
                  <enum>(II)</enum>
                  <text>information on the accreditation status of an agency, or the approval status of a person, as an adoption service provider;</text>
                </subclause>
                <subclause id="H2B9943556E4740BE9428666FF08E23F0">
                  <enum>(III)</enum>
                  <text>information on the number of applications or petitions filed respecting adoption and the numbers of approvals and denials of the applications or petitions;</text>
                </subclause>
                <subclause id="HEB827E929649426DBC0C5B3042484007">
                  <enum>(IV)</enum>
                  <text>the number of substantiated grievances filed with respect to an adoption service provider; and</text>
                </subclause>
                <subclause id="HC1ED491EAD6046D795CBA88082C7B970">
                  <enum>(V)</enum>
                  <text>a description of any sanctions an adoption service provider, or corrective actions that the provider is required to take to maintain accreditation or approval described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Children in Families First Act of 2013/s:102/ss:c/p:3/sp:A/cl:iii/scl:II" proposed="true">subclause (II)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
                </subclause>
              </clause>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H880C8168495F4DC29D52D19577F7F2C4">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <header>Database on internationally adopted children</header>
              <clause id="HFDBBAEC52FCB4348B16F00120A9B0144">
                <enum>(i)</enum>
                <header>In general</header>
                <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Field Operations Directorate" entity-parent-id="7003">Associate Director</cato:entity-ref>, in conjunction with the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref>, shall establish and operate a database containing data respecting children involved in intercountry adoption cases who have immigrated to the United States.</text>
              </clause>
              <clause id="HB42E982C5C534E08A84DF18E790EFF1C">
                <enum>(ii)</enum>
                <header>Information tracking</header>
                <text>Although the data available for adoptions finalized before the date of the enactment of this Act will likely be incomplete, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Field Operations Directorate" entity-parent-id="7003">Associate Director</cato:entity-ref> should seek to import available data on all adoptions involving children who are younger than 18 years of age on the date of the enactment of this Act. In operating the database established under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Children in Families First Act of 2013/s:102/ss:c/p:3/sp:B/cl:i" proposed="true">clause (i)</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Field Operations Directorate" entity-parent-id="7003">Associate Director</cato:entity-ref> shall track information about each such child before attaining United States citizenship, including—</text>
                <subclause id="H00D5FCD70AF542C6B3B3F414E1DCBE93">
                  <enum>(I)</enum>
                  <text>information identifying a child and the adoptive or prospective adoptive parents, including—</text>
                  <item id="HE03F0CA56AD04AB59161A99E03476E1C">
                    <enum>(aa)</enum>
                    <text>the full name of the child in the country of origin and the full name of the child after the adoption is finalized;</text>
                  </item>
                  <item id="H9B7282EE90BF4161939553A1A38551CC">
                    <enum>(bb)</enum>
                    <text>the gender, date of birth, nationality, and citizenship of the child;</text>
                  </item>
                  <item id="HE5448FA736724B1B90B30B077701B49F">
                    <enum>(cc)</enum>
                    <text>the physical address of the child at the time of the adoption; the type of visa issued to the child; and</text>
                  </item>
                  <item id="H6B804B9D222C4D39800631E453D0C0FA">
                    <enum>(dd)</enum>
                    <text>the date on which the child entered the United States;</text>
                  </item>
                </subclause>
                <subclause id="H2C940F98C6B54301A04855F7140E396A">
                  <enum>(II)</enum>
                  <text>information on the particular adoption service provider, if any, providing services in the particular case; and</text>
                </subclause>
                <subclause id="H37A14262CB7146A88B0F149FEF723DCE">
                  <enum>(III)</enum>
                  <text>information on immigration or citizenship status of the child.</text>
                </subclause>
              </clause>
              <clause id="H01566F10460445E4B80D7B3E8EE87BD9">
                <enum>(iii)</enum>
                <header>Interagency agreement</header>
                <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Field Operations Directorate" entity-parent-id="7003">Associate Director</cato:entity-ref>, the Director, and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref> shall enter into an agreement under which the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref> shall provide, for the database, data on intercountry adoption cases concerning the adopted children, and the adoption service providers.</text>
              </clause>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
      </section>
      <section id="HCEEBEF6491464CEB8C43306B136BF294">
        <enum>103.</enum>
        <header>Transfer of functions and savings provisions</header>
        <subsection id="HC5F1538ACE4241AEAD3A057E3F49A918">
          <enum>(a)</enum>
          <header>Definitions</header>
          <text>In this section, unless otherwise provided or contextually indicated—</text>
          <paragraph id="HB79439B8B8484516AA9DC6D4045B44E2">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <text>the term <term>Federal agency</term> has the meaning given to the term <term>agency</term> under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc/5/551//1">
                <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/5/551">section 551(1)</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code</cato:entity-ref>;</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H32C3E8FDBE994691B1814D87870CCDFE">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <text>the term <term>function</term> means any duty, obligation, power, authority, responsibility, right, privilege, activity, or program; and</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H109B22AF8B8F4BECA6493CBA9D08463C">
            <enum>(3)</enum>
            <text>the term <term>office</term> includes any office, administration, agency, institute, unit, organizational entity, or component thereof.</text>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="H1D4A0098663440DEA5974C3A2A93AF62">
          <enum>(b)</enum>
          <header>Transfer of functions</header>
          <text>There are transferred to the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Field Operations Directorate" entity-parent-id="7003">Directorate</cato:entity-ref>, all functions described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000/s:103A/ss:a">section 103A(a) of the Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000</cato:entity-ref>, as added by <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Children in Families First Act of 2013/s:102/ss:a" proposed="true">section 102(a) of this Act</cato:entity-ref>, which were exercised by the Secretary of State before the date of the enactment of this Act (including all related functions of any officer or employee of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Department of State</cato:entity-ref>), including functions relating to—</text>
          <paragraph id="HEAE3D536490F4EA8970442F99C714AB0">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <text>the accreditation of agencies and approval of persons to provide adoption services;</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H0ED2E0B389404944A2D27B379186E564">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <text>the management and oversight of investigations related to the operation of such providers; and</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="HC55EBEAF06904846A6A88141B1D4A764">
            <enum>(3)</enum>
            <text>liaison responsibilities with respect to required post-placement reports.</text>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="H4FA0D354239141DEB589C06C4D642326">
          <enum>(c)</enum>
          <header>Determinations of certain functions by the Office of Management and Budget</header>
          <text>If necessary, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1103">Director of the Office of Management and Budget</cato:entity-ref> shall make any determination with respect to the transfer of functions under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Children in Families First Act of 2013/s:103/ss:b" proposed="true">subsection (b)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="H3E126D3798444E7384DD70E846A01ADF">
          <enum>(d)</enum>
          <header>Personnel provisions</header>
          <paragraph id="HE175245065F24BD48B97C05EB34F7A7C">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <header>Appointments</header>
            <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Field Operations Directorate" entity-parent-id="7003">Associate Director</cato:entity-ref> may appoint and fix the compensation of such officers and employees, including investigators, attorneys, and administrative law judges, as may be necessary to carry out the respective functions transferred under this section. Except as otherwise provided by law, such officers and employees shall be appointed in accordance with the civil service laws and their compensation fixed in accordance with <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc/5">title 5, United States Code</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H30C23B138AA44D9B9E78D7A359A463E1">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <header>Experts and consultants</header>
            <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Field Operations Directorate" entity-parent-id="7003">Associate Director</cato:entity-ref> may obtain the services of experts and consultants in accordance with <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc/5/3109">
                <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/5/3109">section 3109</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code</cato:entity-ref>, and compensate such experts and consultants for each day (including travel time) at rates not in excess of the rate of pay for level IV of the Executive Schedule under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc/5/5315">section 5315 of such title</cato:entity-ref>. The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Field Operations Directorate" entity-parent-id="7003">Associate Director</cato:entity-ref> may pay experts and consultants who are serving away from their homes or regular place of business travel expenses and per diem in lieu of subsistence at rates authorized by <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc/5/5702">sections 5702</cato:entity-ref> and <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc/5/5703">5703 of such title</cato:entity-ref> for persons in Government service employed intermittently.</text>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="H836D9899A20A406084E082C51476A6E2">
          <enum>(e)</enum>
          <header>Delegation and assignment</header>
          <text>Except where otherwise expressly prohibited by law or otherwise provided under this section—</text>
          <paragraph id="H3C5D96C7C2E14B4DA74FCB8CD4CF3673">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <text>the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Field Operations Directorate" entity-parent-id="7003">Associate Director</cato:entity-ref> may—</text>
            <subparagraph id="H8FB39540DF40417299F8F59B7D77EC04">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>delegate any of the functions transferred to the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Field Operations Directorate" entity-parent-id="7003">Associate Director</cato:entity-ref> under this section and any function transferred or granted to the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Field Operations Directorate" entity-parent-id="7003">Associate Director</cato:entity-ref> after the date of the enactment of this Act to such officers and employees of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Field Operations Directorate" entity-parent-id="7003">Directorate</cato:entity-ref> as the Associate Director may designate; and</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H3D30199D9E164F3CAA69A52AB2ABBB72">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>authorize successive redelegations of such functions as may be necessary or appropriate; and</text>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H4BF61F0C8AF741BD9B68A1045284D385">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <text>no delegation of functions by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Field Operations Directorate" entity-parent-id="7003">Associate Director</cato:entity-ref> under this subsection or under any other provision of this section shall relieve such <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Field Operations Directorate" entity-parent-id="7003">Associate Director</cato:entity-ref> of responsibility for the administration of such functions.</text>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="HED872E85F76642D7AD4EF6FFB4ACC4A3">
          <enum>(f)</enum>
          <header>Reorganization</header>
          <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Field Operations Directorate" entity-parent-id="7003">Associate Director</cato:entity-ref> is authorized—</text>
          <paragraph id="HB040C355FAAD49F0A00E53CDD21DC5F1">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <text>to allocate or reallocate any function transferred under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Children in Families First Act of 2013/s:103/ss:b" proposed="true">subsection (b)</cato:entity-ref> among the officers of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Field Operations Directorate" entity-parent-id="7003">Directorate</cato:entity-ref>; and</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="HDFCF0256DEE94F72B59F3FBC208CFADD">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <text>to establish, consolidate, alter, or discontinue such organizational entities in the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Field Operations Directorate" entity-parent-id="7003">Directorate</cato:entity-ref> as may be necessary or appropriate.</text>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="H88159F301489492CB09C8FAC76CA83CC">
          <enum>(g)</enum>
          <header>Rules</header>
          <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Field Operations Directorate" entity-parent-id="7003">Associate Director</cato:entity-ref> is authorized to prescribe, in accordance with the provisions of <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc-chapter/5/5">chapters 5</cato:entity-ref> and <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc-chapter/5/6">6 of title 5, United States Code</cato:entity-ref>, such rules and regulations as the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Field Operations Directorate" entity-parent-id="7003">Associate Director</cato:entity-ref> determines necessary or appropriate to administer and manage the functions of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Field Operations Directorate" entity-parent-id="7003">Directorate</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="H157DFE4E2A28412084B1E91E4559951D">
          <enum>(h)</enum>
          <header>Transfer and allocations of appropriations and personnel</header>
          <text>Except as otherwise provided under this section and subject to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc/31/1531">
              <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/31/1531">section 1531</external-xref> of title 31, United States Code</cato:entity-ref>, the personnel employed in connection with, and the assets, liabilities, contracts, property, records, and unexpended balances of appropriations, authorizations, allocations, and other funds employed, used, held, arising from, available to, or to be made available in connection with the functions transferred under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Children in Families First Act of 2013/s:103/ss:b" proposed="true">subsection (b)</cato:entity-ref>, shall be transferred to the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Field Operations Directorate" entity-parent-id="7003">Directorate</cato:entity-ref>. Unexpended funds transferred pursuant to this subsection may only be used for the purposes for which the funds were originally authorized and appropriated.</text>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="HB68F8B4D29B247EAB26E589F06995A98">
          <enum>(i)</enum>
          <header>Incidental transfers</header>
          <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1103">Director of the Office of Management and Budget</cato:entity-ref>—</text>
          <paragraph id="HEB78F8A17D8D41CDB813D083AB17CED5">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <text>may, at such time or times as the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1103">Director</cato:entity-ref> may prescribe—</text>
            <subparagraph id="HAE3B238B28A24D60AC39B9855B842F8E">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>make such determinations as may be necessary with regard to the functions transferred under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Children in Families First Act of 2013/s:103/ss:b" proposed="true">subsection (b)</cato:entity-ref>; and</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H44384FB37A054650BBE5127A35892CCE">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>make such additional incidental dispositions of personnel, assets, liabilities, grants, contracts, property, records, and unexpended balances of appropriations, authorizations, allocations, and other funds held, used, arising from, available to, or to be made available in connection with such functions, as may be necessary to carry out the provisions of this section; and</text>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H586B2AF44A904087AE4D24F948B16FBC">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <text>shall provide for—</text>
            <subparagraph id="H0DBC0C5BDA2A4DD3812ED603D4E23375">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>the termination of the affairs of all entities terminated under this section; and</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="HC9B022CF594C4370A5604939CA3F0603">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>such further measures and dispositions as may be necessary to carry out the purposes of this section.</text>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="H7B4AE6D28D204F63929F56B057BA5AA2">
          <enum>(j)</enum>
          <header>Effect on personnel</header>
          <paragraph id="H29DA8E7669244344A817CDDAD293ED78">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <header>In general</header>
            <text>Except as otherwise provided under this section, the transfer under this section of full-time personnel (except special Government employees) and part-time personnel holding permanent positions shall not cause any such employee to be separated or reduced in grade or compensation during the 1-year period beginning on the date of such transfer.</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H4A176275C5804E30A6245534F9CD2830">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <header>Executive schedule positions</header>
            <text>Except as otherwise provided under this section, any person who, on the day preceding the date of the enactment of this Act, held a position compensated in accordance with the Executive Schedule prescribed in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc-chapter/5/53">
                <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/53">chapter 53</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code</cato:entity-ref>, and who, without a break in service, is appointed in the Directorate to a position having duties comparable to the duties performed immediately preceding such appointment shall continue to be compensated in such new position at not less than the rate provided for such previous position, for the duration of the service of such person in such new position.</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="HF355306CC3DC41D1BA1D0D1A0C75DB31">
            <enum>(3)</enum>
            <header>Termination of certain positions</header>
            <text>All positions whose functions are transferred under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Children in Families First Act of 2013/s:103/ss:b" proposed="true">subsection (b)</cato:entity-ref> and whose incumbents have been appointed by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref>, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, shall terminate on the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="H75BB59A7CF8243B8A501E8D1A91FBF9F">
          <enum>(k)</enum>
          <header>Savings provisions</header>
          <paragraph id="HFA8BE1969007422EA6E63819E969C098">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <header>Continuing effect of legal documents</header>
            <text>All orders, determinations, rules, regulations, permits, agreements, grants, contracts, certificates, licenses, registrations, privileges, and other administrative actions which—</text>
            <subparagraph id="H20ABB180C5D246069D42D4168CDAC901">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>have been issued, made, granted, or allowed to become effective by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref>, any Federal agency or official thereof, or by a court of competent jurisdiction, in the performance of functions which are transferred under this section; and</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="HFCE6809A0EC745C6B79908DF097C740C">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>are in effect on the date of the enactment of this Act, or were final before such date of enactment and are to become effective on or after the date of the enactment of this Act,</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph">shall continue in effect according to their terms until modified, terminated, superseded, set aside, or revoked in accordance with law by the President, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Field Operations Directorate" entity-parent-id="7003">Associate Director</cato:entity-ref> or other authorized official, a court of competent jurisdiction, or by operation of law.</continuation-text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H5496646052BE462397D7D4B7E2B917DB">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <header>Proceedings not affected</header>
            <text>Nothing in this section may be construed to affect any proceeding, including a notice of proposed rulemaking, or any application for any license, permit, certificate, or financial assistance pending before the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Department of State</cato:entity-ref> on the effective date of this section, with respect to functions transferred under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Children in Families First Act of 2013/s:103/ss:b" proposed="true">subsection (b)</cato:entity-ref>. Orders shall be issued in such proceedings, appeals shall be taken therefrom, and payments shall be made pursuant to such orders, as if this section had not been enacted. Orders issued in any such proceedings shall continue in effect until modified, terminated, superseded, or revoked by a duly authorized official, by a court of competent jurisdiction, or by operation of law. Nothing in this paragraph may be construed to prohibit the discontinuance or modification of any such proceeding under the same terms and conditions and to the same extent that such proceeding could have been discontinued or modified if this section had not been enacted.</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H1A37AF5BA6A54989B8E2D937BE7448F0">
            <enum>(3)</enum>
            <header>Suits not affected</header>
            <text>Nothing in this section may be construed to affect suits commenced before the date of the enactment of this Act. In all such suits, proceedings shall be had, appeals taken, and judgments rendered in the same manner and with the same effect as if this section had not been enacted.</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H1BA16746DF4F4D408F5CB7C472BFCA52">
            <enum>(4)</enum>
            <header>Nonabatement of actions</header>
            <text>No suit, action, or other proceeding commenced by or against the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Department of State</cato:entity-ref>, or by or against any individual in the official capacity of such individual as an officer of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Department of State</cato:entity-ref>, shall abate by reason of the enactment of this section.</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="HCDE89AD1A659482B97ACE7D8B1F212CE">
            <enum>(5)</enum>
            <header>Administrative actions relating to promulgation of regulations</header>
            <text>Any administrative action relating to the preparation or promulgation of a regulation by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Department of State</cato:entity-ref> relating to a function transferred under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Children in Families First Act of 2013/s:103/ss:b" proposed="true">subsection (b)</cato:entity-ref> may be continued by the Directorate with the same effect as if this section had not been enacted.</text>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="HDE7F062BA7254A1F97681070CC22DB2B">
          <enum>(l)</enum>
          <header>Separability</header>
          <text>If a provision of this section or its application to any person or circumstance is held invalid, neither the remainder of this section nor the application of the provision to other persons or circumstances shall be affected.</text>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="H7BAA7C45A7394D0C9AF6536189B6DC9E">
          <enum>(m)</enum>
          <header>Transition</header>
          <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Field Operations Directorate" entity-parent-id="7003">Associate Director</cato:entity-ref> is authorized to utilize—</text>
          <paragraph id="HD80C9CA5DCCD4A3DA98B779EA865EBDC">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <text>the services of such officers, employees, and other personnel of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Department of State</cato:entity-ref> with respect to functions transferred to the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Field Operations Directorate" entity-parent-id="7003">Directorate</cato:entity-ref> by this section; and</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="HCFCFE6CDB7B74C7CA0E5CED8A609A7E3">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <text>funds appropriated to such functions for such period of time as may reasonably be needed to facilitate the orderly implementation of this section.</text>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="H817DF508166844329A16ABCAE51A2253">
          <enum>(n)</enum>
          <header>References</header>
          <text>Reference in any other Federal law, Executive order, rule, regulation, or delegation of authority, or any document of or relating to—</text>
          <paragraph id="H2C80BF5BC17D4E4383328161A37990BE">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <text>the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref> with regard to functions transferred under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Children in Families First Act of 2013/s:103/ss:b" proposed="true">subsection (b)</cato:entity-ref>, shall be deemed to refer to the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Field Operations Directorate" entity-parent-id="7003">Associate Director</cato:entity-ref>; and</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="HD7E01CE4DE8F439ABDB6CC7FD77E42D2">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <text>the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Department of State</cato:entity-ref> with regard to functions transferred under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Children in Families First Act of 2013/s:103/ss:b" proposed="true">subsection (b)</cato:entity-ref>, shall be deemed to refer to the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Field Operations Directorate" entity-parent-id="7003">Directorate</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="H3249D09FAF784668830FCFF12DA7DD13">
          <enum>(o)</enum>
          <header>Additional conforming amendments</header>
          <paragraph id="HF380B4C5172B4611A9B7C9D97F2C33BD">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <header>Recommended legislation</header>
            <text>After consultation with the appropriate committees of <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1103">Director of the Office of Management and Budget</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Field Operations Directorate" entity-parent-id="7003">Associate Director</cato:entity-ref> shall prepare and submit to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> recommended legislation containing technical and conforming amendments to reflect the changes made by this section.</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBE852FED14F847289B2D518620481168">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <header>Submission to congress</header>
            <text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Field Operations Directorate" entity-parent-id="7003">Associate Director</cato:entity-ref> shall submit the recommended legislation referred to under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Children in Families First Act of 2013/s:103/ss:o/p:1" proposed="true">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref> to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
      </section>
      <section id="H618D629A810149C4BFE4381F9C573295">
        <enum>104.</enum>
        <header>Responsibilities of U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services for adoption-related case processing</header>
        <subsection id="HBA3817C8DB8F4629A60CEFF7E56771AE">
          <enum>(a)</enum>
          <header>In general</header>
          <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7000">Secretary of Homeland Security</cato:entity-ref>, acting through the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7003">Director of U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services</cato:entity-ref>—</text>
          <paragraph id="HF57A86B6C449466ABF8119ACD498A044">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <text>shall be responsible for processing and case-specific decisionmaking on all intercountry adoption cases (up to the point of application for an immigrant visa on behalf of the adopted child), including cases being processed pursuant to the <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000">Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/14901">
                  <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/42/14901/etseq">42 U.S.C. 14901 et seq.</cato:entity-ref>
                </external-xref>)</cato:entity> and <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Intercountry Adoption Universal Accreditation Act of 2012/s:2">section 2 of the Intercountry Adoption Universal Accreditation Act of 2012</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/14925">
                  <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/42/14925">42 U.S.C. 14925</cato:entity-ref>
                </external-xref>)</cato:entity>;</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="HFB44D26871AC49FBA61306FCC41930EF">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <text>shall ensure that all intercountry adoption suitability and eligibility determinations of prospective adoptive parents required under <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Immigration and Nationality Act/s:101/ss:b/p:1/sp:F">subparagraph (F)</cato:entity-ref> or <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Immigration and Nationality Act/s:101/ss:b/p:1/sp:G">(G) of section 101(b)(1) of the Immigration and Nationality Act</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">
                  <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/8/1101/b/1">8 U.S.C. 1101(b)(1)</cato:entity-ref>
                </external-xref>)</cato:entity> are made in accordance with standard criteria that comply with the Hague Adoption Convention so that any such determination justifies a Convention adoption or a non-Convention adoption;</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="HFCA441C86FDC46ABADFB9A0C56AFDCE4">
            <enum>(3)</enum>
            <text>to the maximum extent possible, and to the extent permitted by the country in which the child resides, shall ensure that all non-Convention adoption cases undergo preprocessing, including—</text>
            <subparagraph id="HF11165FD87394371A732D2182734B0AE">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>the filing of a petition and the review of a child’s eligibility to immigrate to the United States before the adoption or grant of legal custody (for purposes of emigration and adoption in the United States) of that child is completed in the country of origin; and</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H970BF30D20B540D4886AE593235BCF37">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>the completion of all necessary and relevant investigations associated with the petition before the country of origin finalizes the adoption or grants legal custody for purposes of emigration and adoption in the United States;</text>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H3C083362B7CE4177BCA5693D79ABB3F8">
            <enum>(4)</enum>
            <text>except as provided in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Children in Families First Act of 2013/s:104/ss:a/p:5" proposed="true">paragraph (5)</cato:entity-ref>, shall be responsible for all case processing steps in Convention and non-Convention adoption petitions on behalf of children whom United States parents propose to immigrate to the United States (except for the processing of immigrant visas), including processing of all necessary Hague Adoption Convention certifications and the final adjudication of the immigration petitions; and</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H346481D704EF498A8688B8F0D8CC0341">
            <enum>(5)</enum>
            <text>may delegate the responsibility for completing certain elements of case adjudication to the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref> if the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7000">Department of Homeland Security</cato:entity-ref>—</text>
            <subparagraph id="H3DB1A603F2C240D3BED23673A2F409C8">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>cannot adequately complete such elements due to the need for physical presence in the country of origin or other processing-related circumstances; and</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="HDB3F95B19C224929818F284B9A3EDAB9">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>defines and monitors the parameters for the elements delegated to the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref> and retains final decisionmaking authority.</text>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="H2F76D6758ABA40AB92F21DADDEDF7A13">
          <enum>(b)</enum>
          <header>Foreign adoption decrees</header>
          <paragraph id="H40882E1EB0C24ADBA58D97DC1F58FE18">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <header>Convention countries</header>
            <text>The 2-year legal custody and joint residence requirements set forth in <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Immigration and Nationality Act/s:101/ss:b/p:1/sp:E">section 101(b)(1)(E) of the Immigration and Nationality Act</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">
                  <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/8/1101/b/1/E">8 U.S.C. 1101(b)(1)(E)</cato:entity-ref>
                </external-xref>)</cato:entity> shall not apply if the documentation submitted on behalf of a child includes—</text>
            <subparagraph id="HE4A669EA211E45A1BC9F8B3BE4B6E8F5">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>an adoption decree issued by a competent authority (as such term is used in the Hague Adoption Convention) of the child’s country of origin and evidence that the adoption was granted in compliance with the Hague Adoption Convention; or</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="HBAECB7D4508A402E97FE19F33E009874">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>a custody or guardianship decree issued by the competent authority of the child’s country of origin to the adoptive parents, and a final adoption decree, verifying that the adoption of the child was later finalized outside the United States by the adoptive parents, in addition to evidence that the custody or guardianship was granted in compliance with the Hague Adoption Convention.</text>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="HEB4A8F09AF8246568C13D1B8DCBA92AB">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <header>Substantial compliance with Hague adoption convention</header>
            <text>
              <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Children in Families First Act of 2013/s:104/ss:b/p:1" proposed="true">Paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref> shall not apply unless—</text>
            <subparagraph id="HE9EAF5F6A71D4D65AFFF0156928CC6A7">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>on the date on which the underlying adoption, custody, or guardianship decree was issued by the child’s country of origin—</text>
              <clause id="H1959CE5EB8ED422796B1265D9D42B502">
                <enum>(i)</enum>
                <text>that country’s adoption procedures complied with the requirements of the Hague Adoption Convention (as determined by the United States central authority); and</text>
              </clause>
              <clause id="HD22868A6C0924B4AA60D30E23E4F02C2">
                <enum>(ii)</enum>
                <text>the competent authority of the country of origin certified that the adoption is consistent with Article 23 of the Hague Adoption Convention; and</text>
              </clause>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H75C77605DC764FDB92A5B438F5CF5ACF">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>the adoption was a Convention adoption that was completed between 2 Convention countries other than the United States.</text>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H6263406A77A64500A9F4A096EA286098">
            <enum>(3)</enum>
            <header>Non-convention countries</header>
            <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7000">Secretary of Homeland Security</cato:entity-ref> may accept the filing of petitions on behalf of children living in non-Convention countries in the absence of a final adoption decree.</text>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="H094AA488676B46F48B0839924F7B7FCE">
          <enum>(c)</enum>
          <header>Cooperation with foreign governments</header>
          <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7000">Secretary of Homeland Security</cato:entity-ref> may interact directly with the central authority of a Convention country or a competent authority of a non-Convention country, as appropriate—</text>
          <paragraph id="HCE59225D155642C28109CB7B9AA10F4D">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <text>to facilitate the processing of intercountry adoption cases, including making habitual residence determinations relevant to children and prospective adoptive parents in adoption proceedings; and</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H650ADE38E3C24CE18B2851DD03C84EA9">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <text>to negotiate, in coordination with the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Department of State</cato:entity-ref>, and to implement bilateral agreements with respect to intercountry adoptions.</text>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="HDDBC16F811B04C66930FB266C7192704">
          <enum>(d)</enum>
          <header>Amendments to the Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000</header>
          <paragraph id="H7D0D872910A34E5B8ED2B88C1563B251">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <header>Transfer of responsibilities to the Secretary of Homeland Security</header>
            <text>The <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000">Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/14901">
                  <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/42/14901/etseq">42 U.S.C. 14901 et seq.</cato:entity-ref>
                </external-xref>)</cato:entity> is amended—</text>
            <subparagraph id="H5128C6635BB34174BD7F59059546E8EF">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>by striking <quote>
                  <short-title>Attorney General</short-title>
                </quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>
                  <short-title>
                    <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7000">Secretary of Homeland Security</cato:entity-ref>
                  </short-title>
                </quote>; and</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H2AF59480D860431FA04BEFD6A68F11D3">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>in the heading of <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000/s:103">section 103</cato:entity-ref>, by striking <quote>
                  <short-title>
                    <header-in-text level="section" style="OLC">Attorney General</header-in-text>
                  </short-title>
                </quote> and inserting <quote>
                  <short-title>
                    <header-in-text level="section" style="OLC">
                      <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7000">Secretary of Homeland Security</cato:entity-ref>
                    </header-in-text>
                  </short-title>
                </quote>.</text>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H8DE55E5883964015B1DB5A4953D89978">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <header>Hague convention certificates</header>
            <text>
              <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000/s:301">Section 301 of such Act</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/14931">
                  <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/42/14931">42 U.S.C. 14931</cato:entity-ref>
                </external-xref>)</cato:entity> is amended—</text>
            <subparagraph id="HB661B249CA59417499032F26EB97C580">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000/s:301/ss:a">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref>—</text>
              <clause id="HB2DC0ECA873243FE918B892AD7616542">
                <enum>(i)</enum>
                <text>in the subsection heading, by striking <quote>
                    <short-title>
                      <header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">Secretary of State</header-in-text>
                    </short-title>
                  </quote> and inserting <quote>
                    <short-title>
                      <header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">
                        <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7000">Secretary of Homeland Security</cato:entity-ref>
                      </header-in-text>
                    </short-title>
                  </quote>; and</text>
              </clause>
              <clause id="H869903577A6D4AEEBE95DC5515A0084E">
                <enum>(ii)</enum>
                <text>in the heading to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000/s:301/ss:a/p:1">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref>, by striking <quote>
                    <short-title>
                      <header-in-text level="paragraph" style="OLC">Secretary of State</header-in-text>
                    </short-title>
                  </quote> and inserting <quote>
                    <short-title>
                      <header-in-text level="paragraph" style="OLC">
                        <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7000">Secretary of Homeland Security</cato:entity-ref>
                      </header-in-text>
                    </short-title>
                  </quote>; and</text>
              </clause>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H215B605142EC45BF819FAFE7D7C7384C">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>by striking <quote>
                  <short-title>Secretary of State</short-title>
                </quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>
                  <short-title>
                    <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7000">Secretary of Homeland Security</cato:entity-ref>
                  </short-title>
                </quote>.</text>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H1E9798A5B21C4C2089E64B4077F8B202">
            <enum>(3)</enum>
            <header>Clerical amendment</header>
            <text>The table of contents of such Act is amended by striking the item relating to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000/s:103">section 103</cato:entity-ref> and inserting the following:</text>
            <quoted-block id="HA4D44074665E482180971615D0CC36A9" style="OLC">
              <toc>
                <toc-entry level="section">Sec. 103. Responsibilities of the Secretary of Homeland Security.</toc-entry>
              </toc>
              <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
            </quoted-block>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="HBA941D0E8EFE4533B46DDB25B0A8AD60">
          <enum>(e)</enum>
          <header>Definition of child</header>
          <text>
            <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Immigration and Nationality Act/s:101/ss:b/p:1">Section 101(b)(1) of the Immigration and Nationality Act</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/8/1101/b/1">8 U.S.C. 1101(b)(1)</cato:entity-ref>
              </external-xref>)</cato:entity> is amended—</text>
          <paragraph id="H96E28A58D5054220B9C2D0104C7E8FAF">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <text>in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Immigration and Nationality Act/s:101/ss:b/p:1/sp:E">subparagraph (E)</cato:entity-ref>—</text>
            <subparagraph id="HE7F49F92EFE84A83A02DD61C17273FD8">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Immigration and Nationality Act/s:101/ss:b/p:1/sp:E/cl:i">clause (i)</cato:entity-ref>, by striking <quote>
                  <short-title>(i) a child adopted while under the age of sixteen years</short-title>
                </quote> and inserting <quote>
                  <short-title>a child adopted while younger than 18 years of age</short-title>
                </quote>; and</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H782E30C93B96484F86852486BED24950">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>by striking <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Immigration and Nationality Act/s:101/ss:b/p:1/sp:E/cl:ii">clause (ii)</cato:entity-ref>;</text>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H1A5C0498DC3443D498497F6312C46E17">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <text>by amending <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Immigration and Nationality Act/s:101/ss:b/p:1/sp:F">subparagraph (F)</cato:entity-ref> to read as follows:</text>
            <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDDA05EF3CA8C4CC1B4BE0D8BF0116F5C" style="OLC">
              <subparagraph id="HAD6DF53A44314E0294C798937753F49E">
                <enum>(F)</enum>
                <clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H5893DEAE617D444C9AF7A536C2D0F452">
                  <enum>(i)</enum>
                  <text>a child, younger than 18 years of age at the time a petition is filed on the child's behalf to accord a classification as an immediate relative under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Immigration and Nationality Act/s:201/ss:b">section 201(b)</cato:entity-ref>, and who has been adopted in a foreign state that is not a party to the Convention on Protection of Children and Co-operation in Respect of Intercountry Adoption, done at The Hague May 29, 1993, or who is emigrating from such a foreign state to be adopted in the United States by a United States citizen and spouse jointly, or by an unmarried United States citizen who is at least 25 years of age, if—</text>
                  <subclause id="HDDBC79ABF783446B9C2358E42F5B8EAC" indent="up1">
                    <enum>(I)</enum>
                    <text>the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7000">Secretary of Homeland Security</cato:entity-ref> is satisfied that proper care will be furnished the child if admitted to the United States;</text>
                  </subclause>
                  <subclause id="H74FCBE973C4740208F270E1548E57A61" indent="up1">
                    <enum>(II)</enum>
                    <text>the child’s natural parents (or parent, in the case of a child who has 1 sole or surviving parent), or other persons or institutions that retain legal custody of the child, have freely given their written irrevocable consent to the termination of their legal relationship with the child, and to the child's emigration and adoption;</text>
                  </subclause>
                  <subclause id="H92E91A5B0A524D668CDBDCABFB7DEB4A" indent="up1">
                    <enum>(III)</enum>
                    <text>the child has a living parent or parents who has or have relinquished, or will relinquish, the child voluntarily for the purposes of intercountry adoption, and the parent or parents are incapable of providing proper care for the child;</text>
                  </subclause>
                  <subclause id="H6637487E37FD4A70BD5F2890EDAFE354" indent="up1">
                    <enum>(IV)</enum>
                    <text>the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7000">Secretary of Homeland Security</cato:entity-ref>, after considering whether there is a petition pending to confer immigrant status on one or both natural parents, is satisfied that the purpose of the adoption is to form a bona fide parent-child relationship, and the parent-child relationship of the child and the natural parents has been terminated; and</text>
                  </subclause>
                  <subclause id="H73B4A7A895434E8CA3749D3985107E2C" indent="up1">
                    <enum>(V)</enum>
                    <text>in the case of a child who has not been adopted—</text>
                    <item id="HDA638F7DA6794D689798B47FACEC2446">
                      <enum>(aa)</enum>
                      <text>the competent authority of the foreign state has approved the child’s emigration to the United States for the purpose of adoption by the prospective adoptive parent or parents; and</text>
                    </item>
                    <item id="HF58A9CB7193C49F2BB0D4D9614E7ED3E">
                      <enum>(bb)</enum>
                      <text>the prospective adoptive parent or parents has or have complied with any preadoption requirements of the child’s proposed residence; and</text>
                    </item>
                  </subclause>
                </clause>
                <clause id="HF050C996BCB548728A8319AEC88879DA" indent="up1">
                  <enum>(ii)</enum>
                  <text>except that no natural parent or prior adoptive parent of any such child shall thereafter, by virtue of such parentage, be accorded any right, privilege, or status under this chapter;</text>
                </clause>
              </subparagraph>
              <after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block>
            </quoted-block>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H30A9FA8FC82A471F80E7093FFF2B0347">
            <enum>(3)</enum>
            <text>in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Immigration and Nationality Act/s:101/ss:b/p:1/sp:G">subparagraph (G)</cato:entity-ref>—</text>
            <subparagraph id="H9E5CBD07EBF2457793A95A361E4DC671">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>in the matter preceding <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Immigration and Nationality Act/s:101/ss:b/p:1/sp:G/cl:i">clause (i)</cato:entity-ref>, by striking <quote>
                  <short-title>16</short-title>
                </quote> and inserting <quote>
                  <short-title>18</short-title>
                </quote>;</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="HAB1692BBAC134969BF1B1C748CA36464">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Immigration and Nationality Act/s:101/ss:b/p:1/sp:G/cl:i">clause (i)</cato:entity-ref>—</text>
              <clause id="H335C48760A0F468BA93FA1D19995EF1B">
                <enum>(i)</enum>
                <text>in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Immigration and Nationality Act/s:101/ss:b/p:1/sp:G/cl:i/scl:II">subclause (II)</cato:entity-ref>, by striking <quote>
                    <short-title>because of the death or disappearance of, abandonment or desertion by, the other parent</short-title>
                  </quote>; and</text>
              </clause>
              <clause id="H60183AAE0833471C8B87798C078455FE">
                <enum>(ii)</enum>
                <text>in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Immigration and Nationality Act/s:101/ss:b/p:1/sp:G/cl:i/scl:III">subclause (III)</cato:entity-ref>, by striking <quote>
                    <short-title>two living natural parents, the natural parents are</short-title>
                  </quote> and inserting <quote>
                    <short-title>a living parent or parents, who have relinquished or will relinquish the child voluntarily for the purposes of intercountry adoption, the parent or parents are</short-title>
                  </quote>;</text>
              </clause>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="HB53B212E50CA465295B57178767F3348">
              <enum>(C)</enum>
              <text>in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Immigration and Nationality Act/s:101/ss:b/p:1/sp:G/cl:ii">clause (ii)</cato:entity-ref>, by striking <quote>
                  <short-title>; or</short-title>
                </quote> and inserting a period; and</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="HFEA98D79FF7E4705A34604C159430FEE">
              <enum>(D)</enum>
              <text>by striking <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Immigration and Nationality Act/s:101/ss:b/p:1/sp:G/cl:iii">clause (iii)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="HDF76AED5AAF443FD86B5DA0C407BD80E">
          <enum>(f)</enum>
          <header>Relative adoptions; waiver authority</header>
          <text>
            <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Intercountry Adoption Act/s:502">Section 502 of the Intercountry Adoption Act</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/14952">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/42/14952">42 U.S.C. 14952</cato:entity-ref>
              </external-xref>)</cato:entity> is amended to read as follows:</text>
          <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4AE60710A65C4447BE291259F47CBD7C" style="OLC">
            <subsection id="HA4EC2ED93118431FA25A712FBD7DF591">
              <enum>(a)</enum>
              <header>Authority To establish alternative procedures for adoption of children by relatives</header>
              <text>Not later than 2 years after the date of the enactment of the <short-title>
                  <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Children in Families First Act of 2013" proposed="true">Children in Families First Act of 2013</cato:entity-ref>
                </short-title>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7000">Secretary of Homeland Security</cato:entity-ref> shall establish, by regulation, alternative procedures for completing the intercountry adoption of children by United States citizens who are related to such children by blood, marriage, or adoption.</text>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="H59532B95F5F14163B1EF2B1C7068FBEA">
              <enum>(b)</enum>
              <header>Waiver authority</header>
              <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7000">Secretary of Homeland Security</cato:entity-ref>, acting through the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7003">Director of U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services</cato:entity-ref>, may waive, on a case-by-case basis, applicable requirements for meeting the definition of a child under <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
                  <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Immigration and Nationality Act/s:101/ss:b/p:1/sp:E">subparagraph (E)</cato:entity-ref>, <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Immigration and Nationality Act/s:101/ss:b/p:1/sp:F">(F)</cato:entity-ref>, or <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Immigration and Nationality Act/s:101/ss:b/p:1/sp:G">(G) of section 101(b)(1) of the Immigration and Nationality Act</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">
                    <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/8/1101/b/1">8 U.S.C. 1101(b)(1)</cato:entity-ref>
                  </external-xref>)</cato:entity>, or regulations issued with respect to such definitions, in the interests of justice or to prevent or respond to the threat of grave physical or emotional harm to the child if the petitioner establishes that—</text>
              <paragraph id="H0FB6B763B26D40AD800F5C3D22CAF001">
                <enum>(1)</enum>
                <text>the child substantially complies with the requirements under one of such subparagraphs; and</text>
              </paragraph>
              <paragraph id="H8B1E21DE38BF442E99C779B2869F9492">
                <enum>(2)</enum>
                <text>such a waiver would be in the child’s best interests.</text>
              </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
          </quoted-block>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="H1632CA5E5ED84FCA8FC127AB77956390">
          <enum>(g)</enum>
          <header>Determination of applicability of the Hague Adoption Convention in certain cases</header>
          <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7000">Secretary of Homeland Security</cato:entity-ref>, acting through the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7003">Director of U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services</cato:entity-ref>, may determine, on a case-by-case basis, that a specific intercountry adoption case may proceed as a non-Convention adoption if—</text>
          <paragraph id="H70932B89898044FAAE5799E4D2ABE70C">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <text>the child’s country of origin or habitual residence is a Convention country;</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H9C6FF89BB1E84317B5457A911908F839">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <text>the central authority of the child’s country of origin or habitual residence has issued, or will issue, an adoption decree which that country considers to be legal and valid under that country’s laws to the United States adoptive or prospective adoptive parents; and</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="HC395555377B44134AE93A62904414CAB">
            <enum>(3)</enum>
            <text>the central authority of the child’s country of origin or habitual residence has informed the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7000">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> or the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7003">Director</cato:entity-ref> that it does not consider the specific case to fall within the scope of the Hague Adoption Convention.</text>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="H6CDBB37D177F4C068FD99439E7546447">
          <enum>(h)</enum>
          <header>Special use of parole authority</header>
          <paragraph id="H9D23B60B38704719AC8C5C27F177B6C0">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <header>In general</header>
            <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7000">Secretary of Homeland Security</cato:entity-ref>, acting through the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7003">Director of U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services</cato:entity-ref>, may grant parole to a child if the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7000">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> or the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7003">Director</cato:entity-ref> determines that—</text>
            <subparagraph id="H569387B3CE334BC3879EE2CCEDB0D8DB">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>the child’s circumstances indicate that immediate unification with the parties seeking parole is in the child’s best interests;</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="HE74A132A30EE4C2187EA69D774365F8C">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>waiting to complete other, more time consuming immigration processing could be significantly harmful to the child’s well-being;</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H83E92395650041A791288E67334B10FF">
              <enum>(C)</enum>
              <text>the party or parties seeking parole on behalf of the child—</text>
              <clause id="H902DB3F1CA8E4DB4B45B5A4FBFF6D784">
                <enum>(i)</enum>
                <text>have a pre-existing legal relationship with the child, as evidenced by an adoption decree or a custody order; or</text>
              </clause>
              <clause id="H99CEFFE7B13F445A8FC3B7ABFD9764B6">
                <enum>(ii)</enum>
                <text>demonstrate a pre-existing relationship with the child and an intent to establish a legal relationship with the child, which may be evidenced by—</text>
                <subclause id="H430D2FF41B404D2CB5B1B5256C6A3494">
                  <enum>(I)</enum>
                  <text>a familial relationship with the child;</text>
                </subclause>
                <subclause id="H656A1BFB45E14FE98E1613477F6CD84F">
                  <enum>(II)</enum>
                  <text>a close personal relationship with the child, such as—</text>
                  <item id="H7D6F9093BE24451A8D88CBA0BC58EFBF">
                    <enum>(aa)</enum>
                    <text>being matched with the child for an international adoption by an adoption service provider or the competent authority of the child’s country of origin; or</text>
                  </item>
                  <item id="HEB8E3EECE1CD4520853C1CBD6040D9F3">
                    <enum>(bb)</enum>
                    <text>documentation showing that the child’s parents, if deceased or otherwise incapacitated and unable to provide proper care for the child, intended for the parties seeking parole to take custody of the child; or</text>
                  </item>
                </subclause>
                <subclause id="H1EA4DD1BE8534783BE0DB6B6FAB6DC76">
                  <enum>(III)</enum>
                  <text>the filing of adoption-related applications or petitions related to the adoption of the child; and</text>
                </subclause>
              </clause>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="HDDD1664D9C8246BD8BD188637785ACE3">
              <enum>(D)</enum>
              <text>the child will receive proper care in the United States by the party or parties who seek parole on behalf of the child, based on a review of the suitability of the party or parties, which may include background check or completion of a home study conducted by a competent authority.</text>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H94C9A7EF2CE54154A41143F70E41C924">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <header>Meeting the 2-year periods for the purposes of filing an immediate relative petition on behalf of an adopted child</header>
            <text>If a child is granted parole under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Children in Families First Act of 2013/s:104/ss:h/p:1" proposed="true">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref>, is subsequently adopted by the parties who sought parole, and such parties seek permanent immigration status for the child under <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Immigration and Nationality Act/s:101/ss:b/p:1/sp:E">section 101(b)(1)(E) of the Immigration and Nationality Act</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">
                  <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/8/1101/b/1/E">8 U.S.C. 1101(b)(1)(E)</cato:entity-ref>
                </external-xref>)</cato:entity>—</text>
            <subparagraph id="HC2BC09D68582498CAFB1CFAA9A3A7760">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>the 2-year period for legal custody of the child shall begin to accrue on the effective date of a grant of custody in the child’s country of origin or habitual residence or in the United States;</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="HCBA11FC8CBCA4BCA84CFB3C2B194AE60">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>the 2-year period for physical custody of the child shall begin to accrue on the date on which the party or parties seeking parole for the child begin joint residence with the child, in the child’s country of origin or habitual residence or in the United States; and</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H090FE37C4862408FBDAF7B716C5B5402">
              <enum>(C)</enum>
              <text>the 2-year periods of joint residence and legal custody may accrue within or outside the United States.</text>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H587EEC78B1514DC3994A936A00B467F9">
          <enum>(i)</enum>
          <header>Rulemaking</header>
          <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7000">Secretary of Homeland Security</cato:entity-ref>, in consultation with the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref> and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7003">Director of U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services</cato:entity-ref>, shall issue regulations to carry out this section and the amendments made by this section.</text>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </title>
    <title id="H79306F4C5E74482DBE5E8DDC13A5E3C4">
      <enum>II</enum>
      <header>Annual reporting</header>
      <section id="H9D7101E2D201448E85EE29BF6E513D9E">
        <enum>201.</enum>
        <header>Annual report on children living without families</header>
        <subsection id="H1C44FCF72FC644FBB204F0698C75CA9D">
          <enum>(a)</enum>
          <header>In general</header>
          <text>Not later than September 30, 2014, and annually thereafter, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref>, in consultation with the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7200">Director of the United States Agency for International Development</cato:entity-ref> and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref>, shall submit a report to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">
              <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="committee" entity-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate</cato:entity-ref>
            </committee-name> and the <committee-name committee-id="">
              <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="committee" entity-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives</cato:entity-ref>
            </committee-name> that—</text>
          <paragraph id="HECDE8608230F476DA2F6D40F2FA8B9E1">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <text>identifies the number of children living without families; and</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="HC74C9D56D7AA4D6394A880F6380094DB">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <text>describes the degree to which the various family permanence solutions are being utilized.</text>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="HD73E9E31B46E4D9A9B4475621827FCBD">
          <enum>(b)</enum>
          <header>Content</header>
          <text>The report required under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Children in Families First Act of 2013/s:201/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref> shall include—</text>
          <paragraph id="HA4083CDEC1AA48E598AB0D765E7DB4E0">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <text>a description of the world’s unparented children, including—</text>
            <subparagraph id="H2AF5A86A146A4D8390842B9D469C5FA5">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>a description and quantitative analysis of the world’s unparented children by country, identifying the nationality of the children physically present in each country and distinguishing among children who are citizens of the country, noncitizen children lawfully present in the country, and noncitizen children unlawfully in the country, irrespective of a child’s particular immigration status;</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H8F07CA48DEA245F386F21B2F0A846D47">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>available data about such children broken into detailed categories and including—</text>
              <clause id="H46BC5BCB99154AE8918A7E217ACD1FF9">
                <enum>(i)</enum>
                <text>information on their nationality, age, gender, and status;</text>
              </clause>
              <clause id="H0CF5AD311006471C8D2B4DA48DB34FF8">
                <enum>(ii)</enum>
                <text>whether they have a living parent or parents and the status of those parents;</text>
              </clause>
              <clause id="H6995690A29F84FC6859A77E70728D8D8">
                <enum>(iii)</enum>
                <text>whether the unparented children are considered abandoned, separated, relinquished, or have some other status;</text>
              </clause>
              <clause id="HE8E5A28BBDAD4859BD235C3617A7EC8A">
                <enum>(iv)</enum>
                <text>whether they are institutionalized or homeless;</text>
              </clause>
              <clause id="H6890B3F8093F477FBB03A55F9ACB2DE2">
                <enum>(v)</enum>
                <text>information on how they are documented, including through birth registries, orphanage registries, United Nations High Commissioner for Refugees registration, or identity cards; and</text>
              </clause>
              <clause id="H3F6454C1F36743249E7E6CD724C3A7FA">
                <enum>(vi)</enum>
                <text>an assessment of their living conditions based on indicators such as crude mortality rate, malnutrition rate, or other similar indicators;</text>
              </clause>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H6B7E20D24281400A80C3423450A92AB5">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <text>a review of the previous fiscal year’s programming in support of appropriate, protective, and permanent family care solutions, including project descriptions for each project by country, goals of each project, amount awarded for each project, and evaluation of outcomes during the fiscal year;</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="HEAF650D6D84C4360B4357F61EA24A202">
            <enum>(3)</enum>
            <text>an action plan covering proposed programming and activities for the next fiscal year in support of family permanency solutions, including goals for each country in which programming will occur, proposed allocations of resources by country, types of projects proposed by country, amounts of awards proposed for each project, and desired outcomes for each country;</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="HFC99CDBE7B214CBAB0F41741F06F31A2">
            <enum>(4)</enum>
            <text>a review of trends over the last five years, including changes in the numbers and locations of unparented children and the reasons for the changes, such as new refugee arrivals, growing numbers of children abandoned at birth, and decreases in number of children in institutions;</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="HB74D8BB687C84B98B67D81A19265E0CD">
            <enum>(5)</enum>
            <text>an overall analysis of highest priority situations of concern for unparented children, including analysis of whether the children are in a location that provides a cooperative environment for assistance programming and intercountry adoptions;</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H2B5CFC13973B42DDA7B3A0EA9F5099C3">
            <enum>(6)</enum>
            <text>a description of how intercountry adoption and refugee resettlement for unparented refugee children has played a role in each country over the last 10 years and the current status of such programs, including analysis of the situation with respect to the Hague Adoption Convention and how the Convention has affected intercountry adoptions from the country;</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H58E015A107B5432BAF4D1C83E47A0E9F">
            <enum>(7)</enum>
            <text>aggregate reporting on intercountry adoptions to the United States, distinguishing between Convention adoptions and non-Convention adoptions and including—</text>
            <subparagraph id="HBC5D4EC4F5364ED99A11DE09F17A12FF">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>the total number of intercountry adoptions involving immigration to the United States by year over the past 10 years and projected data for the next fiscal year, distinguishing between Convention and non-Convention adoptions, including aggregate data on the country from which each child emigrated, the State of residence of the adoptive parents, and the country in which the adoption was finalized;</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H3A61ACEA53384415A25F8FC58B31CEE5">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>the number of intercountry adoptions involving emigration from the United States, regardless of whether the adoption occurred under the Convention and distinguishing between Convention and non-Convention adoptions, including the country to which each child immigrated and the State from which each child emigrated;</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H5502CA353CA44F678257C2AB65F1208D">
              <enum>(C)</enum>
              <text>the average time required for completion of the immigration portion of intercountry adoptions, distinguishing between Convention and non-Convention adoptions, calculated as the time between filing of the initial immigration-related adoption petition on behalf of a child and the approval of that child’s immigrant visa; and</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="HE808F49CBD974F72B1EF942F725A5332">
              <enum>(D)</enum>
              <text>the range of adoption fees charged in connection with intercountry adoptions involving immigration to the United States and the median of such fees; and</text>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H1A4CD598A16247BCA3C4577B9259AD59">
            <enum>(8)</enum>
            <text>such additional information as may be requested by members of the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">
                <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="committee" entity-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate</cato:entity-ref>
              </committee-name> and the <committee-name committee-id="">
                <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="committee" entity-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives</cato:entity-ref>
              </committee-name>.</text>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="H27F4620262114E6C8964CF77BD2E3DC4">
          <enum>(c)</enum>
          <header>Consultations</header>
          <text>To the extent possible, designated representatives of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> should meet with members of the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">
              <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="committee" entity-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate</cato:entity-ref>
            </committee-name> and the <committee-name committee-id="">
              <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="committee" entity-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives</cato:entity-ref>
            </committee-name> not later than 2 weeks before the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref> submits the report required under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Children in Families First Act of 2013/s:201/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref> to discuss the information described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Children in Families First Act of 2013/s:201/ss:b" proposed="true">subsection (b)</cato:entity-ref>. The substance of such consultations should be printed in the Congressional Record.</text>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="HEF0BBA84E0164AB399E54E09B8AB9E16">
          <enum>(d)</enum>
          <header>Repeal</header>
          <text>
            <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Intercountry Adoption Act/s:104">Section 104 of the Intercountry Adoption Act</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/14914">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/42/14914">42 U.S.C. 14914</cato:entity-ref>
              </external-xref>)</cato:entity> is repealed.</text>
        </subsection>
      </section>
      <section id="H8179F3B451314614BBFDE9F613F81FCD">
        <enum>202.</enum>
        <header>Country reports regarding severe forms of trafficking</header>
        <text display-inline="no-display-inline">
          <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Foreign Assistance Act of 1961/s:502B/ss:h/p:1/sp:B">Section 502B(h)(1)(B) of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2304">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/22/2304/h/1/B">22 U.S.C. 2304(h)(1)(B)</cato:entity-ref>
            </external-xref>)</cato:entity> is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
        <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0E15A5E81FC54A22A5868DE6EDE1E8D6" style="OLC">
          <clause id="H21EA2AAF016A48C1882C7F2A80DF9494" indent="up1">
            <enum>(x)</enum>
            <text>What steps the government of that country has taken to reduce the number of children living outside of family care.</text>
          </clause>
          <clause id="H71A0A1AC7C2642FDADC50586F53412E2" indent="up1">
            <enum>(xi)</enum>
            <text>What steps the government of that country has taken to reduce the number of children abused, neglected, or exploited.</text>
          </clause>
          <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
        </quoted-block>
      </section>
    </title>
    <title id="HCB464E65BAB046BBA24A94BA6A574E55">
      <enum>III</enum>
      <header>Promotion of a comprehensive approach for children in adversity</header>
      <section id="HE08FF54C8FBB4CB685E2FBEF057E3687">
        <enum>301.</enum>
        <header>Establishment of a USAID Center for Excellence for Children in Adversity</header>
        <subsection id="H050AFD3642B247FF87672B8C361AD10B">
          <enum>(a)</enum>
          <header>Center for Excellence for Children in Adversity</header>
          <paragraph id="HF4400F26D8B44424A9E55C250BD8AE9D">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <header>In general</header>
            <text>There is established within the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7200">United States Agency for International Development</cato:entity-ref> a <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Center of Excellence on Children in Adversity" entity-id="7200" proposed="true">Center of Excellence on Children in Adversity</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="HA1A16EA0914E4645A317DCC52C7D4865">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <header>Coordinator</header>
            <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Center of Excellence on Children in Adversity" entity-parent-id="7200" proposed="true">Center for Excellence</cato:entity-ref> shall be headed by the Children in Adversity Coordinator, who shall be appointed by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref>, in consultation with the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7200">Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="HD2257E0601C34D71A700C402FC21CFAF">
            <enum>(3)</enum>
            <header>Objectives</header>
            <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Center of Excellence on Children in Adversity" entity-parent-id="7200" proposed="true">Center of Excellence on Children in Adversity</cato:entity-ref> shall work in consultation with the Assistant Secretary of the Bureau of Vulnerable Children and Family Security of the Department of State to promote greater United States Government coherence and accountability for whole-of-government assistance to children in adversity and ensure that United States foreign assistance and development programs are focused on the following objectives:</text>
            <subparagraph id="HF11C114984B644FC8ACD1CB136D6B047">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>The sound development of children through the integration of health, nutrition, and family support.</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="HC027F0E6B49641F3A3C2FD03AE1D1FF3">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>Supporting and enabling families to care for children through family preservation, reunification, and support of kinship care, guardianship, and domestic and intercountry adoption.</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H63E2475698AF41EDAE275EAD16BC13C4">
              <enum>(C)</enum>
              <text>Facilitating the efforts of national governments and partners to prevent, respond to, and protect children from violence, exploitation, abuse, and neglect.</text>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H4956E481AF3349E7BC459EEC71DED381">
            <enum>(4)</enum>
            <header>Authorities</header>
            <text>The Children in Adversity Coordinator, acting through nongovernmental organizations (including faith-based and community-based organizations), partner country finance, health, education, social welfare, and other ministries, and relevant executive branch agencies, is authorized to—</text>
            <subparagraph id="H4CA2DFA7033B4FD19F8D4B1988982C9B">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>operate internationally to carry out the programs and activities outlined in the Action Plan for Children in Adversity;</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H8AB2E098062341E0B83560877D381B3C">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>provide grants to, and enter into contracts and cooperative agreements with, nongovernmental organizations (including faith-based organizations) to carry out this section; and</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="HFA45D5886EF346628DD7ECCC9C0B8405">
              <enum>(C)</enum>
              <text>transfer and allocate <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7200">United States Agency for International Development</cato:entity-ref> funds that have been appropriated for the purposes described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Children in Families First Act of 2013/s:301/ss:a/p:4/sp:A" proposed="true">subparagraphs (A)</cato:entity-ref> and <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Children in Families First Act of 2013/s:301/ss:a/p:4/sp:B" proposed="true">(B)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H70A33D718ED0451DA9D909610D737A7B">
            <enum>(5)</enum>
            <header>Functions</header>
            <text>In consultation with the Assistant Secretary of the Bureau of Children's Affairs in the Department of State, the Children in Adversity Coordinator shall, through the Center of Excellence—</text>
            <subparagraph id="HBA379667671248359ADBEB8DFD81D6B1">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>facilitate program and policy coordination related to the goals and objectives of the Action Plan for Children in Adversity among relevant executive branch agencies and nongovernmental organizations by auditing, monitoring, and evaluating such programs;</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="HDB3EF7BB18234D0FBE4FA6F4DA027DBB">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>ensure that each relevant executive branch agency undertakes responsibility for activities related primarily to those areas in which the agency has the greatest expertise, technical capability, and potential for success;</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="HBB4195850B2F4258B1C8F3993236B536">
              <enum>(C)</enum>
              <text>coordinate relevant executive branch agency activities related to the Action Plan for Children in Adversity;</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H914B3261121E4F4AADEA79FC0829A606">
              <enum>(D)</enum>
              <text>establish due diligence criteria for all recipients of funds appropriated by the United States Government for assistance to children in adversity; and</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="HA8CD991E78574E68AD1D976B9945F3A7">
              <enum>(E)</enum>
              <text>oversee the administration of the priority country demonstration program as described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Children in Families First Act of 2013/s:301/ss:f" proposed="true">subsection (f)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H05A2912D85B54517AF7655D6B440EE44">
            <enum>(6)</enum>
            <header>Assistance</header>
            <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> is authorized to provide assistance, including through international, nongovernmental, or faith-based organizations, for programs in developing countries—</text>
            <subparagraph id="H52A1EB58E5654699A09D0AD2F45EE4CC">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>to increase the percentage of children achieving age-appropriate growth and developmental milestones;</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H4B36D618F4D8454E85C024DCF97C4A01">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>to increase the percentage of children under 5 years of age demonstrating secure attachment with a primary caregiver;</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H6DC7E2DBC19E4D97ACDC33F3E75521A5">
              <enum>(C)</enum>
              <text>to integrate health, nutrition, developmental protections, and caregiving support for vulnerable children and their families;</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H6F31D8D89704490A91E42A4C411AD6AF">
              <enum>(D)</enum>
              <text>to increase the percentage of children living within appropriate, permanent, safe, and protective family care, through family preservation and reunification, and through kinship care, guardianship, and domestic and intercountry adoption, and to reduce the percentage of children living in institutions;</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H7D6E98F54ABE4600A1B07741205CC4B4">
              <enum>(E)</enum>
              <text>to increase the percentage of families providing adequate nutrition, education opportunities, care, and protection for their children;</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H50C17F3D21D149F484EFB2063FFF78E7">
              <enum>(F)</enum>
              <text>to reduce the percentage of children who experience violence, exploitation, abuse, and neglect;</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H858ACD1393FE43B596CC02EDECF3F930">
              <enum>(G)</enum>
              <text>to increase the percentage of children who receive appropriate care and protection after experiencing violence, exploitation, abuse, or neglect;</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="HDA3124D5D9544F7DB4362F893E3BE60A">
              <enum>(H)</enum>
              <text>to increase public awareness that violence, exploitation, abuse, or neglect of children as unacceptable;</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H0C3DDF94E7BB46F198FCBA0D6220D782">
              <enum>(I)</enum>
              <text>to increase the percentage of countries that ratify and implement relevant conventions or formally adopt internationally recognized principles, standards, and procedural safeguards to protect children from violence, exploitation, abuse, and neglect;</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H6945589813C64F378397D1421DB4BA1E">
              <enum>(J)</enum>
              <text>to increase the percentage of children who have legal documentation and birth registration;</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H93A6168246D74739BE56FCDA4AFDD00F">
              <enum>(K)</enum>
              <text>to increase the number of laws, policies, and practices in partner states that promote and strengthen child welfare and protection at household, community, and national levels is increased;</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H3E6D9201E9F54A7180A717DAF8B1A096">
              <enum>(L)</enum>
              <text>to increase national and local human resource capacity for child welfare and protection;</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H55625379F9D949F89C5D21DD24D448DF">
              <enum>(M)</enum>
              <text>to increase the number of national and community systems effectively monitoring child welfare and protection concerns, programs, and outcomes;</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="HCB0DA12CF4BB4F039EE42B48C6BBB7FA">
              <enum>(N)</enum>
              <text>to encourage and assist in the collection of data related to children outside of family care;</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="HC4A17A9253DB48A2AB20D9E7D5D34766">
              <enum>(O)</enum>
              <text>to increase the number of prevalence studies that measure and track trends in children’s exposure to violence, exploitation, abuse, and neglect;</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="HD96170C843E84CC09DFFA2B8A9E99542">
              <enum>(P)</enum>
              <text>to increase the number of published outcome/impact evaluations on interventions to assist children outside of family care or minimize exposure to violence, exploitation, abuse, and neglect that can be generalized to larger target groups;</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H2C765F3A77454B42997BC6D4B698243F">
              <enum>(Q)</enum>
              <text>to increase the number of national governments and universities leading rigorous data collection, research, and monitoring and evaluation studies related to child welfare and protection; and</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="HF9B042DA17F0406F9D6EAB1249ACDBF0">
              <enum>(R)</enum>
              <text>to increase the number of United States Government-supported interventions for children in adversity designed using data from rigorous research methodologies.</text>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="H936573D933774DDB89CC7F1F47EFF394">
          <enum>(b)</enum>
          <header>Monitoring and evaluation</header>
          <paragraph id="H4CE189923CC84BBEBAFA86337AA435D0">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <header>Establishment of system</header>
            <text>To maximize the sustainable development impact of assistance authorized under this section, and pursuant to the primary objective of the Action Plan for Children in Adversity, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> shall establish a monitoring and evaluation system to measure the effectiveness of United States assistance to children in adversity.</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="HFE1DEFC6BA084E72A125206AD69348E7">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <header>Requirements</header>
            <text>The monitoring and evaluation system shall—</text>
            <subparagraph id="HD7C39ED259864C0AB07053CFDED343E9">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>be aligned with the objectives and outcomes outlined by the Action Plan for Children in Adversity; and</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H29A5FD3BB84B4600826278DA9804619D">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>provide a basis for recommendations for adjustments to the assistance provided under this part.</text>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="HB9F15C4EEC5644D2893832D60AB00692">
          <enum>(c)</enum>
          <header>Priority Country Demonstration Program</header>
          <paragraph id="H0F28A0EA2EF44C4D91E64180AAE5AF96">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <header>In general</header>
            <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7200">Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development</cato:entity-ref>, in consultation with the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref>, shall establish and carry out a priority country demonstration program implementing the Action Plan for Children in Adversity over a period of 5 years in at least 6 countries.</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H5CF61558EA114E5880AFCDD58E8B70B0">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <header>Purposes</header>
            <text>The purposes of the programs established under sub<cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Children in Families First Act of 2013/s:301/ss:c/p:1" proposed="true">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref> shall be—</text>
            <subparagraph id="H0203F0D92B384D28991B33285C9D5F5F">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>to demonstrate how research-based policies and programs to achieve the core objectives of the Action Plan for Children in Adversity can be successfully implemented on a national level;</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H29DDD8DCF8AE453E9B111CC793C56F64">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>to establish model programs that, once tested for efficacy, will be available for replication on a global basis;</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H803AD58C41FA449CA185DC8FB779F1E8">
              <enum>(C)</enum>
              <text>to identify a comprehensive series of interventions which result in meeting the outcomes and objectives of the Action Plan for Children in Adversity; and</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="HD626B44511FB41199785F4B92E553D19">
              <enum>(D)</enum>
              <text>to determine which in-country factors advance or negate the successful achievement of the outcomes and objectives of the action plan.</text>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H3A5E1F9E44F647C29D37639722240617">
            <enum>(3)</enum>
            <header>Criteria for selection of countries</header>
            <text>The criteria for selection of countries shall include—</text>
            <subparagraph id="HC80EFFD27A74479F9A97E51E9AB728DD">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>magnitude and severity of the problems to be addressed;</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H90F1A9413D6744F49FA1204A170ECFC6">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>partner country interest in participation in a comprehensive implementation of all 3 goals of the Action Plan for Children in Adversity, including, with respect to the second objective (Families First), expressed willingness to support the full complement of permanence solutions (including family preservation, reunification, kinship care, guardianship, and domestic and intercountry adoption), and commitments to support and allow monitoring and evaluation, as well as transparent reporting;</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H01601AFA7C3D4EFBB4F76F0685613627">
              <enum>(C)</enum>
              <text>potential to leverage bilateral, multilateral, and foundation investments;</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H7CF1CF600BDC48A8998B41B58DA31CAB">
              <enum>(D)</enum>
              <text>potential to leverage other United States development investments;</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H05191434B04A44F18A6935421D853D85">
              <enum>(E)</enum>
              <text>regional diversity to maximize learning opportunities; and</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H8DED329E623C47CE93CF36444C96F27D">
              <enum>(F)</enum>
              <text>level of economic development, with a focus on low- and middle-income countries.</text>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="H532F8AE78FD943DF946B3B5A8D2C8DE2">
          <enum>(d)</enum>
          <header>Repeals</header>
          <paragraph id="HE384659B4959479F8F3C8336A5A857D0">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <header>Assistance to orphans and other vulnerable children</header>
            <text>
              <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Foreign Assistance Act of 1961/s:135">Section 135 of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2152f">
                  <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/22/2152f">22 U.S.C. 2152f</cato:entity-ref>
                </external-xref>)</cato:entity> is repealed.</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="HE853F4C439C942F6A69C83A95573355C">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <header>Annual report</header>
            <text>
              <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Assistance for Orphans and Other Vulnerable Children in Developing Countries Act of 2005/s:5">Section 5 of the Assistance for Orphans and Other Vulnerable Children in Developing Countries Act of 2005</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2152g">
                  <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/22/2152g">22 U.S.C. 2152g</cato:entity-ref>
                </external-xref>)</cato:entity> is hereby repealed.</text>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </title>
    <title id="HC03C66B2B1A94E4B8586716350785D05">
      <enum>IV</enum>
      <header>Funding and effective dates</header>
      <section id="H8CED157AC2834B8C959B3A90CC8A8F44">
        <enum>401.</enum>
        <header>Funding</header>
        <subsection id="HA6E882916C07468EA7EFCC8D20CDED9F">
          <enum>(a)</enum>
          <header>Prohibition on new appropriations</header>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No additional funds are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this Act and the amendments made by this Act. This Act and such amendments shall be carried out using amounts otherwise available for such purposes, including unobligated balances of funds made available to carry out activities under the <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Foreign Assistance Act of 1961">Foreign Assistance Act of 1961</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2151">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/22/2151/etseq">22 U.S.C. 2151 et seq.</cato:entity-ref>
              </external-xref>)</cato:entity>.</text>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="HBBC695A6B4D34B11A651432CDDAA397C">
          <enum>(b)</enum>
          <header>Limitations on use of funds</header>
          <paragraph id="H329E98D24DB04C21AAF97BD08DE5AA89">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <header>United Nations</header>
            <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No funds may be awarded to the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="19UN">United Nations</cato:entity-ref> or any of its subsidiaries.</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H3F5E1026EC2F480BB6A50E813CA420FE">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <header>Administrative expenses</header>
            <text>Not more than two percent of the amounts described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Children in Families First Act of 2013/s:401/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref> may be used for administrative expenses.</text>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="HD3FC90B169CF472D9BB239579A4C3E50">
          <enum>(c)</enum>
          <header>Focus of assistance</header>
          <text>Assistance provided under this Act—</text>
          <paragraph id="HB1CE93FA20AE4E7782748056C692DC5A">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <text>shall focus primarily on promoting international child welfare, as set forth in this Act, for all children in adversity; and</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H8BEC73A32B514767990604EF9F283079">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <text>may be provided on such terms and conditions as the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> determines appropriate.</text>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
      </section>
      <section id="H528147D69C184495BEB3E57C4C1F4E7B">
        <enum>402.</enum>
        <header>Effective dates</header>
        <subsection id="H35F35E9E3C954B81B7E5E4DF5F775A71">
          <enum>(a)</enum>
          <header>Effective upon enactment</header>
          <text>
            <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Children in Families First Act of 2013/s:104" proposed="true">Sections 104</cato:entity-ref> and <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Children in Families First Act of 2013/s:202" proposed="true">202</cato:entity-ref> and <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Children in Families First Act of 2013/t:III" proposed="true">titles III</cato:entity-ref> and <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Children in Families First Act of 2013/t:IV" proposed="true">IV</cato:entity-ref> shall take effect on the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="H03DA38B3E52E4684B1B4D045F46CD4F1">
          <enum>(b)</enum>
          <header>Delayed effective date</header>
          <text>
            <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Children in Families First Act of 2013/s:101" proposed="true">Sections 101</cato:entity-ref>, <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Children in Families First Act of 2013/s:102" proposed="true">102</cato:entity-ref>, <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Children in Families First Act of 2013/s:103" proposed="true">103</cato:entity-ref>, and <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Children in Families First Act of 2013/s:201" proposed="true">201</cato:entity-ref> shall take effect on the date that is 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </title>
  </legis-body>
</bill>
</doc>