<doc>
  <docmeta id="113hres667ih">
    <bill congress="113" type="hres" number="667" version="ih"/>
    <revision size="3137" annotations="0" status="complete" id="4" commit-time="2014-07-22T20:55:57Z" committer="zwilliams" doc="113hres667ih/4.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <resolution xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" dms-id="HC507612A1C884CC5B8705F10864FA920" key="H" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print">
	<metadata>
<dublinCore>
<dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">113 HRES 667 IH: Expressing support for dancing as a form of valuable exercise and artistic expression, and for the designation of July 26, 2014, as National Dance Day.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">2014-07-11</dc:date>
<dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">113th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session display="yes">2d Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. RES. 667</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20140711">July 11, 2014</action-date>
			<action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>
      </action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">Expressing support for dancing as a form of valuable exercise and artistic expression, and for the
			 designation of July 26, 2014, as National Dance Day.</official-title>
	</form>
	<preamble>
		<whereas>
      <text>Whereas Nigel Lythgoe, executive producer and celebrity judge for the dance-themed television show
			 <quote>So You Think You Can Dance</quote>, in association with the Dizzy Feet
			 Foundation, has encouraged the creation of National Dance Day in nations
			 around the world, beginning with the first National Dance Day on the
			 National Mall in 2010;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the Dizzy Feet Foundation and the Kennedy Center, in conjunction with the office of
			 Congresswoman Eleanor Holmes Norton, will celebrate National Dance Day on
			 Saturday, July 26, 2014, in the Nation’s Capital at the Kennedy Center;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas National Dance Day has captured the imagination of people throughout the Nation and around
			 the world and has helped popularize dancing as an art, for fun, and as a
			 form of exercise;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas National Dance Day encourages many forms of dance expression, representing the Nation’s
			 rich artistic, regional, ethnic, and racial diversity;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas National Dance Day features the spectrum of dance, from classical to popular to line and
			 partner dances;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas dancing helps improve heart health, burn calories, strengthen muscles, and improve
			 flexibility for people of all ages;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas health officials have repeatedly documented an overweight and obesity epidemic among every
			 age group in the United States;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas dancing, in all its variations, is a popular form of physical exercise;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas National Dance Day in the Nation’s Capital will begin at 1 p.m. with performances by Dizzy
			 Feet and other local talent; and</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the last Saturday in July continues to be an appropriate day to celebrate National Dance
			 Day as it has been for the past 3 years: Now, therefore, be it</text>
    </whereas>
  </preamble>
	<resolution-body id="HE4836B98D7844763BA2C38BE0FF54A49" style="traditional">
		<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H1AF96CCF8FFC4AF1A9B8E5C8307732E1" section-type="undesignated-section">
      <enum/>
      <text>That the <cato:entity-ref entity-id="0050" entity-type="federal-body">House of Representatives</cato:entity-ref>—</text>
			<paragraph id="H6D6B551631C84A9BB748AB80458A8354">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">supports the designation of National Dance Day to celebrate and encourage the national commitment
			 to dance education and physical fitness;</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H07F50F3EC17A4183BF099BEFB1523DCC">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text>acknowledges that dance is making an important contribution to health by encouraging physical
			 fitness and reducing overweight and obesity; and</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HA12D941CC0FD4DB888CE94EFC579BEBB">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <text>commends Nigel Lythgoe for his leadership in promoting National Dance Day.</text>
			</paragraph>
    </section>
  </resolution-body>
</resolution>
</doc>