<doc>
  <docmeta id="113hr4143ih">
    <bill congress="113" type="hr" number="4143" version="ih"/>
    <revision size="97247" annotations="0" status="complete" id="16" commit-time="2014-03-28T17:18:45Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113hr4143ih/16.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H793305B8B1424BE7B7DE3798B616603B" public-private="public">
	<metadata>
<dublinCore>
<dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">113 HR 4143 IH: Children in Families First Act of 2014</dc:title>
<dc:publisher xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">2014-03-04</dc:date>
<dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>113th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>2d Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 4143</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20140304">March 4, 2014</action-date>
			<action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="G000377">Ms. Granger</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="B001270">Ms. Bass</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001256">Mrs. Bachmann</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000600">Mr. Diaz-Balart</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000448">Mr. Franks of Arizona</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000168">Mr. Olson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000244">Mr. Sensenbrenner</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000672">Mr. Wolf</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000126">Ms. Eddie Bernice Johnson of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C000754">Mr. Cooper</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000559">Mr. Langevin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001058">Mr. Huizenga of Michigan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson of Indiana</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001062">Mr. Conaway</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001150">Mr. Schiff</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000588">Mr. Richmond</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000472">Mr. Takano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001242">Mr. Bishop of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001162">Ms. Schwartz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001259">Mr. Braley of Iowa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000399">Mr. Doggett</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001047">Mrs. Capito</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001284">Mrs. Brooks of Indiana</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="I000057">Mr. Israel</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000592">Mr. Rokita</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001068">Mr. Cohen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000032">Ms. Jackson Lee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001278">Ms. Bonamici</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000312">Mr. McGovern</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000186">Mr. Nunnelee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000382">Ms. Kuster</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000445">Mr. Forbes</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001191">Mr. Murphy of Florida</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Judiciary</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To realign structures and reallocate resources in the Federal Government, in keeping with the core
			 American belief that families are the best protection for children and the
			 bedrock of any society, to bolster United States diplomacy and assistance
			 targeted at ensuring that every child can grow up in a permanent, safe,
			 nurturing, and loving family, and to strengthen intercountry adoption to
			 the United States and around the world and ensure that it becomes a viable
			 and fully developed option for providing families for children in need,
			 and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H8EBB7D75307B475AA3A541E99572B09B" style="OLC">
		<section id="H3C3BBD25E05D41D380DB1442E62F067B" section-type="section-one">
      <enum>1.</enum>
      <header>Short title; table of contents</header>
			<subsection id="H4D1ABF3A093049CF8EC5F53A05F0279B">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Short title</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote>
            <short-title>
              <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Children in Families First Act of 2014" proposed="true">Children in Families First Act of 2014</cato:entity-ref>
            </short-title>
          </quote>.</text>
			</subsection>
      <subsection id="H8EABE918CD1743FDBAC559E5F8047078">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Table of contents</header>
        <text>The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text>
				<toc container-level="legis-body-container" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded" lowest-level="section" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" regeneration="yes-regeneration">
					<toc-entry idref="H3C3BBD25E05D41D380DB1442E62F067B" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title; table of contents.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H5D0CCB373BB344919098BAE1992BAC62" level="section">Sec. 2. Findings; purposes.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H1067559E0DF6419C805A5E7B19C56871" level="section">Sec. 3. Definitions.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HB06AB744E4F048FA825E32A1E054D089" level="title">Title I—Realignment of certain international child welfare responsibilities and functions</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HED2E356FE5D4483B9361AE8C01F7C6E3" level="section">Sec. 101. Establishment of Bureau of Vulnerable Children and Family Security in the Department of
			 State.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H05C5E05C99F241768B3178639BFB7E6E" level="section">Sec. 102. Responsibilities of U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services for accreditation of
			 adoption service providers.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HC43C5E2F3F1843ED866EB89A7FF5FE62" level="section">Sec. 103. Transfer of functions and savings provisions.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H82B8CC03437A458BA38C5547581B466E" level="section">Sec. 104. Responsibilities of U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services for adoption-related case
			 processing.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H6E63448E42594AC6916CB846353BA435" level="title">Title II—Annual reporting</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H1AEE7791A82E484CBEAA2EDE1631CA9C" level="section">Sec. 201. Annual report on children living without families.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HF4E0304CA08A470CBF111410514A618F" level="section">Sec. 202. Country reports regarding severe forms of trafficking.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H78E3385E1105473E8B1C836C4F814E77" level="title">Title III—Promotion of a comprehensive approach for children in adversity</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H4910A5C66B7843DF92B7BEF7F63E10B6" level="section">Sec. 301. Establishment of a USAID Center for Excellence for Children in Adversity.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H97792D8DE5AA40679472ABE397DF9FD0" level="title">Title IV—Funding and effective dates</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H5C823F24B44547E4A4DB43DC3A3C28DA" level="section">Sec. 401. Funding.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H1DF413AFB66648E99A4A8B61728FBE33" level="section">Sec. 402. Effective dates.</toc-entry>
        </toc>
			</subsection>
    </section>
    <section id="H5D0CCB373BB344919098BAE1992BAC62">
      <enum>2.</enum>
      <header>Findings; purposes</header>
			<subsection id="H658F6BA7E2E94125A3703E8EAE28081C">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Findings</header>
        <text>Congress makes the following findings:</text>
				<paragraph id="HA10E96AA171547A8A2E4D388C2063B17">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>The people of the United States recognize and believe that children must grow up in permanent,
			 safe, and nurturing families in order to develop and thrive.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H3D79ED9B772A4B629A195B92F2047CA9">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>Science now proves conclusively that children suffer immediate, lasting, and in many cases
			 irreversible damage from time spent living in institutions or outside of
			 families, including reduced brain activity, reduced IQ, smaller brain
			 size, and inability to form emotional bonds with others.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H6B6B17E22AA04C10B5D29769BD2115AE">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <text>Governments in other countries seek models that promote the placement of children who are living
			 outside family care in permanent, safe, and nurturing families, rather
			 than in foster care or institutions, but many governments lack the
			 resources or infrastructure to adequately address this need.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H770BD857E11C4D8C8B9072B00FBBC1C1">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
          <text>Despite the good efforts of countless governments and nongovernmental organizations, millions of
			 children remain uncounted and outside of the protection, nurturing care,
			 permanence, safety, and love of a family. Without the care of a family,
			 these children are forced to live on the streets, in institutions, in paid
			 foster care, in child-headed households, in group homes, or as household
			 servants.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HD5DADB4214484F7F8979EFB8FC4DB6C2">
          <enum>(5)</enum>
          <text>No reliable data currently exists to define and document the number and needs of children in the
			 world currently living without families, but available evidence
			 demonstrates that there are millions of children in this situation needing
			 immediate help.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HB94E29A354DB467093DB4E4C6FD5462F">
          <enum>(6)</enum>
          <text>The December 2012 Action Plan for Children in Adversity commits the United States Government to
			 achieving a world in which all children grow up within protective family
			 care and free from deprivation, exploitation, and danger. To effectively
			 and efficiently accomplish this goal, it is necessary to realign the
			 United States Government’s current operational system for assisting
			 orphans and vulnerable children, and processing intercountry adoptions.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HB0EB3F407B9C479E989B6C2CED633D9E">
          <enum>(7)</enum>
          <text>All options for providing appropriate, protective, and permanent family care to children living
			 without families must be considered concurrently and permanent solutions
			 must be put in place as quickly as possible. Solutions include family
			 preservation and reunification, kinship care, guardianship, domestic and
			 intercountry adoption, and other culturally acceptable forms of care that
			 will result in appropriate, protective, and permanent family care.
			 Preference should be given to options that optimize child best interests,
			 which generally means options which provide children with fully protected
			 legal status and parents with full legal status as parents, including full
			 parental rights and responsibilities. The principle of subsidiarity, which
			 gives preference to in-country solutions, should be implemented within the
			 context of a concurrent planning strategy, exploring in- and
			 out-of-country options simultaneously. If an in-country placement serving
			 the child’s best interest and providing appropriate, protective, and
			 permanent care is not quickly available, and such an international home is
			 available, the child should be placed in that international home without
			 delay.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HCF73CF803B374183AB492CEC7FC37BD5">
          <enum>(8)</enum>
          <text>Significant resources are already dedicated to international assistance for orphans and vulnerable
			 children, and a relatively small portion of these resources can be
			 reallocated to achieve more timely, effective, nurturing, and permanent
			 familial solutions for children living without families, resulting in
			 fewer children worldwide living in institutions or on the streets, more
			 families preserved or reunified, and increased domestic and international
			 adoptions.</text>
				</paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="H25CBB59AD8194C8FBFDB20E92A9442A4">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Purposes</header>
        <text>The purposes of this Act are—</text>
				<paragraph id="HF71752ACA5C7465A85E4CAC6C7C756C4">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>to support the core American value that families are the bedrock of any society;</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HE358B80F514146AAB872A53DE5388C11">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>to protect the fundamental human right of all children to grow up within the loving care of
			 permanent, safe, and nurturing families;</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H6E84E283D6814803A3AD15ECB9CBFBB7">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <text>to address a critical gap in United States foreign policy implementation by adjusting the Federal
			 Government’s international policy and operational structures so that
			 seeking permanent families for children living without families receives
			 more prominence, focus, and resources (through the reallocation of
			 existing personnel and resources);</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H2029AAC84E734A63904609740272A7AE">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
          <text>to harness the diplomatic and operational power of the United States Government in the
			 international sphere by helping to identify and implement timely,
			 permanent, safe, and nurturing familial solutions for children living
			 without families, including refugee or stateless children;</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H42082416416D4154B7A7C9811885163C">
          <enum>(5)</enum>
          <text>to ensure that intercountry adoption by United States citizens becomes a viable and fully developed
			 option for creating permanent families for children who need them;</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H991CD11995804E1CAC91F235DE435C4B">
          <enum>(6)</enum>
          <text>to protect against abuses of children, birth families, and adoptive parents involved in
			 intercountry adoptions, and to ensure that such adoptions are in the
			 individual child’s best interests; and</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H972904D49C184DDF86747F09DC3251B3">
          <enum>(7)</enum>
          <text>to harmonize and strengthen existing intercountry adoption processes under United States law—</text>
					<subparagraph id="H99F20A1767D54A129128FDF64E51BAF6">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>by ensuring that the same set of procedures and criteria govern suitability and eligibility
			 determinations for prospective adoptive parents seeking to complete
			 intercountry adoptions, whether or not the child is from a foreign state
			 that is a party to the Hague Adoption Convention; and</text>
					</subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="HC5779CC431184C838B2117A4805FE24C">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>by aligning the definitions of eligible child for Convention adoptions and non-Convention adoptions
			 to the maximum extent possible.</text>
					</subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
    </section>
    <section id="H1067559E0DF6419C805A5E7B19C56871">
      <enum>3.</enum>
      <header>Definitions</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text>
			<paragraph id="H167757CA48584DC38E96D0BF9C4ABB7C">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <header>Action plan for children in adversity</header>
        <text>The term <term>Action Plan for Children in Adversity</term> means the policy document entitled <term>United States Government Action Plan on Children in Adversity: A Framework for International
			 Assistance: 2012–2017</term>, released on December 19, 2012.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H1A1F3B5691C94314ABDBE51E25392125">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <header>Appropriate, protective, and permanent family care</header>
        <text>The term <term>appropriate, protective, and permanent family care</term> means a nurturing, lifelong, commitment to a child by an adult, or adults with parental roles and
			 responsibilities that—</text>
				<subparagraph id="H3EBA849CC2F944E58DD9240640917C6A">
          <enum>(A)</enum>
          <text>provides physical and emotional support;</text>
				</subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="H78BECE0A9BD743E69B9C132E5269B3CD">
          <enum>(B)</enum>
          <text>provides the child with a sense of belonging; and</text>
				</subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="HD63EDACECB2D474B98E543C22A13CD3F">
          <enum>(C)</enum>
          <text>generally involves full legal recognition of the child’s status as child of the parents and of the
			 parents’ rights and responsibilities regarding the child.</text>
				</subparagraph>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H43CB9CA70BC74A31AC0F2CE040234258">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <header>Central authority</header>
        <text>The term <term>central authority</term> has the meaning given the term in <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000/s:3">section 3 of the Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000</cato:entity-ref> (<cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/42/14902">42 U.S.C.
			 14902</cato:entity-ref>)</cato:entity>.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H6895594E4F2042DFB4FBA723042CD5B7">
        <enum>(4)</enum>
        <header>Children in adversity</header>
        <text>The term <term>children in adversity</term> means children living inside or outside of family care who are deprived, excluded, vulnerable, or
			 at risk for violence, abuse, exploitation, or neglect.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H21F6D3346F3A4DF38457B712CE924087">
        <enum>(5)</enum>
        <header>Convention adoption</header>
        <text>The term <term>Convention adoption</term> has the meaning given the term in <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000/s:3">section 3 of the Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000</cato:entity-ref> (<cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/42/14902">42 U.S.C.
			 14902</cato:entity-ref>)</cato:entity>.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HE1C0AD180A144A7B88AE3E10E4C6F54D">
        <enum>(6)</enum>
        <header>Convention country</header>
        <text>The term <term>Convention country</term> has the meaning given the term in <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000/s:3">section 3 of the Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000</cato:entity-ref> (<cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/42/14902">42 U.S.C.
			 14902</cato:entity-ref>)</cato:entity> and for which the Hague Adoption Convention has entered into force.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HCC834A3FF8464D959E70944529DA9015">
        <enum>(7)</enum>
        <header>Guardianship</header>
        <text>The term <term>guardianship</term> means a permanent legal relationship between an adult and a child, whereby the adult is lawfully
			 invested with the power, and charged with the duty, of taking care of the
			 child. While some forms of guardianship are not truly permanent, the form
			 of guardianship referred to and supported under this Act is permanent
			 guardianship. A Kefala order issued by a country that follows traditional
			 Islamic law does not qualify as an adoption under United States law, but
			 may be a form of guardianship in some circumstances.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H129D023028AA4D8D8A85AA1FD667A36D">
        <enum>(8)</enum>
        <header>Habitual residence determination</header>
        <text>The term <term>habitual residence determination</term> means a factual determination of where a prospective adoptive parent (or parents) resides and
			 where the child resides for purposes of an intercountry adoption case.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H21A5AACC39C440228B1B1CA26F02213A">
        <enum>(9)</enum>
        <header>Hague adoption convention</header>
        <text>The term <term>Hague Adoption Convention</term> means the Convention of Protection of Children and Cooperation in Respect of Intercountry
			 Adoption, concluded at The Hague May 29, 1993.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HDF86DA5EB7D748DE9B817BB9BEDD9ED5">
        <enum>(10)</enum>
        <header>Kinship care</header>
        <text>The term <term>kinship care</term> means the full time care, nurturing, and protection of children by relatives, members of their
			 tribes or clans, godparents, stepparents, or any adult who has a kinship
			 bond with a child, so long as those persons have the capacity and
			 commitment to function as true parents for the child on a permanent basis.
			 It does not include paid kinship foster care.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H73BAAC32E94242A8834D7027F9C136F0">
        <enum>(11)</enum>
        <header>Non-convention adoption</header>
        <text>The term <term>non-Convention adoption</term> means—</text>
				<subparagraph id="H5EED6020F36444D894DB77C641162EDA">
          <enum>(A)</enum>
          <text>an adoption by United States parents of a child from a non-Convention country in accordance with
			 <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Immigration and Nationality Act/s:101/ss:b/p:1/sp:F">subparagraph (F) of section 101(b)(1) of the Immigration and Nationality
			 Act</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/8/1101/b/1">8 U.S.C. 1101(b)(1)</cato:entity-ref>
            </external-xref>)</cato:entity>;</text>
				</subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="H8F663C9BAD424C8D8B355CAC15667930">
          <enum>(B)</enum>
          <text>an adoption by United States parents of a child under the laws of the child’s country of origin
			 (generally when the parents are living in the child’s country of origin
			 and therefore able legally to complete a domestic adoption); or</text>
				</subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="H233B61B6B316456F82D4D5430D546903">
          <enum>(C)</enum>
          <text>in certain circumstances (generally with respect to relative adoptions or adoptions by dual
			 national parents), an adoption by United States parents of a child from a
			 Convention country if that country allows legal and valid adoptions to
			 take place outside the scope of the Convention.</text>
				</subparagraph>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H04416FEC71F34788ABA68A4101E70749">
        <enum>(12)</enum>
        <header>Non-convention country</header>
        <text>The term <term>non-Convention country</term> means a country in which the Hague Adoption Convention has not entered into force, regardless of
			 whether or not that country has signed the Convention.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H34064D31B4C0434F8A23EA19D4472468">
        <enum>(13)</enum>
        <header>Unparented children</header>
        <text>The term <term>unparented children</term> means children lacking the legal, permanent, safe, and nurturing care of a parental figure or
			 figures, either inside their country of origin, in the country of their
			 habitual residence, or elsewhere, regardless of their lawful or unlawful
			 immigration status in their current country of residence.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HC31E5377A2C041CCAD491EBEB9A237C6">
        <enum>(14)</enum>
        <header>Vulnerable children</header>
        <text>The term <term>vulnerable children</term>, consistent with the United States Agency for International Development's definition, means
			 children and youth who are under 18 years whose safety, well-being,
			 growth, and development are at significant risk due to inadequate care,
			 protection, or access to essential services.</text>
			</paragraph>
    </section>
    <title id="HB06AB744E4F048FA825E32A1E054D089">
      <enum>I</enum>
      <header>Realignment of certain international child welfare responsibilities and functions</header>
			<section id="HED2E356FE5D4483B9361AE8C01F7C6E3">
        <enum>101.</enum>
        <header>Establishment of Bureau of Vulnerable Children and Family Security in the Department of State</header>
				<subsection id="HE2F86F72B69545D79F3B057C826760DF">
          <enum>(a)</enum>
          <header>Establishment</header>
          <text>There is established within the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Department of State</cato:entity-ref> the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Bureau of Vulnerable Children and Family Security" entity-parent-id="1900" proposed="true">Bureau of Vulnerable Children and Family
			 Security</cato:entity-ref> (referred to in this Act as the <term>VCFS</term>), which shall be located in the Secretariat for Civilian Security, Democracy and Human Rights and
			 shall promote and support the following activities:</text>
					<paragraph id="HCDB4788255214610A3150CB702340A1B">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <text>The development and implementation in foreign countries of child welfare laws, regulations,
			 policies, best practices, and procedures in keeping with the goals
			 articulated in the Action Plan for Children in Adversity, including—</text>
						<subparagraph id="H95D6AC9686D1414CBB1D4E11026DC7BE">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>the sound development of children through the integration of health, nutrition, and family support;</text>
						</subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H6066D430646147099FAEB6385BE5D1DF">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>supporting and enabling families to care for children through family preservation, reunification,
			 and support of kinship care, guardianship, and domestic and intercountry
			 adoption; and</text>
						</subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H748225424A79418AA7F468663D1FACC0">
              <enum>(C)</enum>
              <text>facilitating the efforts of national governments and partners to prevent, respond to, and protect
			 children from violence, exploitation, abuse, and neglect.</text>
						</subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H169CDFE75C1E459DB2C47BFC0C447DEE">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <text>Addressing the gap in United States Government diplomacy, policy, and operations with respect to
			 promoting appropriate, protective, and permanent family care for children
			 living without families by establishing within the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Bureau of Vulnerable Children and Family Security" entity-parent-id="1900" proposed="true">VCFS</cato:entity-ref> a Senior
			 Coordinator for Permanence, who—</text>
						<subparagraph id="H4FF12D2BAF474D59A2374823E0FE8C90">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>shall occupy at least a Deputy Assistant Secretary-level position in the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Bureau of Vulnerable Children and Family Security" proposed="true" entity-parent-id="1900">VCFS</cato:entity-ref>; and</text>
						</subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H59A1EC8B3504444891AA2A41948B3A20">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>shall lead the development and implementation of policies that will ensure the timely provision of
			 appropriate, protective, and permanent family care for children living
			 without families, including refugee and stateless children, through the
			 full continuum of permanence solutions, including family preservation and
			 reunification, kinship care, guardianship, and domestic and intercountry
			 adoption.</text>
						</subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="H925477DAA0854030947F7A8D42A9C120">
          <enum>(b)</enum>
          <header>Assistant Secretary</header>
					<paragraph id="H3DEC4E3304CD4F15B4D4AA558CAEC1D9">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <header>Appointment</header>
            <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Bureau of Vulnerable Children and Family Security" entity-parent-id="1900" proposed="true">VCFS</cato:entity-ref> shall be headed by an <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Bureau of Vulnerable Children and Family Security" entity-parent-id="1900" proposed="true">Assistant Secretary</cato:entity-ref>, who shall be appointed by the President by and
			 with the consent of the Senate.</text>
					</paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H5E48C213CD594537B318D5AD6379DE22">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <header>Qualifications</header>
            <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Bureau of Vulnerable Children and Family Security" entity-parent-id="1900" proposed="true">Assistant Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall—</text>
						<subparagraph id="HB85B4ADAA3FB4692AD59EF27D3257D55">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>have experience in the development of policies and systems and the implementation of programs that
			 promote the goals of the Action Plan for Children in Adversity;</text>
						</subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="HCB0166C665494481BEC1E100292C83D9">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>be knowledgeable of international child welfare, family permanence, and family creation through
			 domestic and intercountry adoption; and</text>
						</subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H80BC71317B70489B92D90B32A670D6E0">
              <enum>(C)</enum>
              <text>be committed to developing an integrated United States Government approach to international child
			 welfare that places equal emphasis on—</text>
							<clause id="H04D2786AD2134FD6B31CD8B3C707D01A">
                <enum>(i)</enum>
                <text>early childhood survival and development;</text>
							</clause>
              <clause id="H382CDC51AB864C749A7C99C5A70DFCCD">
                <enum>(ii)</enum>
                <text>family permanence; and</text>
							</clause>
              <clause id="H9C8D68EB6CA046E9A23A6710C0CDE39E">
                <enum>(iii)</enum>
                <text>protection from abuse and exploitation.</text>
							</clause>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H2D9DC9C04412466F84F11D34782B8B40">
            <enum>(3)</enum>
            <header>Authority</header>
            <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Bureau of Vulnerable Children and Family Security" proposed="true" entity-parent-id="1900">Assistant Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall report to the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Under Secretary for Civilian Security, Democracy and Human Rights" entity-parent-id="1900">Under Secretary for Civilian Security, Democracy and
			 Human Rights</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
					</paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H8C5AB1EF710142EE9D8FBF4873247596">
            <enum>(4)</enum>
            <header>Increase in authorized assistant secretary positions</header>
						<subparagraph id="H409A371D58F7421EB5BBBE6A1E5037EC">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <header>Amendment to State Department Basic Authorities Act of 1956</header>
              <text>
                <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
                  <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="State Department Basic Authorities Act of 1956/s:1/ss:c/p:1">Section 1(c)(1) of the State Department Basic Authorities Act of 1956</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2651a">
                  <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/22/2651a/c/1">22 U.S.C. 2651a(c)(1)</cato:entity-ref>
                </external-xref>)</cato:entity> is
			 amended by striking <quote>not more than 24 Assistant Secretaries</quote> and inserting <quote>not more than 25 Assistant Secretaries</quote>.</text>
						</subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H8E8063E8C1EC4638B57FAF21AAB8C43C">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <header>Amendment to title 5, United States Code</header>
              <text>
                <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc/5/5315">
                  <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/5/5315">Section 5315</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code</cato:entity-ref>, is amended by striking <quote>Assistant Secretaries of State (24)</quote> and inserting <quote>Assistant Secretaries of State (25)</quote>.</text>
						</subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="H6E825705407B40FEB48F53740400AC9C">
          <enum>(c)</enum>
          <header>Functions</header>
					<paragraph id="H8783B7F346124912AF5BB821B29875D0">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <header>Advisory</header>
            <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Bureau of Vulnerable Children and Family Security" entity-parent-id="1900" proposed="true">Assistant Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall serve as a primary advisor to the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref> and the
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> in all matters related to vulnerable children and family
			 security in foreign countries.</text>
					</paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H58F83C0CB68440A383F97ABA8E13FF3F">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <header>Diplomatic representation</header>
            <text>Subject to the direction of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref>, and in consultation and
			 coordination with the Senior Coordinator for Children in Adversity of the
			 United States Agency for International Development, and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7000">Secretary of
			 Homeland Security</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Bureau of Vulnerable Children and Family Security" entity-parent-id="1900" proposed="true">Assistant Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall represent the United
			 States in matters relevant to international child welfare, family
			 preservation and reunification, and provision of permanent, safe parental
			 care through kinship, domestic and intercountry adoption in—</text>
						<subparagraph id="H5458132476B54FFBA74B09705024D6EB">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>contacts with foreign governments, nongovernmental organizations, intergovernmental agencies, and
			 specialized agencies of the United Nations and other international
			 organizations of which the United States is a member;</text>
						</subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="HF667CBCD275540C0B09EB9B9F7C16906">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>multilateral conferences and meetings relevant to family preservation, reunification, and creating
			 appropriate, protective, and permanent care for unparented children; and</text>
						</subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H7D0A1D209EC6440EB4521471F122A6C3">
              <enum>(C)</enum>
              <text>fulfillment of the diplomatic responsibilities designated to the central authority under <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
                  <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000/t:I">title I of
			 the Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/14911">
                  <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/42/14911/etseq">42 U.S.C. 14911 et seq</cato:entity-ref>.</external-xref>)</cato:entity>, as
			 amended by this Act.</text>
						</subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H2B8DF65E270D4787B36D1E16E5E6F0E5">
            <enum>(3)</enum>
            <header>Policy development with respect to permanence for unparented children</header>
						<subparagraph id="HED4D6463952B4C5CB2D285D8C42D9D4D">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <header>In general</header>
              <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Bureau of Vulnerable Children and Family Security" entity-parent-id="1900" proposed="true">Assistant Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall—</text>
							<clause id="HBA1FC4C60E954882B7821D42F9A93121">
                <enum>(i)</enum>
                <text>develop and advocate for policies and practices to ensure that children in foreign countries who
			 are living without families find appropriate, protective, and permanent
			 family care which is in the best interest of each child;</text>
							</clause>
              <clause id="H0B16A72A885645058D40049DF414CA05">
                <enum>(ii)</enum>
                <text>give consideration to family preservation and reunification, kinship care, guardianship, and
			 domestic and intercountry adoption; and</text>
							</clause>
              <clause id="H485E37FF62B242478586916C29CB2F4D">
                <enum>(iii)</enum>
                <text>seek to develop and implement policies that lead to the use of all options for providing
			 appropriate, protective, and permanent family care to children living
			 without families as quickly as possible.</text>
							</clause>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H65C40E870A1446508BBC2DAE6C19B2AE">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <header>Best interest determination</header>
              <text>In carrying out <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Children in Families First Act of 2014/s:101/ss:c/p:3/sp:A" proposed="true">subparagraph (A)</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Bureau of Vulnerable Children and Family Security" entity-parent-id="1900" proposed="true">Assistant Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall give preference to options that
			 optimize the best interests of children, including options which provide
			 children with fully protected legal status as children and parents with
			 full legal status as parents, including full parental rights and
			 responsibilities.</text>
						</subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H2C651C6626E94AE8B5F8AD1FB11140B7">
              <enum>(C)</enum>
              <header>Subsidiarity</header>
              <text>The principle of subsidiarity, which gives preference to in-country solutions, should be
			 implemented within the context of a concurrent planning strategy,
			 exploring in- and out-of-country options simultaneously. If an in-country
			 placement serving the child’s best interests and providing appropriate,
			 protective, and permanent care is not quickly available, and such an
			 international home is available, the child should be placed in that
			 international home without delay.</text>
						</subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="HBF2F20D98E49443FA7C2310A071FEAB7">
              <enum>(D)</enum>
              <header>Best practices</header>
              <text>In developing policies and programs under this Act, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Bureau of Vulnerable Children and Family Security" entity-parent-id="1900" proposed="true">Assistant Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall identify and
			 utilize evidence-based programs and best practices in family preservation
			 and reunification and provision of permanent parental care through
			 guardianship, kinship care, and domestic and intercountry adoption as
			 derived from a wide variety of domestic, foreign, and global policies and
			 practices.</text>
						</subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="HEAF2DF116ED44C5AA19534B9971249CD">
              <enum>(E)</enum>
              <header>Technical assistance</header>
              <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Bureau of Vulnerable Children and Family Security" entity-parent-id="1900" proposed="true">Assistant Secretary</cato:entity-ref>, in consultation with other appropriate Federal agencies, shall provide
			 technical assistance to governments of foreign countries to help build
			 their child welfare capacities and to strengthen appropriate family
			 preservation and reunification and the provision of appropriate,
			 protective, and permanent family care through kinship care, guardianship,
			 and domestic and intercountry adoption, including assistance with—</text>
							<clause id="HD59EEFA8AAFA4D55BAD3A8DB70F1E3BE">
                <enum>(i)</enum>
                <text>the drafting, disseminating, and implementing of legislation;</text>
							</clause>
              <clause id="H478630F84EF14131A3655072B97D44B8">
                <enum>(ii)</enum>
                <text>the development of implementing systems and procedures;</text>
							</clause>
              <clause id="H923002F784E0429BA403A5224D554E7F">
                <enum>(iii)</enum>
                <text>the establishment of public, private, and faith- and community-based partnerships;</text>
							</clause>
              <clause id="HDC0248519C004528847DBCB8CE45B822">
                <enum>(iv)</enum>
                <text>the development of workforce training for governmental and nongovernmental staff; and</text>
							</clause>
              <clause id="H0E05D24C10EF4B37AD4F9947666B04DF">
                <enum>(v)</enum>
                <text>infrastructure development and data collection techniques necessary to identify and document the
			 number and needs of children living without appropriate, protective, and
			 permanent family care.</text>
							</clause>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H8DED3613A8BB4CF488FE01EAB4963DB7">
            <enum>(4)</enum>
            <header>Responsibilities with respect to intercountry adoption</header>
						<subparagraph id="H4DA0D93FFD9A43C2A3EC67C5D76E1E38">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <header>In general</header>
              <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Bureau of Vulnerable Children and Family Security" entity-parent-id="1900" proposed="true">VCFS</cato:entity-ref>, in coordination with other offices of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Department of State</cato:entity-ref> and <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7003">U.S. Citizenship and
			 Immigration Services</cato:entity-ref>, shall have lead responsibility for representing the
			 United States Government in discussions, negotiations, and diplomatic
			 contacts pertaining to intercountry adoptions.</text>
						</subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="HD020A7DC2B3946E69F5AF5688D75BF42">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <header>Central authority responsibility under the intercountry adoption act of 2000</header>
              <text>
                <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
                  <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000/s:101/ss:b/p:2">Section 101(b)(2) of the Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/14911">
                  <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/42/14911/b/2">42 U.S.C. 14911(b)(2)</cato:entity-ref>
                </external-xref>)</cato:entity> is amended by
			 striking <quote>Office of Children's Issues</quote> and inserting <quote>Bureau of Vulnerable Children and Family Security</quote>.</text>
						</subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H8F1E58501DE74DE09664D4B0C1E957FD">
              <enum>(C)</enum>
              <header>Determinations of Hague adoption convention compliance</header>
              <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Bureau of Vulnerable Children and Family Security" entity-parent-id="1900" proposed="true">VCFS</cato:entity-ref>, in consultation with other offices of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Department of State</cato:entity-ref>, and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7000">Department of
			 Homeland Security</cato:entity-ref>, shall have lead responsibility for determining whether
			 a Convention partner country has met its obligations under the Hague
			 Adoption Convention and is eligible to participate in intercountry
			 adoptions in accordance with United States law. Such determinations shall
			 be documented in writing, based on standardized criteria, and available
			 for public review and comment.</text>
						</subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H2AD5EA2BA62F47EB893F74957F8ED12E">
              <enum>(D)</enum>
              <header>Negotiation of bilateral agreements</header>
              <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Bureau of Vulnerable Children and Family Security" entity-parent-id="1900" proposed="true">VCFS</cato:entity-ref>, in consultation with the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7000">Secretary of Homeland Security</cato:entity-ref>, shall have lead responsibility
			 for the negotiation of bilateral agreements with other countries
			 pertaining to intercountry adoption and in conformity with the provisions
			 of the Hague Adoption Convention when the other country is a Convention
			 partner.</text>
						</subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="HCE65BB87973A42EE823988B8C9881259">
            <enum>(5)</enum>
            <header>Policy coordination</header>
            <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Bureau of Vulnerable Children and Family Security" entity-parent-id="1900" proposed="true">Assistant Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall coordinate with the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7000">Secretary of Homeland Security</cato:entity-ref> and the
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7200">Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development</cato:entity-ref> to
			 maintain consistency in United States foreign and domestic policy and
			 operations with respect to children living outside family care in foreign
			 countries, particularly those living without families.</text>
					</paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H879D32043B9A404B9240D90089A239C1">
            <enum>(6)</enum>
            <header>Information coordination</header>
            <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Bureau of Vulnerable Children and Family Security" entity-parent-id="1900" proposed="true">Assistant Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall transmit—</text>
						<subparagraph id="HC070FD9668D946CC99C7A4AF12CBB365">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>any intercountry adoption related case information received from the Central Authority of another
			 Convention country to the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7000">Secretary of Homeland Security</cato:entity-ref>; and</text>
						</subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="HAACB7EB73F28429D833BF85AB9069CC8">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>any intercountry adoption related case information that the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7000">Secretary of Homeland Security</cato:entity-ref> requests
			 to the Central Authority of another Convention country.</text>
						</subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
      </section>
      <section id="H05C5E05C99F241768B3178639BFB7E6E">
        <enum>102.</enum>
        <header>Responsibilities of U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services for accreditation of adoption service
			 providers</header>
				<subsection id="H23B565E126424CAE8B073036441D1E94">
          <enum>(a)</enum>
          <header>General responsibilities under the Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000</header>
					<paragraph id="HBF3DF6BDF5CB4A97A6FBC6D3D3192CD8">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <header>In general</header>
            <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000">Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/106/279">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="public-law" value="public-law/106/279">Public Law 106–279</cato:entity-ref>
              </external-xref>; <cato:entity-ref entity-type="statute-at-large" value="statute-at-large/114/825">114 Stat. 825</cato:entity-ref>)</cato:entity> is amended by inserting
			 after <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000/s:103">section 103</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/14913">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/42/14913">42 U.S.C. 14913</cato:entity-ref>
              </external-xref>)</cato:entity> the following:</text>
						<quoted-block act-name="" id="H30197810D3CA4AD783821804E513BD1A" style="OLC">
							<section id="H3E72FF51621E4E11A859402CD8A039F8">
                <enum>103A.</enum>
                <header>Responsibilities of the Department of Homeland Security</header>
								<subsection id="H4F61851D7C1D4B5D8C8E105DD7309DDA">
                  <enum>(a)</enum>
                  <header>Accreditation and approval responsibilities</header>
                  <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7000">Secretary of Homeland Security</cato:entity-ref>, working through the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7003">Director of U.S. Citizenship and
			 Immigration Services</cato:entity-ref>, shall carry out the functions prescribed by the
			 Convention with respect to the accreditation of agencies and the approval
			 of persons to provide adoption services in the United States in cases
			 subject to the Convention as provided in title II. Such functions may not
			 be delegated to any other Federal agency.</text>
								</subsection>
                <subsection id="H319A21A2C3A1435DAC66DD034E1756B5">
                  <enum>(b)</enum>
                  <header>Investigations</header>
                  <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7000">Secretary of Homeland Security</cato:entity-ref> shall be responsible for managing and overseeing investigations
			 related to the operation and services of adoption service providers,
			 whether directly or indirectly.</text>
								</subsection>
                <subsection id="H6569C4E038BE4A268FB96ADFA22EEC9D">
                  <enum>(c)</enum>
                  <header>Liaison with foreign governments on post-Placement reports and certain adoption cases</header>
                  <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7000">Secretary of Homeland Security</cato:entity-ref> shall serve as the liaison with foreign governments with respect
			 to queries about required post-placement reports and about specific
			 intercountry adoption cases once the adopted children are living in the
			 United States, including queries about the status of adopted children who
			 are living in the United States in cases involving allegations of abuse,
			 neglect, abandonment, or death.</text>
                </subsection>
              </section>
              <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
            </quoted-block>
					</paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H8B0C5B1259FE4F4BA6293C3F916AE625">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <header>Clerical amendment</header>
            <text>
              <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000/s:1">Section 1 of such Act</cato:entity-ref> is amended by inserting after the item relating to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000/s:103">section 103</cato:entity-ref> the following:</text>
						<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2F17A6B527A7400C96BE60816020B16C" style="OLC">
							<toc>
								<toc-entry bold="off" level="section">Sec. 103A. Responsibilities of the Department of Homeland Security.</toc-entry>
              </toc>
              <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
            </quoted-block>
					</paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H66534C609E1E427AA57C8A33DC68AB21">
            <enum>(3)</enum>
            <header>Conforming amendments</header>
            <text>
              <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000/s:102">Section 102 of such Act</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/14912">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/42/14912">42 U.S.C. 14912</cato:entity-ref>
              </external-xref>)</cato:entity> is amended—</text>
						<subparagraph id="H364B88F7B9444964B9EC54C260E42C82">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000/s:102/ss:a">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref>, by striking <quote>The Secretary</quote> and inserting <quote>Except as provided for under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000/s:103A" proposed="true">section 103A</cato:entity-ref>, the Secretary</quote>;</text>
						</subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="HF09EDFA85FAF47EB9E28F4B904CE7848">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000/s:102/ss:b">subsection (b)</cato:entity-ref>, by inserting <quote>, in coordination with the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7000">Secretary of Homeland Security</cato:entity-ref>,</quote> after <quote>The Secretary</quote>;</text>
						</subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="HAD343C0169DF4D52A3B27F8C97834787">
              <enum>(C)</enum>
              <text>by striking <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000/s:102/ss:c">subsection (c)</cato:entity-ref>;</text>
						</subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H2A0BA6A421B64488AB22B8FC613C6709">
              <enum>(D)</enum>
              <text>by redesignating <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000/s:102/ss:d, f">subsections (d) and (f)</cato:entity-ref> as <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000/s:102/ss:c, d" proposed="true">subsections (c) and (d)</cato:entity-ref>, respectively; and</text>
						</subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H4B3BA68639C941CBA265EF857C53793D">
              <enum>(E)</enum>
              <text>by striking <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000/s:102/ss:e">subsection (e)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
						</subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="HCBEABE87E66A4948A5D01EAC6077C12E">
          <enum>(b)</enum>
          <header>Accreditation responsibilities under the Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000</header>
					<paragraph id="HE5E521BE74BB4B20B9C2C66B35095812">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <header>Designation of accrediting agencies</header>
            <text>
              <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000/s:202">Section 202 of the Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/14922">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/42/14922">42 U.S.C. 14922</cato:entity-ref>
              </external-xref>)</cato:entity> is amended by inserting <quote>of Homeland Security</quote> after <quote>Secretary</quote> each place it appears.</text>
					</paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H4BB1A6D2AA4C4A23BDAC37D5BA26CB27">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <header>Standards and procedures for providing accreditation or approval</header>
            <text>
              <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000/s:203">Section 203 of the Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/14923">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/42/14923">42 U.S.C. 14923</cato:entity-ref>
              </external-xref>)</cato:entity> is amended by inserting <quote>of Homeland Security</quote> after <quote>Secretary</quote> each place it appears in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000/s:203/ss:a">subsections (a)</cato:entity-ref> and <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000/s:203/ss:b">(b)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
					</paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H6F46CF69775C4E48931D775A4F2793B2">
            <enum>(3)</enum>
            <header>Oversight of accreditation and approval</header>
            <text>
              <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000/s:204">Section 204 of the Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/14924">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/42/14924">42 U.S.C. 14924</cato:entity-ref>
              </external-xref>)</cato:entity> is amended—</text>
						<subparagraph id="H2D2E571028E641708C3C5B3C1304FE57">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>by inserting <quote>of Homeland Security</quote> after <quote>Secretary</quote> each place it appears; and</text>
						</subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H2FA3BA5C2AE546EBA67DF70B38EB90BB">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000/s:204/ss:c">subsection (c)</cato:entity-ref>—</text>
							<clause id="H5D56F84C5729488087BF3142B5FEB5A5">
                <enum>(i)</enum>
                <text>in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000/s:204/ss:c/p:1">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref>, by amending the paragraph heading to read as follows:</text>
								<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9885012024814A94AF0E60B4C3205583" style="OLC">
									<paragraph id="H7D7C62012AFE4C3E9686942042E5F03D">
                    <enum>(4)</enum>
                    <header>Authority of the secretary of homeland security</header>
                  </paragraph>
                  <after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block>
                </quoted-block>
							</clause>
              <clause id="HB41F0A75BAB4408EAD3391A322316F19">
                <enum>(ii)</enum>
                <text>in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000/s:204/ss:c/p:2">paragraph (2)</cato:entity-ref>, by striking <quote>Secretary's debarment order</quote> and inserting <quote>debarment order of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7000">Secretary of Homeland Security</cato:entity-ref>
                  </quote>.</text>
							</clause>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H73A95324DD39482A99C797157A0EC70F">
            <enum>(4)</enum>
            <header>Administrative provisions</header>
						<subparagraph id="H60999BC8A99B47CC9C84E0292DFFC870">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <header>Access to convention records</header>
              <text>
                <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
                  <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000/s:401/ss:b">Section 401(b) of the Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/14941">
                  <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/42/14941/b">42 U.S.C. 14941(b)</cato:entity-ref>
                </external-xref>)</cato:entity> is amended—</text>
							<clause id="HFB6095261B7C4C83B0C1E50A2E07444D">
                <enum>(i)</enum>
                <text>in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000/s:401/ss:b/p:1">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref>, by inserting <quote>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7003">Director of U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services</cato:entity-ref>,</quote> after <quote>Secretary</quote>; and</text>
							</clause>
              <clause id="H3D4DBD053B95485DA698CDF1C81B69D2">
                <enum>(ii)</enum>
                <text>in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000/s:401/ss:b/p:2">paragraph (2)</cato:entity-ref>, by inserting <quote>the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7003">Director of U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services</cato:entity-ref>,</quote> after <quote>Secretary,</quote>.</text>
							</clause>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H867765076BEE4EEA92C1354ACD47DBA4">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <header>Assessment of fees</header>
              <text>
                <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
                  <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000/s:403/ss:b">Section 403(b) of the Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/14943">
                  <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/42/14943/b">42 U.S.C. 14943(b)</cato:entity-ref>
                </external-xref>)</cato:entity> is amended—</text>
							<clause id="H149A3001F44E416598785EE635763C9A">
                <enum>(i)</enum>
                <text>in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000/s:403/ss:b/p:1">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref>—</text>
								<subclause id="HF7B5966DFD1C48DFBD6D4121F0BF6BD3">
                  <enum>(I)</enum>
                  <text>by inserting <quote>or the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7003">Director of U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services</cato:entity-ref>
                    </quote> after <quote>Secretary</quote>; and</text>
								</subclause>
                <subclause id="H0E39092279884534A95DEC4267B7B2F5">
                  <enum>(II)</enum>
                  <text>by inserting <quote>or U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services, respectively,</quote> after <quote>Department of State</quote>; and</text>
								</subclause>
              </clause>
              <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD72EDE200EC644E988CFEB135C2A6C3B">
                <enum>(ii)</enum>
                <text>in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000/s:403/ss:b/p:2">paragraph (2)</cato:entity-ref>, by inserting <quote>or <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7003">U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services</cato:entity-ref> appropriation, as the case may be,</quote> after <quote>Department of State appropriation</quote>.</text>
							</clause>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="HEE8D4018DDF54B808D2FE906114B6020">
          <enum>(c)</enum>
          <header>Intercountry adoption functions of U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services</header>
					<paragraph id="HC506BA836B24440198F9DE4111E8333F">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <header>Definitions</header>
            <text>In this subsection and in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Children in Families First Act of 2014/s:103" proposed="true">section 103</cato:entity-ref>:</text>
						<subparagraph id="H24DF93BC054A4C46A53AC14F7559D16C">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <header>Adoption service</header>
              <text>The term <term>adoption service</term> has the meaning given the term in <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
                  <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000/s:3">section 3 of the Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000</cato:entity-ref> (<cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/42/14902">42 U.S.C.
			 14902</cato:entity-ref>)</cato:entity>.</text>
						</subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H0928F16F07864453B5450ACAB46EA717">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <header>Associate director</header>
              <text>The term <term>Associate Director</term> means the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Field Operations Directorate" entity-parent-id="7003">Associate Director</cato:entity-ref> of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Field Operations Directorate" entity-parent-id="7003">Directorate</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
						</subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="HD22250BAD4C64C318EA5893E1EF19DDF">
              <enum>(C)</enum>
              <header>Directorate</header>
              <text>Except as otherwise provided in this subsection, the term <term>Directorate</term> means the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Field Operations Directorate" entity-parent-id="7003">Field Operations Directorate of U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
						</subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H5CB4B29558884FBA96D1E43F7657CF7C">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <header>Intercountry adoption functions</header>
            <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Field Operations Directorate" entity-parent-id="7003">Associate Director</cato:entity-ref> shall carry out—</text>
						<subparagraph id="H196EFA088F784DBEB7C5F26E3ED1607A">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>the functions described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000/s:103A/ss:a" proposed="true">section 103A(a) of the Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000</cato:entity-ref>, relating to
			 accreditation of agencies and approval of persons to provide adoption
			 services;</text>
						</subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="HCC18506AB4104F4EB346139FAEEAFAAD">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>the functions described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000/s:103A/ss:b" proposed="true">section 103A(b) of such Act</cato:entity-ref>, relating to management and oversight of
			 investigations related to the operation of such providers; and</text>
						</subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="HC2A24C705C354C8194790CB4896FC878">
              <enum>(C)</enum>
              <text>the functions described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000/s:103A/ss:c" proposed="true">section 103A(c) of such Act</cato:entity-ref>, relating to liaison responsibilities
			 regarding post-placement reports and certain adoption cases.</text>
						</subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="HFAAED3D0FEEA42DB80F8A6AB4272C548">
            <enum>(3)</enum>
            <header>Informational responsibilities</header>
						<subparagraph id="HEFC613FD25A84694959B3421B38272BD">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <header>Database on adoption service providers</header>
							<clause id="H98BEEE7A03DD49AC9CC170AFED611CAE">
                <enum>(i)</enum>
                <header>In general</header>
                <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Field Operations Directorate" entity-parent-id="7003">Associate Director</cato:entity-ref> shall establish and operate, in conjunction with the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref>, a
			 publicly accessible database of adoption service providers.</text>
							</clause>
              <clause id="H8FDECB49108D431AAAFF62DB001037C9">
                <enum>(ii)</enum>
                <header>Agreement</header>
                <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Field Operations Directorate" entity-parent-id="7003">Associate Director</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7003">Director</cato:entity-ref>, and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref> shall enter into an agreement
			 under which the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7003">Director</cato:entity-ref> and the Secretary shall provide, for the
			 database, data on intercountry adoption cases relating to adoption service
			 providers.</text>
							</clause>
              <clause id="HA985DD12571F49AD834F7D51B17F745F">
                <enum>(iii)</enum>
                <header>Contents</header>
                <text>The database shall include, with respect to each accredited agency and approved person, who is an
			 adoption service provider individually, and to the aggregate of all
			 adoption service providers—</text>
								<subclause id="H16964F55F102416180D39CE9FB6D6770">
                  <enum>(I)</enum>
                  <text>information identifying such a provider;</text>
								</subclause>
                <subclause id="H83466CFF69D14A72A12F7E235CCE3FA2">
                  <enum>(II)</enum>
                  <text>information on the accreditation status of an agency, or the approval status of a person, as an
			 adoption service provider;</text>
								</subclause>
                <subclause id="H1253599A433A483393D0E5B7B6D7FF3B">
                  <enum>(III)</enum>
                  <text>information on the number of applications or petitions filed respecting adoption and the numbers of
			 approvals and denials of the applications or petitions;</text>
								</subclause>
                <subclause id="HB11F3BCD829E410DB2105C0486461CF5">
                  <enum>(IV)</enum>
                  <text>the number of substantiated grievances filed with respect to an adoption service provider; and</text>
								</subclause>
                <subclause id="HDF25140E166D443BA04CB959C7E1C640">
                  <enum>(V)</enum>
                  <text>a description of any sanctions an adoption service provider, or corrective actions that the
			 provider is required to take to maintain accreditation or approval
			 described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Children in Families First Act of 2014/s:102/ss:c/p:3/sp:A/cl:iii/scl:II" proposed="true">subclause (II)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
								</subclause>
              </clause>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="HF3FF6395117A404AA810F7DE8650BB67">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <header>Database on internationally adopted children</header>
							<clause id="HF0DA5264958C412C9EFAAE0E3CDC44F3">
                <enum>(i)</enum>
                <header>In general</header>
                <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Field Operations Directorate" entity-parent-id="7003">Associate Director</cato:entity-ref>, in conjunction with the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref>, shall establish and operate a
			 database containing data respecting children involved in intercountry
			 adoption cases who have immigrated to the United States.</text>
							</clause>
              <clause id="HA102BF0A64114CFC9C0E5CA801D5D345">
                <enum>(ii)</enum>
                <header>Information tracking</header>
                <text>Although the data available for adoptions finalized before the date of the enactment of this Act
			 will likely be incomplete, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Field Operations Directorate" entity-parent-id="7003">Associate Director</cato:entity-ref> should seek to import
			 available data on all adoptions involving children who are younger than 18
			 years of age on the date of the enactment of this Act. In operating the
			 database established under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Children in Families First Act of 2014/s:102/ss:c/p:3/sp:B/cl:i" proposed="true">clause (i)</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Field Operations Directorate" entity-parent-id="7003">Associate Director</cato:entity-ref> shall track
			 information about each such child before attaining United States
			 citizenship, including—</text>
								<subclause id="H7AD20F5946244C91BE108498F19F3395">
                  <enum>(I)</enum>
                  <text>information identifying a child and the adoptive or prospective adoptive parents, including—</text>
									<item id="HF07F1D88AFD64CA98D68F0E724D2395B">
                    <enum>(aa)</enum>
                    <text>the full name of the child in the country of origin and the full name of the child after the
			 adoption is finalized;</text>
									</item>
                  <item id="H718FB34C780B4F47A3ECE4ABFB6411BE">
                    <enum>(bb)</enum>
                    <text>the gender, date of birth, nationality, and citizenship of the child;</text>
									</item>
                  <item id="HA2CCB095917E4F47BF5DFD8F1F9652D5">
                    <enum>(cc)</enum>
                    <text>the physical address of the child at the time of the adoption; the type of visa issued to the
			 child; and</text>
									</item>
                  <item id="H1F1A8F0003504614B1B0CD27CBBD2683">
                    <enum>(dd)</enum>
                    <text>the date on which the child entered the United States;</text>
									</item>
                </subclause>
                <subclause id="HF4D6BB0872F74BF89BC2B04377B2B0FA">
                  <enum>(II)</enum>
                  <text>information on the particular adoption service provider, if any, providing services in the
			 particular case; and</text>
								</subclause>
                <subclause id="HFA8DC0CF55C84E72993CEAE4E8639595">
                  <enum>(III)</enum>
                  <text>information on immigration or citizenship status of the child.</text>
								</subclause>
              </clause>
              <clause id="H6AE5E9C3FE5A44C197D8FDC255738C52">
                <enum>(iii)</enum>
                <header>Interagency agreement</header>
                <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Field Operations Directorate" entity-parent-id="7003">Associate Director</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7003">Director</cato:entity-ref>, and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref> shall enter into an agreement
			 under which the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref> shall provide, for the database, data
			 on intercountry adoption cases concerning the adopted children, and the
			 adoption service providers.</text>
							</clause>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
      </section>
      <section id="HC43C5E2F3F1843ED866EB89A7FF5FE62">
        <enum>103.</enum>
        <header>Transfer of functions and savings provisions</header>
				<subsection id="HB3788A2ADB634EF9961D875281E891B1">
          <enum>(a)</enum>
          <header>Definitions</header>
          <text>In this section, unless otherwise provided or contextually indicated—</text>
					<paragraph id="HDE1C4E71066841E0A47A9553AF6387FD">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <text>the term <term>Federal agency</term> has the meaning given to the term <term>agency</term> under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc/5/551//1">
                <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/5/551">section 551(1)</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code</cato:entity-ref>;</text>
					</paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H20DBA7DF855242699CDA96A173E58042">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <text>the term <term>function</term> means any duty, obligation, power, authority, responsibility, right, privilege, activity, or
			 program; and</text>
					</paragraph>
          <paragraph id="HA9FB1D8F7BFE453CB78F17F19A92193C">
            <enum>(3)</enum>
            <text>the term <term>office</term> includes any office, administration, agency, institute, unit, organizational entity, or component
			 thereof.</text>
					</paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="HAC15B2B247E1436EBD1C31E8F1306C10">
          <enum>(b)</enum>
          <header>Transfer of functions</header>
          <text>There are transferred to the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Field Operations Directorate" entity-parent-id="7003">Directorate</cato:entity-ref>, all functions described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000/s:103A/ss:a" proposed="true">section 103A(a) of the
			 Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000</cato:entity-ref>, as added by <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Children in Families First Act of 2014/s:102/ss:a" proposed="true">section 102(a) of this Act</cato:entity-ref>,
			 which were exercised by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref> before the date of the
			 enactment of this Act (including all related functions of any officer or
			 employee of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Department of State</cato:entity-ref>), including functions relating to—</text>
					<paragraph id="H525677F7DAD945A6A5AA5E6D0F969D61">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <text>the accreditation of agencies and approval of persons to provide adoption services;</text>
					</paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H7B1D5F671DAC49B79B8A9B9A2C1EF6BE">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <text>the management and oversight of investigations related to the operation of such providers; and</text>
					</paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H22294F455E5442D3BF845663DEBBA9E9">
            <enum>(3)</enum>
            <text>liaison responsibilities with respect to required post-placement reports.</text>
					</paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="H577684DF2426447DA730054BC70049CB">
          <enum>(c)</enum>
          <header>Determinations of certain functions by the Office of Management and Budget</header>
          <text>If necessary, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1103">Director of the Office of Management and Budget</cato:entity-ref> shall make any determination with
			 respect to the transfer of functions under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Children in Families First Act of 2014/s:103/ss:b" proposed="true">subsection (b)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
				</subsection>
        <subsection id="H23FFF33B70A743E0B6D58E5CC8CC0509">
          <enum>(d)</enum>
          <header>Personnel provisions</header>
					<paragraph id="HEF783751B7AF462DA165A9314F1C8F75">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <header>Appointments</header>
            <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Field Operations Directorate" entity-parent-id="7003">Associate Director</cato:entity-ref> may appoint and fix the compensation of such officers and employees,
			 including investigators, attorneys, and administrative law judges, as may
			 be necessary to carry out the respective functions transferred under this
			 section. Except as otherwise provided by law, such officers and employees
			 shall be appointed in accordance with the civil service laws and their
			 compensation fixed in accordance with <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc/5">title 5, United States Code</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
					</paragraph>
          <paragraph id="HD14E65667C4C454E9B52184BEE4BD575">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <header>Experts and consultants</header>
            <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Field Operations Directorate" entity-parent-id="7003">Associate Director</cato:entity-ref> may obtain the services of experts and consultants in accordance with
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc/5/3109">
                <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/5/3109">section 3109</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code</cato:entity-ref>, and compensate such experts
			 and consultants for each day (including travel time) at rates not in
			 excess of the rate of pay for level IV of the Executive Schedule under
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc/5/5315">section 5315 of such title</cato:entity-ref>. The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Field Operations Directorate" entity-parent-id="7003">Associate Director</cato:entity-ref> may pay experts and
			 consultants who are serving away from their homes or regular place of
			 business travel expenses and per diem in lieu of subsistence at rates
			 authorized by <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc/5/5702">sections 5702</cato:entity-ref> and <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc/5/5703">5703 of such title</cato:entity-ref> for persons in
			 Government service employed intermittently.</text>
					</paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="H543F5710165B4109BDFA178E4A911F16">
          <enum>(e)</enum>
          <header>Delegation and assignment</header>
          <text>Except where otherwise expressly prohibited by law or otherwise provided under this section—</text>
					<paragraph id="HE2F9F537045A4148B1B831266B233996">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <text>the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Field Operations Directorate" entity-parent-id="7003">Associate Director</cato:entity-ref> may—</text>
						<subparagraph id="HD333EB2BF2E148908BB38758BC944A17">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>delegate any of the functions transferred to the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Field Operations Directorate" entity-parent-id="7003">Associate Director</cato:entity-ref> under this section and any
			 function transferred or granted to the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Field Operations Directorate" entity-parent-id="7003">Associate Director</cato:entity-ref> after the date
			 of the enactment of this Act to such officers and employees of the
			 Directorate as the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Field Operations Directorate" entity-parent-id="7003">Associate Director</cato:entity-ref> may designate; and</text>
						</subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="HF46363123840473B96640547B37D81C5">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>authorize successive redelegations of such functions as may be necessary or appropriate; and</text>
						</subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H1F29579DAB09425082CC2C01E0CABE96">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <text>no delegation of functions by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Field Operations Directorate" entity-parent-id="7003">Associate Director</cato:entity-ref> under this subsection or under any other
			 provision of this section shall relieve such Associate Director of
			 responsibility for the administration of such functions.</text>
					</paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="H9B5F3085D3114D3B92E39B7B158CE0E8">
          <enum>(f)</enum>
          <header>Reorganization</header>
          <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Field Operations Directorate" entity-parent-id="7003">Associate Director</cato:entity-ref> is authorized—</text>
					<paragraph id="HE2DAF41344C040208978ED10E09FB5C9">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <text>to allocate or reallocate any function transferred under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Children in Families First Act of 2014/s:103/ss:b" proposed="true">subsection (b)</cato:entity-ref> among the officers of the
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Field Operations Directorate" entity-parent-id="7003">Directorate</cato:entity-ref>; and</text>
					</paragraph>
          <paragraph id="HBCC3FBC2931D49219974AAD25A0C4D4E">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <text>to establish, consolidate, alter, or discontinue such organizational entities in the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Field Operations Directorate" entity-parent-id="7003">Directorate</cato:entity-ref> as
			 may be necessary or appropriate.</text>
					</paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="H096AEDC89150460EB01E66CE00580A42">
          <enum>(g)</enum>
          <header>Rules</header>
          <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Field Operations Directorate" entity-parent-id="7003">Associate Director</cato:entity-ref> is authorized to prescribe, in accordance with the provisions of <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc-chapter/5/5">chapters 5</cato:entity-ref>
			 and <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc-chapter/5/6">6 of title 5, United States Code</cato:entity-ref>, such rules and regulations as the
			 Associate Director determines necessary or appropriate to administer and
			 manage the functions of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Field Operations Directorate" entity-parent-id="7003">Directorate</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
				</subsection>
        <subsection id="H8AFAA1E64F5E42A2887BB54E003A3F75">
          <enum>(h)</enum>
          <header>Transfer and allocations of appropriations and personnel</header>
          <text>Except as otherwise provided under this section and subject to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc/31/1531">
              <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/31/1531">section 1531</external-xref> of title 31, United
			 States Code</cato:entity-ref>, the personnel employed in connection with, and the assets,
			 liabilities, contracts, property, records, and unexpended balances of
			 appropriations, authorizations, allocations, and other funds employed,
			 used, held, arising from, available to, or to be made available in
			 connection with the functions transferred under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Children in Families First Act of 2014/s:103/ss:b" proposed="true">subsection (b)</cato:entity-ref>, shall be
			 transferred to the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Field Operations Directorate" entity-parent-id="7003">Directorate</cato:entity-ref>. Unexpended funds transferred pursuant to
			 this subsection may only be used for the purposes for which the funds were
			 originally authorized and appropriated.</text>
				</subsection>
        <subsection id="H14839ABD429047CC97DF1CAA04C40EE6">
          <enum>(i)</enum>
          <header>Incidental transfers</header>
          <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1103">Director of the Office of Management and Budget</cato:entity-ref>—</text>
					<paragraph id="H7281484D69BD41A697E02B103C52B651">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <text>may, at such time or times as the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7003">Director</cato:entity-ref> may prescribe—</text>
						<subparagraph id="HB9C682E2FA344048A861870361CA1108">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>make such determinations as may be necessary with regard to the functions transferred under
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Children in Families First Act of 2014/s:103/ss:b" proposed="true">subsection (b)</cato:entity-ref>; and</text>
						</subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H369B09D3CF4B40CA903960CC9580E65D">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>make such additional incidental dispositions of personnel, assets, liabilities, grants, contracts,
			 property, records, and unexpended balances of appropriations,
			 authorizations, allocations, and other funds held, used, arising from,
			 available to, or to be made available in connection with such functions,
			 as may be necessary to carry out the provisions of this section; and</text>
						</subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H5571656CD1AE45B79A350866C79B468C">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <text>shall provide for—</text>
						<subparagraph id="H0FFC6222DC9242A1A8245D8FEC9FB900">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>the termination of the affairs of all entities terminated under this section; and</text>
						</subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H623CEFED26F441DBB0FE152819A19495">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>such further measures and dispositions as may be necessary to carry out the purposes of this
			 section.</text>
						</subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="H2025B0BB4BEC42B6A718575A1783D528">
          <enum>(j)</enum>
          <header>Effect on personnel</header>
					<paragraph id="HFFE650E74F664557B030DB276C52963A">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <header>In general</header>
            <text>Except as otherwise provided under this section, the transfer under this section of full-time
			 personnel (except special Government employees) and part-time personnel
			 holding permanent positions shall not cause any such employee to be
			 separated or reduced in grade or compensation during the 1-year period
			 beginning on the date of such transfer.</text>
					</paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H756B24770F6A4936BC0D3C3DAEC462B0">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <header>Executive schedule positions</header>
            <text>Except as otherwise provided under this section, any person who, on the day preceding the date of
			 the enactment of this Act, held a position compensated in accordance with
			 the Executive Schedule prescribed in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc-chapter/5/53">
                <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/53">chapter 53</external-xref> of title 5, United States
			 Code</cato:entity-ref>, and who, without a break in service, is appointed in the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Field Operations Directorate" entity-parent-id="7003">Directorate</cato:entity-ref>
			 to a position having duties comparable to the duties performed immediately
			 preceding such appointment shall continue to be compensated in such new
			 position at not less than the rate provided for such previous position,
			 for the duration of the service of such person in such new position.</text>
					</paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H5FBF4FFCECFC4723A9C654C8D3BDD39C">
            <enum>(3)</enum>
            <header>Termination of certain positions</header>
            <text>All positions whose functions are transferred under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Children in Families First Act of 2014/s:103/ss:b" proposed="true">subsection (b)</cato:entity-ref> and whose incumbents have been
			 appointed by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref>, by and with the advice and consent of the
			 Senate, shall terminate on the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
					</paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="H0D2D65F405264035BF08217EF08DF15D">
          <enum>(k)</enum>
          <header>Savings provisions</header>
					<paragraph id="H810590A54B8348149683763DAB08E83F">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <header>Continuing effect of legal documents</header>
            <text>All orders, determinations, rules, regulations, permits, agreements, grants, contracts,
			 certificates, licenses, registrations, privileges, and other
			 administrative actions which—</text>
						<subparagraph id="H4596E545040B48A7B783B55958AB0C59">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>have been issued, made, granted, or allowed to become effective by the President, any Federal
			 agency or official thereof, or by a court of competent jurisdiction, in
			 the performance of functions which are transferred under this section; and</text>
						</subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H69801E0C62974A43A2964A97CA05803C">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>are in effect on the date of the enactment of this Act, or were final before such date of enactment
			 and are to become effective on or after the date of the enactment of this
			 Act,</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph">shall continue in effect according to their terms until modified, terminated, superseded, set
			 aside, or revoked in accordance with law by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Field Operations Directorate" entity-parent-id="7003">Associate
			 Director</cato:entity-ref> or other authorized official, a court of competent jurisdiction,
			 or by operation of law.</continuation-text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H8A54A38201804F55A102206A404EE609">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <header>Proceedings not affected</header>
            <text>Nothing in this section may be construed to affect any proceeding, including a notice of proposed
			 rulemaking, or any application for any license, permit, certificate, or
			 financial assistance pending before the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Department of State</cato:entity-ref> on the
			 effective date of this section, with respect to functions transferred
			 under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Children in Families First Act of 2014/s:103/ss:b" proposed="true">subsection (b)</cato:entity-ref>. Orders shall be issued in such proceedings, appeals
			 shall be taken therefrom, and payments shall be made pursuant to such
			 orders, as if this section had not been enacted. Orders issued in any such
			 proceedings shall continue in effect until modified, terminated,
			 superseded, or revoked by a duly authorized official, by a court of
			 competent jurisdiction, or by operation of law. Nothing in this paragraph
			 may be construed to prohibit the discontinuance or modification of any
			 such proceeding under the same terms and conditions and to the same extent
			 that such proceeding could have been discontinued or modified if this
			 section had not been enacted.</text>
					</paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H367855FA32E3495FA1857930E7CFA635">
            <enum>(3)</enum>
            <header>Suits not affected</header>
            <text>Nothing in this section may be construed to affect suits commenced before the date of the enactment
			 of this Act. In all such suits, proceedings shall be had, appeals taken,
			 and judgments rendered in the same manner and with the same effect as if
			 this section had not been enacted.</text>
					</paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H5D3ED41FE41D424AB3F35F3F79C33900">
            <enum>(4)</enum>
            <header>Nonabatement of actions</header>
            <text>No suit, action, or other proceeding commenced by or against the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Department of State</cato:entity-ref>, or by or
			 against any individual in the official capacity of such individual as an
			 officer of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Department of State</cato:entity-ref>, shall abate by reason of the enactment
			 of this section.</text>
					</paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H4707A3C42C70424F9152F007C921DB22">
            <enum>(5)</enum>
            <header>Administrative actions relating to promulgation of regulations</header>
            <text>Any administrative action relating to the preparation or promulgation of a regulation by the
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Department of State</cato:entity-ref> relating to a function transferred under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Children in Families First Act of 2014/s:103/ss:b" proposed="true">subsection
			 (b)</cato:entity-ref> may be continued by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Field Operations Directorate" entity-parent-id="7003">Directorate</cato:entity-ref> with the same effect as if this
			 section had not been enacted.</text>
					</paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="H155FA96DBDDB4E9C94545D96179CD42E">
          <enum>(l)</enum>
          <header>Separability</header>
          <text>If a provision of this section or its application to any person or circumstance is held invalid,
			 neither the remainder of this section nor the application of the provision
			 to other persons or circumstances shall be affected.</text>
				</subsection>
        <subsection id="H11457F2800DE45FABA6B8D5CADD22609">
          <enum>(m)</enum>
          <header>Transition</header>
          <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Field Operations Directorate" entity-parent-id="7003">Associate Director</cato:entity-ref> is authorized to utilize—</text>
					<paragraph id="H657C23547F5D431D8E474AE61B89F388">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <text>the services of such officers, employees, and other personnel of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Department of State</cato:entity-ref> with
			 respect to functions transferred to the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Field Operations Directorate" entity-parent-id="7003">Directorate</cato:entity-ref> by this section; and</text>
					</paragraph>
          <paragraph id="HE9CFCC2B971D47948A184461CBB52DBE">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <text>funds appropriated to such functions for such period of time as may reasonably be needed to
			 facilitate the orderly implementation of this section.</text>
					</paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="H3552DBE0400A4CCB946CD5B5EC90E8ED">
          <enum>(n)</enum>
          <header>References</header>
          <text>Reference in any other Federal law, Executive order, rule, regulation, or delegation of authority,
			 or any document of or relating to—</text>
					<paragraph id="HE7400CEAA36E46C89C25F3756C2B89B6">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <text>the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref> with regard to functions transferred under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Children in Families First Act of 2014/s:103/ss:b" proposed="true">subsection (b)</cato:entity-ref>, shall be deemed
			 to refer to the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Field Operations Directorate" entity-parent-id="7003">Associate Director</cato:entity-ref>; and</text>
					</paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H56FB2910FE824F5EA816012BE752FF56">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <text>the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Department of State</cato:entity-ref> with regard to functions transferred under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Children in Families First Act of 2014/s:103/ss:b" proposed="true">subsection (b)</cato:entity-ref>, shall be deemed
			 to refer to the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Field Operations Directorate" entity-parent-id="7003">Directorate</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
					</paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="H564F7F1B9F384FC9B4DC877CB6D2B843">
          <enum>(o)</enum>
          <header>Additional conforming amendments</header>
					<paragraph id="HA18F68A7FF0D44DBBC505726CFBD01A2">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <header>Recommended legislation</header>
            <text>After consultation with the appropriate committees of <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1103">Director of the Office of
			 Management and Budget</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Field Operations Directorate" entity-parent-id="7003">Associate Director</cato:entity-ref> shall prepare and submit to
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> recommended legislation containing technical and conforming
			 amendments to reflect the changes made by this section.</text>
					</paragraph>
          <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H155E2C05917C45E3AD9376AE2DB9EC1C">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <header>Submission to congress</header>
            <text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Field Operations Directorate" entity-parent-id="7003">Associate Director</cato:entity-ref> shall
			 submit the recommended legislation referred to under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Children in Families First Act of 2014/s:103/ss:o/p:1" proposed="true">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref> to
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
					</paragraph>
        </subsection>
      </section>
      <section id="H82B8CC03437A458BA38C5547581B466E">
        <enum>104.</enum>
        <header>Responsibilities of U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services for adoption-related case processing</header>
				<subsection id="H32E18117C6E64E9C9FADE8643B623C14">
          <enum>(a)</enum>
          <header>In general</header>
          <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7000">Secretary of Homeland Security</cato:entity-ref>, acting through the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7003">Director of U.S. Citizenship and Immigration
			 Services</cato:entity-ref>—</text>
					<paragraph id="HB152409950F04A10852B4F5FEF49F33C">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <text>shall be responsible for processing and case-specific decisionmaking on all intercountry adoption
			 cases (up to the point of application for an immigrant visa on behalf of
			 the adopted child), including cases being processed pursuant to the
			 <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000">Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/14901">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/42/14901/etseq">42 U.S.C. 14901 et seq</cato:entity-ref>.</external-xref>)</cato:entity> and <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Intercountry Adoption Universal Accreditation Act of 2012/s:2">section 2
			 of the Intercountry Adoption Universal Accreditation Act of 2012</cato:entity-ref> (<cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/42/14925">42
			 U.S.C. 14925</cato:entity-ref>)</cato:entity>;</text>
					</paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H8CAAAC552E5A4CA8A0354F2B3712ACDE">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <text>shall ensure that all intercountry adoption suitability and eligibility determinations of
			 prospective adoptive parents required under <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Immigration and Nationality Act/s:101/ss:b/p:1/sp:F">subparagraph (F)</cato:entity-ref> or <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Immigration and Nationality Act/s:101/ss:b/p:1/sp:G">(G) of
			 section 101(b)(1) of the Immigration and Nationality Act</cato:entity-ref> (<cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/8/1101/b/1">8 U.S.C.
			 1101(b)(1)</cato:entity-ref>)</cato:entity> are made in accordance with standard criteria that comply with
			 the Hague Adoption Convention so that any such determination justifies a
			 Convention adoption or a non-Convention adoption;</text>
					</paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H35551DCFA8B14F20A93C98A5FFD66215">
            <enum>(3)</enum>
            <text>to the maximum extent possible, and to the extent permitted by the country in which the child
			 resides, shall ensure that all non-Convention adoption cases undergo
			 preprocessing, including—</text>
						<subparagraph id="HD5809877F3FA49F5AE2180390F8BA28D">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>the filing of a petition and the review of a child’s eligibility to immigrate to the United States
			 before the adoption or grant of legal custody (for purposes of emigration
			 and adoption in the United States) of that child is completed in the
			 country of origin; and</text>
						</subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H8D9BCC87846245D1A928C6E56B15C6E8">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>the completion of all necessary and relevant investigations associated with the petition before the
			 country of origin finalizes the adoption or grants legal custody for
			 purposes of emigration and adoption in the United States;</text>
						</subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="HD3F65D8A617B4E79A3869069E4B44A3C">
            <enum>(4)</enum>
            <text>except as provided in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Children in Families First Act of 2014/s:104/ss:a/p:5" proposed="true">paragraph (5)</cato:entity-ref>, shall be responsible for all case processing steps in
			 Convention and non-Convention adoption petitions on behalf of children
			 whom United States parents propose to immigrate to the United States
			 (except for the processing of immigrant visas), including processing of
			 all necessary Hague Adoption Convention certifications and the final
			 adjudication of the immigration petitions; and</text>
					</paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H65C1EA01E98A4DF5A6CBDABFE59EC964">
            <enum>(5)</enum>
            <text>may delegate the responsibility for completing certain elements of case adjudication to the
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref> if the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7000">Department of Homeland Security</cato:entity-ref>—</text>
						<subparagraph id="H2B0B43749092474D9B4D29981DB3A4FD">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>cannot adequately complete such elements due to the need for physical presence in the country of
			 origin or other processing-related circumstances; and</text>
						</subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="HE05DB9FC7FF84CFFAE7F192C03A3F83B">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>defines and monitors the parameters for the elements delegated to the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref> and
			 retains final decisionmaking authority.</text>
						</subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="HFE9E2B0A6C654EE895BB97D731185FFB">
          <enum>(b)</enum>
          <header>Foreign adoption decrees</header>
					<paragraph id="HEDFEB8E5333C4D4D963169AFAC8749E5">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <header>Convention countries</header>
            <text>The 2-year legal custody and joint residence requirements set forth in <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Immigration and Nationality Act/s:101/ss:b/p:1/sp:E">section 101(b)(1)(E) of the
			 Immigration and Nationality Act</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/8/1101/b/1/E">8 U.S.C. 1101(b)(1)(E)</cato:entity-ref>
              </external-xref>)</cato:entity> shall not apply
			 if the documentation submitted on behalf of a child includes—</text>
						<subparagraph id="HD3F8B988EB6E40B1931A59B5D40189A6">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>an adoption decree issued by a competent authority (as such term is used in the Hague Adoption
			 Convention) of the child’s country of origin and evidence that the
			 adoption was granted in compliance with the Hague Adoption Convention; or</text>
						</subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="HAEA06EB2C3694B5497692DF7BA1654E5">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>a custody or guardianship decree issued by the competent authority of the child’s country of origin
			 to the adoptive parents, and a final adoption decree, verifying that the
			 adoption of the child was later finalized outside the United States by the
			 adoptive parents, in addition to evidence that the custody or guardianship
			 was granted in compliance with the Hague Adoption Convention.</text>
						</subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="HE1DA08ADCA1940D6B594FAE8CC62F288">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <header>Substantial compliance with Hague adoption convention</header>
            <text>
              <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Children in Families First Act of 2014/s:104/ss:b/p:1" proposed="true">Paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref> shall not apply unless—</text>
						<subparagraph id="H58EA51726A9D419B9D4EC3AE6AF3CCE2">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>on the date on which the underlying adoption, custody, or guardianship decree was issued by the
			 child’s country of origin—</text>
							<clause id="H5B828BB35C74457AB70FCAD9F0F9E5E7">
                <enum>(i)</enum>
                <text>that country’s adoption procedures complied with the requirements of the Hague Adoption Convention
			 (as determined by the United States central authority); and</text>
							</clause>
              <clause id="HC6EFCD450D384E3BAA00135AE1B57DE1">
                <enum>(ii)</enum>
                <text>the competent authority of the country of origin certified that the adoption is consistent with
			 Article 23 of the Hague Adoption Convention; and</text>
							</clause>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="HB087773794F840188B231D8A41F05C50">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>the adoption was a Convention adoption that was completed between 2 Convention countries other than
			 the United States.</text>
						</subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="HCF57C57A655540FAB657688E8FFD190A">
            <enum>(3)</enum>
            <header>Non-convention countries</header>
            <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7000">Secretary of Homeland Security</cato:entity-ref> may accept the filing of petitions on behalf of children living
			 in non-Convention countries in the absence of a final adoption decree.</text>
					</paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="H4EB241FB17E14B8F83B8D8C33C829F8D">
          <enum>(c)</enum>
          <header>Cooperation with foreign governments</header>
          <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7000">Secretary of Homeland Security</cato:entity-ref> may interact directly with the central authority of a Convention
			 country or a competent authority of a non-Convention country, as
			 appropriate—</text>
					<paragraph id="H01FD25B36B514278AFB8A8DEB93405EC">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <text>to facilitate the processing of intercountry adoption cases, including making habitual residence
			 determinations relevant to children and prospective adoptive parents in
			 adoption proceedings; and</text>
					</paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H7D94506CF709485C851654394CC2EA26">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <text>to negotiate, in coordination with the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Department of State</cato:entity-ref>, and to implement bilateral agreements
			 with respect to intercountry adoptions.</text>
					</paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="HB02FAD1A540F4DCFA85B82E706761646">
          <enum>(d)</enum>
          <header>Amendments to the Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000</header>
					<paragraph id="HCDC07E57CB8C47B594E61F8FB3617989">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <header>Transfer of responsibilities to the Secretary of Homeland Security
            </header>
            <text>The <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000">Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/14901">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/42/14901/etseq">42 U.S.C. 14901 et seq</cato:entity-ref>.</external-xref>)</cato:entity> is amended—</text>
						<subparagraph id="HF0F6B4A8631E4B5E931FBFBEA91CA595">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>by striking <quote>Attorney General</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>
                  <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7000">Secretary of Homeland Security</cato:entity-ref>
                </quote>; and</text>
						</subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H0CE436DD53D649EEB8D142DF97CDE4AF">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>in the heading of <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000/s:103">section 103</cato:entity-ref>, by striking <quote>
                  <header-in-text level="section" style="OLC">Attorney General</header-in-text>
                </quote> and inserting <quote>
                  <header-in-text level="section" style="OLC">
                    <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7000">Secretary of Homeland Security</cato:entity-ref>
                  </header-in-text>
                </quote>.</text>
						</subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="HA66694DF06E04CF49373F27DF9CB348D">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <header>Hague convention certificates</header>
            <text>
              <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000/s:301">Section 301 of such Act</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/14931">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/42/14931">42 U.S.C. 14931</cato:entity-ref>
              </external-xref>)</cato:entity> is amended—</text>
						<subparagraph id="H5A6EC045C2584650B03D8310A96EAFF3">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000/s:301/ss:a">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref>—</text>
							<clause id="HED9FAAE6C7A349F58D66FEA03D336A15">
                <enum>(i)</enum>
                <text>in the subsection heading, by striking <quote>
                    <header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">Secretary of State</header-in-text>
                  </quote> and inserting <quote>
                    <header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">
                      <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7000">Secretary of Homeland Security</cato:entity-ref>
                    </header-in-text>
                  </quote>; and</text>
							</clause>
              <clause id="H5C60F226576F496C89079374986C6202">
                <enum>(ii)</enum>
                <text>in the heading to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000/s:301/ss:a/p:1">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref>, by striking <quote>
                    <header-in-text level="paragraph" style="OLC">Secretary of State</header-in-text>
                  </quote> and inserting <quote>
                    <header-in-text level="paragraph" style="OLC">
                      <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7000">Secretary of Homeland Security</cato:entity-ref>
                    </header-in-text>
                  </quote>; and</text>
							</clause>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H6E864180B7B54CD883FBF4BE1F320967">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>by striking <quote>Secretary of State</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>
                  <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7000">Secretary of Homeland Security</cato:entity-ref>
                </quote>.</text>
						</subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="HB861241E56D44DA39B136865B437F604">
            <enum>(3)</enum>
            <header>Clerical amendment</header>
            <text>The table of contents of such Act is amended by striking the item relating to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000/s:103">section 103</cato:entity-ref> and
			 inserting the following:</text>
						<quoted-block id="H8B831213419A47E6BA1EB12AEAF3FE43" style="OLC">
							<toc>
								<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 103. Responsibilities of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7000">Secretary of Homeland Security</cato:entity-ref>.</toc-entry>
              </toc>
              <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
            </quoted-block>
					</paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="HF482A36E7C2842A291417E1985F750D7">
          <enum>(e)</enum>
          <header>Definition of child</header>
          <text>
            <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Immigration and Nationality Act/s:101/ss:b/p:1">Section 101(b)(1) of the Immigration and Nationality Act</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/8/1101/b/1">8 U.S.C. 1101(b)(1)</cato:entity-ref>
            </external-xref>)</cato:entity> is amended—</text>
					<paragraph id="HDCDA639C58B448CC800D0F548D2B4111">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <text>in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Immigration and Nationality Act/s:101/ss:b/p:1/sp:E">subparagraph (E)</cato:entity-ref>—</text>
						<subparagraph id="HDC4462C84D4E4CA98CB7B80F8B609C52">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Immigration and Nationality Act/s:101/ss:b/p:1/sp:E/cl:i">clause (i)</cato:entity-ref>, by striking <quote>(i) a child adopted while under the age of sixteen years</quote> and inserting <quote>a child adopted while younger than 18 years of age</quote>; and</text>
						</subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H7396DEF1E03A4B04BA9364EEC423DBE2">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>by striking <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Immigration and Nationality Act/s:101/ss:b/p:1/sp:E/cl:ii">clause (ii)</cato:entity-ref>;</text>
						</subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H1ACB17D50F5040BDA57893343E3C3DB5">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <text>by amending <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Immigration and Nationality Act/s:101/ss:b/p:1/sp:F">subparagraph (F)</cato:entity-ref> to read as follows:</text>
						<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3E32F24A6A3D4B13A19851AD17DF2CB2" style="OLC">
							<subparagraph id="H06B479C2C4B9451B8FF21B45B8344957">
                <enum>(F)</enum>
								<clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H63956088936C4FFB9A99C1FBAE80E928">
                  <enum>(i)</enum>
                  <text>a child, younger than 18 years of age at the time a petition is filed on the child's behalf to
			 accord a classification as an immediate relative under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Immigration and Nationality Act/s:201/ss:b">section 201(b)</cato:entity-ref>, and
			 who has been adopted in a foreign state that is not a party to the
			 Convention on Protection of Children and Co-operation in Respect of
			 Intercountry Adoption, done at The Hague May 29, 1993, or who is
			 emigrating from such a foreign state to be adopted in the United States by
			 a United States citizen and spouse jointly, or by an unmarried United
			 States citizen who is at least 25 years of age, if—</text>
									<subclause id="H9735665AA73C4AAC908D8E4D51BCD68B" indent="up1">
                    <enum>(I)</enum>
                    <text>the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7000">Secretary of Homeland Security</cato:entity-ref> is satisfied that proper care will be furnished the child if
			 admitted to the United States;</text>
									</subclause>
                  <subclause id="H2B15A13C34C44207A2695EF6765C8180" indent="up1">
                    <enum>(II)</enum>
                    <text>the child’s natural parents (or parent, in the case of a child who has 1 sole or surviving parent),
			 or other persons or institutions that retain legal custody of the child,
			 have freely given their written irrevocable consent to the termination of
			 their legal relationship with the child, and to the child's emigration and
			 adoption;</text>
									</subclause>
                  <subclause id="HD960BCD5845C451BBB88A1A5B9E23701" indent="up1">
                    <enum>(III)</enum>
                    <text>the child has a living parent or parents who has or have relinquished, or will relinquish, the
			 child voluntarily for the purposes of intercountry adoption, and the
			 parent or parents are incapable of providing proper care for the child;</text>
									</subclause>
                  <subclause id="H8E7CB57A15FD4BB2AF9A09E97AF8F79A" indent="up1">
                    <enum>(IV)</enum>
                    <text>the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7000">Secretary of Homeland Security</cato:entity-ref>, after considering whether there is a petition pending to confer
			 immigrant status on one or both natural parents, is satisfied that the
			 purpose of the adoption is to form a bona fide parent-child relationship,
			 and the parent-child relationship of the child and the natural parents has
			 been terminated; and</text>
									</subclause>
                  <subclause id="HDDC38325F02D4A888AE1AEC9A9DC542C" indent="up1">
                    <enum>(V)</enum>
                    <text>in the case of a child who has not been adopted—</text>
										<item id="H97F3ADF89BED4F4A806E9DFF62610670">
                      <enum>(aa)</enum>
                      <text>the competent authority of the foreign state has approved the child’s emigration to the United
			 States for the purpose of adoption by the prospective adoptive parent or
			 parents; and</text>
										</item>
                    <item id="HFD206A6E9BE5473A925E546420C3F581">
                      <enum>(bb)</enum>
                      <text>the prospective adoptive parent or parents has or have complied with any preadoption requirements
			 of the child’s proposed residence; and</text>
										</item>
                  </subclause>
                </clause>
                <clause id="H12BCB7CA5E4B41559116C6AC91DBA6EB" indent="up1">
                  <enum>(ii)</enum>
                  <text>except that no natural parent or prior adoptive parent of any such child shall thereafter, by
			 virtue of such parentage, be accorded any right, privilege, or status
			 under this chapter;</text>
                </clause>
              </subparagraph>
              <after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block>
            </quoted-block>
					</paragraph>
          <paragraph id="HD77FDDE1196F406EA68A21120CCDD043">
            <enum>(3)</enum>
            <text>in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Immigration and Nationality Act/s:101/ss:b/p:1/sp:G">subparagraph (G)</cato:entity-ref>—</text>
						<subparagraph id="H56BF128E0CD548A7B3197864A9E6BAC5">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>in the matter preceding <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Immigration and Nationality Act/s:101/ss:b/p:1/sp:G/cl:i">clause (i)</cato:entity-ref>, by striking <quote>16</quote> and inserting <quote>18</quote>;</text>
						</subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H4DFB91A9C2364A58912F4CC4F1B21ED2">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Immigration and Nationality Act/s:101/ss:b/p:1/sp:G/cl:i">clause (i)</cato:entity-ref>—</text>
							<clause id="H796EE4BE0FD34D009FAE94624A4C865E">
                <enum>(i)</enum>
                <text>in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Immigration and Nationality Act/s:101/ss:b/p:1/sp:G/cl:i/scl:II">subclause (II)</cato:entity-ref>, by striking <quote>because of the death or disappearance of, abandonment or desertion by, the other parent</quote>; and</text>
							</clause>
              <clause id="H12D93BCD834A4141B39034DF6B04A8FA">
                <enum>(ii)</enum>
                <text>in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Immigration and Nationality Act/s:101/ss:b/p:1/sp:G/cl:i/scl:III">subclause (III)</cato:entity-ref>, by striking <quote>two living natural parents, the natural parents are</quote> and inserting <quote>a living parent or parents, who have relinquished or will relinquish the child voluntarily for the
			 purposes of intercountry adoption, the parent or parents are</quote>;</text>
							</clause>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="HD28D3032907A4FB4B0D1C30A9C78002C">
              <enum>(C)</enum>
              <text>in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Immigration and Nationality Act/s:101/ss:b/p:1/sp:G/cl:ii">clause (ii)</cato:entity-ref>, by striking <quote>; or</quote> and inserting a period; and</text>
						</subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H6BEC90B5E43A4AC6852447C0E41B70A6">
              <enum>(D)</enum>
              <text>by striking <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Immigration and Nationality Act/s:101/ss:b/p:1/sp:G/cl:iii">clause (iii)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
						</subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="H596768A7691142FD979F7058EBCAFBB2">
          <enum>(f)</enum>
          <header>Relative adoptions; waiver authority</header>
          <text>
            <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Intercountry Adoption Act/s:502">Section 502 of the Intercountry Adoption Act</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/14952">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/42/14952">42 U.S.C. 14952</cato:entity-ref>
            </external-xref>)</cato:entity> is amended to read as follows:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6A970E9CEBBB4ABBA06F5F8C9F4A497B" style="OLC">
						<subsection id="HA891D5F16CEE4BEEA93DFC986CB81284">
              <enum>(a)</enum>
              <header>Authority To establish alternative procedures for adoption of children by relatives</header>
              <text>Not later than 2 years after the date of the enactment of the <short-title>
                  <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Children in Families First Act of 2014" proposed="true">Children in Families First Act of 2014</cato:entity-ref>
                </short-title>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7000">Secretary of Homeland Security</cato:entity-ref> shall establish, by regulation, alternative procedures for
			 completing the intercountry adoption of children by United States citizens
			 who are related to such children by blood, marriage, or adoption.</text>
						</subsection>
            <subsection id="H89218C38B36C4711B24878F908A064F1">
              <enum>(b)</enum>
              <header>Waiver authority</header>
              <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7000">Secretary of Homeland Security</cato:entity-ref>, acting through the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7003">Director of U.S. Citizenship and Immigration
			 Services</cato:entity-ref>, may waive, on a case-by-case basis, applicable requirements for
			 meeting the definition of a child under <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
                  <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Immigration and Nationality Act/s:101/ss:b/p:1/sp:E">subparagraph (E)</cato:entity-ref>, <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Immigration and Nationality Act/s:101/ss:b/p:1/sp:F">(F)</cato:entity-ref>, or <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Immigration and Nationality Act/s:101/ss:b/p:1/sp:G">(G) of
			 section 101(b)(1) of the Immigration and Nationality Act</cato:entity-ref> (<cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/8/1101/b/1">8 U.S.C.
			 1101(b)(1)</cato:entity-ref>)</cato:entity>, or regulations issued with respect to such definitions, in
			 the interests of justice or to prevent or respond to the threat of grave
			 physical or emotional harm to the child if the petitioner establishes
			 that—</text>
							<paragraph id="H20B3DD0022D74664BD8BC03160CC326A">
                <enum>(1)</enum>
                <text>the child substantially complies with the requirements under one of such subparagraphs; and</text>
							</paragraph>
              <paragraph id="HD2E429447E184D268B400A4A4CB705B4">
                <enum>(2)</enum>
                <text>such a waiver would be in the child’s best interests.</text>
              </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
          </quoted-block>
				</subsection>
        <subsection id="H358F5D7285A649D2A26C5B5A466E070A">
          <enum>(g)</enum>
          <header>Determination of applicability of the Hague Adoption Convention in certain cases</header>
          <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7000">Secretary of Homeland Security</cato:entity-ref>, acting through the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7003">Director of U.S. Citizenship and Immigration
			 Services</cato:entity-ref>, may determine, on a case-by-case basis, that a specific
			 intercountry adoption case may proceed as a non-Convention adoption if—</text>
					<paragraph id="H9EBF1C4479DE4F4A8D8B1FD8F4C58E6F">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <text>the child’s country of origin or habitual residence is a Convention country;</text>
					</paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H28FB45191BEB46A49DE74E3353BE314A">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <text>the central authority of the child’s country of origin or habitual residence has issued, or will
			 issue, an adoption decree which that country considers to be legal and
			 valid under that country’s laws to the United States adoptive or
			 prospective adoptive parents; and</text>
					</paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H8B75BD83814F482398742FADF0164BF6">
            <enum>(3)</enum>
            <text>the central authority of the child’s country of origin or habitual residence has informed the
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7000">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> or the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7003">Director</cato:entity-ref> that it does not consider the specific case to
			 fall within the scope of the Hague Adoption Convention.</text>
					</paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="H59E4DF6AEB074C389FA49958C648D9E2">
          <enum>(h)</enum>
          <header>Special use of parole authority</header>
					<paragraph id="H42C909A13B184441B19BA970381493BC">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <header>In general</header>
            <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7000">Secretary of Homeland Security</cato:entity-ref>, acting through the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7003">Director of U.S. Citizenship and Immigration
			 Services</cato:entity-ref>, may grant parole to a child if the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7000">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> or the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7003">Director</cato:entity-ref>
			 determines that—</text>
						<subparagraph id="H994F0BF04F1D459B83506AF5425F3872">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>the child’s circumstances indicate that immediate unification with the parties seeking parole is in
			 the child’s best interests;</text>
						</subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H63B651B51C2942AAAE703E678B460E17">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>waiting to complete other, more time consuming immigration processing could be significantly
			 harmful to the child’s well-being;</text>
						</subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H21983434E36F49C38155EE1288A9E754">
              <enum>(C)</enum>
              <text>the party or parties seeking parole on behalf of the child—</text>
							<clause id="H435F614199E44E6AA98B0A610266C6CF">
                <enum>(i)</enum>
                <text>have a pre-existing legal relationship with the child, as evidenced by an adoption decree or a
			 custody order; or</text>
							</clause>
              <clause id="HF5ED69FF13504BFDBAD16341AC83A525">
                <enum>(ii)</enum>
                <text>demonstrate a pre-existing relationship with the child and an intent to establish a legal
			 relationship with the child, which may be evidenced by—</text>
								<subclause id="H70A8AC9ACC684027B4113B0717FB8E0C">
                  <enum>(I)</enum>
                  <text>a familial relationship with the child;</text>
								</subclause>
                <subclause id="H1224D23A90524ACC95704E1BC7E0EE7A">
                  <enum>(II)</enum>
                  <text>a close personal relationship with the child, such as—</text>
									<item id="HD4A4043FFA9D46E0843BE15BE3B81FE4">
                    <enum>(aa)</enum>
                    <text>being matched with the child for an international adoption by an adoption service provider or the
			 competent authority of the child’s country of origin; or</text>
									</item>
                  <item id="H11DE1EC150224C6E9340EACDFF3C95BE">
                    <enum>(bb)</enum>
                    <text>documentation showing that the child’s parents, if deceased or otherwise incapacitated and unable
			 to provide proper care for the child, intended for the parties seeking
			 parole to take custody of the child; or</text>
									</item>
                </subclause>
                <subclause id="H966437C4AFE7482B8B5A0299D247C087">
                  <enum>(III)</enum>
                  <text>the filing of adoption-related applications or petitions related to the adoption of the child; and</text>
								</subclause>
              </clause>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H20294957867B41C8B6D1DDB880FF2EE3">
              <enum>(D)</enum>
              <text>the child will receive proper care in the United States by the party or parties who seek parole on
			 behalf of the child, based on a review of the suitability of the party or
			 parties, which may include background check or completion of a home study
			 conducted by a competent authority.</text>
						</subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H51FA321C6BE24B7CB074660CA5CFA4FE">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <header>Meeting the 2-year periods for the purposes of filing an immediate relative petition on behalf of
			 an adopted child</header>
            <text>If a child is granted parole under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Children in Families First Act of 2014/s:104/ss:h/p:1" proposed="true">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref>, is subsequently adopted by the parties who sought
			 parole, and such parties seek permanent immigration status for the child
			 under <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Immigration and Nationality Act/s:101/ss:b/p:1/sp:E">section 101(b)(1)(E) of the Immigration and Nationality Act</cato:entity-ref> (<cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/8/1101/b/1/E">8
			 U.S.C. 1101(b)(1)(E)</cato:entity-ref>)</cato:entity>—</text>
						<subparagraph id="H1790E93471D64F59B5BDF139C6396FA1">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>the 2-year period for legal custody of the child shall begin to accrue on the effective date of a
			 grant of custody in the child’s country of origin or habitual residence or
			 in the United States;</text>
						</subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H21BA69E7AD1F4AD280D1A1C597EF9868">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>the 2-year period for physical custody of the child shall begin to accrue on the date on which the
			 party or parties seeking parole for the child begin joint residence with
			 the child, in the child’s country of origin or habitual residence or in
			 the United States; and</text>
						</subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="HB34A4968FA694B2CB449B086FDBAF7D7">
              <enum>(C)</enum>
              <text>the 2-year periods of joint residence and legal custody may accrue within or outside the United
			 States.</text>
						</subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBEE41713A9754D76B5699C40881BFD78">
          <enum>(i)</enum>
          <header>Rulemaking</header>
          <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7000">Secretary of Homeland Security</cato:entity-ref>, in consultation with the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref> and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7003">Director of
			 U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services</cato:entity-ref>, shall issue regulations to
			 carry out this section and the amendments made by this section.</text>
				</subsection>
      </section>
    </title>
    <title id="H6E63448E42594AC6916CB846353BA435">
      <enum>II</enum>
      <header>Annual reporting</header>
			<section id="H1AEE7791A82E484CBEAA2EDE1631CA9C">
        <enum>201.</enum>
        <header>Annual report on children living without families</header>
				<subsection id="H6299455A0DED412787AAE8706787565C">
          <enum>(a)</enum>
          <header>In general</header>
          <text>Not later than September 30, 2014, and annually thereafter, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref>, in consultation
			 with the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7200">Director of the United States Agency for International
			 Development</cato:entity-ref> and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref>, shall submit a report to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">
              <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="committee" entity-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate</cato:entity-ref>
            </committee-name> and the <committee-name committee-id="">
              <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="committee" entity-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives</cato:entity-ref>
            </committee-name> that—</text>
					<paragraph id="H40A9CDE777E045B9941F8066B241D115">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <text>identifies the number of children living without families; and</text>
					</paragraph>
          <paragraph id="HB862C4311C85425D9383D1E9992E789A">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <text>describes the degree to which the various family permanence solutions are being utilized.</text>
					</paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="H75C0CDB6C52D46839E35367158B00CD2">
          <enum>(b)</enum>
          <header>Content</header>
          <text>The report required under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Children in Families First Act of 2014/s:201/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref> shall include—</text>
					<paragraph id="HDB46C7039982479D83CD35D183BB1045">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <text>a description of the world’s unparented children, including—</text>
						<subparagraph id="H831C363707584EC8B38C5D09F11247B9">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>a description and quantitative analysis of the world’s unparented children by country, identifying
			 the nationality of the children physically present in each country and
			 distinguishing among children who are citizens of the country, noncitizen
			 children lawfully present in the country, and noncitizen children
			 unlawfully in the country, irrespective of a child’s particular
			 immigration status; and</text>
						</subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H3FA455F02F49405F9C1D549FDCC0A748">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>available data about such children broken into detailed categories and including—</text>
							<clause id="H6B130C312A124FD9A3BEF5150DC88DD7">
                <enum>(i)</enum>
                <text>information on their nationality, age, gender, and status;</text>
							</clause>
              <clause id="HDFEC6522EE404A4697658485412C0F7F">
                <enum>(ii)</enum>
                <text>whether they have a living parent or parents and the status of those parents;</text>
							</clause>
              <clause id="H6474A53BC2FD4C32AB92C63731D26E8F">
                <enum>(iii)</enum>
                <text>whether the unparented children are considered abandoned, separated, relinquished, or have some
			 other status;</text>
							</clause>
              <clause id="HBFCB560A410547F2AE45135541CC765A">
                <enum>(iv)</enum>
                <text>whether they are institutionalized or homeless;</text>
							</clause>
              <clause id="H069395DECEE647CCAD8CED8DE25F750B">
                <enum>(v)</enum>
                <text>information on how they are documented, including through birth registries, orphanage registries,
			 United Nations High Commissioner for Refugees registration, or identity
			 cards; and</text>
							</clause>
              <clause id="HD1710908C2B24CEB8476CF90BB98D85B">
                <enum>(vi)</enum>
                <text>an assessment of their living conditions based on indicators such as crude mortality rate,
			 malnutrition rate, or other similar indicators;</text>
							</clause>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="HCE9A6B57C613487EBCB74FDACFB39194">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <text>a review of the previous fiscal year’s programming in support of appropriate, protective, and
			 permanent family care solutions, including project descriptions for each
			 project by country, goals of each project, amount awarded for each
			 project, and evaluation of outcomes during the fiscal year;</text>
					</paragraph>
          <paragraph id="HCDFAE7845FFA4C179ED24058008F60DD">
            <enum>(3)</enum>
            <text>an action plan covering proposed programming and activities for the next fiscal year in support of
			 family permanency solutions, including goals for each country in which
			 programming will occur, proposed allocations of resources by country,
			 types of projects proposed by country, amounts of awards proposed for each
			 project, and desired outcomes for each country;</text>
					</paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H55A908E1DB7B42FCB0303BA1D9E9FEB4">
            <enum>(4)</enum>
            <text>a review of trends over the last five years, including changes in the numbers and locations of
			 unparented children and the reasons for the changes, such as new refugee
			 arrivals, growing numbers of children abandoned at birth, and decreases in
			 number of children in institutions;</text>
					</paragraph>
          <paragraph id="HBBA7E07DBAE249638930C31F3010B122">
            <enum>(5)</enum>
            <text>an overall analysis of highest priority situations of concern for unparented children, including
			 analysis of whether the children are in a location that provides a
			 cooperative environment for assistance programming and intercountry
			 adoptions;</text>
					</paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H5D04A3A97E494C3C99C8CAE12658D80F">
            <enum>(6)</enum>
            <text>a description of how intercountry adoption and refugee resettlement for unparented refugee children
			 has played a role in each country over the last 10 years and the current
			 status of such programs, including analysis of the situation with respect
			 to the Hague Adoption Convention and how the Convention has affected
			 intercountry adoptions from the country;</text>
					</paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H170B07BB2718406FB90082BDE9BA50E3">
            <enum>(7)</enum>
            <text>aggregate reporting on intercountry adoptions to the United States, distinguishing between
			 Convention adoptions and non-Convention adoptions and including—</text>
						<subparagraph id="H7193F8EEBE474C82AD15EAF0FFEE8146">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>the total number of intercountry adoptions involving immigration to the United States by year over
			 the past 10 years and projected data for the next fiscal year,
			 distinguishing between Convention and non-Convention adoptions, including
			 aggregate data on the country from which each child emigrated, the State
			 of residence of the adoptive parents, and the country in which the
			 adoption was finalized;</text>
						</subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H4EC52396A8254E8BA7E1267F74BBD043">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>the number of intercountry adoptions involving emigration from the United States, regardless of
			 whether the adoption occurred under the Convention and distinguishing
			 between Convention and non-Convention adoptions, including the country to
			 which each child immigrated and the State from which each child emigrated;</text>
						</subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="HE09C3C90C2F147E7960E1D42E3F11278">
              <enum>(C)</enum>
              <text>the average time required for completion of the immigration portion of intercountry adoptions,
			 distinguishing between Convention and non-Convention adoptions, calculated
			 as the time between filing of the initial immigration-related adoption
			 petition on behalf of a child and the approval of that child’s immigrant
			 visa; and</text>
						</subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H166FCB9B3F6B405788EB917C4B61EFB7">
              <enum>(D)</enum>
              <text>the range of adoption fees charged in connection with intercountry adoptions involving immigration
			 to the United States and the median of such fees; and</text>
						</subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="HCC6AAAC80E3349F5953E4B34FD56D81F">
            <enum>(8)</enum>
            <text>such additional information as may be requested by members of the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">
                <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="committee" entity-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate</cato:entity-ref>
              </committee-name> and the <committee-name committee-id="">
                <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="committee" entity-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives</cato:entity-ref>
              </committee-name>.</text>
					</paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="H035332320B23445983527D039E8C6A0F">
          <enum>(c)</enum>
          <header>Consultations</header>
          <text>To the extent possible, designated representatives of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> should meet with members of the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">
              <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="committee" entity-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate</cato:entity-ref>
            </committee-name> and the <committee-name committee-id="">
              <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="committee" entity-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives</cato:entity-ref>
            </committee-name> not later than 2 weeks before the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref> submits the report required under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Children in Families First Act of 2014/s:201/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection
			 (a)</cato:entity-ref> to discuss the information described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Children in Families First Act of 2014/s:201/ss:b" proposed="true">subsection (b)</cato:entity-ref>. The substance
			 of such consultations should be printed in the Congressional Record.</text>
				</subsection>
        <subsection id="H94C9013B6F4F47A09BD1D3990C796FC6">
          <enum>(d)</enum>
          <header>Repeal</header>
          <text>
            <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Intercountry Adoption Act/s:104">Section 104 of the Intercountry Adoption Act</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/14914">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/42/14914">42 U.S.C. 14914</cato:entity-ref>
            </external-xref>)</cato:entity> is repealed.</text>
				</subsection>
      </section>
      <section id="HF4E0304CA08A470CBF111410514A618F">
        <enum>202.</enum>
        <header>Country reports regarding severe forms of trafficking</header>
        <text display-inline="no-display-inline">
          <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Foreign Assistance Act of 1961/s:502B/ss:h/p:1/sp:B">Section 502B(h)(1)(B) of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2304">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/22/2304/h/1/B">22 U.S.C. 2304(h)(1)(B)</cato:entity-ref>
          </external-xref>)</cato:entity> is amended by
			 adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9FB742D2006C4EAA9B7A371E4F92CF48" style="OLC">
					<clause id="H6AE3E046A6DA45AD8483190AD04215F8" indent="up1">
            <enum>(x)</enum>
            <text>What steps the government of that country has taken to reduce the number of children living outside
			 of family care.</text>
					</clause>
          <clause id="HEC17AAB5696E4B3180B4548AADB21046" indent="up1">
            <enum>(xi)</enum>
            <text>What steps the government of that country has taken to reduce the number of children abused,
			 neglected, or exploited.</text>
          </clause>
          <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
        </quoted-block>
			</section>
    </title>
    <title id="H78E3385E1105473E8B1C836C4F814E77">
      <enum>III</enum>
      <header>Promotion of a comprehensive approach for children in adversity</header>
			<section id="H4910A5C66B7843DF92B7BEF7F63E10B6">
        <enum>301.</enum>
        <header>Establishment of a USAID Center for Excellence for Children in Adversity</header>
				<subsection id="H6EE09FF421F54595AFB488ED0DC34C7E">
          <enum>(a)</enum>
          <header>Center for Excellence for Children in Adversity</header>
					<paragraph id="H3D2443D021304D2594EACA27985C4C35">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <header>In general</header>
            <text>There is established within the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7200">United States Agency for International Development</cato:entity-ref> a <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Center of Excellence on Children in Adversity" entity-parent-id="7200" proposed="true">Center of
			 Excellence on Children in Adversity</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
					</paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H4BBA983A95C241FBBE25E1C10CC192EE">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <header>Coordinator</header>
            <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Center of Excellence on Children in Adversity" entity-parent-id="7200" proposed="true">Center for Excellence</cato:entity-ref> shall be headed by the Children in Adversity Coordinator, who shall be
			 appointed by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref>, in consultation with the
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7200">Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
					</paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H012879F5BB9D4FD0B038BD611DD2AC81">
            <enum>(3)</enum>
            <header>Objectives</header>
            <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Center of Excellence on Children in Adversity" entity-parent-id="7200" proposed="true">Center of Excellence on Children in Adversity</cato:entity-ref> shall work in consultation with the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Bureau of Vulnerable Children and Family Security" entity-parent-id="1900" proposed="true">Assistant
			 Secretary of the Bureau of Vulnerable Children and Family Security of the
			 Department of State</cato:entity-ref> to promote greater United States Government coherence
			 and accountability for whole-of-government assistance to children in
			 adversity and ensure that United States foreign assistance and development
			 programs are focused on the following objectives:</text>
						<subparagraph id="H0E23E8B4C2C34E2B869CEC4AD6AF2D8F">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>The sound development of children through the integration of health, nutrition, and family support.</text>
						</subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H1ACE1F56DFC944F787BDB2CC93B28730">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>Supporting and enabling families to care for children through family preservation, reunification,
			 and support of kinship care, guardianship, and domestic and intercountry
			 adoption.</text>
						</subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H5BF607DB63E7474C841F31681529FCD5">
              <enum>(C)</enum>
              <text>Facilitating the efforts of national governments and partners to prevent, respond to, and protect
			 children from violence, exploitation, abuse, and neglect.</text>
						</subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H9ECD7B8FB9A24A5794DF872A96668127">
            <enum>(4)</enum>
            <header>Authorities</header>
            <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Center of Excellence on Children in Adversity" entity-parent-id="7200" proposed="true">Children in Adversity Coordinator</cato:entity-ref>, acting through nongovernmental organizations (including
			 faith-based and community-based organizations), partner country finance,
			 health, education, social welfare, and other ministries, and relevant
			 executive branch agencies, is authorized to—</text>
						<subparagraph id="H107A6C66E53E454D82FDD141A0EE88CB">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>operate internationally to carry out the programs and activities outlined in the Action Plan for
			 Children in Adversity;</text>
						</subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="HEAFC4ABC0E014F079ED7C6DE110C6AB3">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>provide grants to, and enter into contracts and cooperative agreements with, nongovernmental
			 organizations (including faith-based organizations) to carry out this
			 section; and</text>
						</subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H9943EDC96F3E44E78D1126617012E67F">
              <enum>(C)</enum>
              <text>transfer and allocate <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7200">United States Agency for International Development</cato:entity-ref> funds that have been
			 appropriated for the purposes described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Children in Families First Act of 2014/s:301/ss:a/p:4/sp:A" proposed="true">subparagraphs (A)</cato:entity-ref> and <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Children in Families First Act of 2014/s:301/ss:a/p:4/sp:B" proposed="true">(B)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
						</subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H1528E89BD18E495B979F7F769E9A18BD">
            <enum>(5)</enum>
            <header>Functions</header>
            <text>In consultation with the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Bureau of Vulnerable Children and Family Security" entity-parent-id="1900" proposed="true">Assistant Secretary of the Bureau of Children's Affairs in the Department
			 of State</cato:entity-ref>, the Children in Adversity Coordinator shall, through the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Center of Excellence on Children in Adversity" entity-parent-id="7200" proposed="true">Center
			 of Excellence</cato:entity-ref>—</text>
						<subparagraph id="H16DC937122B243838D9FED9F14E8CCA6">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>facilitate program and policy coordination related to the goals and objectives of the Action Plan
			 for Children in Adversity among relevant executive branch agencies and
			 nongovernmental organizations by auditing, monitoring, and evaluating such
			 programs;</text>
						</subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H4EC6D490D7744EEFAFE3EE8870E78E0E">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>ensure that each relevant executive branch agency undertakes responsibility for activities related
			 primarily to those areas in which the agency has the greatest expertise,
			 technical capability, and potential for success;</text>
						</subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H4FE2462B865042679ED0F417AF76480D">
              <enum>(C)</enum>
              <text>coordinate relevant executive branch agency activities related to the Action Plan for Children in
			 Adversity;</text>
						</subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="HAA33F69AFEFE41C1AD3C60895010871D">
              <enum>(D)</enum>
              <text>establish due diligence criteria for all recipients of funds appropriated by the United States
			 Government for assistance to children in adversity; and</text>
						</subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H64521591D42141229BD61CB55AC0AEC5">
              <enum>(E)</enum>
              <text>oversee the administration of the priority country demonstration program as described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Children in Families First Act of 2014/s:301/ss:f" proposed="true">subsection
			 (f)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
						</subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="HC4F606DE8B894740A05A8A9C7AFD1BF5">
            <enum>(6)</enum>
            <header>Assistance</header>
            <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> is authorized to provide assistance, including through international,
			 nongovernmental, or faith-based organizations, for programs in developing
			 countries—</text>
						<subparagraph id="H3810FD5C12AC4D9A80D3FF4EF9507610">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>to increase the percentage of children achieving age-appropriate growth and developmental
			 milestones;</text>
						</subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H1B2A4C16472F467AABAF0BCF60D5F3D1">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>to increase the percentage of children under 5 years of age demonstrating secure attachment with a
			 primary caregiver;</text>
						</subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H02AC950CC01B4B23AE275543CCB30ECC">
              <enum>(C)</enum>
              <text>to integrate health, nutrition, developmental protections, and caregiving support for vulnerable
			 children and their families;</text>
						</subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H2B26C57D943D4BA181C8EFB95853D8F4">
              <enum>(D)</enum>
              <text>to increase the percentage of children living within appropriate, permanent, safe, and protective
			 family care, through family preservation and reunification, and through
			 kinship care, guardianship, and domestic and intercountry adoption, and to
			 reduce the percentage of children living in institutions;</text>
						</subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="HCFBE9D539AC9458086A87B7DC1BC24B3">
              <enum>(E)</enum>
              <text>to increase the percentage of families providing adequate nutrition, education opportunities, care,
			 and protection for their children;</text>
						</subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="HBBAB1155579F462BABE300F0D71E2578">
              <enum>(F)</enum>
              <text>to reduce the percentage of children who experience violence, exploitation, abuse, and neglect;</text>
						</subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H9FAC3EC822B945DBB9F33B14F8A7A8EA">
              <enum>(G)</enum>
              <text>to increase the percentage of children who receive appropriate care and protection after
			 experiencing violence, exploitation, abuse, or neglect;</text>
						</subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H3A6FFA92C8F64C819DCA2214124F2385">
              <enum>(H)</enum>
              <text>to increase public awareness that violence, exploitation, abuse, or neglect of children as
			 unacceptable;</text>
						</subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H8669801DE97A43C18BE2312FBC94D3E5">
              <enum>(I)</enum>
              <text>to increase the percentage of countries that ratify and implement relevant conventions or formally
			 adopt internationally recognized principles, standards, and procedural
			 safeguards to protect children from violence, exploitation, abuse, and
			 neglect;</text>
						</subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="HEC777BA0F2B843ACB414A065014D91DB">
              <enum>(J)</enum>
              <text>to increase the percentage of children who have legal documentation and birth registration;</text>
						</subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H3053B31169DA4BAD929CCB5EA696D841">
              <enum>(K)</enum>
              <text>to increase the number of laws, policies, and practices in partner states that promote and
			 strengthen child welfare and protection at household, community, and
			 national levels is increased;</text>
						</subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H85E5D9523EB546318EC28E50B801A497">
              <enum>(L)</enum>
              <text>to increase national and local human resource capacity for child welfare and protection;</text>
						</subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H3B9A07D0506E4FE384720820240FA92D">
              <enum>(M)</enum>
              <text>to increase the number of national and community systems effectively monitoring child welfare and
			 protection concerns, programs, and outcomes;</text>
						</subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H027E547B4FB841629AA2BC59C79F2372">
              <enum>(N)</enum>
              <text>to encourage and assist in the collection of data related to children outside of family care;</text>
						</subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="HDF7831958E124500A5F6F8A2F960EEEF">
              <enum>(O)</enum>
              <text>to increase the number of prevalence studies that measure and track trends in children’s exposure
			 to violence, exploitation, abuse, and neglect;</text>
						</subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H7152D9442C7746DEA4A6E450FB17D9FF">
              <enum>(P)</enum>
              <text>to increase the number of published outcome/impact evaluations on interventions to assist children
			 outside of family care or minimize exposure to violence, exploitation,
			 abuse, and neglect that can be generalized to larger target groups;</text>
						</subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="HE5905AC12B3F412EA887D14BB4513B7C">
              <enum>(Q)</enum>
              <text>to increase the number of national governments and universities leading rigorous data collection,
			 research, and monitoring and evaluation studies related to child welfare
			 and protection; and</text>
						</subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H428118CDC6AA47ECA55FA7DE84C48C5D">
              <enum>(R)</enum>
              <text>to increase the number of United States Government-supported interventions for children in
			 adversity designed using data from rigorous research methodologies.</text>
						</subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="HA2BD63258732457582F1BA94350FF40B">
          <enum>(b)</enum>
          <header>Monitoring and evaluation</header>
					<paragraph id="H5640732144074533BF0A9EC0A85DB277">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <header>Establishment of system</header>
            <text>To maximize the sustainable development impact of assistance authorized under this section, and
			 pursuant to the primary objective of the Action Plan for Children in
			 Adversity, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> shall establish a monitoring and evaluation
			 system to measure the effectiveness of United States assistance to
			 children in adversity.</text>
					</paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H989B315347BE4A77A52894183049A6F3">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <header>Requirements</header>
            <text>The monitoring and evaluation system shall—</text>
						<subparagraph id="H3E6A2AE4964844828A516306F2E3B382">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>be aligned with the objectives and outcomes outlined by the Action Plan for Children in Adversity;
			 and</text>
						</subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H91EA3DE4C65E4A519B40E67C730F738E">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>provide a basis for recommendations for adjustments to the assistance provided under this part.</text>
						</subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="H4CE89EF02D76499290A7B3C83C9E598A">
          <enum>(c)</enum>
          <header>Priority Country Demonstration Program</header>
					<paragraph id="H542CEDE00A5A45AEA2AAAD99BB5F8794">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <header>In general</header>
            <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7200">Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development</cato:entity-ref>, in consultation with
			 the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref>, shall establish and carry out a priority country
			 demonstration program implementing the Action Plan for Children in
			 Adversity over a period of 5 years in at least 6 countries.</text>
					</paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H117B7DF3C84E4B79AE601A0C9818F9FD">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <header>Purposes</header>
            <text>The purposes of the programs established under sub<cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Children in Families First Act of 2014/s:301/ss:c/p:1" proposed="true">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref> shall be—</text>
						<subparagraph id="HA483372B818245F3AF1BCE0B13BD57CA">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>to demonstrate how research-based policies and programs to achieve the core objectives of the
			 Action Plan for Children in Adversity can be successfully implemented on a
			 national level;</text>
						</subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H87DD38AFA7F544A2964A4A317B530BD1">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>to establish model programs that, once tested for efficacy, will be available for replication on a
			 global basis;</text>
						</subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H4DD471314FCC4F878091B5164248F718">
              <enum>(C)</enum>
              <text>to identify a comprehensive series of interventions which result in meeting the outcomes and
			 objectives of the Action Plan for Children in Adversity; and</text>
						</subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H1637619006C3454ABCDEB60664DA6B69">
              <enum>(D)</enum>
              <text>to determine which in-country factors advance or negate the successful achievement of the outcomes
			 and objectives of the action plan.</text>
						</subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="HFE0DEE999978460B9381C48CC9B732D2">
            <enum>(3)</enum>
            <header>Criteria for selection of countries</header>
            <text>The criteria for selection of countries shall include—</text>
						<subparagraph id="H32800D1404BF40ED99EE523D67C41C87">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>magnitude and severity of the problems to be addressed;</text>
						</subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H6FA3DAB79D22425695DD199F16AFC5C3">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>partner country interest in participation in a comprehensive implementation of all 3 goals of the
			 Action Plan for Children in Adversity, including, with respect to the
			 second objective (Families First), expressed willingness to support the
			 full complement of permanence solutions (including family preservation,
			 reunification, kinship care, guardianship, and domestic and intercountry
			 adoption), and commitments to support and allow monitoring and evaluation,
			 as well as transparent reporting;</text>
						</subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H1E8A8D6022A84C60803EB99C6B4DC272">
              <enum>(C)</enum>
              <text>potential to leverage bilateral, multilateral, and foundation investments;</text>
						</subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="HB1C81FCDB51544C5BE0258DA08544DC7">
              <enum>(D)</enum>
              <text>potential to leverage other United States development investments;</text>
						</subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="HB69D14D110E74DD79192CD9DF784254B">
              <enum>(E)</enum>
              <text>regional diversity to maximize learning opportunities; and</text>
						</subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H9264C732E42E4B96AE8CFFBFA01963E0">
              <enum>(F)</enum>
              <text>level of economic development, with a focus on low- and middle-income countries.</text>
						</subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="H543F6E1582CA4DCAA1981B74DFC955A0">
          <enum>(d)</enum>
          <header>Repeals</header>
					<paragraph id="HDEDA3BB71F2741ECA76A1C22F680C6CE">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <header>Assistance to orphans and other vulnerable children</header>
            <text>
              <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Foreign Assistance Act of 1961/s:135">Section 135 of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2152f">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/22/2152f">22 U.S.C. 2152f</cato:entity-ref>
              </external-xref>)</cato:entity> is repealed.</text>
					</paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H5881F3B2804B4D3FAE67A13F3DC93F28">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <header>Annual report</header>
            <text>
              <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Assistance for Orphans and Other Vulnerable Children in Developing Countries Act of 2005/s:5">Section 5 of the Assistance for Orphans and Other Vulnerable Children in Developing Countries Act
			 of 2005</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2152g">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/22/2152g">22 U.S.C. 2152g</cato:entity-ref>
              </external-xref>)</cato:entity> is hereby repealed.</text>
					</paragraph>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </title>
    <title id="H97792D8DE5AA40679472ABE397DF9FD0">
      <enum>IV</enum>
      <header>Funding and effective dates</header>
			<section id="H5C823F24B44547E4A4DB43DC3A3C28DA">
        <enum>401.</enum>
        <header>Funding</header>
				<subsection id="H12CB175E50A9405FAE8D6445A963B615">
          <enum>(a)</enum>
          <header>Prohibition on new appropriations</header>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No additional funds are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this Act and the amendments made
			 by this Act. This Act and such amendments shall be carried out using
			 amounts otherwise available for such purposes, including unobligated
			 balances of funds made available to carry out activities under the <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Foreign Assistance Act of 1961">Foreign
			 Assistance Act of 1961</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2151">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/22/2151/etseq">22 U.S.C. 2151 et seq</cato:entity-ref>.</external-xref>)</cato:entity>.</text>
				</subsection>
        <subsection id="H9D808040AB34400E96266AD4994AFA58">
          <enum>(b)</enum>
          <header>Limitations on use of funds</header>
					<paragraph id="H02C02EFE78534DDBA15C7D946455FC0D">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <header>United Nations</header>
            <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No funds obligated in accordance with this Act may be awarded to the United Nations or any of its
			 subsidiaries.</text>
					</paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H9AE725FB0B8446C18E35978B31CE1883">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <header>Administrative expenses</header>
            <text>Not more than two percent of the amounts described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Children in Families First Act of 2014/s:401/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref> may be used for administrative
			 expenses.</text>
					</paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="H9950A88E69094763972A4A9134622C2D">
          <enum>(c)</enum>
          <header>Focus of assistance</header>
          <text>Assistance provided under this Act—</text>
					<paragraph id="H71E96D6173D5473FB17DBEFB1A97CCCB">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <text>shall focus primarily on promoting international child welfare, as set forth in this Act, for all
			 children in adversity; and</text>
					</paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H5713190796DB452C8A833A9F21867127">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <text>may be provided on such terms and conditions as the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> determines appropriate.</text>
					</paragraph>
        </subsection>
      </section>
      <section id="H1DF413AFB66648E99A4A8B61728FBE33">
        <enum>402.</enum>
        <header>Effective dates</header>
				<subsection id="HFB8AFBD133CE4BCC85F29C7ECEE05B37">
          <enum>(a)</enum>
          <header>Effective upon enactment</header>
          <text>
            <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Children in Families First Act of 2014/s:104" proposed="true">Sections 104</cato:entity-ref> and <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Children in Families First Act of 2014/s:202" proposed="true">202</cato:entity-ref> and <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Children in Families First Act of 2014/t:III" proposed="true">title III</cato:entity-ref> and <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Children in Families First Act of 2014/t:IV" proposed="true">IV</cato:entity-ref> shall take effect on the date of the enactment of this
			 Act.</text>
				</subsection>
        <subsection id="HDE0C0BA4D5A3427A9348B91C704F0EA7">
          <enum>(b)</enum>
          <header>Delayed effective date</header>
          <text>
            <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Children in Families First Act of 2014/s:101" proposed="true">Sections 101</cato:entity-ref>, <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Children in Families First Act of 2014/s:102" proposed="true">102</cato:entity-ref>, <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Children in Families First Act of 2014/s:103" proposed="true">103</cato:entity-ref>, and <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Children in Families First Act of 2014/s:201" proposed="true">201</cato:entity-ref> shall take effect on the date that is 1 year after the date of the
			 enactment of this Act.</text>
				</subsection>
      </section>
    </title>
  </legis-body>
</bill>
</doc>