<doc>
  <docmeta id="113hr3545ih">
    <bill congress="113" type="hr" number="3545" version="ih"/>
    <revision size="23945" annotations="0" status="complete" id="4" commit-time="2013-11-27T15:42:25Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113hr3545ih/4.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H18BACC21E5324BFFB33E157AF57F9989" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata>
<dublinCore>
<dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">113 HR 3545 IH: Collegiate Student Athlete Protection Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">2013-11-20</dc:date>
<dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>113th CONGRESS</congress> <session>1st Session</session> 
<legis-num>H. R. 3545</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20131120">November 20, 2013</action-date> 
<action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="C001097">Mr. Cárdenas</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="C000984">Mr. Cummings</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000053">Mr. Rangel</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000577">Mr. Ryan of Ohio</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001068">Mr. Huffman</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001143">Ms. McCollum</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and the Workforce</committee-name>
      </action-desc> 
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To protect the academic futures of collegiate student athletes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H9A16C1CA69274CB2A2AA1DF7D2064298" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H0D60FE423EC64282943A9438270D6503" section-type="section-one">
      <enum>1.</enum>
      <header>Short title; findings; sense of Congress</header> 
<subsection id="HD4826627E3CB40C4A46F2C3B797866AE">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Short title</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote>
            <short-title>Collegiate Student Athlete Protection Act</short-title>
          </quote>.</text>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="HE37FCE56AF2C4C04950131CE8AAF884D">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Findings</header>
        <text>
          <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> finds as follows:</text> 
<paragraph id="HB6A11C810CE548B2BD96DC6DDECA2F9D">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>Institutions of higher education that have athletic programs that offer athletically related student aid collectively generate billions of dollars annually from contracts for media rights, and the revenue from such contracts would not exist without the efforts of student athletes.</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H79F472E67A914D2A846717112CFBB7BD">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>Providing adequate health and safety protection for student athletes can help prevent serious injury and death.</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H55BA9368CCF64F17BC963A88810B148B">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <text>Current and former student athletes are often left to pay for medical expenses incurred from injuries suffered while participating in intercollegiate athletics.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="HF5154B729FB9408EB43746D0319EB494">
        <enum>(c)</enum>
        <header>Sense of congress</header>
        <text>It is the sense of <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> that—</text> 
<paragraph id="H436C9F139CB64685839D545CDD395A83">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>institutions of higher education exist to further educate, and to provide an opportunity to acquire a degree to, all students who attend such institutions;</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDFC4F481457049FC9A19915D32C6BEC6">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>institutions of higher education should ensure that a sports-related injury does not hinder the opportunity of a student athlete to graduate from the institution of higher education the student athlete attends at the time of such injury;</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H369ED3D9434646AD8817D0E900E51EF6">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <text>institutions of higher education should make graduation of all student athletes a priority, regardless of the on-field performance of the student athletes;</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1D14ED96DC6A407A98EA3BBA88C13A63">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
          <text>institutions of higher education should provide student athletes with the same due process protections afforded to students who do not participate in athletics;</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA87998627F6846378993B75D601EFB96">
          <enum>(5)</enum>
          <text>acknowledging the bodily risks taken by the student athletes, institutions of higher education should ensure that student athletes who otherwise could not afford proper health insurance are provided such insurance to pay for sports-related injuries; and</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9079B6D6A4C947F78952E827C89ED612">
          <enum>(6)</enum>
          <text>due to the record level of revenues that athletic programs provide for institutions of higher education, such institutions have the responsibility to provide student athletes with the highest level of education, and to provide effective efforts to ensure that student athletes attain higher education degrees from such institutions.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
    </section> 
<section id="HFE5B6C4F6F3940958CD3436ED1074510">
      <enum>2.</enum>
      <header>Program participation agreements</header> 
<subsection id="HB11E9DE7621E4DB29233ADEC2FBFCBE5">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>New requirement for programs of assistance</header>
        <text>
          <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Higher Education Act of 1965/s:487/ss:a">Section 487(a) of the Higher Education Act of 1965</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1094">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/20/1094/a">20 U.S.C. 1094(a)</cato:entity-ref>
          </external-xref>)</cato:entity> is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA2396B0E0DBB4FBC8734AA4BF4145B73" style="OLC"> 
<paragraph id="H3845CB1395A148BAA3C305761859B463">
            <enum>(30)</enum> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HE9462BF2F8F945FDBF61A158EC26163F">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>In the case of an institution that has an athletic program and that annually receives $10,000,000 or more in income derived from media rights (as calculated in accordance with <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Higher Education Act of 1965/s:47/ss:a/p:30/sp:B" proposed="true">subparagraph (B)</cato:entity-ref>) for the athletic program of the institution, the institution will comply with the requirements under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Higher Education Act of 1965/s:487/ss:k" proposed="true">subsection (k)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
            </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB590D1607A6D4B7B93797DA4255F9755" indent="up1">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>For the purposes of this paragraph, an institution of higher education shall calculate the total amount of income the institution derives annually from media rights by adding—</text> 
<clause id="H9BA6F5020B164B95B80F999268496DAD">
                <enum>(i)</enum>
                <text>annual income derived from any contract for media rights signed with any media entity by the institution, determined by averaging the income derived from the contract annually over the lifetime of the contract;</text>
              </clause> 
<clause id="H87F58999AD094F8DA299B5F251D8BB5F">
                <enum>(ii)</enum>
                <text>disbursements to the institution as a member institution of an athletic conference, representing member shares of the media rights of such conference; and</text>
              </clause> 
<clause id="H8A5166FE373D45A282090B335AB28432">
                <enum>(iii)</enum>
                <text>disbursements to the institution as a participant in an event that is hosted by an entity that—</text> 
<subclause id="H14EBC2515018467E8B264D10F2AEA96B">
                  <enum>(I)</enum>
                  <text>hosts intercollegiate sporting events; and</text>
                </subclause> 
<subclause id="HEC45D254D49F46199FECB1FDCA4A9F4B">
                  <enum>(II)</enum>
                  <text>sells broadcast or media access to that event.</text>
                </subclause>
              </clause>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
        </quoted-block>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="HFCC153E829CB42AF91D5235B07F59AFD">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Athletic program requirements</header>
        <text>
          <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Higher Education Act of 1965/s:487">Section 487 of the Higher Education Act of 1965</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1094">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/20/1094">20 U.S.C. 1094</cato:entity-ref>
          </external-xref>)</cato:entity> is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0869C8F027644D20BACB5842FBB793E7" style="OLC"> 
<subsection id="HD47F3B5D5EC944F1A42F52E69DA2253E">
            <enum>(k)</enum>
            <header>Athletic program requirements</header> 
<paragraph id="HCD93353245BD4738B658D2163592CBEC">
              <enum>(1)</enum>
              <header>Definitions</header>
              <text>For the purposes of this subsection and <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Higher Education Act of 1965/s:487/ss:a/p:30" proposed="true">subsection (a)(30)</cato:entity-ref>, the following definitions shall apply:</text> 
<subparagraph id="H6F6E3A77DC5345EC9068350611834553">
                <enum>(A)</enum>
                <header>Athletic association</header>
                <text>The term <term>athletic association</term> means an organization that is not an institution of higher education and—</text> 
<clause id="HF259481B7F9E4D0E8DC6D53760CEABBD">
                  <enum>(i)</enum>
                  <text>that is responsible for governing athletic programs at multiple institutions of higher education; or</text>
                </clause> 
<clause id="H057E4CA01C6A40CBA87E4D7672EDA090">
                  <enum>(ii)</enum>
                  <text>the primary purpose of which is to host intercollegiate sporting events and sell broadcast or media access to such events.</text>
                </clause>
              </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H38E24030C12142EEA31959A10D76155B">
                <enum>(B)</enum>
                <header>Athletic program</header>
                <text>The term <term>athletic program</term> means an intercollegiate athletic program of an institution of higher education.</text>
              </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H60C5A058C2F440F298FAC5397690329A">
                <enum>(C)</enum>
                <header>Athletically related student aid</header>
                <text>The term <term>athletically related student aid</term> shall have the meaning given such term in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Higher Education Act of 1965/s:485/ss:e">section 485(e)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
              </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HDC12B62763254A23BE723745BA16D0C5">
                <enum>(D)</enum>
                <header>Graduation success rate</header>
                <text>The term <term>graduation success rate</term>—</text> 
<clause id="H31FBF58C31B44F80AC1998913963A4C1">
                  <enum>(i)</enum>
                  <text>means the percentage of student athletes who graduate from an institution of higher education not later than 6 years after initial enrollment at such institution, including students who transfer to such institution from another institution, but excluding students who transfer out of such institution who are in good academic standing and, in accordance with the rules of the athletic association governing such athletic program, have not exhausted their eligibility to participate in such program; and</text>
                </clause> 
<clause id="HA4342B9A2948493BAE46B5AD20005DA8">
                  <enum>(ii)</enum>
                  <text>shall be calculated using the data available for the 4 most recent academic years in the exact manner as the rate is calculated under the rules of the National Collegiate Athletic Association on the date of enactment of the <short-title>
                      <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Collegiate Student Athlete Protection Act">Collegiate Student Athlete Protection Act</cato:entity-ref>
                    </short-title>.</text>
                </clause>
              </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H00CEA27AC75247E4803213CCA70E18A1">
                <enum>(E)</enum>
                <header>Health care professional</header>
                <text>The term <term>health care professional</term> means—</text> 
<clause id="H04789721486E45BE82ADE211F32FA593">
                  <enum>(i)</enum>
                  <text>a physician (including a medical doctor or doctor of osteopathic medicine); or</text>
                </clause> 
<clause id="H131A595A386A4AD1AB4B2BE466414FC1">
                  <enum>(ii)</enum>
                  <text>an athletic trainer—</text> 
<subclause id="H6B8DA5E757DD4A23BCE2FB090429F9A5">
                    <enum>(I)</enum>
                    <text>who is registered, licensed, certified, or otherwise statutorily recognized by the State to provide treatment; and</text>
                  </subclause> 
<subclause id="H6CF886EC37C24020AF12CB429227B562">
                    <enum>(II)</enum>
                    <text>whose scope of practice and experience includes the diagnosis and management of traumatic brain injury.</text>
                  </subclause>
                </clause>
              </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H0DF985159E9B4DC896D0BDEE8331B405">
                <enum>(F)</enum>
                <header>Institution of higher education</header>
                <text>The term <term>institution of higher education</term> has the meaning given the term in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Higher Education Act of 1965/s:102">section 102</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
              </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H05952DCCCB2A4AA9819E5A03B386A443">
                <enum>(G)</enum>
                <header>Media rights</header>
                <text>The term <term>media rights</term> means contractual rights granted by an institution of higher education or an athletic association to a television network, in exchange for monetary payments to the institution or association, to provide media coverage of the institution’s athletic program.</text>
              </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF14FF36221C14B59BDA6035F4FF7409E">
                <enum>(H)</enum>
                <header>Student athlete</header>
                <text>The term <term>student athlete</term> means a student enrolled at an institution of higher education who participates in an athletic program.</text>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC66C4FBC4DC542A09D4B18E00927FC0E">
              <enum>(2)</enum>
              <header>Requirements</header>
              <text>To comply with this subsection for the purposes of <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Higher Education Act of 1965/s:487/ss:a/p:30" proposed="true">subsection (a)(30)</cato:entity-ref>, an athletic program of an institution of higher education described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Higher Education Act of 1965/s:487/ss:a/p:30" proposed="true">subsection (a)(30)</cato:entity-ref> shall meet the following requirements:</text> 
<subparagraph id="HA5F0609DD90343D48E4B6A18B5316C40">
                <enum>(A)</enum>
                <header>Completion of academic program after loss of athletic scholarship</header> 
<clause id="H646A8E4F173C499EB614A3E4FF86B98B">
                  <enum>(i)</enum>
                  <header>Loss due to injury</header> 
<subclause id="HB2AE240B6A7041BE8B13EDD7752DD09C">
                    <enum>(I)</enum>
                    <header>In general</header>
                    <text>Each student athlete who has received or contracted to receive athletically related student aid from an institution of higher education for participation in an athletic program and who subsequently becomes ineligible for such aid for all or part of an academic year due to an injury or illness resulting from the athlete's participation in the athletic program shall, upon a determination by a physician selected by the institution and a physician that is not affiliated with any institution, that the student athlete is medically ineligible to participate in such program, be provided with institutional student aid for the period described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Higher Education Act of 1965/s:487/ss:k/p:2/sp:A/cl:i/scl:II" proposed="true">subclause (II)</cato:entity-ref> in an amount equivalent to the amount the student would have received in athletically related student aid for such academic year (or part thereof) if the student had not suffered such injury or illness. The student shall also receive continued academic supports, including tutoring, at the same level received prior to being deemed medically ineligible, for the entire period that the student receives institutional student aid.</text>
                  </subclause> 
<subclause id="H074BEFF0DF444F1889DBA3410AFB1141">
                    <enum>(II)</enum>
                    <header>Period of aid</header>
                    <text>The institution of higher education shall provide institutional student aid required under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Higher Education Act of 1965/s:487/ss:k/p:2/sp:A/cl:i/scl:I" proposed="true">subclause (I)</cato:entity-ref> for a period that, combined with the total duration of time the student previously received athletically related student aid, is equal to 5 academic years, or until the student athlete completes the athlete's undergraduate degree, whichever time period is shorter. The institution may, at its discretion, provide institutional student aid for an additional period.</text>
                  </subclause> 
<subclause id="H3E092EF9A20448E68830364550C0757F">
                    <enum>(III)</enum>
                    <header>Leave of absence</header>
                    <text>In the case of a student athlete who takes a leave of absence from an institution of higher education due to an injury or illness resulting from the athlete's participation in an athletic program, the duration of such leave of absence shall not be counted as part of the period of required institutional student aid due to the student under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Higher Education Act of 1965/s:487/ss:k/p:2/sp:A/cl:i/scl:II" proposed="true">subclause (II)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
                  </subclause>
                </clause> 
<clause id="H6B5F8165C9EA44979A44001AC6B62D7F">
                  <enum>(ii)</enum>
                  <header>Loss due to exhausted eligibility</header> 
<subclause id="H0499805379704414ACA3848AF66B2D95">
                    <enum>(I)</enum>
                    <header>In general</header>
                    <text>Except as provided in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Higher Education Act of 1965/s:487/ss:k/p:2/sp:A/cl:ii/scl:III" proposed="true">subclause (III)</cato:entity-ref>, each student athlete who has received athletically related student aid from an institution of higher education for participation in an athletic program, and who is maintaining academic standing consistent with the requirements for graduation, but who, in accordance with the rules of the athletic association governing such athletic program, has exhausted the athlete's athletic eligibility to participate in such program before the student has completed an undergraduate degree shall be provided with institutional student aid for the period described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Higher Education Act of 1965/s:487/ss:k/p:2/sp:A/cl:ii/scl:II" proposed="true">subclause (II)</cato:entity-ref> in an amount equivalent to the amount the student would have received in athletically related student aid if the student’s athletic eligibility were not exhausted.</text>
                  </subclause> 
<subclause id="H70DC292F7AC54B44AFD7E1D9ED033295">
                    <enum>(II)</enum>
                    <header>Period of aid</header>
                    <text>The institution shall provide institutional student aid required under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Higher Education Act of 1965/s:487/ss:k/p:2/sp:A/cl:ii/scl:I" proposed="true">subclause (I)</cato:entity-ref> for a period of 1 year, or until the student athlete completes an undergraduate degree, whichever time period is shorter.</text>
                  </subclause> 
<subclause id="H46B8BFF635C4498D84B5B0308C3CC055">
                    <enum>(III)</enum>
                    <header>Exception</header>
                    <text>An institution of higher education shall not be required to provide institutional student aid to a student athlete in accordance with <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Higher Education Act of 1965/s:487/ss:k/p:2/sp:A/cl:ii/scl:I" proposed="true">subclause (I)</cato:entity-ref> if such student athlete received athletically related student aid from the institution for participation in a team sport with a graduation success rate for such team that is 70 percent or higher.</text>
                  </subclause>
                </clause> 
<clause id="HFBBBCF9F7D244F02AD16181BB2BC2EEE">
                  <enum>(iii)</enum>
                  <header>Involuntary loss for any reason other than for cause</header> 
<subclause id="H954DCB8B7E2243E2B3D42917C7FD54D6">
                    <enum>(I)</enum>
                    <header>In general</header>
                    <text>A student athlete who has received athletically related student aid from an institution of higher education for participation in an athletic program and who is maintaining academic standing consistent with the requirements for graduation, but who will not receive such aid for all or part of an academic year because the student was involuntarily dismissed from participation in such athletic program shall be provided with institutional student aid in an amount equivalent to the amount the student would have received in athletically related student aid for such academic year (or part thereof) if the student had not been dismissed.</text>
                  </subclause> 
<subclause id="H9B58FCB5621443B980C9067063A26E54">
                    <enum>(II)</enum>
                    <header>Period of aid</header>
                    <text>The institution shall provide institutional student aid required under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Higher Education Act of 1965/s:487/ss:k/p:2/sp:A/cl:iii/scl:I" proposed="true">subclause (I)</cato:entity-ref> for a period that, combined with the total duration of time the student previously received athletically related student aid, is equal to 5 academic years, or until the student athlete completes the athlete's undergraduate degree, whichever is time period shorter. The institution may, at its discretion, provide institutional student aid for an additional period.</text>
                  </subclause>
                </clause> 
<clause id="HB3DF259E61E24A9FB3052E7270B751C7">
                  <enum>(iv)</enum>
                  <header>Loss for cause</header> 
<subclause id="H7FFFA5B5A89F4F708A2B2A39403BD2B1">
                    <enum>(I)</enum>
                    <header>In general</header>
                    <text>Notwithstanding <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Higher Education Act of 1965/s:487/ss:k/p:2/sp:A/cl:i..iii" proposed="true">clauses (i) through (iii)</cato:entity-ref>, a student athlete who has received athletically related student aid from an institution of higher education for participation in an athletic program shall not be eligible for institutional student aid required under this paragraph if the student is dismissed from participation in such program or otherwise denied such aid for cause, except that a student athlete may appeal the loss of athletically related student aid to the institution or an athletic association of which the institution is a member, as appropriate.</text>
                  </subclause> 
<subclause id="H9FB2E00319C94CC58D5DDE42B46B5740">
                    <enum>(II)</enum>
                    <header>For cause</header>
                    <text>In this clause, the term <term>for cause</term> means that the student was found by the institution of higher education to have violated academic or disciplinary standards of the institution.</text>
                  </subclause>
                </clause>
              </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H89F00D5121B3401CB257E2A6AC6037CA">
                <enum>(B)</enum>
                <header>Mandatory workshop</header>
                <text>At the beginning of each academic year, each first-year and third-year student athlete shall be required to attend and complete an <quote>Athletics Participation Readiness</quote> workshop conducted by the institution of higher education. Such workshop shall include—</text> 
<clause commented="no" id="H4089D19C2F104A628EB40E0FA5E53676">
                  <enum>(i)</enum>
                  <text>information about the long-term dangers of concussions and head injuries that shall be administered by a health care professional and include recent data from the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7523">Centers for Disease Control and Prevention</cato:entity-ref>;</text>
                </clause> 
<clause commented="no" id="H85EB9637198E42129C9ED8A769355EBB">
                  <enum>(ii)</enum>
                  <text>information concerning financial aid and debt management;</text>
                </clause> 
<clause commented="no" id="HE155F39114A14D6F825DB6D8BF6B21E1">
                  <enum>(iii)</enum>
                  <text>a recommended budget for student athletes for the academic year, based on the institution’s cost of attendance for such academic year, that accounts for whether the student athlete receives athletically related student aid that covers all or part of such cost, and whether the student lives on or off campus;</text>
                </clause> 
<clause commented="no" id="H567CA1476DEF4FE7BDE2EDCD1433CBBB">
                  <enum>(iv)</enum>
                  <text>information on time management skills necessary for success as a student athlete;</text>
                </clause> 
<clause commented="no" id="HD241086EB81B45EB9B336B051C12D238">
                  <enum>(v)</enum>
                  <text>academic resources available on campus, including tutoring, career development, and career search resources; and</text>
                </clause> 
<clause commented="no" id="H5CD0E4C5F10240D9BAD23BB8C297DD27">
                  <enum>(vi)</enum>
                  <text>an explanation of the institution’s responsibilities and obligations to the student athletes with respect to scholarship renewal, medical insurance, and medical payments for injury and illness resulting from participation in an athletic program.</text>
                </clause>
              </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9331A14CDFF04A50AB10235C308D2405">
                <enum>(C)</enum>
                <header>Disciplinary actions</header>
                <text>A student athlete who faces loss or reduction of athletically related student aid for a violation of a disciplinary standard of the institution of higher education shall be provided the opportunity for a formal administrative hearing, not less than 1 appeal, and any other due process procedure the Secretary determines by regulation to be necessary.</text>
              </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H55362CCC61BC455C8213AEB2CB356075">
                <enum>(D)</enum>
                <header>Transfer requests</header>
                <text>Each request by a student athlete submitted to the institution of higher education for a transfer to another institution of higher education shall be granted or denied by the institution at which the student is enrolled not later than 7 business days after the date on which such request is submitted to such institution.</text>
              </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE374F98F95174B69993EAB12CB9A45B6">
                <enum>(E)</enum>
                <header>Health care costs</header> 
<clause id="H5DF9E7BE2D274E2DAC63AC83E6E2ACB7">
                  <enum>(i)</enum>
                  <header>Pell eligible students</header>
                  <text>Except as provided in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Higher Education Act of 1965/s:487/ss:k/p:2/sp:E/cl:iv" proposed="true">clause (iv)</cato:entity-ref>, each student athlete who is eligible to receive a Federal Pell Grant under subpart 1 of part A, shall be provided with institutional aid, paid to the student directly or to the insurer of such student on the student’s behalf, in an amount sufficient to cover—</text> 
<subclause id="H61135FF4986B4867B0B24F885DAD4C82">
                    <enum>(I)</enum>
                    <text>during the period of the student’s participation in an athletic program of the institution—</text> 
<item id="HA1408A8525804309B0E1ABB5A2A31515">
                      <enum>(aa)</enum>
                      <text>the premium applicable to the insurance plan in which the student is enrolled;</text>
                    </item> 
<item id="HAB16D50C0C1E4C05B118D80CE0C08706">
                      <enum>(bb)</enum>
                      <text>any deductible applicable to such plan; and</text>
                    </item> 
<item id="H77DD237A1DF14E3E801CA2BB1236C687">
                      <enum>(cc)</enum>
                      <text>any other cost-sharing or other out-of-pocket expenses of the student with respect to such plan, including co-payments; and</text>
                    </item>
                  </subclause> 
<subclause id="HDD042BDC5D1942AC9C1BB0ECD0920496">
                    <enum>(II)</enum>
                    <text>in the case in which the student suffers an injury or illness resulting from the student’s participation in an athletic program of the institution—</text> 
<item id="H208F748EFC9E49709EDB242543300093">
                      <enum>(aa)</enum>
                      <text>the health insurance costs described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Higher Education Act of 1965/s:487/ss:k/p:1/sp:E/cl:i/scl:I/i:aa..cc" proposed="true">items (aa) through (cc) of subclause (I)</cato:entity-ref> during the period of the student’s participation in an athletic program of the institution; and</text>
                    </item> 
<item id="HF2656FF09E1D401891180A90236A0C0E">
                      <enum>(bb)</enum>
                      <text>the costs described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Higher Education Act of 1965/s:487/ss:k/p:1/sp:E/cl:ii/scl:I..III" proposed="true">subclauses (I) through (III) of clause (ii)</cato:entity-ref> for the duration described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Higher Education Act of 1965/s:487/ss:k/p:2/sp:E/cl:iii" proposed="true">clause (iii)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
                    </item>
                  </subclause>
                </clause> 
<clause id="HB642512CC852432C868902D3D086ED8B">
                  <enum>(ii)</enum>
                  <header>Injury-related costs</header>
                  <text>Except as provided in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Higher Education Act of 1965/s:487/ss:k/p:2/sp:E/cl:iv" proposed="true">clause (iv)</cato:entity-ref>, each student athlete who suffers an injury or illness resulting from the student’s participation in an athletic program of the institution shall be provided with institutional aid, paid to the student directly or to the insurer of such student on the student’s behalf, in an amount sufficient to cover—</text> 
<subclause id="HA4974F3AEB7A44A7B9991C11667676BD">
                    <enum>(I)</enum>
                    <text>the premium applicable to the insurance plan in which the student is enrolled;</text>
                  </subclause> 
<subclause id="H66131DB3D4BB4A44922824A3BF78F44F">
                    <enum>(II)</enum>
                    <text>any deductible applicable to such plan; and</text>
                  </subclause> 
<subclause id="H2D229FD0CDDD472792D03ED822E62C90">
                    <enum>(III)</enum>
                    <text>for a period of not less than 2 years after the student athlete’s graduation or separation from the institution—</text> 
<item id="HCAFF0A6D31464B8B822DFE3AF0D19998">
                      <enum>(aa)</enum>
                      <text>any other cost-sharing expenses of the student with respect to such plan, including co-payments; and</text>
                    </item> 
<item id="HE8547A7BD4A54FCE993CB7FDF7C63BA0">
                      <enum>(bb)</enum>
                      <text>any out-of-pocket expenses of the student with respect to such injury or illness.</text>
                    </item>
                  </subclause>
                </clause> 
<clause id="HD7E1625E7A774A42ABB94BE4B884453F">
                  <enum>(iii)</enum>
                  <header>Duration of aid</header>
                  <text>An institution shall provide a student athlete with the institutional aid required under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Higher Education Act of 1965/s:487/ss:k/p:2/sp:E/cl:ii" proposed="true">clause (ii)</cato:entity-ref>—</text> 
<subclause id="H2DE2C737FC574D51BB47A412D019D1DF">
                    <enum>(I)</enum>
                    <text>until the student’s injury or illness has been resolved and the student has been cleared by a physician to resume participation in an athletic program; or</text>
                  </subclause> 
<subclause id="HCB0FCC1DB9014DCA81ED96F98FF15793">
                    <enum>(II)</enum>
                    <text>in the case of a student who is suffering from an injury or illness that requires ongoing medical treatment, for a period of not less than 2 years after the student athlete’s graduation or separation from the institution.</text>
                  </subclause>
                </clause> 
<clause id="H55E2DF6B262E40B9B7E429A9E2D10682">
                  <enum>(iv)</enum>
                  <header>Preexisting conditions</header>
                  <text>An institution shall not be required to provide institutional aid to a student athlete under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Higher Education Act of 1965/s:487/ss:k/p:2/sp:E/cl:i" proposed="true">clause (i)</cato:entity-ref> or <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Higher Education Act of 1965/s:487/ss:k/p:2/sp:E/cl:ii" proposed="true">(ii)</cato:entity-ref> for any preexisting medical condition that predates the student athlete’s participation in the athletic program.</text>
                </clause>
              </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H0646646BA09847CF96DC0D93DADDEEEF">
                <enum>(F)</enum>
                <header>Emergency action plans and written policies</header>
                <text>The institution shall have—</text> 
<clause id="H1747A336235E49E08CD77E0E4F3E701F">
                  <enum>(i)</enum>
                  <text>venue-specific Emergency Action Plans that are coordinated by the institution's health care professional or sports medicine staff and regularly rehearsed with local emergency personnel to prevent, assess, and treat sports-related injuries; and</text>
                </clause> 
<clause id="H35C993FD613545928862C32339CCDD4A">
                  <enum>(ii)</enum>
                  <text>written policies and guidelines related to exercise for and supervision of any student athlete identified before or during participation in an athletic program of the institution to have a medical condition that is potentially life-threatening and that could be affected by the student athlete’s participation in such program.</text>
                </clause>
              </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H91C3457AAAF44515B7E80242334CFDE5">
                <enum>(G)</enum>
                <header>Sports-related concussions</header>
                <text>The institution shall provide annual baseline concussion testing of each student athlete on the active roster of each team participating in a contact or collision sport or a limited-contact or impact sport (based on the most recent classification of sports published by the Committee on Sports Medicine of the American Academy of Pediatrics) that is administered by health care professionals employed by the institution before such student athlete may participate in any contact drills or activities.</text>
              </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB316AC5A228C4F59B93CD5E75002F482">
                <enum>(H)</enum>
                <header>Compliance costs</header>
                <text>Costs to the institution resulting from compliance with this paragraph shall be paid exclusively from institutional revenue derived from income described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Higher Education Act of 1965/s:487/ss:a/p:30/sp:B" proposed="true">subsection (a)(30)(B)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
        </quoted-block>
      </subsection>
    </section> 
</legis-body> 
</bill>
</doc>