<doc>
  <docmeta id="113hjres32ih">
    <bill congress="113" type="hjres" number="32" version="ih"/>
    <revision size="3662" annotations="0" id="4" commit-time="2013-03-25T22:18:25+00:00" committer="favila" doc="113hjres32ih/4.xml" status="complete">
      <description/>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <resolution xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" dms-id="H767571AEE88244D5ACE6653069F0D2E4" key="H" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" resolution-type="constitutional-amendment" star-print="no-star-print">
	<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IA</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">113th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session display="yes">1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. J. RES. 32</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20130226">February 26, 2013</action-date>
			<action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="S001180">Mr. Schrader</sponsor>
			 introduced the following joint resolution; which was referred to the
			 <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the
			 Judiciary</committee-name>
      </action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>JOINT RESOLUTION</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">Proposing an amendment to the Constitution
		  of the United States giving Congress power to regulate campaign contributions
		  for Federal elections.</official-title>
	</form>
	<resolution-body id="H880462D3083448A6A8F1B89BABBE438F" style="constitutional-amendment">
		<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HC9D76EB395FA415A8A3F16C694DF3160" section-type="undesignated-section">
      <enum/>
      <text>That the following article is
			 proposed as an amendment to the Constitution of the United States, which shall
			 be valid to all intents and purposes as part of the Constitution when ratified
			 by the legislatures of three-fourths of the several States within seven years
			 after the date of its submission for ratification:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEE60B90E47B8444AB22C99E65990F1E4" style="traditional">
				<constitution-article id="H1234">
          <enum> —</enum>
					<section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF0608ECCF6234873986697069FB71C82" section-type="section-one">
            <enum>1.</enum>
            <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> shall have power to prohibit,
				limit, and otherwise regulate the contribution of funds or donation of in-kind
				equivalents to candidates standing for election to a Federal office in the
				United States and to prohibit, limit, and otherwise regulate the expenditure of
				funds or donation of in-kind equivalents used to support or purchase media
				advertisements intended to influence the outcome of an election for Federal
				office in the United States.</text>
						<paragraph id="HE8DCD0F5CC3A47D49FE58E99F0D24EE8" indent="up1">
              <enum/>
              <text>Whenever <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> should exercise such power, it must
				apply equally and uniformly to all individual persons recognized as citizens of
				the United States.</text>
						</paragraph>
            <paragraph id="H62D9CA24DE9E4BB287C3CAF70017FC6C" indent="up1">
              <enum/>
              <text>Whenever <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> should exercise such power on
				associations of citizens of the United States, it must apply equally and
				uniformly to all associations of citizens of the United States.</text>
						</paragraph>
          </section>
          <section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H04A71AC904CC4B9E91168D41286B3C59" section-type="section-one">
            <enum>2.</enum>
            <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each of the several States shall have power
				to prohibit, limit, and otherwise regulate the contribution of funds or
				donation of in-kind equivalents to candidates standing for election to public
				office in the State and to prohibit, limit, and otherwise regulate expenditure
				of funds or donation of in-kind equivalents used to support or purchase media
				advertisements intended to influence the outcome of an election for public
				office or plebiscite in the State.</text>
						<paragraph id="H718393F308264E6A9EF7FC7B2788A7FA" indent="up1">
              <enum/>
              <text>Whenever a State should exercise such power, it must
				apply equally and uniformly to all individual persons recognized as citizens of
				the State.</text>
						</paragraph>
            <paragraph id="HCDA3913BFE11473AB769F0E5C588A96F" indent="up1">
              <enum/>
              <text>Whenever a State should exercise such power on
				associations of citizens of the State, it must apply equally and uniformly to
				all associations of citizens of the State.</text>
						</paragraph>
          </section>
          <section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HACB6D465A0EE41709C144FB0DE6F6C18" section-type="section-one">
            <enum>3.</enum>
            <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A person who is not a citizen of the United
				States, including an association of persons who are not citizens of the United
				States, a foreign government, or any person acting as an agent thereof, may not
				contribute funds or donate in-kind equivalents to candidates standing for
				election to public office in the United States or otherwise expend funds or
				donate in-kind equivalents in a manner intended to influence the outcome of an
				election for public office or plebiscite in the United States.</text>
					</section>
          <section id="H4FD1F81D552849E8B000E750750E9141" section-type="section-one">
            <enum>4.</enum>
            <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The powers provided by this article are
				limited to the content neutral regulation of political contributions and
				political expenditures.</text>
					</section>
          <section id="H9E6C2A80BDA24565B07D36DDF92255F0" section-type="section-one">
            <enum>5.</enum>
            <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> shall have the power to enforce
				this article by appropriate
				legislation.</text>
					</section>
        </constitution-article>
        <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
      </quoted-block>
		</section>
  </resolution-body>
</resolution>
</doc>