<doc>
  <docmeta id="113hres23eh">
    <bill congress="113" type="hres" number="23" version="eh"/>
    <revision size="4555" annotations="0" status="complete" id="3" commit-time="2013-08-05T15:32:59Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113hres23eh/3.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <resolution xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" dms-id="H5f44725a-5346-4afa-bae4-c13bd2183bb3" key="H" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Engrossed-in-House" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" stage-count="1"> 
<metadata>
<dublinCore>
<title>113 HRES 23 EH: Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 152) making supplemental appropriations for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2013, and for other purposes.</title>
<publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</publisher>
<date>2013-01-15</date>
<format>text/xml</format>
<language>EN</language>
<rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="no">IV</distribution-code> 
<congress display="no">113th CONGRESS</congress> 
<session display="no">1st Session</session> 
<legis-num>H. RES. 23</legis-num> 
<current-chamber display="yes">In the House of Representatives, U. S.,</current-chamber>
<action>
<action-date date="20130115">January 15, 2013</action-date>
</action> 
<legis-type display="yes">RESOLUTION</legis-type> 
<official-title display="no">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 152) making supplemental appropriations for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2013, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<resolution-body id="H365d457a-3310-46e7-9e69-840c76432e72" style="traditional"> 
<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="Hbb90d2a7-0612-49ea-8e18-4afc135bded5" section-type="undesignated-section">
      <enum/>
      <text>That at any time after the adoption of this resolution the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" value="Speaker of the House of Representatives" entity-parent-id="0050">Speaker</cato:entity-ref> may, pursuant to clause 2(b) of rule XVIII, declare the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0050">House</cato:entity-ref> resolved into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for consideration of the bill (<cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="113 HR 152">H.R. 152</cato:entity-ref>) making supplemental appropriations for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2013, and for other purposes. The first reading of the bill shall be dispensed with. All points of order against consideration of the bill are waived. General debate shall be confined to the bill and shall not exceed one hour equally divided and controlled by the chair and ranking minority member of the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="committee" entity-id="HAP00">Committee on Appropriations</cato:entity-ref>. After general debate the bill shall be considered for amendment under the five-minute rule. It shall be in order to consider as an original bill for the purpose of amendment under the five-minute rule the amendment in the nature of a substitute printed in part A of the report of the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="committee" entity-id="HRU00">Committee on Rules</cato:entity-ref> accompanying this resolution. That amendment in the nature of a substitute shall be considered as read. All points of order against that amendment in the nature of a substitute are waived. No amendment to that amendment in the nature of a substitute shall be in order except those printed in part B of the report of the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="committee" entity-id="HRU00">Committee on Rules</cato:entity-ref>. After disposition of such amendments, the Chair shall put the question on the amendment in the nature of a substitute.</text> </section>
<section id="HAD6E2CE54EA4446CB2248D8DF6FB6B67">
      <enum>2.</enum>
      <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the amendment in the nature of a substitute printed in part A of the report of the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="committee" entity-id="HRU00">Committee on Rules</cato:entity-ref> accompanying this resolution is not adopted, the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="committee" entity-id="HRU00">Committee</cato:entity-ref> shall rise and report that it has come to no resolution on the bill. If the amendment in the nature of a substitute is adopted, the amendment in the nature of a substitute shall be considered as the original bill for the purpose of further amendment. No further amendment shall be in order except the amendments printed in part C of the report of the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="committee" entity-id="HRU00">Committee on Rules</cato:entity-ref>. At the conclusion of consideration of the amendments printed in part C of the report of the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="committee" entity-id="HRU00">Committee on Rules</cato:entity-ref>, the Committee shall rise and report the bill to the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0050">House</cato:entity-ref> with such amendments as may have been adopted. Any Member may demand a separate vote in the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0050">House</cato:entity-ref> on any amendment adopted in the Committee of the Whole to the bill, to the amendment in the nature of a substitute printed in part A of the report of the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="committee" entity-id="HRU00">Committee on Rules</cato:entity-ref>, or to amendment number 1 printed in part C of the report of the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="committee" entity-id="HRU00">Committee on Rules</cato:entity-ref>. The previous question shall be considered as ordered on the bill and amendments thereto to final passage without intervening motion except one motion to recommit with or without instructions.</text> </section>
<section id="HE7168A2E80514CF69BDEBDD51C3CF603">
      <enum>3.</enum>
      <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each amendment printed in part B and part C of the report of the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="committee" entity-id="HRU00">Committee on Rules</cato:entity-ref> accompanying this resolution may be offered only in the order printed in the report, may be offered only by a Member designated in the report, shall be considered as read, shall be debatable for the time specified in the report equally divided and controlled by the proponent and an opponent, shall not be subject to amendment (except as specified in the report), and shall not be subject to a demand for division of the question in the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0050">House</cato:entity-ref> or in the Committee of the Whole. All points of order against such amendments are waived.</text> </section>
<section id="HC4A5E65F447F4E038CF4063A0428210C">
      <enum>4.</enum>
      <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the engrossment of <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="113 HR 152">H.R. 152</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" value="Clerk of the House of Representatives" entity-parent-id="0050">Clerk</cato:entity-ref> shall—</text> 
<subsection id="H267D1691E9B845A1BA55D3640D927733">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">add the text of <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="113 HR 219">H.R. 219</cato:entity-ref>, as passed by the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0050">House</cato:entity-ref>, as new matter at the end of <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="113 HR 152">H.R. 152</cato:entity-ref>;</text> </subsection>
<subsection id="H873CDB599CCE41DC87D58C615374A1B6">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <text>conform the title of <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="113 HR 152">H.R. 152</cato:entity-ref> to reflect the addition of the text of <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="113 HR 219">H.R. 219</cato:entity-ref>, as passed by the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0050">House</cato:entity-ref>, to the engrossment;</text> </subsection>
<subsection id="H5165E5A2ECC849648283E89E7E18B5E6">
        <enum>(c)</enum>
        <text>assign appropriate designations to provisions within the engrossment;</text> </subsection>
<subsection id="H6FF4D0A540124F8F8D6785B2B59ED488">
        <enum>(d)</enum>
        <text>conform cross-references and provisions for short titles within the engrossment.</text> </subsection>
    </section>
</resolution-body> 
<attestation>
    <attestation-group>
      <attestor display="no">Karen L. Haas,</attestor>
      <role>Clerk.</role>
    </attestation-group>
  </attestation>
</resolution>
</doc>