<doc>
  <docmeta id="113hr2552ih">
    <bill congress="113" type="hr" number="2552" version="ih"/>
    <revision size="30459" annotations="0" status="complete" id="4" commit-time="2013-08-23T14:24:47Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113hr2552ih/4.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HA0E75599E7554F89989A823483CBB3A3" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>113 HR 2552 IH: Colorado Wilderness Act of 2013</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2013-06-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>113th CONGRESS</congress>
<session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. R. 2552</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20130627">June 27, 2013</action-date> 
<action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="D000197">Ms. DeGette</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name>
      </action-desc>
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To designate certain lands in the State of Colorado as components of the National Wilderness Preservation System, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H2F09A85E73C04DA7BE8B6E730DFDF52C" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H202991EB37C24F8D86DF11F6274F5E14" section-type="section-one">
      <enum>1.</enum>
      <header>Short title; definition</header> 
<subsection id="H7153D42CC7A7434EA4E5506D59214553">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Short title</header>
        <text>This Act may be cited as the <quote>
            <short-title>Colorado Wilderness Act of 2013</short-title>
          </quote>.</text>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="HA5259B9621844C518A980137D1318A8D">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Secretary defined</header>
        <text>As used in this Act, the term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of the Interior or the Secretary of Agriculture, as appropriate.</text>
      </subsection>
    </section> 
<section id="H54F4C1B7824D4E32B9E7333FF31AF6B5">
      <enum>2.</enum>
      <header>Additions to national wilderness preservation system in the State of Colorado</header> 
<subsection id="HA93E104EBE874E4EBEA60662D464350A">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Additions</header>
        <text>
          <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Colorado Wilderness Act of 1993/s:2/ss:a">Section 2(a) of the Colorado Wilderness Act of 1993</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/103/77">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="public-law" value="public-law/103/77">Public Law 103–77</cato:entity-ref>
            </external-xref>; <cato:entity-ref entity-type="statute-at-large" value="statute-at-large/107/756">107 Stat. 756</cato:entity-ref>; <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/16/1132/note">
              <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1132">16 U.S.C. 1132</external-xref> note</cato:entity-ref>)</cato:entity> is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="H66D0F6234D8C4AC98BD81E60AE1B351A">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Colorado Wilderness Act of 1993/s:2/ss:a/p:4">paragraph (4)</cato:entity-ref> by striking <quote>1993,</quote> and inserting <quote>1993, and certain lands managed by the Gunnison Field Office which comprise approximately 3,325 acres, as depicted on a map titled <quote>Proposed Powderhorn Wilderness Addition</quote> and dated October 20, 2010,</quote>; and</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H61F7C568C5614873A1AD1AA561D7DBEA">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>by adding at the end the following paragraphs:</text> 
<quoted-block id="HF78076557A5C4692B92DA875251AC329" style="OLC"> 
<paragraph id="HBFFB585DAB5D4F2EA44DABEDFBB20BCB">
              <enum>(22)</enum>
              <text>Certain lands managed by the Colorado River Valley Field Office of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1422">Bureau of Land Management</cato:entity-ref> which comprise approximately 15,200 acres, as generally depicted on a map titled <quote>Bull Gulch and Castle Peak Proposed Wilderness Areas</quote>, dated October 20, 2010, which shall be known as the Bull Gulch Wilderness.</text>
            </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H972C61C18FAC48A9996968D3D4840819">
              <enum>(23)</enum>
              <text>Certain lands managed by the Colorado River Valley Field Office of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1422">Bureau of Land Management</cato:entity-ref> which comprise approximately 12,225 acres, as generally depicted on a map titled <quote>Bull Gulch and Castle Peak Proposed Wilderness Areas</quote>, dated October 20, 2010, which shall be known as the Castle Peak Wilderness.</text>
            </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC78A2C1281334A138D4812EB0A2D03CD">
              <enum>(24)</enum>
              <text>Certain lands managed by the Colorado River Valley Field Office of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1422">Bureau of Land Management</cato:entity-ref> which comprise approximately 325 acres, as generally depicted on a map titled <quote>Maroon Bells Proposed Wilderness</quote>, dated October 20, 2010, which is hereby incorporated in and shall be deemed to be a part of the Maroon Bells-Snowmass Wilderness Area designated by <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/88/577">
                  <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="public-law" value="public-law/88/577">Public Law 88–577</cato:entity-ref>
                </external-xref>.</text>
            </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H97603F996B754DF5927F4A6BDF88608D">
              <enum>(25)</enum>
              <text>Certain lands managed by the Gunnison Field Office of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1422">Bureau of Land Management</cato:entity-ref> which comprise approximately 38,180 acres, as generally depicted on a map titled <quote>Redcloud and Handies Peak Proposed Wildernesses</quote>, dated October 21, 2010, which shall be known as the Redcloud Peak Wilderness.</text>
            </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDE72A2FC0B404A51982F59F4E8F1DDF0">
              <enum>(26)</enum>
              <text>Certain lands managed by the Gunnison Field Office of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1422">Bureau of Land Management</cato:entity-ref> which comprise approximately 16,350 acres, as generally depicted on a map titled <quote>Redcloud and Handies Peak Proposed Wildernesses</quote>, dated October 21, 2010, which shall be known as the Handies Peak Wilderness.</text>
            </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4FB146BF70984DC3AB54EA51A648DA7B">
              <enum>(27)</enum>
              <text>Certain lands managed by the Royal Gorge Field Office of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1422">Bureau of Land Management</cato:entity-ref> or located in the Pike National Forest which comprise approximately 19,825 acres, as generally depicted on a map titled <quote>Browns Canyon Proposed Wilderness Area</quote>, dated October 20, 2010, which shall be known as the Browns Canyon Wilderness.</text>
            </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC70010579B4848F2B68BBA8C9BE67AD1">
              <enum>(28)</enum>
              <text>Certain lands managed by the Royal Gorge Field Office of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1422">Bureau of Land Management</cato:entity-ref> which comprise approximately 16,690 acres, as generally depicted on a map titled <quote>McIntyre Hills Proposed Wilderness Area</quote>, dated October 20, 2010, which shall be known as the McIntyre Hills Wilderness.</text>
            </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7C544ACCCAF74ECFA6B509F72346823F">
              <enum>(29)</enum>
              <text>Certain lands managed by the Glenwood Springs Field Office of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1422">Bureau of Land Management</cato:entity-ref> which comprise approximately 11,701 acres, as generally depicted on a map titled <quote>Grand Hogback Proposed Wilderness Area</quote>, dated May 31, 2011, which shall be known as the Grand Hogback Wilderness.</text>
            </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0CB3B757E19B48B8A861E9F3DC1CFD0D">
              <enum>(30)</enum>
              <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Certain lands managed by the Glenwood Springs Field Office of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1422">Bureau of Land Management</cato:entity-ref> or located in the White River National Forest which comprise approximately 16,427 acres, as generally depicted on a map titled <quote>Deep Creek Proposed Wilderness and Flat Tops Proposed Wilderness Addition</quote> and dated is June 26, 2013, and which are hereby incorporated in and shall be deemed to be a part of the Flat Tops Wilderness designated by <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/94/146">
                  <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="public-law" value="public-law/94/146">Public Law 94–146</cato:entity-ref>
                </external-xref>.</text>
            </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3974EF732B764FD5B89D3DE4AC8F47DD">
              <enum>(31)</enum>
              <text>Certain lands managed by the Grand Junction Field Office which comprise approximately 25,881 acres, as generally depicted on a map titled <quote>Demaree Canyon Proposed Wilderness Area</quote>, dated May 31, 2011, which shall be known as the Demaree Canyon Wilderness.</text>
            </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA7E29D5F7D554373869DB15F9D994BE6">
              <enum>(32)</enum>
              <text>Certain lands managed by the Grand Junction Field Office which comprise approximately 30,557 acres, as generally depicted on a map titled <quote>South Shale Ridge and Little Book Cliffs Proposed Wilderness</quote>, dated May 31, 2011, which shall be known as the Little Bookcliffs Wilderness.</text>
            </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDADF51C08CD3494585A80B6352F5A4F7">
              <enum>(33)</enum>
              <text>Certain lands managed by the Grand Junction Field Office which comprise approximately 27,569 acres, as generally depicted on a map titled <quote>South Shale Ridge and Little Book Cliffs Proposed Wilderness</quote>, dated May 31, 2011, which shall be known as the South Shale Ridge Wilderness.</text>
            </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0F6FAB4367834380984811A6CACC38BE">
              <enum>(34)</enum>
              <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Certain lands managed by the Glenwood Springs Field Office or located in the White River National Forest which comprise approximately 20,843 acres, as generally depicted on a map titled <quote>Deep Creek Proposed Wilderness and Flat Tops Proposed Wilderness Addition</quote> and dated is June 26, 2013, upon being designated as wilderness as provided by section 3(h)(2) of the <short-title>Colorado Wilderness Act of 2013</short-title>.</text>
            </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8200869F37E348F1B014D27F329C0474">
              <enum>(35)</enum>
              <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Certain lands managed by the Glenwood Springs Field Office which comprise approximately 15,679 acres, as generally depicted on a map titled <quote>Pisgah Mountain Proposed Wilderness</quote> and date is June 26, 2013, upon being designated as wilderness as provided by <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Colorado Wilderness Act of 2013/s:3/ss:h/p:2" proposed="true">section 3(h)(2) of the <short-title>Colorado Wilderness Act of 2013</short-title>
                </cato:entity-ref>.</text>
            </paragraph>
            <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
          </quoted-block>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="H707403320D1E4640B5E2A5D05E3B893C">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Further additions</header>
        <text>The following lands in the State of Colorado administered by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1422">Bureau of Land Management</cato:entity-ref> or the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="12C2">United States Forest Service</cato:entity-ref> are hereby designated as wilderness and, therefore, as components of the National Wilderness Preservation System:</text> 
<paragraph id="H6DD0436D42BE49B8A152DAF366A9DB61">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>Certain lands managed by the Colorado River Valley Field Office of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1422">Bureau of Land Management</cato:entity-ref> or located in the White River National Forest: which comprise approximately 21,900 acres, as generally depicted on a map titled <quote>Assignation Ridge Proposed Wilderness Area</quote>, dated May 31, 2011, which shall be known as the Thompson Creek Wilderness.</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H452A9EA6D6DC44A5846AC0854F69EB1F">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>Certain lands managed by the Royal Gorge Field Office of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1422">Bureau of Land Management</cato:entity-ref> which comprise approximately 20,950 acres, as generally depicted on a map titled <quote>Badger Creek Proposed Wilderness Area</quote>, dated October 20, 2010, which shall be known as the Badger Creek Wilderness.</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8732471F85A74ACAB84B1BD56297D0FB">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <text>Certain lands managed by the Royal Gorge Field Office of the Bureau of Land Management which comprise approximately 33,425 acres, as generally depicted on a map titled <quote>Beaver Creek Proposed Wilderness Area</quote>, dated October 20, 2010, which shall be known as the Beaver Creek Wilderness.</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3E5C100BA72142B8BC69D304C0140CA1">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
          <text>Certain lands managed by the Royal Gorge Field Office of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1422">Bureau of Land Management</cato:entity-ref> or located in the San Isabel National Forest which comprise approximately 33,525 acres, as generally depicted on a map titled <quote>Grape Creek Proposed Wilderness Area</quote>, October 20, 2010, which shall be known as the Grape Creek Wilderness.</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFEA81E127BCD4A8BAA5B86D383564849">
          <enum>(5)</enum>
          <text>Certain lands managed by the Grand Junction Field Office of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1422">Bureau of Land Management</cato:entity-ref> which comprise approximately 21,110 acres, as generally depicted on a map titled <quote>Bangs Canyon Proposed Wilderness Area</quote>, dated May 31, 2011, which shall be known as the Bangs Canyon Wilderness.</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H71EFFDCDE04B444FBC19C3E7C6BD4366">
          <enum>(6)</enum>
          <text>Certain lands managed by the Grand Junction Field Office of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1422">Bureau of Land Management</cato:entity-ref> which comprise approximately 14,089 acres, as generally depicted on a map titled <quote>Granite Creek, Unaweep and Palisade Proposed Wilderness</quote>, dated June 14, 2011, which shall be known as the Granite Creek Wilderness.</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5EE1C76D550D4E7080947FBC5FFFB6B3">
          <enum>(7)</enum>
          <text>Certain lands managed by the Grand Junction Field Office of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1422">Bureau of Land Management</cato:entity-ref> which comprise approximately 26,914 acres, as generally depicted on a map titled <quote>Granite Creek, Unaweep and Palisade Proposed Wilderness</quote>, dated June 14, 2011, which shall be known as the Palisade Wilderness.</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H07BBB49D7EBB4C48858292DF5E420D65">
          <enum>(8)</enum>
          <text>Certain lands managed by the Grand Junction Field Office of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1422">Bureau of Land Management</cato:entity-ref> or located in the Uncompahgre National Forest, which comprise approximately 39,392 acres, as generally depicted on a map titled <quote>Granite Creek, Unaweep and Palisade Proposed Wilderness</quote>, dated June 14, 2011, which shall be known as the Unaweep Wilderness.</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF1E1B2DC0C7F4106802EC9D9C095C59A">
          <enum>(9)</enum>
          <text>Certain lands managed by the Grand Junction Field Office of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1422">Bureau of Land Management</cato:entity-ref> and San Juan Field Office and in the Manti-LaSal National Forest which comprise approximately 65,448 acres, as generally depicted on a map titled <quote>Sewemup Mesa Proposed Wilderness Area</quote>, dated May 31, 2011, which shall be known as the Sewemup Mesa Wilderness.</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H069C58ACEA6B47C6BF5FB69A059990B6">
          <enum>(10)</enum>
          <text>Certain lands managed by the Kremmling Field Office of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1422">Bureau of Land Management</cato:entity-ref> which comprise approximately 33 acres, as generally depicted on a map titled <quote>Platte River Addition Proposed Wilderness Area</quote>, dated May 31, 2011, and which are hereby incorporated in and shall be deemed to be part of the Platte River Wilderness designated by <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/98/550">
              <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="public-law" value="public-law/98/550">Public Law 98–550</cato:entity-ref>
            </external-xref>.</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBB35497F631E4170AB8089BF5CEB9489">
          <enum>(11)</enum>
          <text>Certain lands managed by the Uncompahgre Field Office of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1422">Bureau of Land Management</cato:entity-ref> or located in the Uncompahgre National Forest which comprise approximately 22,604 acres, as generally depicted on a map titled <quote>Roubideau Proposed Wilderness Area</quote>, dated May 31, 2011, which shall be known as the Roubideau Wilderness.</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0421B8FFAFCE4A42A4A4CD281AED056F">
          <enum>(12)</enum>
          <text>Certain lands managed by the Uncompahgre Field Office of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1422">Bureau of Land Management</cato:entity-ref> or located in the Uncompahgre National Forest which comprise approximately 13,288 acres, as generally depicted on a map titled <quote>Norwood Canyon Proposed Wilderness Area</quote>, dated May 31, 2011, which shall be known as the Norwood Canyon Wilderness.</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE4705623D938478BAF4839D4A2BF4DDB">
          <enum>(13)</enum>
          <text>Certain lands managed by the San Juan Field Office of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1422">Bureau of Land Management</cato:entity-ref> which comprise approximately 25,947 acres, as generally depicted on a map titled <quote>Cross Canyon Proposed Wilderness Area</quote>, dated May 31, 2011, which shall be known as the Cross Canyon Wilderness.</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3E2E06477C64478793F01F6AEE47F652">
          <enum>(14)</enum>
          <text>Certain lands managed by the San Juan Field Office of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1422">Bureau of Land Management</cato:entity-ref> which comprise approximately 33,467 acres, as generally depicted on a map titled <quote>McKenna Peak Proposed Wilderness Area</quote>, May 31, 2011, which shall be known as the McKenna Peak Wilderness.</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4743CC71BE8744A185E18B6AE7A7D36E">
          <enum>(15)</enum>
          <text>Certain lands managed by the San Juan Field Office of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1422">Bureau of Land Management</cato:entity-ref> Certain lands which comprise approximately 14,598 acres, as generally depicted on a map titled <quote>Weber-Menefee Mountain Proposed Wilderness Area</quote>, dated May 31, 2011, which shall be known as the Weber-Menefee Mountain Wilderness.</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC6E9C3EB56774BAC9D6A3AE17A73796A">
          <enum>(16)</enum>
          <text>Certain lands managed by the Uncompahgre and San Juan Field Offices of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1422">Bureau of Land Management</cato:entity-ref> which comprise approximately 41,133 acres, as generally depicted on a map titled <quote>Dolores River Canyon Proposed Wilderness Area</quote>, dated May 31, 2011, which shall be known as the Dolores River Canyon Wilderness.</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8D8D7D953A4442ECA280D86F59A8D52D">
          <enum>(17)</enum>
          <text>Certain lands managed by the San Juan Field Office of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1422">Bureau of Land Management</cato:entity-ref> or located in the San Juan National Forest which comprise approximately 32,050 acres, as generally depicted on a map titled <quote>Snaggletooth Proposed Wilderness Area</quote>, dated May 31, 2011, which shall be known as the Snaggletooth Wilderness.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="H183EB74CE2F444ECB06A704CA0709EEF">
        <enum>(c)</enum>
        <header>West elk addition</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Certain lands in the State of Colorado administered by the Gunnison Field Office of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1422">Bureau of Land Management</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="12C2">United States Forest Service</cato:entity-ref>, and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1425">Bureau of Reclamation</cato:entity-ref> which comprise approximately 5,000 acres, as generally depicted on a map titled <quote>West Elk Addition Proposed Wilderness Area</quote>, dated December 13, 2010, are hereby designated as wilderness and, therefore, as components of the National Wilderness Preservation System and are hereby incorporated in and shall be deemed to be a part of the West Elk Wilderness designated by <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/88/577">
            <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="public-law" value="public-law/88/577">Public Law 88–577</cato:entity-ref>
          </external-xref>. The boundary adjacent to Blue Mesa Reservoir shall be 50 feet landward from the water’s edge, and shall change according to the water level.</text>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="H1B665BF08D6B497A8D6C0B5C1C2637B0">
        <enum>(d)</enum>
        <header>Blue mesa reservoir</header>
        <text>If the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1425">Bureau of Reclamation</cato:entity-ref> determines that lands within the West Elk Wilderness Addition are necessary for future expansion of the Blue Mesa Reservoir, the Secretary shall by publication of a revised boundary description in the Federal Register revise the boundary of the West Elk Wilderness Addition.</text>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="HC94F0BE61F7842F8B69B4ED4CDB61289">
        <enum>(e)</enum>
        <header>Maps and descriptions</header>
        <text>As soon as practicable after the date of enactment of the Act, the Secretary shall file a map and a boundary description of each area designated as wilderness by this section with the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="committee" entity-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives</cato:entity-ref> and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="committee" entity-id="SSEG00">Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate</cato:entity-ref>. Each map and boundary description shall have the same force and effect as if included in this Act, except that the Secretary may correct clerical and typographical errors in the map or boundary description. The maps and boundary descriptions shall be on file and available for public inspection in the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Office of the Director" entity-parent-id="1422">Office of the Director of the Bureau of Land Management</cato:entity-ref>, <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1400">Department of the Interior</cato:entity-ref>, and in the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Office of the Chief" entity-parent-id="12C2">Office of the Chief of the Forest Service</cato:entity-ref>, <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1200">Department of Agriculture</cato:entity-ref>, as appropriate.</text>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="H678A13C166584702B7FF2EE6C47D0725">
        <enum>(f)</enum>
        <header>State and private lands</header>
        <text>Lands within the exterior boundaries of any wilderness area designated under this section that are owned by the State of Colorado or by a private entity shall be included within such wilderness area if such lands are acquired by the United States. Such lands may be acquired by the United States only as provided in the <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Wilderness Act">Wilderness Act</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1131">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/16/1131/etseq">16 U.S.C. 1131 et seq.</cato:entity-ref>
            </external-xref>)</cato:entity>.</text>
      </subsection>
    </section> 
<section id="H583A94C088A046A8AB4130214FE635FE">
      <enum>3.</enum>
      <header>Administrative provisions</header> 
<subsection id="H19E4E37318194354BCEB2C248A843BA2">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>In general</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to valid existing rights, lands designated as wilderness by this Act shall be managed by the Secretary in accordance with the <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Wilderness Act">Wilderness Act</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1131">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/16/1131/etseq">16 U.S.C. 1131 et seq.</cato:entity-ref>
            </external-xref>)</cato:entity> and this Act, except that, with respect to any wilderness areas designated by this Act, any reference in the Wilderness Act to the effective date of the Wilderness Act shall be deemed to be a reference to the date of enactment of this Act.</text>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="H7DC4960EA4A0422FA61DB62846183009">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Grazing</header>
        <text>Grazing of livestock in wilderness areas designated by this Act shall be administered in accordance with the provisions of <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Wilderness Act/s:4/ss:d/p:4">section 4(d)(4) of the Wilderness Act</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1133">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/16/1133/d/4">16 U.S.C. 1133(d)(4)</cato:entity-ref>
            </external-xref>)</cato:entity>, as further interpreted by <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="public-law" value="public-law/96/560/s:108">section 108 of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/96/560">Public Law 96–560</external-xref>
          </cato:entity-ref>, and the guidelines set forth in appendix A of House Report 101–405 of the 101st Congress.</text>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="HC0D3E20A388D422A95BC8143BAB58970">
        <enum>(c)</enum>
        <header>State jurisdiction</header>
        <text>As provided in <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Wilderness Act/s:4/ss:d/p:7">section 4(d)(7) of the Wilderness Act</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1133">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/16/1133/d/7">16 U.S.C. 1133(d)(7)</cato:entity-ref>
            </external-xref>)</cato:entity>, nothing in this Act shall be construed as affecting the jurisdiction or responsibilities of the State of Colorado with respect to wildlife and fish in Colorado.</text>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="HAB1E8922CCAD47F0B1DD8FB6BF88F803">
        <enum>(d)</enum>
        <header>Buffer zones</header> 
<paragraph id="H4B0D1532634041EC8796FD008ECD8E4A">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>In general</header>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this Act creates a protective perimeter or buffer zone around any area designated as wilderness by <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Colorado Wilderness Act of 2013/s:2" proposed="true">section 2</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE2210BB35A5C4D4EB9B63A9D97F65913">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Activities outside wilderness</header>
          <text>The fact that an activity or use on land outside the areas designated as wilderness by <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Colorado Wilderness Act of 2013/s:2" proposed="true">section 2</cato:entity-ref> can be seen or heard within the wilderness shall not preclude the activity or use outside the boundary of the wilderness.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="H9CA8C9825C2D4EEEB22762235A78D7F3">
        <enum>(e)</enum>
        <header>Military helicopter overflights</header> 
<paragraph id="H93EB10B1CEC248F8B8A239019AF547F8">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>In general</header>
          <text>Nothing in this Act restricts or precludes—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H64FC23B7D79F4097852B2B35B71E3FD7">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>low-level overflights of military helicopters over the areas designated as wilderness by <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Colorado Wilderness Act of 2013/s:2" proposed="true">section 2</cato:entity-ref>, including military overflights that can be seen or heard within any wilderness area;</text>
          </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA7A8A190E4C54C53B7A10F417AB8018C">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>military flight testing and evaluation; or</text>
          </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6C70EF2E8CCB416790F702B512D19CB1">
            <enum>(C)</enum>
            <text>the designation or creation of new units of special use airspace, or the establishment of military flight training routes over any wilderness area.</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6BDFEA4FD3404B8185975D6838123EC5">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Aerial navigation training exercises</header>
          <text>The Colorado Army National Guard, through the High-Altitude Army National Guard Aviation Training Site, may conduct aerial navigation training maneuver exercises over the wilderness areas designated by this Act—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H37342B0498024C32B70B4A0D3E745F6A">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in a manner consistent with the memorandum of understanding dated August 4, 1987, entered into among the Colorado Army National Guard, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1422">Bureau of Land Management</cato:entity-ref>, and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="12C2">Forest Service</cato:entity-ref>; or</text>
          </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5ED890619E4E4FF3B8CD44438B39FDD6">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>in a manner consistent with a subsequent memorandum of understanding entered into among the Colorado Army National Guard, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1422">Bureau of Land Management</cato:entity-ref>, and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="12C2">Forest Service</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="H61EEE06025F84A95A05DD7E45DB20171">
        <enum>(f)</enum>
        <header>Running events</header>
        <text>The Secretary may continue to authorize competitive running events currently permitted in the Redcloud Peak Wilderness Area and Handies Peak Wilderness Area in a manner compatible with the preservation of such areas as wilderness.</text>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="H0552875030E042538AA294E0649DF8AE">
        <enum>(g)</enum>
        <header>Land trades</header>
        <text>If the Secretary trades privately owned land within the perimeter of the Redcloud Peak Wilderness Area or the Handies Peak Wilderness Area in exchange for Federal land, then such Federal land shall be located in Hinsdale County, Colorado.</text>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="H3EB484718C1F4BFD9C57D3121E6F05B1">
        <enum>(h)</enum>
        <header>Potential wilderness designations</header> 
<paragraph id="H8A73FE02E01F414C85DA6E2C6457B491">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>In general</header>
          <text>The following lands are designated as potential wilderness areas:</text> 
<subparagraph id="HA6A450E5068E4642B9E9B9915D7CFAC0">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Certain lands managed by the Glenwood Springs Field Office or located in the White River National Forest which comprise approximately 20,843 acres, as generally depicted on a map titled <quote>Deep Creek Proposed Wilderness and Flat Tops Proposed Wilderness Addition</quote> and dated is June 26, 2013, which, upon designation as wilderness under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Colorado Wilderness Act of 2013/s:3/ss:h/p:2" proposed="true">paragraph (2)</cato:entity-ref>, shall be known as the Deep Creek Wilderness.</text>
          </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF8DEB19433BA451BB99D6666085399C4">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Certain lands managed by the Glenwood Springs Field Office which comprise approximately 15,679 acres, as generally depicted on a map titled <quote>Pisgah Mountain Proposed Wilderness</quote> and date is June 26, 2013, which, upon designation as wilderness under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Colorado Wilderness Act of 2013/s:3/ss:h/p:2" proposed="true">paragraph (2)</cato:entity-ref>, shall be known as the Pisgah Mountain Wilderness.</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB4C6F34995AB4BC99B887C0C317F4CCC">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Designation as wilderness</header>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Lands designated as a potential wilderness area by <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Colorado Wilderness Act of 2013/s:3/ss:h/p:1/sp:A" proposed="true">subparagraph (A)</cato:entity-ref> or <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Colorado Wilderness Act of 2013/s:3/ss:h/p:1/sp:B" proposed="true">(B) of paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref> shall be designated as wilderness on the date on which the Secretary publishes in the Federal Register a notice that all nonconforming uses of those lands authorized by <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Colorado Wilderness Act of 2013/s:3/ss:e" proposed="true">subsection (e)</cato:entity-ref> in the potential wilderness area that would be in violation of the <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Wilderness Act">Wilderness Act</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1131">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/16/1131/etseq">16 U.S.C. 1131 et seq.</cato:entity-ref>
              </external-xref>)</cato:entity> have ceased. Such publication in the Federal Register and designation as wilderness shall occur for the potential wilderness area as the nonconforming uses cease in that potential wilderness area and designation as wilderness is not dependent on cessation of nonconforming uses in the other potential wilderness area.</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H538C936672424A43B4C7EB7187440446">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <header>Management</header>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except for activities provided for under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Colorado Wilderness Act of 2013/s:3/ss:e" proposed="true">subsection (e)</cato:entity-ref>, lands designated as a potential wilderness area by <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Colorado Wilderness Act of 2013/s:3/ss:h/p:1" proposed="true">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref> shall be managed by the Secretary in accordance with the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Wilderness Act">Wilderness Act</cato:entity-ref> as wilderness pending the designation of such lands as wilderness under this subsection.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
    </section> 
<section id="HFD5F4234D4DD40989C84A769BF7FF506">
      <enum>4.</enum>
      <header>Water</header> 
<subsection id="H91E14CD647B44C869BE03D54203A9C3E">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Effect on water rights</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this Act—</text> 
<paragraph id="HB925579FDF7B4445A997CCDB42B0CDFE">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>affects the use or allocation, in existence on the date of enactment of this Act, of any water, water right, or interest in water;</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD7CA3AC4DBC848C9B7A43A5FDA591059">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>affects any vested absolute or decreed conditional water right in existence on the date of enactment of this Act, including any water right held by the United States;</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1EABBB031BD946DDA6EAF1E514A7D9F8">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <text>affects any interstate water compact in existence on the date of enactment of this Act;</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H15239A18274D429E966D7378D8B4D1A0">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
          <text>authorizes or imposes any new reserved Federal water rights; and</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2FF0E85CA0C24AD9B4C857E27900D93C">
          <enum>(5)</enum>
          <text>shall be considered to be a relinquishment or reduction of any water rights reserved or appropriated by the United States in the State on or before the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="H4A2EEA4AA3174EB6B5DB107786EA15AD">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Midstream areas</header> 
<paragraph id="HF8DBA418884A4D1189B4C05B035D4F62">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>Purpose</header>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The purpose of this subsection is to protect for the benefit and enjoyment of present and future generations—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H626F7F8A3F194A82956745F87B6D688C">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>the unique and nationally important values of areas designated as wilderness by <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Colorado Wilderness Act of 2013/s:2/ss:b" proposed="true">section 2(b)</cato:entity-ref> (including the geological, cultural, archaeological, paleontological, natural, scientific, recreational, environmental, biological, wilderness, wildlife, riparian, historical, educational, and scenic resources of the public land); and</text>
          </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H4D0CC92743094C5AB40711DC87728CDD">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>the water resources of area streams, based on seasonally available flows, that are necessary to support aquatic, riparian, and terrestrial species and communities.</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF4C90F7B39B5421CB89F5A2A476CC879">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Wilderness water rights</header> 
<subparagraph id="H3BDD16286C4E4B0B8659D3531BF83217">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <header>In general</header>
            <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall ensure that any water rights within the wilderness designated by <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Colorado Wilderness Act of 2013/s:2/ss:b" proposed="true">section 2(b)</cato:entity-ref> required to fulfill the purposes of such wilderness are secured in accordance with <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Colorado Wilderness Act of 2013/s:4/ss:b/p:2/sp:B..G" proposed="true">subparagraphs (B) through (G)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
          </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE827DCE032784474949A257AFB5725BE">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <header>State law</header> 
<clause id="H48E19A6CFF484C3EB4770A37438FE6DF">
              <enum>(i)</enum>
              <header>Procedural requirements</header>
              <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any water rights for which the Secretary pursues adjudication shall be appropriated, adjudicated, changed, and administered in accordance with the procedural requirements and priority system of State law.</text>
            </clause> 
<clause id="H7E7B826276F64F1B959741EC40EFA56D">
              <enum>(ii)</enum>
              <header>Establishment of water rights</header> 
<subclause id="H5A77E7A00AC04AF790BA7B7F7334F1F0">
                <enum>(I)</enum>
                <header>In general</header>
                <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Colorado Wilderness Act of 2013/s:4/ss:b/p:2/sp:B/cl:ii/scl:II" proposed="true">subclause (II)</cato:entity-ref>, the purposes and other substantive characteristics of the water rights pursued under this paragraph shall be established in accordance with State law.</text>
              </subclause> 
<subclause id="HF574D1F6F8BD4CE7AFD2C91384435CA3">
                <enum>(II)</enum>
                <header>Exception</header>
                <text>Notwithstanding <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Colorado Wilderness Act of 2013/s:4/ss:b/p:2/sp:B/cl:ii/scl:I" proposed="true">subclause (I)</cato:entity-ref> and in accordance with this Act, the Secretary may appropriate and seek adjudication of water rights to maintain surface water levels and stream flows on and across the wilderness designated by <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Colorado Wilderness Act of 2013/s:2/ss:b" proposed="true">section 2(b)</cato:entity-ref> to fulfill the purposes of such wilderness.</text>
              </subclause>
            </clause>
          </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H7C8D1AEF7A784E55A65B999A35BFC85E">
            <enum>(C)</enum>
            <header>Deadline</header>
            <text>The Secretary shall promptly, but not earlier than January 1, 2016, appropriate the water rights required to fulfill the purposes of the wilderness designated by <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Colorado Wilderness Act of 2013/s:2/ss:b" proposed="true">section 2(b)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
          </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H65E1A7B47ED843E4A15A5D2DF7602C72">
            <enum>(D)</enum>
            <header>Required determination</header>
            <text>The Secretary shall not pursue adjudication for any instream flow water rights unless the Secretary makes a determination pursuant to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Colorado Wilderness Act of 2013/s:4/ss:b/p:2/sp:E/cl:ii" proposed="true">subparagraph (E)(ii)</cato:entity-ref> or <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Colorado Wilderness Act of 2013/s:4/ss:b/p:2/sp:F" proposed="true">(F)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
          </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF4D56E43FB1A4BCE802446091010499E">
            <enum>(E)</enum>
            <header>Cooperative enforcement</header> 
<clause id="H75A3E19311C54D138AB7B896842B5E88">
              <enum>(i)</enum>
              <header>In general</header>
              <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall not pursue adjudication of any Federal instream flow water rights established under this paragraph if—</text> 
<subclause id="HEFEEA1A68FDC4A6186C5BA855A7FBD12">
                <enum>(I)</enum>
                <text>the Secretary determines, upon adjudication of the water rights by the Colorado Water Conservation Board, that the Board holds water rights sufficient in priority, amount, and timing to fulfill the purposes of this subsection; and</text>
              </subclause> 
<subclause id="HC68E334861C147258E43A72D558A4A84">
                <enum>(II)</enum>
                <text>the Secretary has entered into a perpetual agreement with the Colorado Water Conservation Board to ensure full exercise, protection, and enforcement of the State water rights within the Wilderness to reliably fulfill the purposes of this subsection.</text>
              </subclause>
            </clause> 
<clause id="H3E6090AE68854307877C04CA47B8F50B">
              <enum>(ii)</enum>
              <header>Adjudication</header>
              <text>If the Secretary determines that the provisions of <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Colorado Wilderness Act of 2013/s:4/ss:b/p:2/sp:E/cl:i" proposed="true">clause (i)</cato:entity-ref> have not been met, the Secretary shall adjudicate and exercise any Federal water rights required to fulfill the purposes of the Wilderness in accordance with this paragraph.</text>
            </clause>
          </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2D6A6651B406449B846A34D5F700DE99">
            <enum>(F)</enum>
            <header>Insufficient water rights</header>
            <text>If the Colorado Water Conservation Board modifies the instream flow water rights obtained under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Colorado Wilderness Act of 2013/s:4/ss:b/p:2/sp:E" proposed="true">subparagraph (E)</cato:entity-ref> to such a degree that the Secretary determines that water rights held by the State are insufficient to fulfill the purposes of this Act, the Secretary shall adjudicate and exercise Federal water rights required to fulfill the purposes of this Act in accordance with <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Colorado Wilderness Act of 2013/s:4/ss:b/p:2/sp:B" proposed="true">subparagraph (B)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
          </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE3C0B0B076C64EA09502E63333A84020">
            <enum>(G)</enum>
            <header>Failure to comply</header>
            <text>The Secretary shall promptly act to exercise and enforce the water rights described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Colorado Wilderness Act of 2013/s:4/ss:b/p:2/sp:E" proposed="true">subparagraph (E)</cato:entity-ref> if the Secretary determines that—</text> 
<clause id="HFB717B4624CA47F294E71F7EF408FB3D">
              <enum>(i)</enum>
              <text>the State is not exercising its water rights consistent with <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Colorado Wilderness Act of 2013/s:4/ss:b/p:2/sp:E/cl:i/scl:I" proposed="true">subparagraph (E)(i)(I)</cato:entity-ref>; or</text>
            </clause> 
<clause id="H3FF9D9154BE04A60A010F3F171030CE0">
              <enum>(ii)</enum>
              <text>the agreement described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Colorado Wilderness Act of 2013/s:4/ss:b/p:2/sp:E/cl:i/scl:II" proposed="true">subparagraph (E)(i)(II)</cato:entity-ref> is not fulfilled or complied with sufficiently to fulfill the purposes of this Act.</text>
            </clause>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H63D40F5D14624DE6869967EF843E6DB9">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <header>Water resource facility</header>
          <text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, beginning on the date of enactment of this Act, neither the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> nor any other officer, employee, or agent of the United States shall fund, assist, authorize, or issue a license or permit for development of any new irrigation and pumping facility, reservoir, water conservation work, aqueduct, canal, ditch, pipeline, well, hydropower project, transmission, other ancillary facility, or other water, diversion, storage, or carriage structure in the wilderness designated by <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Colorado Wilderness Act of 2013/s:2/ss:b" proposed="true">section 2(b)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="H9E64DCD4429840B9B88B759F3DF537FA">
        <enum>(c)</enum>
        <header>Access and operation</header> 
<paragraph id="H3D6BA2A323EB4D3E8DB3CF5714C260E5">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>Definition</header>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">As used in this subsection, the term <term>water resource facility</term> means irrigation and pumping facilities, reservoirs, water conservation works, aqueducts, canals, ditches, pipelines, wells, hydropower projects, and transmission and other ancillary facilities, and other water diversion, storage, and carriage structures.</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6D4AB934809A409898C24AE819F9CFEC">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Access to water resource facilities</header>
          <text>Subject to the provisions of this subsection, the Secretary shall allow reasonable access to water resource facilities in existence on the date of enactment of this Act within the areas described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Colorado Wilderness Act of 2013/s:2/ss:b" proposed="true">sections 2(b)</cato:entity-ref> and <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Colorado Wilderness Act of 2013/s:2/ss:c" proposed="true">2(c)</cato:entity-ref>, including motorized access where necessary and customarily employed on routes existing as of the date of enactment of this Act.</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4B2130CD65904DEB835CA008CC8FAA1B">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <header>Access routes</header>
          <text>Existing access routes within such areas customarily employed as of the date of enactment of this Act may be used, maintained, repaired, and replaced to the extent necessary to maintain their present function, design, and serviceable operation, so long as such activities have no increased adverse impacts on the resources and values of the areas described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Colorado Wilderness Act of 2013/s:2/ss:b" proposed="true">sections 2(b)</cato:entity-ref> and <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Colorado Wilderness Act of 2013/s:2/ss:c" proposed="true">2(c)</cato:entity-ref> than existed as of the date of enactment of this Act.</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC37D672D1B854BAE8540A0FFF41D5345">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
          <header>Use of water resource facilities</header>
          <text>Subject to the provisions of this subsection and <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Colorado Wilderness Act of 2013/s:4/ss:a/p:4" proposed="true">subsection (a)(4)</cato:entity-ref>, the Secretary shall allow water resource facilities existing on the date of enactment of this Act within areas described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Colorado Wilderness Act of 2013/s:2/ss:b" proposed="true">sections 2(b)</cato:entity-ref> and <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Colorado Wilderness Act of 2013/s:2/ss:c" proposed="true">2(c)</cato:entity-ref> to be used, operated, maintained, repaired, and replaced to the extent necessary for the continued exercise, in accordance with Colorado State law, of vested water rights adjudicated for use in connection with such facilities by a court of competent jurisdiction prior to the date of enactment of this Act. The impact of an existing facility on the water resources and values of the area shall not be increased as a result of changes in the adjudicated type of use of such facility as of the date of enactment of this Act.</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFF2C338E0C9E494F9794EDF790D005CB">
          <enum>(5)</enum>
          <header>Repair and maintenance</header>
          <text>Water resource facilities, and access routes serving such facilities, existing within the areas described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Colorado Wilderness Act of 2013/s:2/ss:b" proposed="true">sections 2(b)</cato:entity-ref> and <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Colorado Wilderness Act of 2013/s:2/ss:c" proposed="true">2(c)</cato:entity-ref> on the date of enactment of this Act shall be maintained and repaired when and to the extent necessary to prevent increased adverse impacts on the resources and values of the areas described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Colorado Wilderness Act of 2013/s:2/ss:b" proposed="true">sections 2(b)</cato:entity-ref> and <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Colorado Wilderness Act of 2013/s:2/ss:c" proposed="true">2(c)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
    </section> 
</legis-body> 
</bill>
</doc>