<doc>
  <docmeta id="113hres273ih">
    <bill congress="113" type="hres" number="273" version="ih"/>
    <revision size="3889" annotations="0" status="complete" id="3" commit-time="2013-08-05T18:27:13Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113hres273ih/3.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <resolution xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" dms-id="H0A6E2A902A724CE1B657F23172D53A4A" key="H" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>113 HRES 273 IH: Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives that the President should nominate a qualified and independent individual for the position of Inspector General of the Department of State and Broadcasting Board of Governors to be confirmed by the Senate without delay.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2013-06-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">113th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session display="yes">1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. RES. 273</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20130625">June 25, 2013</action-date>
			<action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="R000487">Mr. Royce</sponsor> (for
			 himself and <cosponsor name-id="E000179">Mr. Engel</cosponsor>) submitted the
			 following resolution; which was referred to the
			 <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign
			 Affairs</committee-name>
      </action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">Expressing the sense of the House of
		  Representatives that the President should nominate a qualified and independent
		  individual for the position of Inspector General of the Department of State and
		  Broadcasting Board of Governors to be confirmed by the Senate without
		  delay.</official-title>
	</form>
	<preamble>
		<whereas>
      <text>Whereas the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Inspector General Act of 1978">Inspector General Act of 1978</cato:entity-ref> mandates that
			 Inspectors General are to conduct independent and objective audits,
			 investigations, and inspections, prevent and detect waste, fraud, and abuse,
			 promote economy, effectiveness, and efficiency, review pending legislation and
			 regulations, and keep the agency heads and <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> fully and currently
			 informed;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1904">Office of Inspector General (OIG) of the
			 Department of State</cato:entity-ref> and <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="195C">Broadcasting Board of Governors</cato:entity-ref> (BBG) detects,
			 investigates, and prevents instances of fraud, waste, and mismanagement that
			 may constitute either criminal wrongdoing or violation of <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Department of State</cato:entity-ref>
			 or <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="195C">BBG</cato:entity-ref> regulations;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1904">OIG</cato:entity-ref> inspects United States diplomatic and
			 consular posts and international broadcasting installations throughout the
			 world to determine whether policy goals are being achieved and whether the
			 interests of the United States are being represented and advanced
			 effectively;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1904">OIG</cato:entity-ref> conducts specialized security inspections
			 and audits in support of the Department of State’s mission to provide effective
			 protection to United States personnel, facilities, and sensitive
			 information;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Department of State</cato:entity-ref> employs a total of nearly
			 70,000 personnel, consisting of approximately 24,500 direct hire Foreign
			 Service and Civil Service personnel, over 9,300 of whom are stationed overseas,
			 and more than 45,000 locally employed staff, creating difficult accountability
			 challenges;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas a presidentially appointed, Senate-confirmed
			 Inspector General provides the leadership and accountability within an <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1904">OIG</cato:entity-ref>
			 necessary to oversee a cabinet-level agency and fulfill the duties described in
			 this resolution, while instilling confidence in agency interlocutors and
			 <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref>;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the position of <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1904">Inspector General for the
			 Department of State</cato:entity-ref> and <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="195C">BBG</cato:entity-ref> has been vacant since January 16, 2008, a span of
			 nearly 2,000 days, and is being filled by an interim appointment;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas this vacancy is the longest of any <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1904">OIG</cato:entity-ref> across the
			 Federal Government; and</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas filling this vacancy will help ensure that the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1904">OIG</cato:entity-ref>
			 provides the robust oversight necessary to keep <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> fully and currently
			 informed, protect the United States taxpayer, and ensure good governance: Now,
			 therefore, be it</text>
		</whereas>
  </preamble>
	<resolution-body id="HB31AA0A26CFE4CCC809F2EED6B473B95" style="traditional">
		<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H60FCE13A2FEF4E399D8034E3D02C6901" section-type="undesignated-section">
      <enum/>
      <text>That it is the sense of the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0050">House of
			 Representatives</cato:entity-ref> that the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> should nominate a qualified and independent
			 individual for the position of <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1904">Inspector General for the Department of State</cato:entity-ref>
			 and <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="195C">Broadcasting Board of Governors</cato:entity-ref> to be confirmed by the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0010">Senate</cato:entity-ref> without
			 delay.</text>
		</section>
  </resolution-body>
</resolution>
</doc>