<doc>
  <docmeta id="113hr3526ih">
    <bill congress="113" type="hr" number="3526" version="ih"/>
    <revision size="18086" annotations="0" status="complete" id="3" commit-time="2013-11-23T16:47:32Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113hr3526ih/3.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H32A226D848954165A18131A664F0D88F" public-private="public">
  <metadata>
<dublinCore>
<dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">113 HR 3526 IH: Humanitarian Assistance Facilitation Act of 2013</dc:title>
<dc:publisher xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">2013-11-18</dc:date>
<dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
    <congress>113th CONGRESS</congress>
    <session>1st Session</session>
    <legis-num>H. R. 3526</legis-num>
    <current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
    <action>
      <action-date date="20131118">November 18, 2013</action-date>
      <action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="S000522">Mr. Smith of New Jersey</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Judiciary</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
    </action>
    <legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
    <official-title>To permit persons subject to the jurisdiction of the United States to enter into transactions with certain sanctioned foreign persons that are customary, necessary, and incidental to the donation or provision of goods or services to prevent or alleviate the suffering of civilian populations, and for other purposes.</official-title>
  </form>
  <legis-body id="H22518F291FF647408E0D1DAE29A557BD" style="OLC">
    <section id="H049A0C3C7E584F12A4BC8D3EE4B7723C" section-type="section-one">
      <enum>1.</enum>
      <header>Short title</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote>
          <short-title>Humanitarian Assistance Facilitation Act of 2013</short-title>
        </quote>.</text>
    </section>
    <section id="H2BB49548562D411FAB2F44D75007D5D3">
      <enum>2.</enum>
      <header>Findings</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">
        <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> finds the following:</text>
      <paragraph id="H9306752F34BA42F59D8563E5BB577EA1">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The 2011–2012 drought in East Africa, part of a persistent weather trend in the region, was exacerbated by stagnating agricultural development and unsustainable forms of livelihood. Moreover, in Somalia, the hardest hit country in the region, the terrorist group al-Shabaab obstructed the delivery of humanitarian assistance and directly threatened aid agencies. Thus, the famine was a foreseeable and, with unimpeded delivery of aid, a preventable event.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H094E995F495C4861945BC24341D18E7F">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text>It is estimated that 4 million Somalis were affected by the drought and famine in the region and several million remain vulnerable to this day. According to the May 2013 report issued by the United Nations Food and Agriculture Organization and the Famine Early Warning System Network, the Somalia famine resulted in 258,000 deaths between October 2010 and April 2012. More than half of those deaths were children under the age of five.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H3826C03B5FA341B4BBEF2A3D6A1DDBD2">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <text>Because of laws prohibiting activities that may directly or indirectly support terrorist organizations, a general or specific license issued by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Office of Foreign Assets Control" entity-parent-id="2000">Department of the Treasury’s Office of Foreign Assets Control</cato:entity-ref> (OFAC) is needed to enable United States humanitarian organizations to legally provide assistance in al-Shabaab-controlled areas of Somalia particularly with respect to activities that require interactions or dealings with al-Shabaab.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph commented="no" id="H2770FA02488941B58CFF9C321A3DB138">
        <enum>(4)</enum>
        <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7200">United States Agency for International Development</cato:entity-ref> (USAID) has an OFAC-specific license to operate in these conditions in Somalia that covers the organizations that USAID funds, but not organizations that operate with their own funding or funding solely from non-United States Government sources, and also not the non-United States Government funding of organizations that operate with both United States Government and non-United States Government funding, unless USAID authorizes both types of funding to be covered under such OFAC-specific license. Organizations that operate in al-Shabaab-controlled areas without such a license can be subject to prosecution for violating United States law, at least with respect to activities or transactions that involve al-Shabaab, even incidentally.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H29A747996A8E4E0EA9B5B1975648F083">
        <enum>(5)</enum>
        <text>Prior to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Office of Foreign Assets Control" entity-parent-id="2000">OFAC</cato:entity-ref> issuing <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7200">USAID</cato:entity-ref> its license, no licenses for humanitarian assistance to the people of Somalia were issued before the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="19UN">United Nations</cato:entity-ref> declared a famine in al-Shabaab-controlled areas of Somalia.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H4E86449773E84CD483E87136A05B1E80">
        <enum>(6)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In pursuit of eliminating aid in any form to terrorist organizations, Executive orders have had the effect of undoing protections for humanitarian operations in areas controlled by such organizations previously contained in the <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="International Emergency Economic Powers Act">International Emergency Economic Powers Act</cato:entity-ref> (<cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/50/1701/etseq">50 U.S.C.1701 et seq.</cato:entity-ref>)</cato:entity> and <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/18/2339A">sections <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/18/2339A">2339A</external-xref>
            </cato:entity-ref> and <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/18/2339B">
              <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/18/2339">2339B</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code</cato:entity-ref> (commonly known as the ‘‘<cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Material Support Statutes">Material Support Statutes</cato:entity-ref>’’)</cato:entity>. Furthermore, the prohibitions contained in such Executive orders and the Material Support Statutes discouraged and, in some instances, prohibited donors from contributing to aid efforts for all of Somalia. In some cases, the unintended consequences included preventing humanitarian organizations from establishing access to civilians and providing them with life-saving aid, while empowering terrorist organizations that became the sole conduit of aid.</text>
      </paragraph>
    </section>
    <section id="HF3A9C262A9CB4B618F0161E2B3D3B56D">
      <enum>3.</enum>
      <header>Sense of Congress</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> that humanitarian organizations, acting in good faith and with the appropriate restrictions and controls in place, should not be prevented, directly or indirectly by Executive orders or counterterrorism laws, from accessing and providing aid to civilian populations before or early on in humanitarian crises, such as in the famine in al-Shabaab-controlled areas of Somalia.</text>
    </section>
    <section id="H326430C9E60F4734979704D3345371F8">
      <enum>4.</enum>
      <header>Amendments to section 203 of the International Emergency Economic Powers Act</header>
      <subsection id="HE561BE5953FC4CA4B631DB02145BD348">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Additional exception</header>
        <paragraph id="H61654719AD604024B981A6386454EDA8">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>In general</header>
          <text>
            <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="International Emergency Economic Powers Act/s:203">Section 203 of the International Emergency Economic Powers Act</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1702">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/50/1702">50 U.S.C. 1702</cato:entity-ref>
              </external-xref>)</cato:entity> is amended—</text>
          <subparagraph id="H5B953E20B5654A419B28930F48DC88C1">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="International Emergency Economic Powers Act/s:203/ss:b/p:2">subsection (b)(2)</cato:entity-ref>—</text>
            <clause commented="no" id="H22CBB50142E645279E7DF10C19E2A997">
              <enum>(i)</enum>
              <text>by inserting after <quote>to relieve human suffering</quote> the following: <quote>including donations to foreign persons subject to sanctions under this Act in order to achieve such purposes,</quote>; and</text>
            </clause>
            <clause id="HACE502F8F3644A769149E6B3E3A809B5">
              <enum>(ii)</enum>
              <text>by striking <quote>or</quote> at the end;</text>
            </clause>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H25943F9F413E40CB9641EFFD661FE512">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>by redesignating <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="International Emergency Economic Powers Act/s:203/ss:c">subsection (c)</cato:entity-ref> as <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="International Emergency Economic Powers Act/s:203/ss:d" proposed="true">subsection (d)</cato:entity-ref>; and</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H15FEB8C7F6364361A297C2AF654219BE">
            <enum>(C)</enum>
            <text>by inserting after <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="International Emergency Economic Powers Act/s:203/ss:b">subsection (b)</cato:entity-ref> the following:</text>
            <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6A090C68DCCF4CF08401AA8C7206E872" style="OLC">
              <subsection id="HB8A8BA93ACDD48A59C4A4DFB0211EACF">
                <enum>(c)</enum>
                <header>Additional exception</header>
                <paragraph id="HDB89D1A08E58407392DBA0D9DD483DD4">
                  <enum>(1)</enum>
                  <header>In general</header>
                  <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The authority granted to the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> by this section does not include the authority to further restrict, by regulation or otherwise, directly or indirectly—</text>
                  <subparagraph id="H32ECD44FA4284529ABDBFCA4E5798167">
                    <enum>(A)</enum>
                    <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">transactions, by a person subject to the jurisdiction of the United States, with a foreign person that is subject to sanctions under this Act that are customary, necessary, and incidental to the donation or provision of goods or services by the person subject to the jurisdiction of the United States or its foreign representatives to civilian populations to prevent or alleviate the suffering of such civilian populations, if—</text>
                    <clause id="H6285ADF2C4214273A6D9B017123DF5C2">
                      <enum>(i)</enum>
                      <text>the person subject to the jurisdiction of the United States has acted in good faith without intent to further the aims or objectives of the foreign person and has used its best efforts to minimize any such transactions;</text>
                    </clause>
                    <clause id="H407239ACA8E64079AB1E233ED65B5C90">
                      <enum>(ii)</enum>
                      <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the goods or services provided to the civilian population—</text>
                      <subclause id="H16667E7EDEC8495B903DF527B18098A0">
                        <enum>(I)</enum>
                        <text>are limited to articles such as food, clothing, and medicine; and</text>
                      </subclause>
                      <subclause id="H207E8988101F4E0D8EE0A368D0E53E56">
                        <enum>(II)</enum>
                        <text>are not capable of being used to carry out any terrorist activity (as defined in <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
                            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Immigration and Nationality Act/s:212/ss:a/p:3/sp:B/cl:iii">section 212(a)(3)(B)(iii) of the Immigration and Nationality Act</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1182">
                              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/8/1182/a/3/B/iii">8 U.S.C. 1182(a)(3)(B)(iii)</cato:entity-ref>
                            </external-xref>)</cato:entity>);</text>
                      </subclause>
                    </clause>
                    <clause id="H3E973BF2308C402683EA9750DC7C3018">
                      <enum>(iii)</enum>
                      <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the person subject to the jurisdiction of the United States—</text>
                      <subclause id="HD1E7FA2CA2904185BEA4F77A53DD53DD">
                        <enum>(I)</enum>
                        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">prior to, or not later than 10 business days after, the first instance of entering into any transaction described in this subparagraph, provides to the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref> initial notice summarizing the nature and extent of its operations in connection with providing such goods or services; and</text>
                      </subclause>
                      <subclause id="HF7B07CF31335490DAE8E5DD2351F0AC7">
                        <enum>(II)</enum>
                        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">at least once each year during which the person enters into any transaction described in this subparagraph, provides to the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref> subsequent notice summarizing the nature and extent of its operations in connection with donating or providing such goods or services; and</text>
                      </subclause>
                    </clause>
                    <clause id="HAE1D8861B7D644EA98E29C280815BF6D">
                      <enum>(iv)</enum>
                      <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the person, including any director, officer, or employee of the person, is not the subject of or directly named in any publicly-available debarment, suspension, or Executive order that prohibits receipt of funding from the United States Government; and</text>
                    </clause>
                  </subparagraph>
                  <subparagraph id="HB3CB5AA77CE34336941B8CD5796141C4">
                    <enum>(B)</enum>
                    <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">engaging in any speech or communication with a foreign person that is subject to sanctions under this Act to prevent or alleviate the suffering of a civilian population, including speech or communication to reduce or eliminate the frequency and severity of violent conflict and reducing its impact on the civilian population.</text>
                  </subparagraph>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="H6C493697091E4591A243AFA009CAF8F6">
                  <enum>(2)</enum>
                  <header>Rule of construction</header>
                  <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing contained in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="International Emergency Economic Powers Act/s:203/ss:c/p:1" proposed="true">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref> shall be construed to authorize the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> to prohibit the export of standard, commercially-available goods or services, including communications equipment, software and computers, that are necessary to carry out operations related to the provision of goods or services to prevent or alleviate the suffering of civilian populations that are under the control of a foreign person subject to sanctions under this Act.</text>
                </paragraph>
              </subsection>
              <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
            </quoted-block>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph commented="no" id="HE81ECB5F9F7742D48D1D2FE0C2D48712">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Effective date</header>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendments made by <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Humanitarian Assistance Facilitation Act of 2013/s:4/ss:a/p:1" proposed="true">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref> take effect on the date of enactment of this Act and apply with respect to transactions described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="International Emergency Economic Powers Act/s:203/ss:c/p:1" proposed="true">section 203(c)(1) of the International Emergency Economic Powers Act</cato:entity-ref>, as added by <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Humanitarian Assistance Facilitation Act of 2013/s:4/ss:a/p:1" proposed="true">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref>, entered into on or after such date of enactment.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="H31BF08EAB766465696A46FC8296C25A0">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Advisory Council To Prevent and Alleviate Human Suffering in Areas Under the Control of Certain Sanctioned Foreign Persons</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">
          <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="International Emergency Economic Powers Act/s:203">Section 203 of the International Emergency Economic Powers Act</cato:entity-ref> (<cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/50/1702">50 U.S.C.1702</cato:entity-ref>)</cato:entity>, as amended by <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Humanitarian Assistance Facilitation Act of 2013/s:4/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a) of this section</cato:entity-ref>, is further amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
        <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB389E43F5D744E28B361FD52C1494140" style="OLC">
          <subsection id="H4A68B2DBCD2649DD9B867E68D42996EC">
            <enum>(e)</enum>
            <header>Advisory Council To Prevent and Respond to Human Suffering in Areas Affected by Certain Sanctioned Foreign Persons</header>
            <paragraph id="H9C050DCD622C4628A0BA70773678E42D">
              <enum>(1)</enum>
              <header>Establishment</header>
              <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No later than 90 days after the date of enactment of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Humanitarian Assistance Facilitation Act of 2013" proposed="true">Humanitarian Assistance Facilitation Act of 2013</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref> shall, in consultation with the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1500">Attorney General</cato:entity-ref>, <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="9700">Secretary of Defense</cato:entity-ref>, <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary of the Treasury</cato:entity-ref> and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1300">Secretary of Commerce</cato:entity-ref>, establish an <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Advisory Council on United States Policy Related to Non-Governmental Activities to Prevent and Respond to Human Suffering in Areas Affected By Certain Sanctioned Foreign Persons" proposed="true">Advisory Council on United States Policy Related to Non-Governmental Activities to Prevent and Respond to Human Suffering in Areas Affected By Certain Sanctioned Foreign Persons</cato:entity-ref> (hereafter in this subsection referred to as the <quote>Advisory Council</quote>).</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="H1FCC97011D054396AEF0A5D4880236B1">
              <enum>(2)</enum>
              <header>Membership</header>
              <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Advisory Council on United States Policy Related to Non-Governmental Activities to Prevent and Respond to Human Suffering in Areas Affected By Certain Sanctioned Foreign Persons" proposed="true">Advisory Council</cato:entity-ref> shall be composed of not less than 15 members appointed by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref> from among individuals who are experts in the fields of peace-building, humanitarian aid in areas of armed conflict, representatives from organizations directly involved in the delivery of aid in areas of armed conflict, and other experts with relevant expertise as determined by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="H4815BB71E57E47FE85F545D03D0BA790">
              <enum>(3)</enum>
              <header>Duties</header>
              <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Advisory Council on United States Policy Related to Non-Governmental Activities to Prevent and Respond to Human Suffering in Areas Affected By Certain Sanctioned Foreign Persons" proposed="true">Advisory Council</cato:entity-ref> shall—</text>
              <subparagraph id="H36E8498C823444EDADF92302CDFDCC77">
                <enum>(A)</enum>
                <text>review existing laws, regulations, Executive orders, and administrative actions regulating or prohibiting, directly or indirectly, peacebuilding activities and the provision of humanitarian aid and development assistance in areas under the control of foreign persons that are subject to sanctions under United States law;</text>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="HF2869935A6D84AAFB70983F7A72DA810">
                <enum>(B)</enum>
                <text>conduct additional research and study as necessary on the subjects of counter-terrorism and security measures in relation to the delivery of humanitarian aid and development assistance;</text>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="H8F1B652365554CEAA6EEED3CB17B4831">
                <enum>(C)</enum>
                <text>report to the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref> on its findings; and</text>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="H43D071C4A021437C99086A75CAB50378">
                <enum>(D)</enum>
                <text>make recommendations to the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref> and other officials described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="International Emergency Economic Powers Act/s:203/ss:e/p:1" proposed="true">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref> (as appropriate) on the most efficient and effective means of limiting diversion of humanitarian aid and development assistance while also preserving the impartiality of humanitarian aid and development assistance and the ability of humanitarian organizations to prevent and relieve human suffering of civilian populations.</text>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="H157CB0C9DC9A410CA75DAFD38D42C377">
              <enum>(4)</enum>
              <header>Termination</header>
              <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">
                <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
                  <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Federal Advisory Committee Act/s:14/ss:a/p:2">Section 14(a)(2) of the Federal Advisory Committee Act</cato:entity-ref> (<cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc-appendix/5">5 U.S.C. App.</cato:entity-ref>)</cato:entity> (relating to termination of advisory committees) shall not apply to the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Advisory Council on United States Policy Related to Non-Governmental Activities to Prevent and Respond to Human Suffering in Areas Affected By Certain Sanctioned Foreign Persons" proposed="true">Advisory Council</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
        </quoted-block>
      </subsection>
    </section>
    <section id="H79D83E98B3874BE692BC392C0EE2AA76">
      <enum>5.</enum>
      <header>Amendments to <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/18/2339B">section 2339B</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code</header>
      <subsection id="HE737E5CDAC4545EC99096B6B8DCBC71E">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Definition of material support or resources</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">
          <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc/18/2339B/g/4">
            <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/18/2339B">Section 2339B(g)(4)</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code</cato:entity-ref>, is amended by adding at the end before the semicolon the following: <quote>, except that such term does not include engaging in speech or communication with a terrorist organization to prevent or alleviate the suffering of a civilian population, including speech or communication to reduce or eliminate the frequency and severity of violent conflict and reducing its impact on the civilian population</quote>.</text>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="HE1701754EB7E495383DF19BDED5D4BD7">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Additional exception</header>
        <text>
          <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc/18/2339B/j">
            <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/18/2339B">Section 2339B(j)</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code</cato:entity-ref>, is amended—</text>
        <paragraph id="H279BAF3375DD49C998414345807ADE35">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>by striking <quote>No person</quote> and inserting the following:</text>
          <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H09A53780B84746A6A10C73677B621252" style="OLC">
            <paragraph id="HDF90FAA6C4494A5897D6E692F6EFA6DF">
              <enum>(1)</enum>
              <header>In general</header>
              <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No person</text>
            </paragraph>
            <after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block>
          </quoted-block>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H8687FB89A52D496E9BF92DEC2118FC8D">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>by adding at the end the following:</text>
          <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H805C3464382347C8A7BCD0AB5D1B6C25" style="OLC">
            <paragraph id="H1D2B87AB52E847228735421EDAD5FB25">
              <enum>(2)</enum>
              <header>Additional exception</header>
              <text>No person may be prosecuted under this section in connection with knowingly providing <quote>material support or resources</quote> to a foreign terrorist organization, or attempting or conspiring to do so, if—</text>
              <subparagraph id="H5B5D406261644F4EB676E37A744A934F">
                <enum>(A)</enum>
                <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the material support or resources consists only of transactions that are customary, necessary, and incidental to the donation or provision of goods or services by persons who are not controlled by the foreign terrorist organization to civilian populations, if—</text>
                <clause id="HCE9D6E442FCB45E09E7AB996F129CF10">
                  <enum>(i)</enum>
                  <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the goods or services are limited articles such as food, clothing, and medicine intended to be used to relieve human suffering; and</text>
                </clause>
                <clause id="H3E4F831A3A9D4C258B560BDBC5938EA1">
                  <enum>(ii)</enum>
                  <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the goods or services are not capable of being used to carry out any terrorist activity (as defined in <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
                      <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Immigration and Nationality Act/s:212/ss:a/p:3/sp:B/cl:iii">section 212(a)(3)(B)(iii) of the Immigration and Nationality Act</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1182">
                        <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/8/1182/a/3/B/iii">8 U.S.C. 1182(a)(3)(B)(iii)</cato:entity-ref>
                      </external-xref>)</cato:entity>);</text>
                </clause>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="H8CF49E7397794472B0E2BA32E6FDB656">
                <enum>(B)</enum>
                <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the person, in donating or providing such goods or services to the civilian population, acts in good faith without intent to further the aims or objectives of the foreign terrorist organization and uses its best efforts to minimize any transaction with a foreign terrorist organization;</text>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="H0CDABF93AF3E480F95197C9E66BC467D">
                <enum>(C)</enum>
                <text>the person—</text>
                <clause id="H700388F02917494A885281A7F02DD297">
                  <enum>(i)</enum>
                  <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">prior to, or not later than 10 business days after, the first instance of entering into any transaction described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc/18/2339B/j/2/A" proposed="true">subparagraph (A)</cato:entity-ref>, provides to the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref> notice summarizing the nature and extent of its operations in connection with providing such goods or services; and</text>
                </clause>
                <clause id="HA9F5180A22444F5B83824CE1DD02B7B1">
                  <enum>(ii)</enum>
                  <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">at least once each year during which the person enters into any transaction described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc/18/2339B/j/2/A" proposed="true">subparagraph (A)</cato:entity-ref>, provides to the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref> notice summarizing the nature and extent of its operations in connection with providing such goods or services; and</text>
                </clause>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="H6C17F2EDE29B4AA0B55E16C24B51E620">
                <enum>(D)</enum>
                <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the person donating or providing such goods or services, including any director, officer, or employee of the person is not the subject of or directly named in any publicly-available debarment, suspension, or Executive order that prohibits receipt of funding from the Federal Government.</text>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
          </quoted-block>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H151236C0BF964A6A902EA874C303EC5F">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <header>Effective date</header>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendments made by <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Humanitarian Assistance Facilitation Act of 2013/s:5/ss:b/p:1" proposed="true">paragraphs (1)</cato:entity-ref> and <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Humanitarian Assistance Facilitation Act of 2013/s:5/ss:b/p:2" proposed="true">(2)</cato:entity-ref> take effect on the date of enactment of this Act and apply with respect to transactions described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc/18/2339B/j/2" proposed="true">
              <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/18/2339B">section 2339B(j)(2)</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code</cato:entity-ref>, as added by <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Humanitarian Assistance Facilitation Act of 2013/s:5/ss:b/p:2" proposed="true">paragraph (2)</cato:entity-ref>, entered into on or after such date of enactment.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
    </section>
  </legis-body>
</bill>
</doc>