<doc>
  <docmeta id="113hr5521ih">
    <bill congress="113" type="hr" number="5521" version="ih"/>
    <revision size="8933" annotations="0" status="complete" id="4" commit-time="2014-10-08T20:33:55Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113hr5521ih/4.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H91E644E776E144EC9924A4DF626025A1" public-private="public">
	<metadata>
<dublinCore>
<dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">113 HR 5521 IH: Urban Flooding Awareness Act of 2014</dc:title>
<dc:publisher xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">2014-09-17</dc:date>
<dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>113th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>2d Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 5521</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20140917">September 17, 2014</action-date>
			<action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="Q000023">Mr. Quigley</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="K000210">Mr. King of New York</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Financial Services</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To direct the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency to enter into an agreement
			 with the National Research Council to conduct a study on urban flooding,
			 and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H31CD3B5B085E4984A592D42E3D223972" style="OLC">
		<section id="H1AD56ADC96E0486FAE92B5CE249DFB81" section-type="section-one">
      <enum>1.</enum>
      <header>Short title</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote>
          <short-title>
            <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Urban Flooding Awareness Act of 2014" proposed="true">Urban Flooding Awareness Act of 2014</cato:entity-ref>
          </short-title>
        </quote>.</text>
		</section>
    <section id="H55650B377D694BA6BF37FA30044F68F2">
      <enum>2.</enum>
      <header>Urban flooding defined</header>
			<subsection id="HADB0168A0F8F4C8E9B4D0FFE3FFD9C2E">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>In general</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this Act, the term <quote>urban flooding</quote> means the inundation of property in a built environment, particularly in more densely populated
			 areas, caused by rain falling on increased amounts of impervious surface
			 and overwhelming the capacity of drainage systems, such as storm sewers.</text>
			</subsection>
      <subsection id="H691DD4777CC54DB4AD6A2575460EF90C">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Inclusions</header>
        <text>In this Act, the term <quote>urban flooding</quote> includes—</text>
				<paragraph id="H366A60FCD40642F0B7A9BF0F480E643C">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">situations in which stormwater enters buildings through windows, doors, or other openings;</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HE62D51A8D399442DAEACE8F1162661C9">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>water backup through sewer pipes, showers, toilets, sinks, and floor drains;</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H64BB9842974F49FEA365FFDB09BF4542">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <text>seepage through walls and floors;</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HB131A6671B4D49EAB8F2C57BF2925056">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
          <text>the accumulation of water on property or public rights-of-way; and</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H96678FF42B7644B6BC6D9F75C5220F57">
          <enum>(5)</enum>
          <text>the overflow from water bodies, such as rivers and lakes.</text>
				</paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="H26905D66E4DA440685D348B5C482D804">
        <enum>(c)</enum>
        <header>Exclusion</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this Act, the term <quote>urban flooding</quote> does not include flooding in undeveloped or agricultural areas.</text>
			</subsection>
    </section>
    <section id="HFF2C068292794536A9469DB5F6C394D1">
      <enum>3.</enum>
      <header>Urban flooding study</header>
			<subsection id="HAABC76C09DE946A89DABD67A18E6339D">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Agreement with National Research Council</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="7022" entity-type="federal-body">Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency</cato:entity-ref> shall enter into an agreement with the
			 National Research Council under which the National Research Council will
			 conduct a study on urban flooding in accordance with the requirements of
			 this section.</text>
			</subsection>
      <subsection id="H304C05F782AB472BBCF1328D8BB38D88">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Contents</header>
				<paragraph id="H6D923B99A5E84CE8A619F5501AC0696B">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>General review and evaluation</header>
          <text>In conducting the study, the National Research Council shall review and evaluate the latest
			 available research, laws, regulations, policies, best practices,
			 procedures, and institutional knowledge regarding urban flooding.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HBBA58FFB5BFB44A29358D14C7CAF96C8">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Specific issue areas</header>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The study shall include, at a minimum, an examination of the following:</text>
					<subparagraph id="H70806093248B4C9CA4A582AD59DBBF83">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>The prevalence and costs associated with urban flooding events across the United States, with a
			 focus on the largest metropolitan areas and any clear trends in frequency
			 and severity over the past 2 decades.</text>
					</subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="HF6A79D2042C64A9F8E9909D170F5AD3F">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>The adequacy of existing federally provided flood risk information and the most cost-effective
			 methods and products to identify, map, or otherwise characterize the risk
			 of property damage from urban flooding on a property-by-property basis,
			 whether or not a property is in or adjacent to a 1-percent (100-year)
			 flood plain, and the potential for training and certifying local experts
			 in flood risk characterization as a service to property purchasers and
			 owners and their communities.</text>
					</subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="HD4991B9D5D9B4EC99ED96E5667E6E7F9">
            <enum>(C)</enum>
            <text>The causes of urban flooding and its apparent increase over the past 20 years, including the
			 impacts of—</text>
						<clause id="HFA1504703CAA4F3BB05EF1193BC9F61E">
              <enum>(i)</enum>
              <text>global climate change;</text>
						</clause>
            <clause id="H67066676414646BA85780D076289B00A">
              <enum>(ii)</enum>
              <text>increasing urbanization and the associated increase in impervious surfaces; and</text>
						</clause>
            <clause id="H5A4E416B87C44DD2B32D1008AFEB0EE3">
              <enum>(iii)</enum>
              <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">undersized, deteriorating and otherwise ineffective stormwater infrastructure.</text>
						</clause>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="HE3BE692B596845DCB0EB3E479E2B9B09">
            <enum>(D)</enum>
            <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The most cost-effective strategies, practices, and technologies used to reduce the impacts of urban
			 flooding, with a focus on decentralized, easy-to-install, and low-cost
			 approaches, such as nonstructural and natural infrastructure on public and
			 private property. The examination under this subparagraph shall include an
			 assessment of opportunities for implementing innovative strategies and
			 practices on government-controlled land, such as Federal, State, and local
			 roads, parking lots, alleys, sidewalks, buildings, recreational areas, and
			 open space.</text>
					</subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H8ADB9B6E1749477E8AFA5A721E801593">
            <enum>(E)</enum>
            <text>The role of the Federal Government and State governments, as conveners, funders, and advocates, in
			 spurring market innovations based on public-private-nonprofit
			 partnerships. Such innovations may include smart home technologies for
			 improved flood warning systems connected to high-resolution weather
			 forecast data and Internet- and cellular-based communications systems.</text>
					</subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H15AA82FE37A043BEA12BBC3DC0DEEF3E">
            <enum>(F)</enum>
            <text>The most sustainable and effective methods for funding flood risk and flood damage reduction at all
			 levels of government, including—</text>
						<clause id="HA21B685C80194FE7A3A19F2B9B28CAD5">
              <enum>(i)</enum>
              <text>the potential for establishing a State revolving fund program for flood prevention projects similar
			 to the revolving fund programs under the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Federal Water Pollution Control Act">Federal Water Pollution Control
			 Act</cato:entity-ref> and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Safe Drinking Water Act">Safe Drinking Water Act</cato:entity-ref>;</text>
						</clause>
            <clause id="H95FE83C398514139899DD3506FDD830D">
              <enum>(ii)</enum>
              <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">stormwater fee programs using impervious surface as the basis for fee rates and providing credits
			 for the installation of flood prevention or other stormwater management
			 features;</text>
						</clause>
            <clause id="H5626675D5D5C48A9850567CAD30F0827">
              <enum>(iii)</enum>
              <text>grant programs; and</text>
						</clause>
            <clause id="H7C76934409BD4AC986ABC903A4D9225C">
              <enum>(iv)</enum>
              <text>public-private partnerships.</text>
						</clause>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H6753A813A0D947AE96439E1E18B2D055">
            <enum>(G)</enum>
            <text>Information and education strategies and practices, including nontraditional approaches such as the
			 use of social media, for community leaders, government staff, and property
			 owners on—</text>
						<clause id="H2B0450EECCCC4FD4A05007F43057A951">
              <enum>(i)</enum>
              <text>flood risks;</text>
						</clause>
            <clause id="HE4B197B387C44FEBA9B8B1D9A8453AA4">
              <enum>(ii)</enum>
              <text>flood risk reduction strategies and practices; and</text>
						</clause>
            <clause id="HC31D701A32324249AC6A20521EF761DC">
              <enum>(iii)</enum>
              <text>the availability and effectiveness of different types of flood insurance policies.</text>
						</clause>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H1182093776804B8D8F0A4ADDDCF49A08">
            <enum>(H)</enum>
            <text>The relevance of the National Flood Insurance Program and Community Rating System to urban flooding
			 areas outside traditional flood plains, and strategies for broadening
			 coverage and increasing participation under the programs.</text>
					</subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H45E37D43639243BCB258B22BC0E8DE36">
            <enum>(I)</enum>
            <text>Strategies for protecting downstream communities from the flooding impacts of development in
			 upstream communities, including a review of—</text>
						<clause id="H2D246D8DA58B44E6BF4EAD8843EE04F6">
              <enum>(i)</enum>
              <text>potential standards for watershed-wide flood protection planning; and</text>
						</clause>
            <clause id="HDDDB3735151D4A08A688C76568E7AF4C">
              <enum>(ii)</enum>
              <text>the potential establishment of streamlined legal processes for victims of flood damage, to avoid
			 the need for expensive litigation.</text>
						</clause>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="H6701F7E695A94A32BF8FE65597905C94">
        <enum>(c)</enum>
        <header>Consultation</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="7022" entity-type="federal-body">Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency</cato:entity-ref> shall carry out this section in
			 consultation with the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="2100" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of the Army</cato:entity-ref> (acting through the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="96CE" entity-type="federal-body">Chief of
			 Engineers</cato:entity-ref>), the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="8600" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of Housing and Urban Development</cato:entity-ref>, the
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="6800" entity-type="federal-body">Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency</cato:entity-ref>, and State, regional,
			 and local stormwater management agencies, and such other interested
			 parties as the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="7022" entity-type="federal-body">Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency</cato:entity-ref>
			 considers appropriate.</text>
			</subsection>
      <subsection id="HB4B50439CE1844F699090F0E8792B462">
        <enum>(d)</enum>
        <header>Report to Congress</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 3 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="7022" entity-type="federal-body">Administrator of the Federal
			 Emergency Management Agency</cato:entity-ref> shall submit to the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="HBA00" entity-type="committee">Committee on Financial
			 Services</cato:entity-ref> and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="HAP00" entity-type="committee">Committee on Appropriations of the House of
			 Representatives</cato:entity-ref> and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="SSBK00" entity-type="committee">Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs</cato:entity-ref>
			 and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="SSAP00" entity-type="committee">Committee on Appropriations of the Senate</cato:entity-ref> a report containing the
			 findings of the National Research Council based on the results of the
			 study, including recommendations for implementation of strategies,
			 practices, and technologies relating to urban flooding by <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> and the
			 executive branch.</text>
			</subsection>
    </section>
  </legis-body>
</bill>
</doc>