<doc>
  <docmeta id="113hr3583ih">
    <bill congress="113" type="hr" number="3583" version="ih"/>
    <revision size="9322" annotations="0" status="complete" id="4" commit-time="2013-11-27T21:23:14Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113hr3583ih/4.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H2E2C6770256F47FD87E094444C534643" public-private="public">
  <metadata>
<dublinCore>
<dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">113 HR 3583 IH: Malala Yousafzai Scholarship Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">2013-11-21</dc:date>
<dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
    <congress>113th CONGRESS</congress>
    <session>1st Session</session>
    <legis-num>H. R. 3583</legis-num>
    <current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
    <action>
      <action-date date="20131121">November 21, 2013</action-date>
      <action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="R000435">Ms. Ros-Lehtinen</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="G000377">Ms. Granger</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="L000480">Mrs. Lowey</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name>
      </action-desc>
    </action>
    <legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
    <official-title>To expand the number of scholarships available to Pakistani women under the Merit and Needs-Based Scholarship Program.</official-title>
  </form>
  <legis-body id="H0A40EBDAC8B541ECB8604BD8FDD735EE" style="OLC">
    <section id="H6709E02E4C1D44379AE018EA853F5379" section-type="section-one">
      <enum>1.</enum>
      <header>Short title</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote>
          <short-title>Malala Yousafzai Scholarship Act</short-title>
        </quote>.</text>
    </section>
    <section id="HEED3FFE9B33147D1B502146D78D86989">
      <enum>2.</enum>
      <header>Findings</header>
      <subsection id="HF8530BCC52F74FA486EB0DAB27DA954E">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Findings</header>
        <text>
          <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> makes the following findings:</text>
        <paragraph id="H9B805DC753D84DAB8C14264385A6E144">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>On October 9, 2012, 15-year-old Malala Yousafzai was shot in the head by Taliban gunmen in Pakistan on her way home from school.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H8F87A06349C541479F8F41CE524FC31F">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>When Malala was 11 years old, she bravely stood up to the Taliban and wrote a secret blog documenting their crackdown on women’s rights and education in 2009.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H09DA855285D24B00B696E3D22699E4BC">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <text>Malala’s advocacy for women’s education made her a target of the Taliban.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H25AC90318578473D8267AAC0E1EA889C">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
          <text>The Taliban called Malala’s efforts to highlight the need for women’s education an <quote>obscenity</quote>.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HB6BAA82AF32B4824B6F3FE7267CB5ED2">
          <enum>(5)</enum>
          <text>On July 12, 2013, Malala celebrated her 16th birthday by delivering a speech before the United Nations General Assembly in which she said, <quote>So let us wage a glorious struggle against illiteracy, poverty, and terrorism. Let us pick up our books and our pens. They are the most powerful weapons. One child, one teacher, one book, and one pen can change the world. Education is the only solution.</quote>.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H2C5511FEFE1C4E4292AA9F0BBE693CBB">
          <enum>(6)</enum>
          <text>According to the United Nation’s 2012 Education for All Global Monitoring Report, <quote>Pakistan has the second largest number of children out of school [in the world]</quote> and <quote>nearly half of rural females have never been to school.</quote>.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H79435470A90F4091B26D4EB5B2208957">
          <enum>(7)</enum>
          <text>According to a Council on Foreign Relations report titled <quote>What Works in Girls’ Education</quote>, <quote>A 100-country study by the World Bank shows that increasing the share of women with a secondary education by 1 percent boosts annual per capita income growth by 0.3 percentage points.</quote>.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HC30860642EBF470697FF861BFF731E40">
          <enum>(8)</enum>
          <text>According to the World Bank, <quote>The benefits of women’s education go beyond higher productivity for 50 percent of the population. More educated women also tend to be healthier, participate more in the formal labor market, earn more income, have fewer children, and provide better health care and education to their children, all of which eventually improve the well-being of all individuals and lift households out of poverty. These benefits also transmit across generations, as well as to their communities at large.</quote>.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HA241EFD02283480FBDBA9543F1771C35">
          <enum>(9)</enum>
          <text>According to United Nation’s 2012 Education For All Global Monitoring Report, <quote>education can make a big difference to women’s earnings. In Pakistan, women with a high level of literacy earned 95 percent more than women with no literacy skills.</quote>.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HE5D2E08870944377B2FB25C42350A16D">
          <enum>(10)</enum>
          <text>In January 2010, Secretary of State Hillary Rodham Clinton stated, <quote>We will open the doors of education to all citizens, but especially to girls and women … We are doing all of these things because we have seen that when women and girls have the tools to stay healthy and the opportunity to contribute to their families’ well-being, they flourish and so do the people around them.</quote>.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H3DFD516677A04F52BC56A96CF45ADFA0">
          <enum>(11)</enum>
          <text>The United States provides critical foreign assistance to Pakistan’s education sector to improve access to and the quality of basic and higher education.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HEF727389CB0E45C48212C65289D87493">
          <enum>(12)</enum>
          <text>The Merit and Needs-Based Scholarship Program administered by the United States Agency for International Development awards scholarships to academically talented, financially needy Pakistani students from remote regions of the country to pursue bachelor’s or master’s degrees at participating Pakistani universities.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H2BB00191AFD24FD6AF5C25BC8BA0AC04">
          <enum>(13)</enum>
          <text>Fifty percent of the 974 Merit and Needs-Based Scholarships awarded during fiscal year 2013 were awarded to Pakistani women. Historically, only 25 percent of such scholarships have been awarded to women.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H3721582C706046F184A10FD9F07F07FC">
          <enum>(14)</enum>
          <text>The United Nations declared July 12 as <quote>Malala Day</quote>—a global day of support for and recognition of Malala’s bravery and courage in promoting women’s education.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H31FD734C08954BBA9FD62F38C3562446">
          <enum>(15)</enum>
          <text>On December 10, 2012, the United Nations and the Government of Pakistan launched the <quote>Malala Fund for Girls' Education</quote> to improve girls' access to education worldwide, with Pakistan donating the first $10,000,000 to the Fund.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H1C82E9F431F0481FADCB680F7FB69BEE">
          <enum>(16)</enum>
          <text>More than 1,000,000 people around the world have signed the United Nations Special Envoy for Global Education petition calling on the Government of Pakistan to enroll every boy and girl in primary school.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H5D96E80C124A43C1A0326D3B24E28737">
          <enum>(17)</enum>
          <text>Pakistani civil society organizations collected almost 2,000,000 signatures from Pakistanis on a petition dedicated to Malala’s cause of education for all.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
    </section>
    <section id="HAAF3357866544C72AB5C09CD93C9BBC8">
      <enum>3.</enum>
      <header>Sense of Congress</header>
      <subsection id="H06B15588563743849E28863EF2987F45">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>In general</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It is the sense of <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> that—</text>
        <paragraph id="HA463470C2DB3421CB49159A9BE9756D8">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>every individual should have the opportunity to pursue an education;</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H1350AC27DDAF4BD381822EA9F97F31F5">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>every individual, regardless of gender, should have the opportunity to pursue an education without fear of discrimination; and</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H8903EEBEF8CC40FB803EBD96CAD5FC83">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <text>educational exchanges promote institutional linkages between the United States and Pakistan.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H83995A86BCB24A5C8603EE91AC2E34FD">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Continued support for educational initiatives in Pakistan</header>
        <text>Congress encourages the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Department of State</cato:entity-ref> and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7200">United States Agency for International Development</cato:entity-ref> to continue their support for initiatives led by the Government of Pakistan and Pakistani civil society that promote education in Pakistan, especially education for women.</text>
      </subsection>
    </section>
    <section id="H39E662023A734E4F9039E740C0D14395">
      <enum>4.</enum>
      <header>Merit and Needs-Based Scholarship Program</header>
      <subsection id="H8CB9656E031B42A0961AD24EA1B7F11F">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Expansion</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Using funding made available under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Malala Yousafzai Scholarship Act/s:6" proposed="true">section 6</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7200">Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development</cato:entity-ref> (referred to in this Act as the <quote>USAID Administrator</quote>) shall increase the number of scholarships to women under the Merit and Needs-Based Scholarship Program (referred to in this Act as the <quote>Program</quote>) during each of the calendar years 2013 through 2015 over the level awarded to women in calendar year 2011.</text>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="H4B780C9794D64206A0F2B56D0C896B2B">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Limitations</header>
        <paragraph id="H8496847E2FB14D8BAE373B496F3535B9">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>Criteria</header>
          <text>The additional scholarships available under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Malala Yousafzai Scholarship Act/s:4/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref> may only be awarded in accordance with other scholarship eligibility criteria already established by <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7200">USAID</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H80BBEC83644E4B6B9233345676DBDC1F">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Academic disciplines</header>
          <text>Additional scholarships authorized under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Malala Yousafzai Scholarship Act/s:4/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref> shall be awarded for a range of disciplines to improve the employability of graduates and to meet the needs of the scholarship recipients.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H6DE49AACF50B4AB89A08FC011C3D69B2">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <header>Other scholarships</header>
          <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7200">USAID Administrator</cato:entity-ref> shall make every effort to award 50 percent of the scholarships available under the Program to Pakistani women.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
    </section>
    <section id="H183EC27ACA35403CB318DD6AAFBC9B51">
      <enum>5.</enum>
      <header>Annual congressional briefing</header>
      <subsection id="HCEB93848AF9A4781AE8C762C4393DC80">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>In general</header>
        <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7200">USAID Administrator</cato:entity-ref> shall designate appropriate USAID officials to brief the appropriate congressional committees, not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter for the next 3 years, on the implementation of <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Malala Yousafzai Scholarship Act/s:4" proposed="true">section 4</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="H7613080E6E8040828A588C63E699DFF4">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Contents</header>
        <text>The briefing described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Malala Yousafzai Scholarship Act/s:5/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref> shall include, among other relevant information, for the most recently concluded fiscal year—</text>
        <paragraph id="HB9573B17190346FFA38034904C844F3C">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>the total number of scholarships that were awarded through the Program, including a breakdown by gender;</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HE60C2C6682DF4C649708EE5A1487A243">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>the disciplines of study chosen by the scholarship recipients;</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H35D9A2B1815C4415BD8B8B8DCDA16F0C">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <text>the percentage of the scholarships that were awarded to students seeking a bachelor’s degree or a master’s degree, respectively; and</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H1F4791891DAF41228B4004C395AAC18D">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
          <text>the percentage of scholarship recipients that voluntarily dropped out of school or were involuntarily pushed out of the program for failure to meet program requirements.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
    </section>
    <section id="H473088B6DE94412F8C8B4707869125BF">
      <enum>6.</enum>
      <header>Funding</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">
        <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="auth-auth-approp">Of the amounts authorized to be appropriated for fiscal year 2014 pursuant to <cato:entity entity-type="law-citation">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act">title I of the Enhanced Partnership with Pakistan Act of 2009</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/8411">
          <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/22/8411/etseq">22 U.S.C. 8411 et seq</cato:entity-ref>.</external-xref>)</cato:entity>, <cato:funds-and-year amount="3000000">$3,000,000</cato:funds-and-year> shall be made available <cato:property name="purpose">for scholarships authorized under <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Malala Yousafzai Scholarship Act/s:4/ss:a" proposed="true">section 4(a)</cato:entity-ref>
          </cato:property>.</cato:entity>
      </text>
    </section>
  </legis-body>
</bill>
</doc>