<doc>
  <docmeta id="113hr2037ih">
    <bill congress="113" type="hr" number="2037" version="ih"/>
    <revision size="12624" annotations="0" status="complete" id="6" commit-time="2013-07-09T15:47:07Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113hr2037ih/6.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HA7701E3B56D84E48887B93C0ED71044C" public-private="public"> 
<metadata>
<dublinCore>
<title>113 HR 2037 IH: Native American Psychiatric and Mental Health Care Improvement Act</title>
<publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</publisher>
<date>2013-05-16</date>
<format>text/xml</format>
<language>EN</language>
<rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>113th CONGRESS</congress> <session>1st Session</session> 
<legis-num>H. R. 2037</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20130516">May 16, 2013</action-date> 
<action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="S001180">Mr. Schrader</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Natural Resources</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc> 
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To establish a demonstration grant program to recruit, train, deploy, and professionally support psychiatric physicians in Indian health programs.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="HEBCC7FAE47904222AAF314B98CCDE73C" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HC9DB1DC761804B4CB9B6660C7EFFB741" section-type="section-one">
      <enum>1.</enum>
      <header>Short title</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote>
          <short-title>Native American Psychiatric and Mental Health Care Improvement Act</short-title>
        </quote>.</text> </section>
<section id="HEEADF403266A4879A1EAD4495A9CC53A">
      <enum>2.</enum>
      <header>Findings</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">
        <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> makes the following findings:</text> 
<paragraph id="HA75A10FBFF5B4726B6F29C8D8EB322F6">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7522">Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration</cato:entity-ref> concludes the rate of serious mental illness in American Indians and Alaska Natives is twice that of any other race or ethnicity.</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H5493CE0462FA4CC79E14257E6A743D73">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7523">Centers for Disease Control and Prevention</cato:entity-ref> concludes the suicide rate among American Indian and Alaska Native youth is more than twice that of any other race or ethnicity.</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H6A26CE74CA6C4E6CB515ED5E12BC3BC8">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="21MD">United States Surgeon General</cato:entity-ref> attributes high rates of homelessness, incarceration, alcohol and drug abuse, stress, and trauma as principal causes of mental illness in American Indians and Alaska Natives.</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H5944F57B829E470595964E656CC044F7">
        <enum>(4)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7528">Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality</cato:entity-ref> concludes in The National Health Disparity Report, 2011, that American Indians and Alaska Natives had worse care than Whites in 28 measures of health care quality and access.</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H96ABEFDB4E5648B6854D659313397DC7">
        <enum>(5)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Indian Health Service reports that per capita spending on personal health care of American Indians and Alaska Natives was $2,741 in 2012—nearly two-thirds below the national average of $7,239.</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H1BAF0235FB3345D9A3217791131FBD0D">
        <enum>(6)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7504">Department of Health and Human Services, Office of Inspector General</cato:entity-ref>, reports that a shortage of psychiatrists at the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7527">Indian Health Service</cato:entity-ref> and other tribal health facilities significantly limits mental health access to American Indians and Alaska Natives.</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HD2B4ADB22D0A4EA8954751EF1FFCC574">
        <enum>(7)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The One Sky Center, the American Indian/Alaska Native National Resource Center for Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services, identifies 20 psychiatrists currently practicing in Indian country (out of approximately 60,000 psychiatrists practicing nationwide), and 2 Native American psychiatrists currently practicing in Indian country (out of 13 practicing nationwide).</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H7B7E4C44324341F2BA5B3D4DC9004231">
        <enum>(8)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">According to the American Psychiatric Association, psychiatric physicians practicing in American Indian and Alaska Native population groups often face cultural competency challenges, professional isolation, high demand for medical and mental health services, relatively low compensation, and high burnout rates.</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H10E2C76A6F8E4FEC9ED99FAFC723DB06">
        <enum>(9)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A legislative initiative is warranted to create a nationally-replicable workforce model that identifies and incorporates best practices for recruiting, training, deploying, and professionally supporting Native American psychiatric physicians or non-Native American psychiatric physicians (or both), who are fully integrated into existing medical, mental, and behavioral health systems in Indian health programs.</text> </paragraph>
    </section>
<section id="H917DBC31EB4545BF8F0145D77571F63D">
      <enum>3.</enum>
      <header>Demonstration grant program to recruit, train, deploy, and professionally support psychiatric physicians in Indian health programs</header> 
<subsection id="H3CCF46EF35D244379251BBFE1F32A213">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Establishment</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary of Health and Human Services</cato:entity-ref> (in this section referred to as the <quote>Secretary</quote>), in consultation with the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7527">Director of the Indian Health Service</cato:entity-ref> and demonstration programs established under <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Indian Health Care Improvement Act/s:123">section 123 of the Indian Health Care Improvement Act</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/1616p">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/25/1616p">25 U.S.C. 1616p</cato:entity-ref>
            </external-xref>)</cato:entity>, shall award one 5-year grant to one eligible entity to carry out a demonstration program (in this Act referred to as the <quote>Program</quote>) under which the eligible entity shall carry out the activities described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Native American Psychiatric and Mental Health Care Improvement Act/s:3/ss:b" proposed="true">subsection (b)</cato:entity-ref>.</text> </subsection>
<subsection id="HBD7BB6E2FC0B4FB7A974844C9E0C5FAD">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Activities To be carried out by recipient of grant under Program</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Under the Program, the grant recipient shall—</text> 
<paragraph id="HB7CE3A42FC1943AFA3D1355C6A8658BC">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>create a nationally-replicable workforce model that identifies and incorporates best practices for recruiting, training, deploying, and professionally supporting Native American and non-Native American psychiatric physicians to be fully integrated into medical, mental, and behavioral health systems in Indian health programs;</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H1C785ACED58D4831AAD8CE2E771ABA52">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>recruit to participate in the Program Native American and non-Native American psychiatric physicians who demonstrate interest in providing specialty health care services (as defined in <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Indian Health Care Improvement Act/s:313/ss:a/p:3">section 313(a)(3) of the Indian Health Care Improvement Act</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/1638g">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/25/1638g/a/3">25 U.S.C. 1638g(a)(3)</cato:entity-ref>
              </external-xref>)</cato:entity>) and primary care services to American Indians and Alaska Natives;</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H8177C7BA55E44BEE89AD2EAA059799CC">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <text>provide such psychiatric physicians participating in the Program with not more than 1 year of supplemental clinical and cultural competency training to enable such physicians to provide such specialty health care services and primary care services in Indian health programs;</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HED4B6F4F34B44057A55933C93A779203">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
          <text>with respect to such psychiatric physicians who are participating in the Program and trained under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Native American Psychiatric and Mental Health Care Improvement Act/s:3/ss:b/p:3" proposed="true">paragraph (3)</cato:entity-ref>, deploy such physicians to practice specialty care or primary care in Indian health programs for a period of not less than 2 years and professionally support such physicians for such period with respect to practicing such care in such programs; and</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HDAD139AB5E5F42BB8500D490532C4AAB">
          <enum>(5)</enum>
          <text>not later than 1 year after the last day of the 5-year period for which the grant is awarded under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Native American Psychiatric and Mental Health Care Improvement Act/s:3/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref>, submit to the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> and to the appropriate committees of <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> a report that shall include—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HB6E4D7B940AA4DA8BC1581D2A7B3FE4B">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>the workforce model created under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Native American Psychiatric and Mental Health Care Improvement Act/s:3/ss:b/p:1" proposed="true">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref>;</text> </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HB702CDC7F5834F3B848F05A09F81CC23">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>strategies for disseminating the workforce model to other entities with the capability of adopting it; and</text> </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H4E58276AFDDE471BBB36C6CAB2FE1B00">
            <enum>(C)</enum>
            <text>recommendations for the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> and <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> with respect to supporting an effective and stable psychiatric and mental health workforce that serves American Indians and Alaska Natives.</text> </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
<subsection id="H91353A6723EB4610BFE03C1E6DA619E3">
        <enum>(c)</enum>
        <header>Eligible entities</header> 
<paragraph id="H780F2A990E4A473F8E47900BA6A3E48E">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>Requirements</header>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To be eligible to receive the grant under this section, an entity shall—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H5C884545ED074AE69F10E82752361FEF">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>submit to the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> may require;</text> </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HAF951ED405EC4EFDB71E3A4E8551FB0E">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">be a department of psychiatry within a medical school in the United States that is accredited by the Liaison Committee on Medical Education or a public or private non-profit entity affiliated with a medical school in the United States that is accredited by the Liaison Committee on Medical Education; and</text> </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HD1B3505F0C524F4BB9EBC7BD1EB1C278">
            <enum>(C)</enum>
            <text>have in existence, as of the time of submission of the application under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Native American Psychiatric and Mental Health Care Improvement Act/s:3/ss:c/p:1/sp:A" proposed="true">subparagraph (A)</cato:entity-ref>, a relationship with Indian health programs in at least two States with a demonstrated need for psychiatric physicians and provide assurances that the grant will be used to serve rural and non-rural American Indian and Alaska Native populations in at least two States.</text> </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H3A35FB7BF79A46CEA16D567368868F9A">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Priority in selecting grant recipient</header>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In awarding the grant under this section, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall give priority to an eligible entity that satisfies each of the following:</text> 
<subparagraph id="HAF1D87ABA0BD480DA0B52C2FB16C9F50">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>Demonstrates sufficient infrastructure in size, scope, and capacity to undertake the supplemental clinical and cultural competency training of a minimum of 5 psychiatric physicians, and to provide ongoing professional support to psychiatric physicians during the deployment period to an Indian health program.</text> </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H9BB9AB86A6E845D3A466C5ACC139BD8B">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>Demonstrates a record in successfully recruiting, training, and deploying physicians who are American Indians and Alaska Natives.</text> </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H5F31D45FC9B44CFFBDB2305C1BA94724">
            <enum>(C)</enum>
            <text>Demonstrates the ability to establish a program advisory board, which may be primarily composed of representatives of federally-recognized tribes, Alaska Natives, and Indian health programs to be served by the Program.</text> </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
<subsection commented="no" id="H7C8A18658DFE479694FDC8859DF6331A">
        <enum>(d)</enum>
        <header>Eligibility of psychiatric physicians To participate in the Program</header> 
<paragraph commented="no" id="H8007283C9420474B84CD7252FCEFD021">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>In general</header>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To be eligible to participate in the Program, as described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Native American Psychiatric and Mental Health Care Improvement Act/s:3/ss:b" proposed="true">subsection (b)</cato:entity-ref>, a psychiatric physician shall—</text> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H4D75FAC2E12C42CBB8D017AB412436B0">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>be licensed or eligible for licensure to practice in the State to which the physician is to be deployed under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Native American Psychiatric and Mental Health Care Improvement Act/s:3/ss:b/p:4" proposed="true">subsection (b)(4)</cato:entity-ref>; and</text> </subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H76993CEE3BDC49B0AF5595491E5A3534">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>demonstrate a commitment beyond the one year of training described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Native American Psychiatric and Mental Health Care Improvement Act/s:3/ss:b/p:3" proposed="true">subsection (b)(3)</cato:entity-ref> and two years of deployment described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Native American Psychiatric and Mental Health Care Improvement Act/s:3/ss:b/p:4" proposed="true">subsection (b)(4)</cato:entity-ref> to a career as a specialty care physician or primary care physician providing mental health services in Indian health programs.</text> </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" id="H68492CFA2AB744E5984D0981B640ED51">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Preference</header>
          <text>In selecting physicians to participate under the Program, as described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Native American Psychiatric and Mental Health Care Improvement Act/s:3/ss:b/p:2" proposed="true">subsection (b)(2)</cato:entity-ref>, the grant recipient shall give preference to physicians who are American Indians and Alaska Natives.</text> </paragraph>
      </subsection>
<subsection commented="no" id="H1ACDB2ACB1AC4BBCB242676621E921D0">
        <enum>(e)</enum>
        <header>Loan forgiveness</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Under the Program, any psychiatric physician accepted to participate in the Program shall, notwithstanding the provisions of <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Indian Health Care Improvement Act/s:108/ss:b">subsection (b) of section 108 of the Indian Health Care Improvement Act</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/1616a">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/25/1616a">25 U.S.C. 1616a</cato:entity-ref>
            </external-xref>)</cato:entity> and upon acceptance into the Program, be deemed eligible and enrolled to participate in the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Indian Health Service Loan Repayment Program">Indian Health Service Loan Repayment Program</cato:entity-ref> under such <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Indian Health Care Improvement Act/s:108">section 108</cato:entity-ref>. Under such <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Indian Health Service Loan Repayment Program">Loan Repayment Program</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall pay on behalf of the physician for each year of deployment under the Program under this section up to $35,000 for loans described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Indian Health Care Improvement Act/s:108/ss:g/p:1">subsection (g)(1) of such section 108</cato:entity-ref>.</text> </subsection>
<subsection commented="no" id="HEE270FA47F2847C78B7CBF53B6455146">
        <enum>(f)</enum>
        <header>Deferral of certain service</header>
        <text>The starting date of required service of individuals in the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="National Health Service Corps Service Program">National Health Service Corps Service Program</cato:entity-ref> under <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Public Health Service Act/t:II">title II of the Public Health Service Act</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/202">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/42/202/etseq">42 U.S.C. 202 et seq.</cato:entity-ref>
            </external-xref>)</cato:entity> who are psychiatric physicians participating under the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Indian Health Service Loan Repayment Program">Program</cato:entity-ref> under this section shall be deferred until the date that is 30 days after the date of completion of the participation of such a physician in the Program under this section.</text> </subsection>
<subsection id="H5880EE1F49D84AE288EB992F66B911FA">
        <enum>(g)</enum>
        <header>Definitions</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this Act:</text> 
<paragraph id="H881FBA6F9CE144248E361C45C1A23788">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>American Indians and Alaska Natives</header>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>American Indians and Alaska Natives</term> has the meaning given the term <term>Indian</term> in <external-xref legal-doc="regulation" parsable-cite="cfr/42/447.50">section 447.50(b)(1)</external-xref> of title 42, Code of Federal Regulations, as in existence as of the date of the enactment of this Act.</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HD220A069A423464486111064925DBDE3">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Indian health program</header>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Indian health program</term> has the meaning given such term in <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Indian Health Care Improvement Act/s:104/p:12">section 104(12) of the Indian Health Care Improvement Act</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/1603">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/25/1603//12">25 U.S.C. 1603(12)</cato:entity-ref>
              </external-xref>)</cato:entity>.</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H829F8ECE8E0F41ED9B949C4A964C2256">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <header>Professionally support</header>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>professionally support</term> means, with respect to psychiatric physicians participating in the Program and deployed to practice specialty care or primary care in Indian health programs, the provision of compensation to such physicians for the provision of such care during such deployment and may include the provision, dissemination, or sharing of best practices, field training, and other activities deemed appropriate by the recipient of the grant under this section.</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H50D4C290DD864FA1AFB844B6C0BB5F40">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
          <header>Psychiatric physician</header>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>psychiatric physician</term> means a medical doctor or doctor of osteopathy in good standing who has successfully completed four-year psychiatric residency training or who is enrolled in four-year psychiatric residency training in a residency program accredited by the Accreditation Council for Graduate Medical Education.</text> </paragraph>
      </subsection>
<subsection id="H0EFD5CA810A8459D9F48FEB9141E0DDA">
        <enum>(h)</enum>
        <header>Authorization of appropriations</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">
          <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="auth-auth-approp">There is authorized to be appropriated <cato:property name="purpose">to carry out <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Native American Psychiatric and Mental Health Care Improvement Act/s:3" proposed="true">this section</cato:entity-ref>
            </cato:property> <cato:funds-and-year amount="1000000" year="2014, 2015, 2016, 2017, 2018">$1,000,000 for each of the fiscal years 2014 through 2018</cato:funds-and-year>.</cato:entity>
        </text> </subsection>
    </section>
</legis-body> 
</bill>
</doc>