<doc>
  <docmeta id="113hr2480ih">
    <bill congress="113" type="hr" number="2480" version="ih"/>
    <revision size="17235" annotations="0" status="complete" id="3" commit-time="2013-08-20T22:27:14Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113hr2480ih/3.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H8ECA35CDF07E434A8559ECA653317B46" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>113 HR 2480 IH: Nurse and Health Care Worker Protection Act of 2013</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2013-06-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>113th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 2480</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20130625">June 25, 2013</action-date>
			<action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="C000714">Mr. Conyers</sponsor> (for
			 himself and <cosponsor name-id="M000725">Mr. George Miller of
			 California</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to
			 the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and the
			 Workforce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on
			 <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name> and
			 <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a
			 period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for
			 consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the
			 committee concerned</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To direct the Secretary of Labor to issue an occupational
		  safety and health standard to reduce injuries to patients, nurses, and all
		  other health care workers by establishing a safe patient handling, mobility,
		  and injury prevention standard, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H0115AFABF33543AA80B4778E182D0075" style="OLC">
		<section id="H0AAB4B3165914F3489BCB5E2A1663786" section-type="section-one">
      <enum>1.</enum>
      <header>Short title; findings; table
			 of contents</header>
			<subsection id="H35C0CE79DD4642A383C07748C47FAF6B">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Short
			 Title</header>
        <text>This Act may be cited as the <quote>
            <short-title>Nurse and Health Care Worker Protection Act of
			 2013</short-title>
          </quote>.</text>
			</subsection>
      <subsection id="HBCCF65BAEF2546ED98ABFE6C4DE30A54">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Findings</header>
        <text>
          <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref>
			 finds the following:</text>
				<paragraph id="HB7C26BF7FEEC430F92A7F19BA6C49F50">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In 2011, registered nurses ranked fifth
			 among all occupations for the number of cases of musculoskeletal disorders
			 resulting in days away from work, with 11,880 total cases. In 2011, nursing
			 assistants reported 25,010 cases—the highest of all occupations. The leading
			 cause of these health care employees’ injuries is patient lifting,
			 transferring, and repositioning injuries, which constitute a significant risk
			 to the health and welfare of those employees.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HC2EAAF7C95EB46729281643D443B4557">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The physical demands of the nursing
			 profession lead many nurses to leave the profession. Fifty-two percent of
			 nurses complain of chronic back pain and 38 percent suffer from pain severe
			 enough to require leave from work. Many nurses and other health care workers
			 suffering back injury do not return to work. These consequences constitute a
			 material impairment of health for these employees.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HF90D35E6DE0B458E9B3F23DEA4E9A07B">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Patients are not at optimum levels of
			 safety while being lifted, transferred, or repositioned manually. Mechanical
			 and other appropriate lift programs can substantially reduce skin tears and
			 pressure ulcers suffered by patients and the frequency of patients being
			 dropped, thus allowing patients a safer means to progress through their
			 care.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H108F6E28E2E341BEAA43827A6D32ACE1">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The development of assistive patient
			 handling technology, equipment, and devices has essentially rendered the act of
			 strict manual patient handling outdated and typically unnecessary as a function
			 of nursing care.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HAB88F6CFC21141D289F928ADE70B48B0">
          <enum>(5)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A growing number of health care facilities
			 that have incorporated patient handling technology and practices have reported
			 positive results. Injuries among nursing staff and health care workers have
			 dramatically declined at health care facilities implementing safe patient
			 handling technology, equipment, devices, and practices. As a result, the number
			 of lost work days due to injury and staff turnover has declined. Studies have
			 also shown that assistive patient handling technology successfully reduces
			 workers’ compensation costs for musculoskeletal disorders.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph commented="no" id="H536DAD3196F746F38B926A752AA510A1">
          <enum>(6)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A number of States have implemented safe
			 patient handling, mobility and injury prevention standards. The success of
			 these programs at the facility and State level demonstrates the feasibility of
			 such standards.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H2A99713F610547E58F98E1AF9EA6D861">
          <enum>(7)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Establishing a safe patient handling,
			 mobility, and injury prevention standard for direct-care registered nurses and
			 other health care workers is a critical component reasonably necessary for
			 protecting the health and safety of nurses and other health care workers,
			 addressing the nursing shortage, and increasing patient safety.</text>
				</paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection commented="no" id="HDD69D0B886D84F50AF0B87DE0D69E7EE">
        <enum>(c)</enum>
        <header>Table of
			 contents</header>
        <text>The table of contents of this Act is as follows:</text>
				<toc container-level="legis-body-container" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded" lowest-level="section" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" regeneration="yes-regeneration">
					<toc-entry idref="H0AAB4B3165914F3489BCB5E2A1663786" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title; findings; table of contents.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H04E0A1A5392D43929621B4EACD86826B" level="section">Sec. 2. Safe patient handling, mobility, and injury prevention
				standard.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H9EF1BE6E5D7D45F981E59F749C2687FF" level="section">Sec. 3. Application of safe patient handling, mobility, and
				injury prevention standard to facilities receiving Medicare and Medicaid
				funds.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HB6B50F92858647EF832708D397EA037B" level="section">Sec. 4. Nonpreemption.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HB1BFE4F85B6443768DA032C3F91CE62F" level="section">Sec. 5. Definitions.</toc-entry>
				</toc>
			</subsection>
    </section>
    <section id="H04E0A1A5392D43929621B4EACD86826B">
      <enum>2.</enum>
      <header>Safe patient
			 handling, mobility, and injury prevention standard</header>
			<subsection id="H79B9B4811CB149C891EC4844F5B06601">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Rulemaking</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law,
			 not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1600">Secretary of
			 Labor</cato:entity-ref> shall, pursuant to <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Occupational Safety and Health Act of 1970/s:6">section 6 of the Occupational Safety and Health Act of
			 1970</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/655">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/29/655">29 U.S.C. 655</cato:entity-ref>
            </external-xref>)</cato:entity>, promulgate an interim final standard on safe patient
			 handling, mobility, and injury prevention (in this section such standard is
			 referred to as the <term>safe patient handling, mobility, and injury prevention
			 standard</term>) to prevent musculoskeletal disorders for direct-care
			 registered nurses and all other health care workers handling patients. A final
			 safe patient handling, mobility, and injury prevention standard shall be
			 promulgated not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this
			 Act.</text>
			</subsection>
      <subsection id="H6BE99FA4854A486A8AE2E8C2A29E3F18">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Requirements</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The safe patient handling, mobility, and
			 injury prevention standard shall require the use of engineering and safety
			 controls to perform handling of patients and the elimination of injuries from
			 manual handling of patients by direct-care registered nurses and all other
			 health care workers, through the development of a comprehensive program, to
			 include the use of mechanical technology and devices to the greatest degree
			 feasible. Where the use of mechanical technology and devices is not feasible,
			 the standards shall require the use of alternative controls and measures,
			 including trained, designated lift teams, to minimize the risk of injury to
			 nurses and health care workers resulting from the manual handling of patients.
			 The standard shall apply to all health care employers, shall generally align
			 with interprofessional national safe patient handling, mobility, and injury
			 prevention standards, and shall include the following:</text>
				<paragraph id="H39EFD578944F4699903AA337A405BDE3">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>Program
			 development</header>
          <text>A requirement that each health care employer shall
			 develop and implement a safe patient handling, mobility, and injury prevention
			 program within 6 months of the date of promulgation of the final standard,
			 which program shall include hazard identification, risk assessments, and
			 control measures in relation to patient care duties and patient
			 handling.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H555B65716E8B4A2283EA7C0F3EB243F3">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Technology and
			 equipment purchase and management</header>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A requirement that, within 2 years of the
			 date of promulgation of the final standard, each health care employer shall
			 purchase, use, maintain, and make accessible to health care workers, such safe
			 patient handling equipment, technology, and accessories as the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1600">Secretary</cato:entity-ref>
			 determines appropriate.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HDA8CD7A8BB9E4735990C69AE5BAE29E9">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <header>Health care
			 worker participation</header>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A
			 requirement that each health care employer shall obtain input from health care
			 workers, to include direct care registered nurses, health care workers, their
			 representatives, and their collective bargaining agents, in developing and
			 implementing the safe patient handling, mobility, and injury prevention
			 program, including the purchase of technology and equipment and necessary
			 accessories.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph commented="no" id="H773A2FF0D7CB4ADBA6EF94C5F5C4B7D9">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
          <header>Data tracking
			 and review</header>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A requirement that
			 each health care employer shall establish a review program to analyze data
			 relevant to the implementation of the employers’ safe patient handling,
			 mobility, and injury prevention program, and shall account for circumstances
			 where safe patient handling technology and equipment, or trained, designated
			 lift teams, were not utilized in accordance with the health care employers safe
			 patient handling, mobility, and injury prevention standard. Each health care
			 employer shall upon request, make available their findings and data used in
			 such review, to health care workers, their representatives, their collective
			 bargaining agents, and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1600">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> or other Federal agency.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HF842704C41F04DB3875169E4EE3AE70E">
          <enum>(5)</enum>
          <header>Incorporation of
			 Technology into Facilities</header>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A
			 requirement that each health care employer shall consider the feasibility of
			 incorporating safe patient handling technology as part of process of new
			 facility design and construction, or facility remodeling.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HB6C298E61C1D454B80AB9900F7E75453">
          <enum>(6)</enum>
          <header>Education and
			 training</header>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A requirement that
			 each health care employer shall train health care workers on safe patient
			 handling, mobility, and injury prevention policies, technology, equipment, and
			 devices, initially, and on a continuing annual basis, and as necessary. Such
			 training shall prepare health care workers, including designated lift teams, to
			 identify, assess, and control musculoskeletal hazards of a general nature, and
			 those specific to particular patient care areas, and shall be conducted by an
			 individual with knowledge in the subject matter, and delivered, at least in
			 part, in an interactive simulated point-of-care training and hands-on format
			 that reflects the specific demands of a health care workers’ duties.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HAE8602E668C0447C9D4139E8C1115BFA">
          <enum>(7)</enum>
          <header>Notice of safe
			 patient handling and rights under this Act</header>
          <text>A requirement that
			 each health care employer shall post a uniform notice in a form specified by
			 the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1600">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> that—</text>
					<subparagraph id="H9B3466DF241C4AB78E650882A1A22092">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>explains the safe
			 patient handling, mobility, and injury prevention standard;</text>
					</subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="HCEA2147E44DA4B49B441C025FB4C43CB">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>includes
			 information regarding safe patient handling, mobility, and injury prevention
			 policies and training;</text>
					</subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H822486A7F5BD46E4B11A5CCDF71281DD">
            <enum>(C)</enum>
            <text>explains
			 procedures to report patient handling-related injuries; and</text>
					</subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="HECA8BE785C9F48598AA554D1CF5ECEDE">
            <enum>(D)</enum>
            <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">explains health care workers’ rights under
			 this Act.</text>
					</subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HF484504C799A4D1EB7CAAF94A6586BF0">
          <enum>(8)</enum>
          <header>Annual
			 evaluation</header>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A requirement that
			 each health care employer shall conduct an annual written evaluation of the
			 implementation of the safe patient handling, mobility, and injury prevention
			 program, including handling procedures, selection of technology, equipment, and
			 engineering controls, assessment of injuries, and new safe patient handling,
			 mobility, and injury prevention technology and devices that have been
			 developed. The evaluation shall be conducted with the involvement of nurses,
			 other health care workers, their representatives, and their collective
			 bargaining agents, and their input shall be documented in the evaluation.
			 Health care employers shall take corrective action as recommended in the
			 written evaluation.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HE64A885579A447F8ACAB508C7460429A">
          <enum>(9)</enum>
          <header>Right to Refuse
			 Unsafe Assignment</header>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A
			 requirement that each health care employer shall provide procedures under which
			 a health care worker or employee may refuse to perform the employee’s duties if
			 the employee has a reasonable apprehension that performing such duties would
			 violate the safe patient handling, mobility, and injury prevention standard,
			 and would result in injury or impairment of health to the health care worker,
			 other health care workers, or patients. Where practicable, the health care
			 worker must have communicated the health or safety concern to the health care
			 employer and have not been able to obtain a correction of the violation.</text>
				</paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="HAC0E3275A6704129BD24ADCEDE4F3C31">
        <enum>(c)</enum>
        <header>Inspections</header>
        <text>The
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1600">Secretary of Labor</cato:entity-ref> shall conduct unscheduled inspections under <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Occupational Safety and Health Act of 1970/s:8">section 8 of the
			 Occupational Safety and Health Act of 1970</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/657">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/29/657">29 U.S.C. 657</cato:entity-ref>
            </external-xref>)</cato:entity> to ensure
			 implementation of and compliance with the safe patient handling, mobility, and
			 injury prevention standard.</text>
			</subsection>
    </section>
    <section id="H9EF1BE6E5D7D45F981E59F749C2687FF">
      <enum>3.</enum>
      <header>Application of
			 safe patient handling, mobility, and injury prevention standard to facilities
			 receiving Medicare and Medicaid funds</header>
			<subsection id="H6624C637C87E474DAB99FC80F622C9ED">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>In
			 general</header>
        <text>
          <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Social Security Act/s:1866">Section 1866 of the Social Security Act</cato:entity-ref> (<cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/42/1395cc">42 U.S.C.
			 1395cc</cato:entity-ref>)</cato:entity> is amended—</text>
				<paragraph id="H7E38067842944FA59C756A8CAF807970">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Social Security Act/s:1866/ss:a/p:1/sp:V">subsection
			 (a)(1)(V)</cato:entity-ref>, by inserting <quote>and safe patient handling, mobility, and injury
			 prevention standard (as initially promulgated under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Nurse and Health Care Worker Protection Act of 2009/s:2">section 2 of the Nurse and
			 Health Care Worker Protection Act of 2009</cato:entity-ref>)</quote> before the period at the
			 end; and</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HEA01B77221E345C7AD41AD6DE2EA9D31">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Social Security Act/s:1866/ss:b/p:4">subsection
			 (b)(4)</cato:entity-ref>—</text>
					<subparagraph id="H8F314ED6F1964F128B0C46D9D3A8D040">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Social Security Act/s:1866/ss:b/p:4/sp:A">subparagraph
			 (A)</cato:entity-ref>, inserting <quote>and the safe patient handling, mobility, and injury
			 prevention standard</quote> after <quote>Bloodborne Pathogens standard</quote>;
			 and</text>
					</subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H58B5035E1E734FA19D8FB35EE7BC6BC4">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Social Security Act/s:1866/ss:b/p:4/sp:B">subparagraph
			 (B)</cato:entity-ref>, inserting <quote>or the safe patient handling, mobility, and injury
			 prevention standard</quote> after <quote>Bloodborne Pathogens
			 standard</quote>.</text>
					</subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="H12B08AC4DB81419BA4E1099D972224A6">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Effective
			 date</header>
        <text>The amendments made by <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Nurse and Health Care Worker Protection Act of 2013/s:3/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref> shall apply to health
			 care facilities 1 year after date of issuance of the final safe patient
			 handling, mobility, and injury prevention standard required under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Nurse and Health Care Worker Protection Act of 2013/s:2" proposed="true">section
			 2</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
			</subsection>
    </section>
    <section id="HB6B50F92858647EF832708D397EA037B">
      <enum>4.</enum>
      <header>Nonpreemption</header>
			<subsection id="H134732132D804856A4364350AD95E99C">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Effect on other
			 laws</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this Act
			 shall be construed to—</text>
				<paragraph id="HCF639A32666E4C35B68AD5F477E164D4">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>preempt any law,
			 rule, or regulation of a State or political subdivision of a State, unless such
			 law, rule, or regulation is in conflict with this Act or a regulation or order
			 issued under this Act; or</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H25DB80AA7EB6459781317F43E5033795">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>impair or diminish
			 in any way the authority of any State to enact and enforce any law which
			 provides equivalent or greater protections for employees engaging in conduct
			 protected under this Act.</text>
				</paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="H8629ABCDBD2343B9A8485B6BC7E64DD8">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Rights Retained
			 by Health Care Workers</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this Act shall be construed to
			 diminish the rights, privileges, or remedies of any health care worker or
			 employee under any Federal or State law, or under any collective bargaining
			 agreement.</text>
			</subsection>
    </section>
    <section id="HB1BFE4F85B6443768DA032C3F91CE62F">
      <enum>5.</enum>
      <header>Definitions</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">For purposes of this Act:</text>
			<paragraph id="H2B9560C5AB81488781D07EBF12E9F9C1">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <header>Direct-care
			 registered nurse</header>
        <text>The term <term>direct-care registered
			 nurse</term> means an individual who has been granted a license by at least one
			 State to practice as a registered nurse and who provides bedside care or
			 outpatient services for one or more patients or residents.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H60B51D75D8424DFF97A26C560FB17A87">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <header>Employee</header>
        <text>The
			 term <term>employee </term> means any individual employed by a health care
			 employer, to include health care workers, as well as employees who do not
			 qualify as health care workers, including independent contractors.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H4767D0C7A5EA494A8A907882235DC40A">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <header>Employment</header>
        <text>The
			 term <term>employment</term> includes the provision of services under a
			 contract or other arrangement.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H993B1BB5DE934A549C705C8704A143BC">
        <enum>(4)</enum>
        <header>Handling</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>handling</term> includes
			 actions such as lifting, transferring, repositioning, mobilizing, moving, or
			 any other action involving the physical movement, manipulation, or support of a
			 patient by a health care worker, or any direct patient care action which
			 presents a risk of musculoskeletal injury.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H624FA86344CD430F805B877873661561">
        <enum>(5)</enum>
        <header>Health care
			 employer</header>
        <text>The term <term>health care employer</term> means an
			 outpatient health care facility, hospital, nursing home, home health care
			 agency, social assistance facility or program, hospice, federally qualified
			 health center, nurse managed health center, rural health clinic, or any similar
			 health care facility that employs direct-care registered nurses or other health
			 care workers.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H18D1196A13914CC4ACFEFC918D0C2B0B">
        <enum>(6)</enum>
        <header>Health care
			 worker</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>health
			 care worker</term> means an individual who has been assigned by a health care
			 employer to engage in patient handling, including direct-care registered
			 nurses, independent contractors, or individuals who perform the duties of
			 health care workers.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HB4E7D38A2FED4BE08F55590E791072C2">
        <enum>(7)</enum>
        <header>Lift
			 team</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>lift
			 team</term> means health care workers with specialized training and knowledge
			 of safe patient handling, mobility, and injury prevention practices and
			 technology.</text>
			</paragraph>
    </section>
  </legis-body>
</bill>
</doc>