<doc>
  <docmeta id="113hr4851ih">
    <bill congress="113" type="hr" number="4851" version="ih"/>
    <revision size="16207" annotations="0" status="complete" id="4" commit-time="2014-06-25T23:01:15Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113hr4851ih/4.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H349ED0A2D73C495993CE7F08B477C34A" public-private="public">
	<metadata>
<dublinCore>
<dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">113 HR 4851 IH: Reciprocal Access to Tibet Act of 2014</dc:title>
<dc:publisher xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">2014-06-12</dc:date>
<dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>113th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>2d Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 4851</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20140612">June 12, 2014</action-date>
			<action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="M000312">Mr. McGovern</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="P000373">Mr. Pitts</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000672">Mr. Wolf</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="E000288">Mr. Ellison</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To promote access for United States officials, journalists, and other citizens to Tibetan areas of
			 the People’s Republic of China, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H0C71105689D94DA9B14F2B0D4627EEAD" style="OLC">
		<section id="H883173040A5B401085AB0A0FD8DF4545" section-type="section-one">
      <enum>1.</enum>
      <header>Short title</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote>
          <short-title>
            <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Reciprocal Access to Tibet Act of 2014" proposed="true">Reciprocal Access to Tibet Act of 2014</cato:entity-ref>
          </short-title>
        </quote>.</text>
		</section>
    <section id="H53464B339F20477385442A0E16E13A30">
      <enum>2.</enum>
      <header>Findings</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">
        <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> finds the following:</text>
			<paragraph id="H812BDC89EBCC4248ACFB69675B2383B4">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text>The Chinese Government does not grant United States officials, journalists, and other citizens
			 access to the People’s Republic of China on a reciprocal basis to the
			 access the United States Government grants Chinese officials, journalists,
			 and citizens.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HEB45D99F127146929DC2782E6D6ECFE3">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text>The Chinese Government imposes greater restrictions on travel to Tibetan areas than to other areas
			 of the People’s Republic of China.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H9A3B9904414C476EB62D28E657AA0E4A">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <text>Officials of the People’s Republic of China have stated that Tibet is open to foreign visitors.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HAD4BD507EC3E49CFA7B3737B5D7075C7">
        <enum>(4)</enum>
        <text>The Chinese Government is promoting tourism in Tibetan areas, and has announced plans to make
			 tourism a <quote>pillar industry</quote> for the region.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HB0945872232A4CC9A4186E8471570B4F">
        <enum>(5)</enum>
        <text>The Chinese Government requires foreigners to obtain permission from the Tibet Foreign and Overseas
			 Affairs Office or from the Tibet Tourism Bureau to enter the Tibet
			 Autonomous Region, a restriction that is not imposed on travel to any
			 other provincial-level jurisdiction in the People’s Republic of China.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H8A053E5823474646BE1E48E70B04B1AF">
        <enum>(6)</enum>
        <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1900" entity-type="federal-body">Department of State</cato:entity-ref> reports that the Tibet Foreign and Overseas Affairs Office denied more than
			 10 requests for United States diplomatic access to the Tibet Autonomous
			 Region between May 2011 and December 2012, and that when such requests are
			 granted, diplomatic personnel are closely supervised and given few
			 opportunities to meet local residents not approved by authorities.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H773216E9DB8A4223A7DF90EC72145830">
        <enum>(7)</enum>
        <text>The Chinese Government restricted United States consular access after an October 28, 2013, bus
			 crash in the Tibet Autonomous Region, in which at least two Americans died
			 and more than a dozen others, all from Walnut, California, were injured.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HD83A80D5DF444AF3A8C7456787BACFE2">
        <enum>(8)</enum>
        <text>The Chinese Government has failed to respond positively to the United States Government’s request
			 to open a consulate in Lhasa, Tibet Autonomous Region.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H99123FEB53354EBE9E0EC7B685D84D7F">
        <enum>(9)</enum>
        <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1900" entity-type="federal-body">Department of State</cato:entity-ref> reports that the Chinese government regularly denies requests by American
			 diplomats, foreign journalists, and observers to visit Tibetan areas, and
			 that those permitted to visit are subject to <quote>highly structured, government-organized tours</quote> that limit independent, objective reporting.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HB66C703628AC431E8528729667D76660">
        <enum>(10)</enum>
        <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1900" entity-type="federal-body">Department of State</cato:entity-ref> reports that foreign diplomats who were permitted to travel in Tibetan
			 areas outside the Tibet Autonomous Region were <quote>repeatedly approached by local police and sometimes forced to leave without reasonable explanation</quote>.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H24426C92B8244BDBB39352789DE80D4B">
        <enum>(11)</enum>
        <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1900" entity-type="federal-body">Department of State</cato:entity-ref> reports that permission is not always granted to foreign tourists, and that
			 when granted, Lhasa, Rikaze (Shigatse), and Shannan (Lhoka) are usually
			 the only places in the Tibet Autonomous Region open to foreigners.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HC21E8C71B84F4C88A2970F7B8CA2B51A">
        <enum>(12)</enum>
        <text>Foreign visitors also face restrictions in their ability to travel freely in Tibetan areas outside
			 the Tibet Autonomous Region.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HC5C4485ED3BD4049802222A0ADB76FC8">
        <enum>(13)</enum>
        <text>Foreign visitors to Tibetan areas are explicitly limited to tours that are tightly managed by
			 authorities.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H10F0F66CEA7C40239CFA4019F7E4684D">
        <enum>(14)</enum>
        <text>Restrictions on journalists’ access to Tibetan areas conflict with government regulations, adopted
			 in 2008, lifting requirements that foreign journalists get permission of
			 local authorities to travel in the country and interview Chinese citizens.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HA1879BF6EF354975B33725B797D6F121">
        <enum>(15)</enum>
        <text>The United States Government generally allows journalists and other citizens of the People’s
			 Republic of China to travel freely within the United States. The United
			 States Government requires Chinese diplomats to notify the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1900" entity-type="federal-body">Department of
			 State</cato:entity-ref> of their travel plans, and in certain situations, the United States
			 Government requires Chinese diplomats to obtain approval from the
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1900" entity-type="federal-body">Department of State</cato:entity-ref> before travel. However, where approval is required, it
			 is almost always granted expeditiously.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H643715786105496EBACBA18D7F932C53">
        <enum>(16)</enum>
        <text>The United States regularly grants visas to Chinese officials, scholars, and others who travel to
			 the United States to discuss, promote and display the Chinese Government’s
			 perspective on the situation in Tibetan areas, even as the Chinese
			 Government restricts the ability of United States citizens to travel to
			 Tibetan areas to gain their own perspective.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H6EF76E51E9584054A8DD28E62551E77B">
        <enum>(17)</enum>
        <text>Chinese diplomats based in the United States generally avail themselves of the freedom to travel to
			 United States cities and lobby city councils, mayors, and governors to
			 refrain from passing resolutions, issuing proclamations, or making
			 statements of concern on Tibet.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HBA61CB27E4964DDE9AADAE89291FAEE1">
        <enum>(18)</enum>
        <text>The Chinese Government characterizes statements made by United States officials about the situation
			 in Tibetan areas as inappropriate interference in the internal affairs of
			 China.</text>
			</paragraph>
    </section>
    <section id="H564882AB1A9947DC8840ABF674AF7419">
      <enum>3.</enum>
      <header>Definitions</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text>
			<paragraph id="H151198E27AE3401C93F13E4D77551BCA">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <header>Tibetan areas</header>
        <text>The term <quote>Tibetan areas</quote> includes—</text>
				<subparagraph id="HE01998ACC5734A54AAB9D3C633581137">
          <enum>(A)</enum>
          <text>the Tibet Autonomous Region (TAR); and</text>
				</subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="H406AA28263CD40E9B1A631BCC8276136">
          <enum>(B)</enum>
          <text>the prefectures and counties of the provinces of Sichuan, Qinghai, Yunnan, and Gansu of the
			 People’s Republic of China that the Chinese Government designates as <quote>Tibetan Autonomous</quote> areas.</text>
				</subparagraph>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H777CCC841D0E4201967B9202BFBDC1EC">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <header>Senior leadership positions</header>
        <text>The term <quote>senior leadership positions</quote> means—</text>
				<subparagraph id="H01AA81C55AFE4D5896ADE00F5CB38DAC">
          <enum>(A)</enum>
          <text>at the provincial level, the Governor, the Vice Governor, the Party Secretary, the Party
			 Disciplinary Committee Secretary, the Party Politics and Law Committee
			 Secretary, the Organization Department Director, the Chairman of the
			 Standing Committee of the People’s Congress for the Autonomous Region or
			 Province, the Chairman of the Autonomous Region or Provincial Committee of
			 the People’s Political Consultative Conference, the head of the Tibetan
			 Autonomous Region Communist Party Committee United Front Work Department,
			 the head of the Tibetan Autonomous Region Communist Party Committee
			 Political and Legal Commission, the heads of the Tibetan Autonomous Region
			 Public Security and State Security Bureaus, the Commander of the People’s
			 Armed Police, the head of the Foreign and Overseas Affairs Office, the
			 Director of the Tibet Tourism Bureau in the Tibet Autonomous Region, and
			 the Party Secretary and Mayor of Lhasa and the relevant provincial
			 capitals;</text>
				</subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="H55093BFA61E74FDE88D567B5BDD89C03">
          <enum>(B)</enum>
          <text>at the prefectural and county levels, the Party Secretary, the Deputy Party Secretaries, the
			 prefecture and county heads and deputy heads, the Secretary General, and
			 the Deputy Secretary General;</text>
				</subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="H3A9CC8CB291E4B1EAD5E2DFA5B15E964">
          <enum>(C)</enum>
          <text>at the national level, the Director of the Communist Party Central Committee United Front Work
			 Department, the Director of the State Ethnic Affairs Commission, the
			 Director of the State Administration for Religious Affairs, the Director
			 of the State Council Information Office, and the Director of the Foreign
			 Affairs Office of the State Council Information Office;</text>
				</subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="HD74DA72852C949A5ACA05DE5033B6E3B">
          <enum>(D)</enum>
          <text>at the regional level, the Regional People’s Armed Police and Military Commanders with jurisdiction
			 in Tibetan areas; and</text>
				</subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="H7F4CC935D5BA4415A8C2400DF9546BDB">
          <enum>(E)</enum>
          <text>any other individual determined by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1900" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref> to be personally and substantially
			 involved in the formulation or execution of policies in Tibetan areas.</text>
				</subparagraph>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HE8E64E6D5F114513B1AC19DA7E6CFB9A">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <header>Appropriate congressional committees</header>
        <text>The term <quote>appropriate congressional committees</quote> means—</text>
				<subparagraph id="HC9BC23D80EB94A0DB576717F8F3CD02D">
          <enum>(A)</enum>
          <text>the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="HFA00" entity-type="committee">Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives</cato:entity-ref>; and</text>
				</subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="H441F1598A6DB40D5AC6C2F0EC9963EB6">
          <enum>(B)</enum>
          <text>the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="committee" entity-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations of the United States Senate</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
				</subparagraph>
      </paragraph>
    </section>
    <section id="HAFFECB467D444269B788E7EF6828D440">
      <enum>4.</enum>
      <header>Report to Congress</header>
			<subsection id="H009073B6C70547C28C0E9C17B060A12B">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>In general</header>
        <text>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act and every 12 months thereafter,
			 the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1900" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref> shall submit to the appropriate congressional
			 committees a report that provides—</text>
				<paragraph id="HC9F096D5B7044F46AE3E008FFB6E045F">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>an assessment of the level of access Chinese authorities granted United States diplomats,
			 journalists, and tourists to Tibetan areas in the People’s Republic of
			 China, including a comparison with the level of access granted to other
			 areas of the People’s Republic of China, a comparison between the levels
			 of access granted to Tibetan and non-Tibetan areas in relevant provinces,
			 and a description of the required permits and other measures that impede
			 the freedom to travel in Tibetan areas;</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H774D4575BD52495A9CE770CCB24B91E7">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>a list of the persons in senior leadership positions in the Tibet Autonomous Region;</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H1B508FB9A0C048E992CADD8C51D0E793">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <text>a list of the persons in senior leadership positions in the provinces of Sichuan, Qinghai, Yunnan,
			 and Gansu Provinces of the People’s Republic of China;</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H418E5692C9C34649830BD21DDB3FCEC8">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
          <text>a list of the persons in senior leadership positions in Kardze (Ganzi) Tibetan Autonomous
			 Prefecture, Ngawa (Aba) Tibetan and Qiang Tibetan Autonomous Prefecture,
			 Muli (Mili) Autonomous County of Sichuan Province, Tsonub (Haixi) Mongol
			 and Tibetan, Tsojang (Haibei) Tibetan, Malho (Huangnan) Tibetan, Yulshul
			 (Yushu) Tibetan, and Golog (Guoluo) Tibetan Autonomous Prefectures of
			 Qinghai Province, Dechen (Diqing) Tibetan Autonomous Prefecture of Yunnan
			 Province, and the Kanlho (Gannan) Tibetan Autonomous Prefecture and Pari
			 (Tianzhu) Tibetan Autonomous County of Gansu Province;</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H96075C6E1E6146D49CB1DB56270B6AF0">
          <enum>(5)</enum>
          <text>a list of the persons in senior leadership positions at the national level as defined in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Reciprocal Access to Tibet Act of 2014/s:3/p:2/sp:C" proposed="true">section
			 3(2)(C)</cato:entity-ref>; and</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H62AD406BBA14447B848FDB2D3D81DF83">
          <enum>(6)</enum>
          <text>a list of the persons in senior leadership positions at the regional level as defined in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Reciprocal Access to Tibet Act of 2014/s:3/p:2/sp:D" proposed="true">section
			 3(2)(D)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
				</paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="HA84B3C9CDF7D4385AE2E3331E38F7B1F">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Public availability</header>
        <text>The report required under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Reciprocal Access to Tibet Act of 2014/s:4/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref> shall be made available on the website of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1900" entity-type="federal-body">Department
			 of State</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
			</subsection>
    </section>
    <section id="H9F2C74568341421295A6F502842888CE">
      <enum>5.</enum>
      <header>Inadmissibility of certain aliens</header>
			<subsection id="HC5F8FE16589E4887865C7ED5965FAA4F">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Ineligibility for visas</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An alien is ineligible to receive a visa to enter the United States and ineligible to be admitted
			 to the United States if such alien is on the list required by—</text>
				<paragraph id="H3C1515CBECDE440A9EF61CE78DFEC19A">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>
            <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Reciprocal Access to Tibet Act of 2014/s:4/ss:a/p:2" proposed="true">subsection (a)(2) of section 4</cato:entity-ref>, and if the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1900" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref> determines that the requirements for
			 specific official permission for foreigners to travel to the Tibet
			 Autonomous Region remain in effect, or that the current permission system
			 has been replaced by a requirement that has the same effect of requiring
			 foreign travelers to gain a level of permission to enter the Tibet
			 Autonomous Region that is not required for travel to other province-level
			 entities in the People’s Republic of China;</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H5A4164BC94144C72ACB827C011AC96EB">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>
            <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Reciprocal Access to Tibet Act of 2014/s:4/ss:a/p:3" proposed="true">subsections (a)(3)</cato:entity-ref> and <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Reciprocal Access to Tibet Act of 2014/s:4/ss:a/p:4" proposed="true">(a)(4) of section 4</cato:entity-ref>, and if the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1900" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref> determines that
			 restrictions on travel by United States officials, journalists, and
			 citizens to areas designated as <quote>Tibetan autonomous</quote> in the provinces of Sichuan, Qinghai, Yunnan, and Gansu of the People’s Republic of China are
			 greater than any restrictions on travel by United States officials,
			 journalists, and citizens to areas in such provinces that are not so
			 designated; or</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H73E852F04D564CB6A8E27AE3C0E43BB1">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <text>
            <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Reciprocal Access to Tibet Act of 2014/s:4/ss:a/p:5" proposed="true">subsections (a)(5)</cato:entity-ref> and <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Reciprocal Access to Tibet Act of 2014/s:4/ss:a/p:6" proposed="true">(a)(6) of section 4</cato:entity-ref>, and if the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1900" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref> determines that the
			 requirement for a specific permission to enter Tibet pertaining to travel
			 by foreigners to the Tibet Autonomous Region remain in effect, or that the
			 requirement has been replaced by a regulation that has the same effect of
			 requiring foreign travelers to gain a level of permission to enter the
			 Tibet Autonomous Region that is not required for travel to other
			 province-level entities in the People’s Republic of China, and if the
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1900" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref> determines that restrictions on travel by United States
			 officials and citizens to areas designated as <quote>Tibetan Autonomous</quote> in the provinces of Sichuan, Qinghai, Yunnan, and Gansu of the People’s Republic of China are
			 greater than any restrictions on travel by United States officials and
			 citizens to areas in such provinces that are not so designated.</text>
				</paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="H527478B88EBD4212941D7414F771E5DA">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Current visas revoked</header>
        <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1900" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref> shall revoke, in accordance with <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Immigration and Nationality Act/s:221/ss:i">section 221(i) of the Immigration and
			 Nationality Act</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1201">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/8/1201/i">8 U.S.C. 1201(i)</cato:entity-ref>
          </external-xref>)</cato:entity>, the visa or other documentation of any
			 alien who would be ineligible to receive such a visa or documentation
			 under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Reciprocal Access to Tibet Act of 2014/s:5/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
			</subsection>
      <subsection id="H3A99C59BD62047598F67A3E19F7B2747">
        <enum>(c)</enum>
        <header>Waiver for national interests</header>
				<paragraph id="HBD10ACF74FC2465D8A21BFC59718454F">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>In general</header>
          <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1900" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref> may waive the application of <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Reciprocal Access to Tibet Act of 2014/s:5/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref> or <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Reciprocal Access to Tibet Act of 2014/s:5/ss:b" proposed="true">(b)</cato:entity-ref> in the case of an alien
			 if the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> determines that such a waiver—</text>
					<subparagraph id="HF76DB9A7A37B45E48F970D0C6B7F751F">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>is necessary to permit the United States to comply with the Agreement between the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="19UN" entity-type="federal-body">United Nations</cato:entity-ref>
			 and the United States of America regarding the Headquarters of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="19UN" entity-type="federal-body">United
			 Nations</cato:entity-ref>, signed June 26, 1947, and entered into force November 21, 1947,
			 or other applicable international obligations of the United States; or</text>
					</subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="HD34EA4CDC87E4E4D84F2D64D29245820">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>is in the national security interests of the United States.</text>
					</subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H4E5FC8F3A71447CE95C4292CFC1B7EB0">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Notification</header>
          <text>Upon granting a waiver under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Reciprocal Access to Tibet Act of 2014/s:5/ss:c/p:1" proposed="true">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1900" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref> shall submit to the appropriate
			 congressional committees a document detailing the evidence and
			 justification for the necessity of such waiver, including, if such waiver
			 is granted pursuant to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Reciprocal Access to Tibet Act of 2014/s:5/ss:c/p:1/sp:B" proposed="true">subparagraph (B) of such paragraph</cato:entity-ref>, how such waiver
			 relates to the national security interests of the United States.</text>
				</paragraph>
      </subsection>
    </section>
    <section id="HC5F6E1635C504EE2AE8502A33F459F05">
      <enum>6.</enum>
      <header>Visa policy</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> that—</text>
			<paragraph id="H10BB01AA0A7B404D9E65626D8C75E626">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text>reciprocity forms the basis of diplomatic law and the practice of mutual exchanges between
			 countries;</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HE05E5156BF504C97A979B8450E1EBF10">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text>a country should give equivalent consular access to the nationals of another country in a
			 reciprocal manner to the consular access granted by such other country to
			 its own citizens; and</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HF657E259BAE14BABB2BDB7D57C7489AE">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <text>the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1900" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref>, when granting diplomats from the People’s Republic of China access to parts
			 of the United States, should take into account the extent to which the
			 Government of the People’s Republic of China grants United States
			 diplomats access to parts of the People’s Republic of China, including the
			 level of access afforded to such diplomats to Tibetan areas.</text>
			</paragraph>
    </section>
  </legis-body>
</bill>
</doc>