<doc>
  <docmeta id="113hr2055ih">
    <bill congress="113" type="hr" number="2055" version="ih"/>
    <revision size="10294" annotations="0" status="complete" id="5" commit-time="2013-07-09T16:00:33Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113hr2055ih/5.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H2B2CBC6E45A5400FA133506CAF183AA6" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>113 HR 2055 IH: Integrated Electronic Health Records (iEHR) for Military and Veterans Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2013-05-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>113th CONGRESS</congress>
<session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. R. 2055</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20130520">May 20, 2013</action-date> 
<action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="R000582">Mr. Roe of Tennessee</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="D000612">Mr. Denham</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000461">Mr. Flores</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001242">Mr. Bishop of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000292">Mr. Johnson of Ohio</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000619">Mr. Rodney Davis of Illinois</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="T000467">Mr. Thompson of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Veterans’ Affairs</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To establish a prize program to award a prize and contract for the development of a fully-integrated electronic health records program for use by the Department of Defense and the Department of Veterans Affairs.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="HB805F2B6F6C241E09C941A5696040F79" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H46B80472384E42BC9EF7C176AB91E75B" section-type="section-one">
      <enum>1.</enum>
      <header>Short title</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote>
          <short-title>Integrated Electronic Health Records (iEHR) for Military and Veterans Act</short-title>
        </quote>. </text>
    </section> 
<section id="H384F7009AA6948BEA7C3C2210589CF78">
      <enum>2.</enum>
      <header>Prize program for the development of a fully-integrated electronic health records program for use by the Department of Defense and the Department of Veterans Affairs</header> 
<subsection id="H556F1B24E23A4D6EB9C82E872D8D688E">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Prize authority</header> 
<paragraph id="HE68FD85992404035B34ACDEAEE552596">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>In general</header>
          <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="9700">Secretary of Defense</cato:entity-ref> and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="3600">Secretary of Veterans Affairs</cato:entity-ref> shall jointly carry out a program to award a cash prize in the amount of $50,000,000 and contract to an entity that develops a fully-integrated electronic health records program for national use by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="9700">Department of Defense</cato:entity-ref> and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="3600">Department of Veterans Affairs</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H154B74853C114B6CB57AFCF1271CBD68">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Advertising and solicitation of competitors</header> 
<subparagraph id="HAA34259587F648B081B3544B40247D78">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <header>Advertising</header>
            <text>The Secretaries shall widely advertise prize competitions under this section to encourage broad participation by researchers, large and small businesses, institutions of higher education, and any other qualified applicants, including veterans.</text>
          </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE817D1DAAC734295B340EADD8883BF8D">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <header>Announcement through federal register notice</header>
            <text>The Secretaries shall announce each prize competition under this section by publishing a notice in the Federal Register. This notice shall include essential elements of the competition such as the subject of the competition, the duration of the competition, the eligibility requirements for participation in the competition, the process for participants to register for the competition, the amount of the prize, and the criteria for awarding the prize and contract.</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H44C22B073D4D46EBA194448294DFC184">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <header>Announcement of prizes</header>
          <text>The Secretary may not issue a notice required by <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Integrated Electronic Health Records (iEHR) for Military and Veterans Act/s:2/ss:a/p:2/sp:B" proposed="true">paragraph (2)(B)</cato:entity-ref> until all the funds needed to pay out the announced amount of the prize have been appropriated.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="HF383C73C166E4199AABD00ED08A0C1A6">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Eligibility</header>
        <text>To be eligible to win a prize under this section, an individual or entity—</text> 
<paragraph id="H9405FDF4571C44F087F94A91BF8D803E">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>shall have complied with all the requirements in accordance with the Federal Register notice required under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Integrated Electronic Health Records (iEHR) for Military and Veterans Act/s:2/ss:a/p:2/sp:B" proposed="true">subsection (a)(2)(B)</cato:entity-ref>;</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9084F302B47245DDAE3989D32FF8EF0D">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>in the case of a private entity, shall be incorporated in and maintain a primary place of business in the United States, and in the case of an individual, whether participating singly or in a group, shall be a citizen of, or an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence in, the United States; and</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6288ABF076F04E289E8E02EE6905F772">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <text>shall not be a Federal entity, a Federal employee acting within the scope of his employment, or an employee of a national laboratory acting within the scope of his employment.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="H83293632C68F4DF3BC069E5589C6F6ED">
        <enum>(c)</enum>
        <header>Joint panel</header> 
<paragraph id="HCBBF70DF02CA4858AB6E0AD147E58A2E">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>Establishment</header>
          <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="9700">Secretary of Defense</cato:entity-ref> and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="3600">Secretary of Veterans Affairs</cato:entity-ref> shall establish a joint panel to establish the criteria for the development of a fully-integrated electronic health records program eligible for an award and contract under this section to ensure that the program meets the requirements of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="9700">Department of Defense</cato:entity-ref> and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="3600">Department of Veterans Affairs</cato:entity-ref>. </text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC822E950A43E4C578B3292DFB62C45D3">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Membership</header> 
<subparagraph id="H62C674D3C36046E58596BE9EFA7C1C9D">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <header>In general</header>
            <text>The members of the joint panel shall be—</text> 
<clause id="HDC0ACB060F1A4DF4A29347078DB488DE">
              <enum>(i)</enum>
              <text>one physician from each of the military departments, to be appointed by the Secretary of the military department concerned;</text>
            </clause> 
<clause id="HF92950E34FE94CC1BEFF278BDF8E5090">
              <enum>(ii)</enum>
              <text>two physicians employed by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="3600">Department of Veterans Affairs</cato:entity-ref>, to be appointed by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="3600">Secretary of Veterans Affairs</cato:entity-ref>; and</text>
            </clause> 
<clause id="H86EA8C08838E4EBCB52BAB7710F24A7B">
              <enum>(iii)</enum>
              <text>two representatives of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="3640">Veterans Benefits Administration of the Department of Veterans Affairs</cato:entity-ref>, to be appointed by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="3600">Secretary of Veterans Affairs</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
            </clause>
          </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC4E77A2D419940138C8DAB54BC09986D">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <header>Deadline for appointment</header>
            <text>Members of the joint panel shall be appointed by not later than 14 days after the date of the enactment of this Act. Any member who is not appointed by such deadline shall not be appointed to the panel.</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HACC2CB68F60E43BA8E84EBBCC7073EB0">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <header>Deadline for criteria</header>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The joint panel shall establish criteria with sufficient specificity for development, taking best practices of private and public electronic health records under consideration. If the panel fails to agree on such criteria or if an insufficient number of members are appointed to the panel before the deadline under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Integrated Electronic Health Records (iEHR) for Military and Veterans Act/s:2/ss:c/p:2/sp:B" proposed="true">paragraph (2)(B)</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="National Health Information Technology Coordinator">National Health Information Technology Coordinator</cato:entity-ref> shall determine such criteria, taking best practices of private and public electronic health record systems into consideration.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="H08CD70B7011D44499887613877BB0C98">
        <enum>(d)</enum>
        <header>Deadline for submissions</header>
        <text>The deadline for the submission of an application to participate in the competition under this section is the date that is one year after the date on which the criteria are established under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Integrated Electronic Health Records (iEHR) for Military and Veterans Act/s:2/ss:c" proposed="true">subsection (c)</cato:entity-ref>, or if such date falls on a weekend, the next weekday following such date.</text>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="H3B61F7F9F73E4E39B31B4FF7F7B5955E">
        <enum>(e)</enum>
        <header>Award selection</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="9700">Secretary of Defense</cato:entity-ref> and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="3600">Secretary of Veterans Affairs</cato:entity-ref> shall award prizes under this section on the basis of the criteria published in the notice required under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Integrated Electronic Health Records (iEHR) for Military and Veterans Act/s:2/ss:a/p:2/sp:B" proposed="true">subsection (a)(2)(B)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="H471C2D17584F44E780D3BBCB7DFF8CE4">
        <enum>(f)</enum>
        <header>Contract</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the entity that is awarded a prize under this section shall be awarded a contract with the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="9700">Department of Defense</cato:entity-ref> and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="3600">Department of Veterans Affairs</cato:entity-ref> to provide the fully-integrated electronic health records program for which the prize is awarded to the Departments and to provide maintenance and support for such program for a five-year period and under such contract shall be compensated in an amount of $25,000,000 for each year.</text>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="H3B16FB89AB184FA7B5B04F2E43B53E91">
        <enum>(g)</enum>
        <header>Intellectual property</header> 
<paragraph id="H202292D47F9D4650AE8FAA95BAB4FB1F">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>Treatment of winning intellectual property</header>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon the expiration of the contract referred to in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Integrated Electronic Health Records (iEHR) for Military and Veterans Act/s:2/ss:e" proposed="true">subsection (e)</cato:entity-ref> the intellectual property rights in the fully-integrated electronic health records program for which a prize is awarded under this section shall revert to the Federal Government. The entity that is awarded a prize under this section shall retain the intellectual property rights in any upgrades to the program developed by the entity.</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H41934FB26942492DB1E19EECFCC97BCD">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Other intellectual property</header>
          <text>Except as provided in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Integrated Electronic Health Records (iEHR) for Military and Veterans Act/s:2/ss:g/p:1" proposed="true">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref>, the Federal Government shall not, by virtue of offering or awarding a prize under this section, be entitled to any intellectual property rights derived as a consequence of, or direct relation to, the participation by a registered participant in a competition authorized by this section. This subsection shall not be construed to prevent the Federal Government from negotiating a license for the use of intellectual property developed for a prize competition under this section.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="HA48DA30FAA2443C1B5FD5E918ADD8ECD">
        <enum>(h)</enum>
        <header>Liability</header> 
<paragraph id="H424F01F512B4438788420106FBF31234">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>Waiver of liability</header>
          <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="9700">Secretary of Defense</cato:entity-ref> and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="3600">Secretary of Veterans Affairs</cato:entity-ref> may require registered participants to waive claims against the Federal Government (except claims for willful misconduct) for any injury, death, damage, or loss of property, revenue, or profits arising from the registered participants’ participation in a competition under this section. The Secretary shall give notice of any waiver required under this paragraph in the notice required by <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Integrated Electronic Health Records (iEHR) for Military and Veterans Act/s:2/ss:a/p:2/sp:B" proposed="true">subsection (a)(2)(B)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3C5E455F778041A98028A04504D5E42D">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Liability insurance</header> 
<subparagraph id="H98C9443772DE4B9E8C2D37C87D9583B1">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <header>Requirements</header>
            <text>Registered participants in a prize competition under this section shall be required to obtain liability insurance or demonstrate financial responsibility, in amounts determined by the Secretary, for claims by—</text> 
<clause id="H871CC4D2FCF042559E7FAB10E61B7C82">
              <enum>(i)</enum>
              <text>a third party for death, bodily injury, or property damage or loss resulting from an activity carried out in connection with participation in a competition under this section; and</text>
            </clause> 
<clause id="H24F5906890A84600866C7E2B5E9788BD">
              <enum>(ii)</enum>
              <text>the Federal Government for damage or loss to Government property resulting from such an activity.</text>
            </clause>
          </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H121248916EF84A699EF03B6BFB634294">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <header>Federal government insured</header>
            <text>The Federal Government shall be named as an additional insured under a registered participant’s insurance policy required under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Integrated Electronic Health Records (iEHR) for Military and Veterans Act/s:2/ss:h/p:2/sp:A" proposed="true">subparagraph (A)</cato:entity-ref> with respect to claims described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Integrated Electronic Health Records (iEHR) for Military and Veterans Act/s:2/ss:h/p:2/sp:A/cl:i" proposed="true">clause (i)</cato:entity-ref> of that subparagraph, and registered participants shall be required to agree to indemnify the Federal Government against third party claims for damages arising from or related to competition activities under this section.</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="HDBFEB416B27A46A5924338746E461FFF">
        <enum>(i)</enum>
        <header>Nonsubstitution</header>
        <text>The programs created under this section shall not be considered a substitute for Federal research and development programs.</text>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="H0196F86DBE71471DA99939708660CB1B">
        <enum>(j)</enum>
        <header>Authorization of appropriations</header>
        <text>
          <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="auth-auth-approp">There is authorized to be appropriated <cato:funds-and-year amount="50000000">$50,000,000</cato:funds-and-year> <cato:property name="purpose">to carry out <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Integrated Electronic Health Records (iEHR) for Military and Veterans Act/s:2" proposed="true">this section</cato:entity-ref>
            </cato:property>.</cato:entity>
        </text>
      </subsection>
    </section> 
</legis-body> 
</bill>
</doc>