<doc>
  <docmeta id="113hr2468ih">
    <bill congress="113" type="hr" number="2468" version="ih"/>
    <revision size="18988" annotations="0" status="complete" id="3" commit-time="2013-08-22T20:48:34Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113hr2468ih/3.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H6B018FAF2C27409EA5554661863C1E85" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>113 HR 2468 IH: Safe Streets Act of 2013</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2013-06-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>113th CONGRESS</congress>
<session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. R. 2468</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20130620">June 20, 2013</action-date> 
<action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="M001163">Ms. Matsui</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="J000295">Mr. Joyce</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>
      </action-desc>
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To ensure the safety of all users of the transportation system, including pedestrians, bicyclists, transit users, children, older individuals, and individuals with disabilities, as they travel on and across federally funded streets and highways.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H6BFCEF957BF94057A293B8167631FD23" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H3A4ADC14DC0F411EB64731704D864F9D" section-type="section-one">
      <enum>1.</enum>
      <header>Short title</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote>
          <short-title>Safe Streets Act of 2013</short-title>
        </quote>.</text>
    </section> 
<section id="HB378EBF49C7146CFA5F648EDA10B635A">
      <enum>2.</enum>
      <header>Definitions</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> 
<paragraph id="HF4F820F83E5B479E95A4CFABEA337A1B">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <header>Complete street</header>
        <text>The term <term>complete street</term> means a roadway that safely accommodates all travelers, particularly public transit users, bicyclists, pedestrians (including individuals of all ages and individuals with mobility, sensory, neurological, or hidden disabilities), motorists and freight vehicles, to enable all travelers to use the roadway safely and efficiently.</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H415D4ECF2018493996323705D43F7E6C">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <header>Complete streets policy; complete streets principle</header>
        <text>The terms <term>complete streets policy</term> and <term>complete streets principle</term> mean a transportation law, policy, or principle at the local, State, regional, or Federal level that ensures—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HB4BA95FBE7E94CBDA966C352A026F1DE">
          <enum>(A)</enum>
          <text>the safe and adequate accommodation, in all phases of project planning and development, of all users of the transportation system, including pedestrians, bicyclists, public transit users, children, older individuals, individuals with disabilities, motorists, and freight vehicles; and</text>
        </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6C2F571E8F3A418BA4A3EBC5632372A3">
          <enum>(B)</enum>
          <text>the consideration of the safety and convenience of all users in all phases of project planning and development.</text>
        </subparagraph>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H33E6033F1FED400393853FBA1A425A42">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <header>Local jurisdiction</header>
        <text>The term <term>local jurisdiction</term> means any unit of local government.</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA6968B8303FB433D94E2BE9C9649E55B">
        <enum>(4)</enum>
        <header>Metropolitan planning organization</header>
        <text>The term <term>metropolitan planning organization</term> has the meaning given the term in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc/23/134/b">
            <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/23/134">section 134(b)</external-xref> of title 23, United States Code</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7D9477B4C65B43658921F0BEA189344D">
        <enum>(5)</enum>
        <header>Roadway</header>
        <text>The term <term>roadway</term> means—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HFBEA5D330F02469C8DD573574E5F1DD2">
          <enum>(A)</enum>
          <text>the defined Federal functional classification roadway system; and</text>
        </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2714117F2C08402D89D7B45D92A3105B">
          <enum>(B)</enum>
          <text>each bridge structure providing a connection for such a roadway system.</text>
        </subparagraph>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H26D29E3397E7417C9122FA041ACB1732">
        <enum>(6)</enum>
        <header>Secretary</header>
        <text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Transportation.</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H45D67942C7A545ADBE44B555D33594A9">
        <enum>(7)</enum>
        <header>Senior manager</header>
        <text>The term <term>senior manager</term> means—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H8B04B43FFF4D468A87FDF76DD595E9C5">
          <enum>(A)</enum>
          <text>the director of a State department of transportation (or a designee);</text>
        </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H84A150487FC149EEA32EB57CCB0DA6CC">
          <enum>(B)</enum>
          <text>the director of a metropolitan planning organization (or a designee); and</text>
        </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HDCC72EBAC9B149C5AB2F7685016CC823">
          <enum>(C)</enum>
          <text>the director of a regional, county, or city transportation agency that is primarily responsible for planning and approval of transportation projects (or a designee).</text>
        </subparagraph>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2FD2F2C5FB0340439455EBED9A13A8EE">
        <enum>(8)</enum>
        <header>Transportation improvement program</header>
        <text>The term <term>transportation improvement program</term> has the meaning given the term <term>TIP</term> in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc/23/134/b">
            <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/23/134">section 134(b)</external-xref> of title 23, United States Code</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
      </paragraph>
    </section> 
<section id="HB7B2ED3BE15343F28A41C0A360A6C62A">
      <enum>3.</enum>
      <header>Complete streets policy</header> 
<subsection id="HE0CDA63C400C4D0D8FC8A8A71684D4F0">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Law or policy</header>
        <text>Not later than October 1 of the fiscal year that begins 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act each State and metropolitan planning organization shall have in effect—</text> 
<paragraph id="H24D3C7409ED74F25ABE53154270FF798">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>in the case of a State—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H4EB70573D6F84C2B8ECB2CBCEDEE8F42">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>a law requiring that, beginning on the effective date of the State law, all transportation projects in the State shall accommodate the safety and convenience of all users in accordance with complete streets principles; or</text>
          </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H8C922930DDDE4E5885C11C2504EC014A">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>an explicit State department of transportation policy that, beginning on the effective date of the policy, all transportation projects in the State shall accommodate the safety and convenience of all users in accordance with complete streets principles; and</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HEA190E812E274C37899FC146A2FBE6CF">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>in the case of a metropolitan planning organization, an explicit statement of policy that, beginning on the effective date of the policy, all transportation projects under the jurisdiction of the metropolitan planning organization shall accommodate the safety and convenience of all users in accordance with complete streets principles.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="H3199A44E153E449EB471135E9E02216F">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Inclusions</header> 
<paragraph id="H2B36D3548F474FFCAB3A5D6E7A4D311B">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>In general</header>
          <text>A law or policy described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Safe Streets Act of 2013/s:3/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref> shall—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H35FF3643E1C24635B7BE02591B801671">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>apply to each federally funded project of each State department of transportation or metropolitan planning organization transportation improvement program;</text>
          </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H75E590B632434481B9BE40B43ECA6479">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>include a statement that each project under the transportation improvement program makes streets or affected rights-of-way accessible to the expected users of that facility, of all ages and abilities, including pedestrians, bicyclists, transit vehicles and users, freight vehicles, and motorists;</text>
          </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H3625362964AA4ECAB0402C1BC6334295">
            <enum>(C)</enum>
            <text>except as provided in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Safe Streets Act of 2013/s:3/ss:b/p:2" proposed="true">paragraph (2)</cato:entity-ref>, apply to new road construction and road modification projects, including design, planning, construction, reconstruction, rehabilitation, maintenance, and operations, for the entire right-of-way;</text>
          </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD294A6CFFA1446C182DD78221D11B53B">
            <enum>(D)</enum>
            <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">indicate that improvements for the safe and convenient travel by pedestrians or bicyclists of all ages and abilities on or across streets shall be fully assessed, considered, and documented as a routine element of pavement resurfacing projects;</text>
          </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H69B57FBCEE35422D9B0403B078347AF6">
            <enum>(E)</enum>
            <text>delineate a clear procedure by which transportation improvement projects may be exempted from complying with complete streets principles, which shall require—</text> 
<clause id="H3487EA8D209D4CAE80D5FAFD9B3E0B8F">
              <enum>(i)</enum>
              <text>approval by the appropriate senior manager, in accordance with <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Safe Streets Act of 2013/s:3/ss:d/p:2" proposed="true">subsection (d)(2)</cato:entity-ref>; and</text>
            </clause> 
<clause id="H3F52EF433B53478E8236D34F6C91433B">
              <enum>(ii)</enum>
              <text>documentation, with supporting data, that indicates the basis for such an exemption;</text>
            </clause>
          </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2E8DFCC172C54917BD21BEA9B510027C">
            <enum>(F)</enum>
            <text>comply with up-to-date design standards, particularly standards relating to providing access for individuals with disabilities;</text>
          </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF9E6A7A246E94D17ABF9AB85C89A72AB">
            <enum>(G)</enum>
            <text>require that complete streets principles be applied in due consideration of the urban, suburban, or rural context in which a project is located;</text>
          </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H7A7665D8B0954724B2B7BAD820332792">
            <enum>(H)</enum>
            <text>include a list of performance standards with measurable outcomes to ensure that the transportation improvement program adheres to complete streets principles; and</text>
          </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H0C84576B82B84C91B53978DFF890DDD1">
            <enum>(I)</enum>
            <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">directs agency staff to create an implementation plan.</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H862CA1BE8830422889C097C8763838E7">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Exception</header>
          <text>A law or policy described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Safe Streets Act of 2013/s:3/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref> shall not apply to a new road construction or modification project for which, as of the effective date of the law or policy, at least 30 percent of the design phase is completed.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="HCC09D39402E94CBA8A09834DF641D592">
        <enum>(c)</enum>
        <header>Exemption requirements and procedures</header>
        <text>A law or policy described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Safe Streets Act of 2013/s:3/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref> shall allow for a project-specific exemption from an applicable complete streets policy if—</text> 
<paragraph id="H52BA7595CCAC432B8A8C1908AFFBE561">
          <enum>(1)</enum> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HDDA3E332CA3741B4B9BA55FECE4DB679">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>an affected roadway prohibits, by law, use of the roadway by specified users, in which case a greater effort shall be made to accommodate those specified users elsewhere, including on roadways that cross or otherwise intersect with the affected roadway;</text>
          </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9451BD7DA1B1466BB08BB3DC79E3FFEA" indent="up1">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>the cost to the exempted project in achieving compliance with the applicable complete streets policy would be excessively disproportionate (as defined in the 2001 Department of Transportation Guidance on Accommodating Bicycle and Pedestrian Travel), as compared to the need or probable use of a particular complete street; or</text>
          </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H390C0EA600B442F68FFD2C2F84464890" indent="up1">
            <enum>(C)</enum>
            <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the existing and planned population, employment densities, traffic volumes, or level of transit service around a particular roadway is so low, that the expected users of the roadway will not include pedestrians, public transportation, freight vehicles, or bicyclists; and</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6175B3EB69C44D7BA70467C1C42F3D1E">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>the project-specific exemption is approved by—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HB6DD848963C148DA8DCE3266D01DB755">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>a senior manager of the metropolitan planning organization that approved the transportation improvement program containing the exempted project;</text>
          </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H16480D5D9A5643FF99C2FB0EE9A9B045">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>a senior manager of the relevant State department of transportation; or</text>
          </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H08AC2AF7A9084C66A613DC9E16D12F1B">
            <enum>(C)</enum>
            <text>in the case of a project for which neither the metropolitan planning organization nor the State department of transportation is the agency with primary transportation planning authority, a senior manager of the regional, county, or city agency responsible for planning and approval of the project.</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="H08F7D6A3C2E74106A6F0249D3D84728C">
        <enum>(d)</enum>
        <header>Integration</header>
        <text>Each State department of transportation and metropolitan planning organization implementing a complete streets policy shall incorporate complete streets principles into all aspects of the transportation project development, programming, and delivery process, including project planning and identification, scoping procedures, design approvals, design manuals, and performance measures.</text>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="H9175EE397C4E4663935BB74036B70E8E">
        <enum>(e)</enum>
        <header>Reports</header> 
<paragraph id="HEE5FCEC008A8449ABAD8C418F6EC2145">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>In general</header>
          <text>Each State department of transportation shall submit to the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="6900">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> a report describing the implementation by the State of measures to achieve compliance with the requirements of this section, at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="6900">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> may require.</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF426E956551F46EEAB1CCCA69A3BE9BF">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Determination by Secretary</header>
          <text>On receipt of a report under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Safe Streets Act of 2013/s:3/ss:e/p:1" proposed="true">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="6900">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall determine whether the applicable State has achieved compliance with the requirements of this section.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
    </section> 
<section id="HD61F71BD522D4E28A701F889FFD15DB7">
      <enum>4.</enum>
      <header>Certification</header> 
<subsection id="H6B5A8D053DB34B1FB384419B217EEFA7">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>In general</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the enactment of this Act, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="6900">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall establish a method of evaluating compliance by State departments of transportation and metropolitan planning organizations with the requirements of this Act, including a requirement that each State department of transportation and metropolitan planning organization shall submit to the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="6900">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> a report describing—</text> 
<paragraph id="HA31554E0C8C44F43AE356CBFB1647A46">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>each complete streets policy adopted by the State department of transportation or metropolitan planning organization;</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3A7B537976754DDDB7CDAE1F7310CB93">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>the means of implementation by the State department of transportation or metropolitan planning organization of the complete streets policy; and</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3D568C236E56437191A533E854F1EEAC">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <text>the process for providing an exemption, from the requirements of the complete streets policy of the State department of transportation or metropolitan planning organization.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="H9CBCD1533F5D41869F60E6F0E9AB98EC">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Report</header>
        <text>Not later than 3 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="6900">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall submit to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> a report describing—</text> 
<paragraph id="H3ACEBDA100894EB6820261AEBA747348">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>the method established under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Safe Streets Act of 2013/s:4/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref>;</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF36151E726BD458485B379D1860EDC71">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>the status of activities for adoption and implementation by State departments of transportation and metropolitan planning organizations of complete streets policies;</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5EE62EAA7972426FBF9BE2FC74D54AAE">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <text>the tools and resources provided by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="6900">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> to State departments of transportation and metropolitan planning organizations to assist with that adoption and implementation; and</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD74620BE21E84B1A9E383AEBB12D1FC0">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
          <text>other measures carried out by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="6900">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> to encourage the adoption of complete streets policies by local jurisdictions.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
    </section> 
<section id="HA6C3A9E9E8474318AC30147DA1792BE7">
      <enum>5.</enum>
      <header>Accessibility standards</header> 
<subsection id="HE8985AA9F1AA4B81A64A21FDE0E0D39D">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Final standards</header>
        <text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="9532">Architectural and Transportation Barriers Compliance Board</cato:entity-ref> established by <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Rehabilitation Act of 1973/s:502/ss:a/p:1">section 502(a)(1) of the Rehabilitation Act of 1973</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/792">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/29/792/a/1">29 U.S.C. 792(a)(1)</cato:entity-ref>
            </external-xref>)</cato:entity> shall promulgate final standards for accessibility of new construction and alteration of pedestrian facilities for public rights-of-way.</text>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="H3BE7CF86E97D4FB59DA90DFE48262912">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Temporary standards</header>
        <text>During the period beginning on the date of enactment of this Act and ending on the date on which the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="9532">Architectural and Transportation Barriers Compliance Board</cato:entity-ref> promulgates final standards under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Safe Streets Act of 2013/s:5/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref>, a State or metropolitan planning organization shall apply to public rights-of-way—</text> 
<paragraph id="H56EC6B33F6AF47B7B3363967FB97F666">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>the standards for accessible transportation facilities contained in <external-xref legal-doc="regulation" parsable-cite="cfr/49/37.9">section 37.9</external-xref> of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations (as in effect on the date of enactment of this Act); or</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7E350B7DE57C4E9A98757C27F3CB5CA6">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>if the standards referred to in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Safe Streets Act of 2013/s:5/ss:b/p:1" proposed="true">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref> do not address, or are inapplicable to, an affected public right-of-way, the revised draft guidelines for accessible public rights-of-way of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="9532">Architectural and Transportation Barriers Compliance Board</cato:entity-ref> dated November 23, 2005.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
    </section> 
<section id="HEFDFD0BE7F994705882B7D1A5CA74DCF">
      <enum>6.</enum>
      <header>Research, technical guidance, and implementation assistance</header> 
<subsection id="H3D05C48FCD57468FBFBD905125A17531">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Research</header> 
<paragraph id="H52CE2E0EBED14D959F273682A3218AAD">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>In general</header>
          <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="6900">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall conduct research regarding complete streets to assist States, metropolitan planning organizations, and local jurisdictions in developing, adopting, and implementing plans, projects, procedures, policies, and training programs that comply with complete streets principles.</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8F4BD699125F41BBAE57F0BEE9E33A47">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Participation</header>
          <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="6900">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall solicit participation in the research program under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Safe Streets Act of 2013/s:6/ss:a/p:1" proposed="true">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref> by—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HC85C7A05449B4833AD3BAD4C3D354911">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>the American Association of State Highway and Transportation Officials;</text>
          </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5114AC206C8D4A64BDF29D7DD0460B33">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>the Institute of Transportation Engineers;</text>
          </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H09B7C3E27F4D40C794A6ED100B638911">
            <enum>(C)</enum>
            <text>the American Public Transportation Association;</text>
          </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9659B8CF5E3649BE9DDED1BC4B7DE158">
            <enum>(D)</enum>
            <text>the American Planning Association;</text>
          </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H64F40A3B4BFB4131AD09C45D6D1BEED8">
            <enum>(E)</enum>
            <text>the National Association of Regional Councils;</text>
          </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6BF74C8882C2448AAFD6732E0BB23387">
            <enum>(F)</enum>
            <text>the Association of Metropolitan Planning Organizations;</text>
          </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H78B7239FFDB447519909ECDC838B3EE8">
            <enum>(G)</enum>
            <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Insurance Institute for Highway Safety;</text>
          </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HABD859120E0B4729B768960D42DE43AC">
            <enum>(H)</enum>
            <text>the American Society of Landscape Architects;</text>
          </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H0DA0CE4B5A8546D1AD11A36EF1AB28EC">
            <enum>(I)</enum>
            <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">representatives of transportation safety, disability, motoring, bicycling, walking, transit user, aging, and air quality organizations; and</text>
          </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE0A5BEC355A14F5CACE52682C95CC172">
            <enum>(J)</enum>
            <text>other affected communities.</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2BC4C2C457DE4C9D9BF9E41D7AA86DF2">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <header>Requirements</header>
          <text>The research under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Safe Streets Act of 2013/s:6/ss:a/p:1" proposed="true">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref> shall—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HCD4CE62F352841FD8E34C53FE5FE347C">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>be based on the applicable statement of complete streets research needs of the Transportation Research Board, as described in TR Circular E110; and</text>
          </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5DFA2286FADC404BA41E2A86F7FC1246">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>seek to develop new areas of inquiry, in addition to that statement.</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="H87869409B2D64501AA88FC2C7DCC0C26">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Benchmarks and guidance</header> 
<paragraph id="HA7C5450FC5F64BC1AAE0C3137553EA49">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>In general</header>
          <text>The research conducted under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Safe Streets Act of 2013/s:6/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref> shall be designed to result in the establishment of benchmarks and the provision of practical guidance on methods of effectively implementing complete streets policies and complete streets principles that will accommodate all users along a facility or corridor, including vehicles, pedestrians, bicyclists, and transit users.</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5436BFF2396041E7A7FCF2A7DCCFC6CA">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Focus</header>
          <text>The benchmarks and guidance under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Safe Streets Act of 2013/s:6/ss:b/p:1" proposed="true">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref> shall—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H2EE5485D9ACF4AEEAE7CC629FD7FA5F7">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>focus on modifying scoping, design, and construction procedures to more effectively combine particular methods of use into integrated facilities that meet the needs of each method in an appropriate balance; and</text>
          </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H0ECBD028B15849259667EAF4A459FA29">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>indicate the expected operational and safety performance of alternative approaches to facility design.</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="H9A07D99DAB2E4DB7BE4B50654F0C2196">
        <enum>(c)</enum>
        <header>Data collection</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="6900">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall collaborate with the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Bureau of Transportation Statistics" entity-parent-id="6900">Bureau of Transportation Statistics</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="6955">Federal Transit Administration</cato:entity-ref>, and appropriate committees of the Transportation Research Board—</text> 
<paragraph id="HA4E44A088F2540BE8EFE4D600689B726">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to collect data regarding a baseline nonmotorized and transit use survey to be integrated into the National Household Travel Survey; and</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H22FEF1C9250E413F816879FFD7EB848D">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>to develop a survey tool for use by State departments of transportation in identifying the multimodal capacity of State and local roadways.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="H9CFA0F17C7BD44B6A3B3E3D97CEBAA35">
        <enum>(d)</enum>
        <header>Technical guidance</header> 
<paragraph id="HBB1333DF095640DFBE1D4F4194CA5922">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>Report</header>
          <text>Not later than 15 months after the date of enactment of this Act, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="6900">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall prepare and make available to all States, metropolitan planning organizations, and local jurisdictions a report that describes the best practices by which transportation agencies throughout the United States have implemented complete streets principles in accordance with, or in anticipation of, the requirements of this Act.</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H51393372823542199062B2CDBF269FB8">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Topics for emphasis</header>
          <text>In preparing the report under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Safe Streets Act of 2013/s:6/ss:d/p:1" proposed="true">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="6900">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall place particular emphasis on the following topics:</text> 
<subparagraph id="HD9D26ED33C014C1B819F762524540495">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>Procedures for identifying the needs of users of all ages and abilities of a particular roadway.</text>
          </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HEC7505357C944DA6AAC216C170AA3ECD">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>Procedures for identifying the types and designs of facilities needed to serve each class of users.</text>
          </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HDB994A3771A74805A425367BD93CBB93">
            <enum>(C)</enum>
            <text>Safety and other benefits provided by the implementation of complete streets principles.</text>
          </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA7538474C3064EA693133692AEC40451">
            <enum>(D)</enum>
            <text>Common barriers to the implementation of complete streets principles.</text>
          </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE4AE098B22AE4473B73B2A44C3E466D7">
            <enum>(E)</enum>
            <text>Procedures for overcoming the most common barriers to the implementation of complete streets principles.</text>
          </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2CC701D5F38D4478B4DA67464EDCC47B">
            <enum>(F)</enum>
            <text>Procedures for identifying the costs associated with the implementation of complete streets principles.</text>
          </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HDE27587BF62741FAA1B1AC667EDF7733">
            <enum>(G)</enum>
            <text>Procedures for maximizing local cooperation in the introduction and implementation of complete streets principles.</text>
          </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF048F363F21F4E7C9988D68BCC63D9AB">
            <enum>(H)</enum>
            <text>Procedures for assessing and modifying the facilities and operational characteristics of existing roadways to improve consistency with complete streets principles.</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
    </section> 
</legis-body> 
</bill>
</doc>