<doc>
  <docmeta id="113hr3544ih">
    <bill congress="113" type="hr" number="3544" version="ih"/>
    <revision size="8610" annotations="0" status="complete" id="3" commit-time="2013-11-26T17:56:19Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113hr3544ih/3.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HB44438169F544E53AD8190C861F79162" public-private="public">
  <metadata>
<dublinCore>
<dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">113 HR 3544 IH: Office of Strategic Services Congressional Gold Medal Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">2013-11-20</dc:date>
<dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
    <congress>113th CONGRESS</congress>
    <session>1st Session</session>
    <legis-num>H. R. 3544</legis-num>
    <current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
    <action>
      <action-date date="20131120">November 20, 2013</action-date>
      <action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="L000566">Mr. Latta</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="K000009">Ms. Kaptur</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000672">Mr. Wolf</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000485">Mr. McIntyre</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000289">Mr. Jordan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001038">Mr. Higgins</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000572">Mr. Rogers of Michigan</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001062">Mr. Conaway</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HHA00">House Administration</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
    </action>
    <legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
    <official-title>To award the Congressional Gold Medal, collectively, to the members of the Office of Strategic Services (OSS) in recognition of their superior service and major contributions during World War II.</official-title>
  </form>
  <legis-body id="HF41D40CD266842539359796D930F0F1E" style="OLC">
    <section id="H532DDD5E1653490DAE925B7AF5E9282C" section-type="section-one">
      <enum>1.</enum>
      <header>Short title</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote>
          <short-title>Office of Strategic Services Congressional Gold Medal Act</short-title>
        </quote>.</text>
    </section>
    <section id="H4829452D780147AAACDF8ACDD1E9CAD3" section-type="subsequent-section">
      <enum>2.</enum>
      <header>Findings</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> finds the following:</text>
      <paragraph id="H306DD3BFA5C34FE8BB97E57E5D4D97EE">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text>The Office of Strategic Services (OSS) was America’s first effort to implement a system of strategic intelligence during World War II and provided the basis for the modern-day American intelligence and special operations communities.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H8D5F6AE7529546318963BCED84B29393">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text>OSS founder General William J. Donovan is the only person in American history to receive our Nation’s four highest military decorations, including the Medal of Honor. Upon learning of his death in 1959, President Eisenhower called General Donovan the <quote>last hero</quote>. In addition to founding and leading the OSS, General Donovan was also selected by President Roosevelt, who called him his <quote>secret legs</quote>, as an emissary to Great Britain and continental Europe before the United States entered World War II.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HD80D55B04F584AA081C98AA090651E45">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <text>All the military branches during World War II contributed personnel to the OSS. The present-day Special Operations Forces trace their lineage to the OSS. Its Maritime Unit was a precursor to the U.S. Navy SEALs. The OSS Operational Groups and Jedburghs were forerunners to U.S. Army Special Forces. The 801st/492nd Bombardment Group (<quote>Carpetbaggers</quote>) were progenitors to the Air Force Special Operations Command. The Marines who served in the OSS, including the actor Sterling Hayden and Col. William Eddy, whom General Donovan described as the <quote>American Lawrence of Arabia</quote>, were predecessors to the Marines Special Operations Command. U.S. Coast Guard personnel were recruited for the Maritime Unit and the Operational Swimmer Group.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H7EAE835CC39F46EFB3B0258E15B9FC3C">
        <enum>(4)</enum>
        <text>The OSS organized, trained, supplied, and fought with resistance organizations throughout Europe and Asia that played an important role in America’s victory during World War II. President Eisenhower credited the work of the OSS with the French Resistance during the liberation of France as the equivalent of having an extra division.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H47041270DF14454CBFA1485C4560528E">
        <enum>(5)</enum>
        <text>Four future directors of central intelligence served as OSS officers: William Casey, William Colby, Allen Dulles, and Richard Helms.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H1965869DB6F64A15A5669742395F3541">
        <enum>(6)</enum>
        <text>Women comprised more than one-third of OSS personnel and played a critical role in the organization. They included Virginia Hall, the only civilian female to receive a Distinguished Service Cross in World War II, and Julia Child.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HB12038DC54004108866078DE8C7EF713">
        <enum>(7)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">OSS recruited Fritz Kolbe, a German diplomat who became America's most important spy against the Nazis in World War II.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H38CE47D1A4AF49A6B283F17E2B516803">
        <enum>(8)</enum>
        <text>America’s leading scientists and scholars served in the OSS Research and Analysis Branch, including Ralph Bunche, the first African-American to receive the Nobel Peace Prize, Pulitzer Prize-winning historian Arthur Schlesinger, Jr., Supreme Court Justice Arthur Goldberg, Sherman Kent, John King Fairbank, and Walt Rostow. It ranks included seven future presidents of the American Historical Association, five of the American Economic Association, and two Nobel laureates. The U.S. Department of State’s Bureau of Intelligence and Research traces its creation to the OSS Research and Analysis Branch.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H404848A7A966462FB05AB85BDC91358B">
        <enum>(9)</enum>
        <text>The OSS invented and employed new technology through its Research and Development Branch, inventing new weapons and revolutionary communications equipment. Dr. Christian Lambertsen invented the first underwater rebreathing apparatus that was first utilized by the OSS and is known today as SCUBA.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HB3CA48D78D0E449F894A418A0F11952C">
        <enum>(10)</enum>
        <text>OSS Detachment 101 operated in Burma and pioneered the art of unconventional warfare. It was the first United States unit to deploy a large guerrilla army deep in enemy territory. It has been credited with the highest kill/loss ratio for any infantry-type unit in American military history and was awarded a Presidential Unit Citation.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HB9163C2B770B43F9884E90B2A9549905">
        <enum>(11)</enum>
        <text>Its X–2 branch pioneered counterintelligence with the British and established the modern counterintelligence community. The network of contacts built by the OSS with foreign intelligence services lead to enduring Cold War alliances.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HFFB9710934704EC2858CB39960B69992">
        <enum>(12)</enum>
        <text>Operation Torch, the Allied invasion of French North Africa in November 1942, was aided by the networks established and information acquired by the OSS to guide Allied landings.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H6B79951CFB1C4DF485C27D824092A724">
        <enum>(13)</enum>
        <text>OSS Operation Halyard rescued more than 500 downed airmen trapped behind enemy lines in Yugoslavia, one of the most daring and successful rescue operations of World War II.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HCF28631232814A028BD6F96827D5CC39">
        <enum>(14)</enum>
        <text>OSS <quote>Mercy Missions</quote> at the end of World War II saved the lives of thousands of Allied prisoners of war whom it was feared would be murdered by the Japanese.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H1CB399FF7479495F94E404E05417D0E4">
        <enum>(15)</enum>
        <text>The handful of surviving men and women of the OSS, whom General Donovan called his <quote>glorious amateurs</quote>, are among the greatest generation. They have never been collectively recognized for their heroic and pioneering service in World War II.</text>
      </paragraph>
    </section>
    <section id="H7BDA193B96BA4038A8C30D7621E24DAD">
      <enum>3.</enum>
      <header>Congressional gold medal</header>
      <subsection id="HD7050DD5E0324E81BB5D0F33C8280A67">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Presentation authorized</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Speaker of the House of Representatives" entity-parent-id="0050">Speaker of the House of Representatives</cato:entity-ref> and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="President pro tempore of the Senate" entity-parent-id="0010">President pro tempore of the Senate</cato:entity-ref> shall make appropriate arrangements for the presentation, on behalf of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref>, of a gold medal of appropriate design in commemoration to the members of the Office of Strategic Services (OSS), in recognition of their superior service and major contributions during World War II.</text>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="H6EDADE85E1244F6AA4D4F47A291B735B">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Design and striking</header>
        <text>For purposes of the presentation referred to in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Office of Strategic Services Congressional Gold Medal Act/s:3/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary of the Treasury</cato:entity-ref> (referred to in this Act as the <quote>Secretary</quote>) shall strike a gold medal with suitable emblems, devices, and inscriptions, to be determined by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="H212712E31FBC4CD4975E1B20187FD06A">
        <enum>(c)</enum>
        <header>Smithsonian Institution</header>
        <paragraph id="H9930AD30EBD24065A1A3CFA7FF2074DE">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>In general</header>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Following the award of the gold medal in commemoration to the members of the Office of Strategic Services under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Office of Strategic Services Congressional Gold Medal Act/s:3/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref>, the gold medal shall be given to the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="3300">Smithsonian Institution</cato:entity-ref>, where it will be displayed as appropriate and made available for research.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HDF173A62FB05446DAAD1C25F67BA4707">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Sense of Congress</header>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It is the sense of <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> that the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="3300">Smithsonian Institution</cato:entity-ref> should make the gold medal received under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Office of Strategic Services Congressional Gold Medal Act/s:3/ss:c/p:1" proposed="true">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref> available for display elsewhere, particularly at other appropriate locations associated with the Office of Strategic Services.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
    </section>
    <section id="HBA8C462CC97540FEB1A81314E816BAC2">
      <enum>4.</enum>
      <header>Duplicate medals</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> may strike and sell duplicates in bronze of the gold medal struck pursuant to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Office of Strategic Services Congressional Gold Medal Act/s:3" proposed="true">section 3</cato:entity-ref> under such regulations as the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> may prescribe, at a price sufficient to cover the cost thereof, including labor, materials, dies, use of machinery, and overhead expenses, and the cost of the gold medal.</text>
    </section>
    <section id="H173D701DEB7A4B1CB609E6724D92CFC3">
      <enum>5.</enum>
      <header>Status of medals</header>
      <subsection id="H0425260E75544B19A64B6B4C11C8E187">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>National medals</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The medals struck pursuant to this Act are national medals for purposes of <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc-chapter/31/51">
            <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/31/51">chapter 51</external-xref> of title 31, United States Code</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="H823AA0AA235349EAB67BC0DCE8E48FFC">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Numismatic items</header>
        <text>For purposes of <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc/31/5134">
            <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/31/5134">section 5134</external-xref> of title 31, United States Code</cato:entity-ref>, all medals struck under this Act shall be considered to be numismatic items.</text>
      </subsection>
    </section>
  </legis-body>
</bill>
</doc>