<doc>
  <docmeta id="113hr3283ih">
    <bill congress="113" type="hr" number="3283" version="ih"/>
    <revision size="22472" annotations="0" status="complete" id="6" commit-time="2013-10-14T17:45:32Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113hr3283ih/6.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HF21254C8006F494DA0307659D6A21811" public-private="public">
  <metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>113 HR 3283 IH: Integrated Public Alert and Warning System Modernization Act of 2013</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2013-10-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
    <congress>113th CONGRESS</congress>
    <session>1st Session</session>
    <legis-num>H. R. 3283</legis-num>
    <current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
    <action>
      <action-date date="20131010">October 10, 2013</action-date>
      <action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="B001257">Mr. Bilirakis</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Committee on Homeland Security</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
    </action>
    <legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
    <official-title>To amend the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to direct the Secretary of Homeland Security to modernize and implement the national integrated public alert and warning system to disseminate homeland security information and other information, and for other purposes.</official-title>
  </form>
  <legis-body id="H013D6D93A9AF4CF68F4AB8331B5D02E0" style="OLC">
    <section id="H9F7A436022634201BF295BB6D966C296" section-type="section-one">
      <enum>1.</enum>
      <header>Short title</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote>
          <short-title>Integrated Public Alert and Warning System Modernization Act of 2013</short-title>
        </quote>.</text>
    </section>
    <section id="H19CFA4D833E041F48E60D7EE0C3CEB71">
      <enum>2.</enum>
      <header>Findings</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">
        <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> finds that—</text>
      <paragraph id="H3EC7FB8B0AEE442DB2412DEF77D58EF7">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text>numerous proven and tested technologies exist to enable the Federal Government to enhance its dissemination of public alerts and warnings;</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HCEE522BCD6DF4F6D93D7DACB4AC33EC4">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text>the expected benefits of these enhancements include—</text>
        <subparagraph id="HD31FBB597FC04380AA6112D20CC05335">
          <enum>(A)</enum>
          <text>greater security, reliability, and redundancy of the Federal Government’s alert and warning capabilities;</text>
        </subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="HE1DD8139B3B24F65AD520D1DC162EA17">
          <enum>(B)</enum>
          <text>rapid alert dissemination;</text>
        </subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="H51269A54DE954ECEA5CE83410E5CFDB3">
          <enum>(C)</enum>
          <text>an improved ability to notify remote locations; and</text>
        </subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="H072ABBAE53CC489A8F18D065218E8ED8">
          <enum>(D)</enum>
          <text>the ability to geographically target and deliver alerts and warnings through multiple communication modes;</text>
        </subparagraph>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HF809D8C03880431DA45ADE384C5F7729">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <text>there is a need to test the viability of delivering messages through diverse communications modes to effectively alert and warn the public;</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HB20D44307D394EAFB69B1C3B27F847D1">
        <enum>(4)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">there is a need to modernize and improve the ability of the Federal Government to provide residents of the United States with timely and effective warnings; and</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H09D3DDB392B7420884695870FF42BDF7">
        <enum>(5)</enum>
        <text>although significant Federal integration efforts are underway, the aggregation, dissemination, and reporting system necessary for effective public alert and warning will require an integrated national network for reliable, secure, and authentic dissemination of emergency alerts and warnings by Federal, State, local, and tribal entities that are authorized to issue alerts to the public.</text>
      </paragraph>
    </section>
    <section id="H71757C60E6F047EAA9B7F741E98B3419">
      <enum>3.</enum>
      <header>national integrated public alert and warning system modernization</header>
      <subsection commented="no" id="H23977674396848F19427BB48F6D5E5E3">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>In general</header>
        <paragraph id="HD1487B1210C0424EA7773527847CFDA9">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>Amendment</header>
          <text>
            <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Homeland Security Act of 2002/t:V">Title V of the Homeland Security Act of 2002</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/311">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/6/311/etseq">6 U.S.C. 311 et seq.</cato:entity-ref>
              </external-xref>)</cato:entity> is amended by adding at the end of the following new section:</text>
          <quoted-block id="H805FD19B92AA43FBA9928BF7A3A6DC45">
            <section commented="no" id="HDC81B68E41CF442EB0490587B4E42A23">
              <enum>526.</enum>
              <header>National integrated public alert and warning system modernization</header>
              <subsection commented="no" id="H15C41DE1E8E94C209E4CEDB2BA8427BE">
                <enum>(a)</enum>
                <header>In general</header>
                <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In order to provide timely and effective warnings and disseminate homeland security information and other information, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7000">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall, considering the recommendations of the advisory committee established under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Homeland Security Act of 2002/s:526/ss:d" proposed="true">subsection (d)</cato:entity-ref>, modernize and implement the national integrated public alert and warning system (in this section referred to as <term>the public alert and warning system</term>).</text>
              </subsection>
              <subsection commented="no" id="H857A758D0DB14DEBB78C73BB456997B3">
                <enum>(b)</enum>
                <header>Implementation requirements</header>
                <text>In carrying out <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Homeland Security Act of 2002/s:526/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7000">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall—</text>
                <paragraph id="H5A7BAF5572F74A97AA34880302EE7536">
                  <enum>(1)</enum>
                  <text>establish or adapt, as appropriate, common alerting and warning protocols, standards, terminology, and operating procedures for the public alert and warning system;</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph commented="no" id="H1ED42E455A3F484EB62D6D3FBB485EFD">
                  <enum>(2)</enum>
                  <text>include in the public alert and warning system the capability to adapt the dissemination of homeland security information and other information and the content of communications on the basis of geographic location, risks, or personal user preferences, as appropriate;</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph commented="no" id="H87262AEB092F48FBA3B525CE913348EE">
                  <enum>(3)</enum>
                  <text>include in the public alert and warning system the capability to alert, warn, and provide the equivalent amount of information to individuals with disabilities and access and functional needs;</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph commented="no" id="H24DDFA1E25B54776A607A343FBEF32DE">
                  <enum>(4)</enum>
                  <text>ensure the conduct of training, tests, and exercises for the public alert and warning system, and that the system is incorporated into other training and exercise programs of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7000">Department</cato:entity-ref>, as appropriate;</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H997E90807A5446E9A415B2E83F58B7AF">
                  <enum>(5)</enum>
                  <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">ensure that ongoing training, integrated into the National Incident Management System, for receiving and disseminating public alert and warning system messages utilizing advanced technologies is provided to State, local, tribal, and other homeland security stakeholders involved in the transmission of such messages;</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="H8F01DDE0BC3B40B8ACA13706986C1BEF">
                  <enum>(6)</enum>
                  <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">ensure that the public alert and warning system uses the National Terrorism Advisory System, including ensuring that the National Terrorism Advisory System participates in tests of the public alert and warning system;</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="HD00EC9ED06EE44FCA632CF6E25B55042">
                  <enum>(7)</enum>
                  <text>conduct, at least once every 3 years, periodic nationwide tests of the public alert and warning system; and</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph commented="no" id="H6358215BAB764BFAB7940E5EA2DA20AE">
                  <enum>(8)</enum>
                  <text>consult, coordinate, and cooperate, to the extent practicable, with other Federal agencies and departments and with State, local, and tribal governments, the private sector, and other key stakeholders to leverage existing alert and warning capabilities.</text>
                </paragraph>
              </subsection>
              <subsection commented="no" id="HEA8E0005797E4364AAD306C5ED0E8DA5">
                <enum>(c)</enum>
                <header>System requirements</header>
                <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7000">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall ensure that the system—</text>
                <paragraph commented="no" id="HA22BD7349E034E2AAEFD9E8307C07C2E">
                  <enum>(1)</enum>
                  <text>incorporates redundant and diverse modes to disseminate homeland security information and other information in warning messages to the public so as to reach the greatest number of individuals;</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph commented="no" id="H563C07AF98D84264A7097D7A155D9067">
                  <enum>(2)</enum>
                  <text>can be adapted to incorporate future technologies;</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph commented="no" id="H1F821F4996284B50A7622B4B649819CC">
                  <enum>(3)</enum>
                  <text>is resilient, secure, and can withstand acts of terrorism and other external attacks;</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph commented="no" id="H5D6A5866AEF3403F8CF2DF017602D22E">
                  <enum>(4)</enum>
                  <text>promotes State, local, tribal, and regional partnerships to enhance coordination;</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="HBA21B50353AF4E9A9F30A13426404C3E">
                  <enum>(5)</enum>
                  <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is designed to provide alerts that are accessible to the largest portion of the affected population feasible, including nonresident visitors and tourists and individuals with disabilities and access and functional needs;</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="H2E020D3C65354DF09ABF27944C5C779A">
                  <enum>(6)</enum>
                  <text>is designed to improve the ability of remote areas and areas with underdeveloped telecommunications infrastructure to receive alerts; and</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="H7BDE8846D19748028E402D2A3ED94B63">
                  <enum>(7)</enum>
                  <text>includes mechanisms to ensure the protection of individual privacy.</text>
                </paragraph>
              </subsection>
              <subsection id="HCF45FCB70E05474F88450655D5DA5943">
                <enum>(d)</enum>
                <header>Integrated public alert and warning system modernization advisory committee</header>
                <paragraph id="HEBF7DE68C33848829B6BD4593B600684">
                  <enum>(1)</enum>
                  <header>Establishment</header>
                  <text>Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of the <short-title>
                      <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Integrated Public Alert and Warning System Modernization Act of 2013" proposed="true">Integrated Public Alert and Warning System Modernization Act of 2013</cato:entity-ref>
                    </short-title>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7000">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall establish an advisory committee to be known as the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Integrated Public Alert and Warning System Advisory Committee" entity-parent-id="7000" proposed="true">Integrated Public Alert and Warning System Advisory Committee</cato:entity-ref> (in this subsection referred to as the <quote>
                      <short-title>Advisory Committee</short-title>
                    </quote>).</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="H9B12DEA4DF3045789B36D48A58C5609D">
                  <enum>(2)</enum>
                  <header>Membership</header>
                  <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Integrated Public Alert and Warning System Advisory Committee" entity-parent-id="7000" proposed="true">Advisory Committee</cato:entity-ref> shall be composed of the following members:</text>
                  <subparagraph id="H75BE7FA377054C948C15A21170FEBCAA">
                    <enum>(A)</enum>
                    <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2700">Chairman of the Federal Communications Commission</cato:entity-ref> (or the Chairman’s designee).</text>
                  </subparagraph>
                  <subparagraph id="H3E4E0922B1CF4A658B2703DD33990B31">
                    <enum>(B)</enum>
                    <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1330">Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration</cato:entity-ref> (or the Administrator’s designee).</text>
                  </subparagraph>
                  <subparagraph id="HEA2D6411D8024AED89E29951C6FDAC54">
                    <enum>(C)</enum>
                    <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1335">Assistant Secretary for Communications and Information of the Department of Commerce</cato:entity-ref> (or the Assistant Secretary’s designee).</text>
                  </subparagraph>
                  <subparagraph id="H623FCC2B6D984A6094F1971368569F83">
                    <enum>(D)</enum>
                    <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7040">Under Secretary for Science and Technology of the Department of Homeland Security</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
                  </subparagraph>
                  <subparagraph id="H980A8F25271C428EAA2A1DDC52A587D6">
                    <enum>(E)</enum>
                    <text>The Director of the Office of Disability Integration and Coordination of the Federal Emergency Management Agency.</text>
                  </subparagraph>
                  <subparagraph id="H2113885BBA9245148A5FA6AEF6872D14">
                    <enum>(F)</enum>
                    <text>The following members, to be appointed by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7000">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> as soon as practicable after the date of enactment of the <short-title>
                        <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Integrated Public Alert and Warning System Modernization Act of 2013" proposed="true">Integrated Public Alert and Warning System Modernization Act of 2013</cato:entity-ref>
                      </short-title>:</text>
                    <clause id="H03E462125E144B0CBB91151968A55B47">
                      <enum>(i)</enum>
                      <text>Representatives of State and local governments, representatives of emergency management agencies, representatives of emergency response providers, and representatives of emergency communication providers, selected from among individuals nominated by national organizations representing governments and personnel.</text>
                    </clause>
                    <clause id="HA6439A32478E494EAE14A18343EACD4A">
                      <enum>(ii)</enum>
                      <text>Representatives from federally recognized Indian tribes and national Indian organizations.</text>
                    </clause>
                    <clause id="H2E20D91EC40D4DD2A95A72A845CA2CA4">
                      <enum>(iii)</enum>
                      <text>Individuals who have the requisite technical knowledge and expertise to serve on the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Integrated Public Alert and Warning System Advisory Committee" entity-parent-id="7000" proposed="true">Advisory Committee</cato:entity-ref>, including representatives of—</text>
                      <subclause id="HB456E5C9C8F9432593441D9286FF50CE">
                        <enum>(I)</enum>
                        <text>communications service providers;</text>
                      </subclause>
                      <subclause id="HB55FF5CE20464C7193EA93E225EEFE50">
                        <enum>(II)</enum>
                        <text>vendors, developers, and manufacturers of systems, facilities, equipment, and capabilities for the provision of communications services;</text>
                      </subclause>
                      <subclause id="HBB3C0F3868F04ED5AA95548B65E74EC0">
                        <enum>(III)</enum>
                        <text>third-party service bureaus;</text>
                      </subclause>
                      <subclause id="H61FEF641AB5B4CD194FB7F0EFEC938F0">
                        <enum>(IV)</enum>
                        <text>the broadcasting industry;</text>
                      </subclause>
                      <subclause id="H8ECEC9FB796D41E38FE5E38F921AF1B0">
                        <enum>(V)</enum>
                        <text>the cellular industry;</text>
                      </subclause>
                      <subclause id="H75EADDC4D0B14E41B538CBBEAD3CF0DA">
                        <enum>(VI)</enum>
                        <text>the cable industry;</text>
                      </subclause>
                      <subclause id="H0051BAF618224D82BE40023129AB821F">
                        <enum>(VII)</enum>
                        <text>the satellite industry;</text>
                      </subclause>
                      <subclause id="H367EB0F3667546CB864460BB867884F4">
                        <enum>(VIII)</enum>
                        <text>national organizations representing individuals with disabilities and access and functional needs, and the elderly; and</text>
                      </subclause>
                      <subclause id="H437CE36BA9F44BF1832F04CB3DC522B1">
                        <enum>(IX)</enum>
                        <text>national organizations representing educational institutions, including higher education.</text>
                      </subclause>
                    </clause>
                    <clause id="HD688D09087744E1F8E341543D9E8357C">
                      <enum>(iv)</enum>
                      <text>Qualified representatives of such other stakeholders and interested and affected parties as the Secretary considers appropriate.</text>
                    </clause>
                  </subparagraph>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="HE3E26DB7E09E406983520A68C00BFB1E">
                  <enum>(3)</enum>
                  <header>Chairperson</header>
                  <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7000">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> (or the Secretary’s designee) shall serve as the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Integrated Public Alert and Warning System Advisory Committee" entity-parent-id="7000" proposed="true">Chairperson of the Advisory Committee</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="HD07EF3B0F7BF4415A975B63EBCB177CB">
                  <enum>(4)</enum>
                  <header>Meetings</header>
                  <subparagraph id="H8E9A1AA8CA3748C78DD9EFED687E9FC5">
                    <enum>(A)</enum>
                    <header>Initial meeting</header>
                    <text>The initial meeting of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Integrated Public Alert and Warning System Advisory Committee" entity-parent-id="7000" proposed="true">Advisory Committee</cato:entity-ref> shall take place not later than 120 days after the date of enactment of the <short-title>
                        <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Integrated Public Alert and Warning System Modernization Act of 2013" proposed="true">Integrated Public Alert and Warning System Modernization Act of 2013</cato:entity-ref>
                      </short-title>.</text>
                  </subparagraph>
                  <subparagraph id="HC4206C0C23464C8287CA87590E44431D">
                    <enum>(B)</enum>
                    <header>Other meetings</header>
                    <text>After the initial meeting, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Integrated Public Alert and Warning System Advisory Committee" entity-parent-id="7000" proposed="true">Advisory Committee</cato:entity-ref> shall meet, at least annually, at the call of the Chairperson.</text>
                  </subparagraph>
                  <subparagraph id="H15BF835538BB4A8782CBF68BA3F77EDA">
                    <enum>(C)</enum>
                    <header>Notice; open meetings</header>
                    <text>Meetings held by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Integrated Public Alert and Warning System Advisory Committee" entity-parent-id="7000" proposed="true">Advisory Committee</cato:entity-ref> shall be duly noticed at least 14 days in advance and shall be open to the public.</text>
                  </subparagraph>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="H2E3391A2AE7449ED95D22FD67797B944">
                  <enum>(5)</enum>
                  <header>Rules</header>
                  <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Integrated Public Alert and Warning System Advisory Committee" entity-parent-id="7000" proposed="true">Advisory Committee</cato:entity-ref> may adopt such rules as are necessary to carry out its duties.</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="HD405D079195644F4956996F6AAAD2590">
                  <enum>(6)</enum>
                  <header>Consultation with nonmembers</header>
                  <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Integrated Public Alert and Warning System Advisory Committee" entity-parent-id="7000" proposed="true">Advisory Committee</cato:entity-ref> and the program office for the integrated public alert and warning system of the United States shall regularly meet with groups that are not represented on the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Integrated Public Alert and Warning System Advisory Committee" entity-parent-id="7000" proposed="true">Advisory Committee</cato:entity-ref> to consider new and developing technology that may be beneficial to the public alert and warning system, such as—</text>
                  <subparagraph id="H06B9673EF4DE4ED5A793249F1599EFA7">
                    <enum>(A)</enum>
                    <text>the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="97AE">Defense Advanced Research Projects Agency</cato:entity-ref>;</text>
                  </subparagraph>
                  <subparagraph id="H2CEF02E9E96B4A969C0379CAE9B7126F">
                    <enum>(B)</enum>
                    <text>entities engaged in federally funded research; and</text>
                  </subparagraph>
                  <subparagraph id="HE63AB6F190C44B73923A88AF232CE7C0">
                    <enum>(C)</enum>
                    <text>academic institutions engaged in relevant work and research.</text>
                  </subparagraph>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="H93C6CC6718A1451AA2EF36EE05AA859F">
                  <enum>(7)</enum>
                  <header>Recommendations</header>
                  <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Integrated Public Alert and Warning System Advisory Committee" entity-parent-id="7000" proposed="true">Advisory Committee</cato:entity-ref> shall develop and submit in the annual reports under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Homeland Security Act of 2002/s:526/ss:d/p:8" proposed="true">paragraph (8)</cato:entity-ref> recommendations for the continuation and improvement of an integrated public alert and warning system, including—</text>
                  <subparagraph id="HAB0808198C9B441DB6C87969C94FA559">
                    <enum>(A)</enum>
                    <text>recommendations for common alerting and warning protocols, standards, terminology, and operating procedures for the public alert and warning system;</text>
                  </subparagraph>
                  <subparagraph id="HC3C56108B8B94C51A71DFF0B0954CC37">
                    <enum>(B)</enum>
                    <text>an assessment of the accomplishments and deficiencies of the public alert and warning system, as well as the impact on current alert and warning systems;</text>
                  </subparagraph>
                  <subparagraph id="HC1662AF68AFE49E08F351BF4D540AA6C">
                    <enum>(C)</enum>
                    <text>recommendations for increasing participation in the system, particularly among elementary, secondary, and higher education institutions; and</text>
                  </subparagraph>
                  <subparagraph id="HF777501AE511451296F8080F449F14B5">
                    <enum>(D)</enum>
                    <text>recommendations for improvements to the system, including recommendations to provide for a public alert and warning system that—</text>
                    <clause id="HA4D86777DC0C4BBFB98479CF4412E923">
                      <enum>(i)</enum>
                      <text>has the capability to adapt the distribution and content of communications on the basis of geographic location, risks, multiple communication systems and technologies or personal user preferences, as appropriate;</text>
                    </clause>
                    <clause id="H8B24759A3D644466B9AD3D0715C1C6F1">
                      <enum>(ii)</enum>
                      <text>has the capability to alert and warn individuals with disabilities and access and functional needs and individuals with limited English proficiency;</text>
                    </clause>
                    <clause id="HA6C44400B14343A7A7DDE077C324A476">
                      <enum>(iii)</enum>
                      <text>incorporates multiple communications technologies;</text>
                    </clause>
                    <clause id="HB5899F93CFEF41C48182F8C23B8FDA4D">
                      <enum>(iv)</enum>
                      <text>is designed to adapt to, and incorporate, future technologies for communicating directly with the public;</text>
                    </clause>
                    <clause id="H6A156A18B3284FD785467BFDC67A1A62">
                      <enum>(v)</enum>
                      <text>encourages proper use by State and local governments of the public alert and warning system through training programs and other means;</text>
                    </clause>
                    <clause id="H09D3B2E636984ECDA2B67ACF888513A1">
                      <enum>(vi)</enum>
                      <text>is designed to provide alerts to the largest portion of the affected population feasible, including nonresident visitors and tourists, and improve the ability of remote areas to receive alerts;</text>
                    </clause>
                    <clause id="H61D3D21908DC4FC5A2A269E8F32E8B36">
                      <enum>(vii)</enum>
                      <text>promotes local and regional public and private partnerships to enhance community preparedness and response;</text>
                    </clause>
                    <clause id="HF21E1686448F498FA369C557A6B1C70D">
                      <enum>(viii)</enum>
                      <text>promotes the participation of representatives from underserved and underrepresented communities, to ensure that alerts and warnings reach such populations; and</text>
                    </clause>
                    <clause id="H5CD3C29F99A14160BEA7DBF923AC0481">
                      <enum>(ix)</enum>
                      <text>provides redundant alert mechanisms where practicable so as to reach the greatest number of people regardless of whether they have access to, or utilize, any specific medium of communication or any particular device.</text>
                    </clause>
                  </subparagraph>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="HBD253F55978A4D8BBAF791D31DC30CC8">
                  <enum>(8)</enum>
                  <header>Report</header>
                  <text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of the <short-title>
                      <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Integrated Public Alert and Warning System Modernization Act of 2013" proposed="true">Integrated Public Alert and Warning System Modernization Act of 2013</cato:entity-ref>
                    </short-title>, and every year after, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Integrated Public Alert and Warning System Advisory Committee" entity-parent-id="7000" proposed="true">Advisory Committee</cato:entity-ref> shall submit to the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7000">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> a report containing the recommendations of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Integrated Public Alert and Warning System Advisory Committee" entity-parent-id="7000" proposed="true">Advisory Committee</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="HFD9B1E25065F44639150A87AEDB53CB9">
                  <enum>(9)</enum>
                  <header>Federal Advisory Committee Act</header>
                  <text>Neither the <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
                      <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Federal Advisory Committee Act">Federal Advisory Committee Act</cato:entity-ref> (<cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc-appendix/5">5 U.S.C. App.</cato:entity-ref>)</cato:entity> nor any rule, order, or regulation promulgated under that Act shall apply to the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Integrated Public Alert and Warning System Advisory Committee" entity-parent-id="7000" proposed="true">Advisory Committee</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
                </paragraph>
              </subsection>
              <subsection commented="no" id="H792DEE3611B14050AB83240BCB93FE42">
                <enum>(e)</enum>
                <header>Report</header>
                <text>Not later than 1 year after the date on which the system established under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Homeland Security Act of 2002/s:526/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref> is fully functional and every six months thereafter, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7000">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall submit to the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="committee" entity-id="HHM00">Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives</cato:entity-ref> and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="committee" entity-id="SSGA00">Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate</cato:entity-ref>, a report on the functionality and performance of the integrated public alert and warning system, including—</text>
                <paragraph id="H301513FDA1CF425099509539DFF09926">
                  <enum>(1)</enum>
                  <text>the findings of the most recent <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Integrated Public Alert and Warning System Advisory Committee" entity-parent-id="7000" proposed="true">Advisory Committee</cato:entity-ref> report under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Homeland Security Act of 2002/s:526/ss:d/p:8" proposed="true">subsection (d)(8)</cato:entity-ref>;</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph commented="no" id="H069780016DAF47CCBEE6825F1E7F691E">
                  <enum>(2)</enum>
                  <text>an assessment of the accomplishments and deficiencies of the system;</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph commented="no" id="H35E91EA5F71F424D97818E3A301CFBFA">
                  <enum>(3)</enum>
                  <text>recommendations for improvements to the system; and</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph commented="no" id="H2158F20651E84FC08326C5FA1EF8C122">
                  <enum>(4)</enum>
                  <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">information on the feasibility and effectiveness of disseminating homeland security information and other information, notices, and alerts prior to and following an incident requiring use of the system.</text>
                </paragraph>
              </subsection>
              <subsection commented="no" id="HA4A4A7227FDB48B7B2538CC7B9A1A97E">
                <enum>(f)</enum>
                <header>Authorization of appropriations</header>
                <text>
                  <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="auth-auth-approp">There is authorized to be appropriated <cato:property name="purpose">to the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7000">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> to carry out <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Homeland Security Act of 2002/s:526" proposed="true">this section</cato:entity-ref>
                    </cato:property> <cato:funds-and-year amount="13400000" year="2014, 2015">$13,400,000 for each of fiscal years 2014 and 2015</cato:funds-and-year>.</cato:entity>
                </text>
              </subsection>
            </section>
            <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
          </quoted-block>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H564F8F870BF64D99A7C842D7A7855E92">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Clerical amendment</header>
          <text>The table of contents in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Homeland Security Act of 2002/s:1/ss:b">section 1(b) of such Act</cato:entity-ref> is amended by adding at the end of the items relating to such title the following:</text>
          <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H31A83AA24F404517BAFB46EBEE698047" style="OLC">
            <toc regeneration="no-regeneration">
              <toc-entry level="section">Sec. 526. National integrated public alert and warning system modernization.</toc-entry>
            </toc>
            <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
          </quoted-block>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="H90DC69FCD9BE4ED199FD51FF47678728">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Limitation on statutory construction</header>
        <paragraph id="H29A61C8F95094D14A365E02484493961">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>In general</header>
          <text>Nothing in this Act (including the amendment made by this Act) shall be construed—</text>
          <subparagraph id="H519B5C54E9DE4011AEA89964238403D8">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>to affect the authority of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1300">Department of Commerce</cato:entity-ref>, the authority of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2700">Federal Communications Commission</cato:entity-ref>, or the <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act">Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5121">
                  <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/42/5121/etseq">42 U.S.C. 5121 et seq.</cato:entity-ref>
                </external-xref>)</cato:entity>;</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="HE7A55EA1B64946F6962083641A1CFBB6">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>to provide the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7000">Secretary of Homeland Security</cato:entity-ref> authority to require any action by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2700">Federal Communications Commission</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1300">Department of Commerce</cato:entity-ref>, or any nongovernment entity, or to affect any existing obligations of those entities; or</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H8855A86004B84CB59FA880AF14101228">
            <enum>(C)</enum>
            <text>to apply to, or provide the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7022">Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency</cato:entity-ref> any authority over, any participating commercial mobile service provider.</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HB10DE71971274B8292F23B128C4E1806">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Participating commercial mobile service provider defined</header>
          <text>For purposes of this subsection, the term <term>participating commercial mobile service provider</term> has the same meaning as such term has in <external-xref legal-doc="regulation" parsable-cite="cfr/47/10.10">section 10.10(f)</external-xref> of title 47, Code of Federal Regulations, as in effect on the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection commented="no" id="H43E8C6C40BED4C2F9F619854A7C89250">
        <enum>(c)</enum>
        <header>Homeland security grants</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">
          <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Homeland Security Act of 2002/s:2008/ss:a">Section 2008(a) of the Homeland Security Act of 2002</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/609">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/6/609/a">6 U.S.C. 609(a)</cato:entity-ref>
            </external-xref>)</cato:entity> is amended—</text>
        <paragraph id="H3D9A8BBD796C4020AA7F67898D0CD954">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Homeland Security Act of 2002/s:2008/ss:a/p:12">paragraph (12)</cato:entity-ref>, by striking <quote>
              <short-title>and</short-title>
            </quote> at the end;</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H88D6B393D16E4C119E2F0216CC1DC97A">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>by redesignating <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Homeland Security Act of 2002/s:2008/ss:a/p:13">paragraph (13)</cato:entity-ref> as <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Homeland Security Act of 2002/s:2008/ss:a/p:14" proposed="true">paragraph (14)</cato:entity-ref>; and</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H680274F2CAB742CDB5733A8608F4B1E0">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <text>by inserting after <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Homeland Security Act of 2002/s:2008/ss:a/p:12">paragraph (12)</cato:entity-ref> the following new paragraph:</text>
          <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEFF921D2229B4843B94080B53970C1FE" style="OLC">
            <paragraph id="H4CC127DA0EDD4B0191468732F7D4D4E2">
              <enum>(13)</enum>
              <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">improving public alert and warning capabilities; and</text>
            </paragraph>
            <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
          </quoted-block>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
    </section>
  </legis-body>
</bill>
</doc>