<doc>
  <docmeta id="113hr301eh">
    <bill congress="113" type="hr" number="301" version="eh"/>
    <revision size="10290" annotations="0" status="complete" id="4" commit-time="2013-10-24T23:09:13Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113hr301eh/4.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <bill bill-stage="Engrossed-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H793FB45F0BE841A2BE21703379FFE1FF" public-private="public" stage-count="1"> 
<metadata>
<dublinCore>
<title>113 HR 301 EH: To provide for the establishment of the Special Envoy to Promote Religious Freedom of Religious Minorities in the Near East and South Central Asia.</title>
<publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</publisher>
<date/>
<format>text/xml</format>
<language>EN</language>
<rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="no">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>113th CONGRESS</congress> <session>1st Session</session> 
<legis-num>H. R. 301</legis-num> 
<current-chamber display="no">IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type> 
<official-title display="yes">To provide for the establishment of the Special Envoy to Promote Religious Freedom of Religious Minorities in the Near East and South Central Asia.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H4D877BB2ED40464F89CAE2D0BA378284" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HD1CFB365D6404F65A7799BD0D333FCCC" section-type="section-one">
      <enum>1.</enum>
      <header>Findings</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="HBAA1CCC24399440BA15B039010E401AD">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">More than 500 Baha'is in Iran have been arbitrarily arrested since 2005. Roughly 100 Baha'is are presently imprisoned because of their religious beliefs.</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HD8A813C392F54150A14B0F4444392CB2">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text>In May 2010, suspected terrorists attacked two mosques in Pakistan belonging to the Ah­mad­diya minority Muslim sect, killing at least 80 people. Ahmadis consider themselves Muslim, but Pakistani law does not recognize them as such.</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HA74C5B1D862E4994B12FF12122F0D4C9">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <text>Said Musa, an Afghan Christian convert, was arrested in May 2010 on charges of apostasy, a crime which can carry the death sentence, and was released in February 2011 only after sustained international pressure.</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HB28B305A26F848BBA4423022AC363E52">
        <enum>(4)</enum>
        <text>On October 31, 2010, gunmen laid siege on Our Lady of Salvation Church in Baghdad, Iraq, killing at least 52 police and worshipers, including two priests, making it the worst massacre of Iraqi Christians since 2003.</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HED2AB146C51E43BDB5059BFD5B2D3B8F">
        <enum>(5)</enum>
        <text>Iraq’s ancient and once vibrant Christian population that numbered an estimated 1,500,000 out of a total population in Iraq of 30,000,000 in 2003 has been reduced by at least one half, due in significant part to Christians fleeing the violence.</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H186B10EA937B488DB4A62366ABB1F2C6">
        <enum>(6)</enum>
        <text>In November 2010, a Pakistani court sentenced Aasia Bibi, a Christian mother of five, to death under the country’s blasphemy law for insulting the Prophet Muhammad.</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H557077363DFB43A8A7BB9DFA155E119D">
        <enum>(7)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Since early 2011, violent sectarian attacks targeting Coptic Orthodox Christians and their property increased significantly, resulting in nearly 100 deaths, mostly Coptic Christians, surpassing the death toll of the 10 previous years combined.</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H459BB40D494F45C0964986823E2A5894">
        <enum>(8)</enum>
        <text>In Egypt, with the ascent of the Muslim Brotherhood, Coptic Christians, numbering 8 to 10 million, have been under increased threat and many are reported to have fled the country during former President Mohamed Morsi’s rule.</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HD7B088A1B4F54024A81F72B4A01FC210">
        <enum>(9)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">On March 2, 2011, Pakistani Federal Minorities Minister Shahbaz Bhatti, the only Christian member of the Cabinet, who was outspoken in his opposition to Pakistan’s blasphemy laws was assassinated by extremists.</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H54C895194F8B4CC0B0AD883301FB8D2D">
        <enum>(10)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The former Special Envoy to Monitor and Combat Anti-Semitism, Hannah Rosenthal, has noted that Holocaust glorification <quote>is especially virulent in Middle Eastern media, some of which is state-owned and operated, which calls for a new Holocaust to finish the job</quote>.</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H5200D191314442DEB63D620076940E19">
        <enum>(11)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the midst of a devastating civil war, Syrian Christians and other religious minorities, which comprise roughly 10 percent of the population, are particularly vulnerable lacking their own militias and regional protectors.</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HF2074B2C3C1F40E3A202F8FF364A809A">
        <enum>(12)</enum>
        <text>Many of these ancient faith communities are being forced to flee the lands which they have inhabited for centuries.</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H498BF70B28E543A680FE1979D2D9D429">
        <enum>(13)</enum>
        <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="4864">United States
			 Commission on International Religious Freedom</cato:entity-ref> has recommended that Egypt,
			 Tajikistan, Iran, Iraq, Pakistan, Saudi Arabia, Turkmenistan, and Uzbekistan be
			 designated by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Department of State</cato:entity-ref> as Countries of Particular Concern in
			 accordance with the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="International Religious Freedom Act of 1998">International Religious Freedom Act of 1998</cato:entity-ref>.</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H6B36B3EDB85644D8B6694FB32B46A1E7">
        <enum>(14)</enum>
        <text>The situation on the ground in the region continues to develop rapidly and the United States Government needs an individual who can respond in kind and focus on the critical situation of religious minorities in these countries.</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HB185783A04374AB3B18113AD39628BE4">
        <enum>(15)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There are historical precedents, including
			 the Special Envoy to Monitor and Combat Anti-Semitism, the Special Envoy for
			 North Korea Human Rights Issues, and the South Sudan and Sudan Special Envoy,
			 for the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Department of State</cato:entity-ref>, either as a result of legislative mandate or
			 initiative of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref>, to create positions with a targeted focus
			 on an area or issue of recognized import.</text> </paragraph>
    </section>
<section id="H8151A195C37A483AB4D608B9D3178723" section-type="subsequent-section">
      <enum>2.</enum>
      <header>Special Envoy to Promote Religious Freedom of Religious Minorities in the Near East and South Central Asia</header> 
<subsection id="H6120B23D835C4EA6951AB24B8BCE04A4">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Appointment</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> shall appoint a Special Envoy
			 to Promote Religious Freedom of Religious Minorities in the Near East and South
			 Central Asia (in this Act referred to as the <term>Special Envoy</term>) within
			 the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Department of State</cato:entity-ref>.</text> </subsection>
<subsection id="H0EF6958840744E8BA414D7473FB14562">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Qualifications</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Special Envoy should be a person of
			 recognized distinction in the field of human rights and religious freedom and
			 with expertise in the Near East and South Central Asia regions. The Special
			 Envoy shall have the rank of ambassador and shall hold the office at the
			 pleasure of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref>.</text> </subsection>
<subsection id="H82999884178C42E1953215562413573F">
        <enum>(c)</enum>
        <header>Prohibition</header>
        <text>The person appointed as Special Envoy may not hold any other position of Federal employment for the period of time during which the person holds the position of Special Envoy.</text> </subsection>
    </section>
<section id="H32B0FB3736474936BA1818FFE6634B15">
      <enum>3.</enum>
      <header>Duties</header> 
<subsection id="H2D0A03528E714F89A077C61978229D8A">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>In general</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Special Envoy shall carry out the following duties:</text> 
<paragraph id="HA1F4CE91D4C3425790EC9189961D13DF">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>Promote the right of religious freedom of religious minorities in the countries of the Near East and the countries of South Central Asia, denounce the violation of such right, and recommend appropriate responses by the United States Government when such right is violated.</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H1383419154B94AE3A6318092824A827F">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Monitor and combat acts of religious intolerance and incitement targeted against religious minorities in the countries of the Near East and the countries of South Central Asia.</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HB5E58D4216D24CB3B93C55471BEB7575">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Work to ensure that the unique needs of religious minority communities in the countries of the Near East and the countries of South Central Asia are addressed, including the economic and security needs of such communities to the extent that such needs are directly tied to religious-based discrimination and persecution.</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HE276FE42FE534D93A238626AEEF18CDE">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Work with foreign governments of the countries of the Near East and the countries of South Central Asia to address laws that are inherently discriminatory toward religious minority communities in such countries.</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H4E92BC47B24E41E79ACF0ADF4E71733C">
          <enum>(5)</enum>
          <text>Coordinate and
			 assist in the preparation of that portion of the report required by <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Foreign Assistance Act of 1961/s:116/ss:d">sections
			 116(d)</cato:entity-ref> and <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Foreign Assistance Act of 1961/s:502B/ss:b">502B(b) of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961</cato:entity-ref> (<cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc/22/2151n/d">22 U.S.C. 2151n(d)</cato:entity-ref>
			 and <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc/22/2304/b">2304(b)</cato:entity-ref>) relating to the nature and extent of religious freedom of
			 religious minorities in the countries of the Near East and the countries of
			 South Central Asia.</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H750B653C74824ED9A5FBCCAB6B84B469">
          <enum>(6)</enum>
          <text>Coordinate and
			 assist in the preparation of that portion of the report required by <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="International Religious Freedom Act of 1998/s:102/ss:b">section
			 102(b) of the International Religious Freedom Act of 1998</cato:entity-ref> (<cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/22/6412/b">22 U.S.C. 6412(b)</cato:entity-ref>)</cato:entity>
			 relating to the nature and extent of religious freedom of religious minorities
			 in the countries of the Near East and the countries of South Central
			 Asia.</text> </paragraph>
      </subsection>
<subsection id="H02B0FEADCA7341DEB4464EC042B100EF">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Coordination</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out the duties under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="113 HR 301/s:3/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection
			 (a)</cato:entity-ref>, the Special Envoy shall, to the maximum extent practicable, coordinate
			 with the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1954">Bureau of Population, Refugees and Migration of the Department of
			 State</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="4864">Ambassador at Large for International Religious Freedom</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="4864">United
			 States Commission on International Religious Freedom</cato:entity-ref>, and other relevant
			 Federal agencies and officials.</text> </subsection>
    </section>
<section id="H9B189B21035B43989A8E588C418B5044">
      <enum>4.</enum>
      <header>Diplomatic representation</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Subject to the
			 direction of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President </cato:entity-ref>and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref>, the Special Envoy is
			 authorized to represent the United States in matters and cases relevant to
			 religious freedom in the countries of the Near East and the countries of South
			 Central Asia in—</text> 
<paragraph id="HDDA981C02E7F4FABA2713F42990214D0">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text>contacts with
			 foreign governments, intergovernmental organizations, and <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="19UN">specialized agencies
			 of the United Nations</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0901">Organization of Security and Cooperation in Europe</cato:entity-ref>,
			 and other international organizations of which the United States is a member;
			 and</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HF09DBFD0E8DD49CE8B0DBFEB745A7FE2">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text>multilateral conferences and meetings relevant to religious freedom in the countries of the Near East and the countries of South Central Asia.</text> </paragraph>
    </section>
<section id="H4EC975B0EDC146C6B6DC03C4A20CED70">
      <enum>5.</enum>
      <header>Priority countries and consultation</header> 
<subsection id="H1D8B32FF2F3D42D0A73489EAD6D45699">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Priority countries</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out this Act, the Special Envoy shall give priority to programs, projects, and activities for Egypt, Iran, Iraq, Afghanistan, and Pakistan.</text> </subsection>
<subsection id="HBD7CBCF7AE6645E3A4FDD3DC25AC5B7A">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Consultation</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Special Envoy shall consult with domestic and international nongovernmental organizations and multilateral organizations and institutions, as the Special Envoy considers appropriate to fulfill the purposes of this Act.</text> </subsection>
    </section>
<section id="HE656736ADF754FFEA578FCA459CAC7F5">
      <enum>6.</enum>
      <header>Funding</header> 
<subsection id="HC280989CFC534E0AB1BED2A0070FEED9">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>In general</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">
          <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="auth-auth-approp">Of the amounts made available for <term>Diplomatic and Consular Programs</term> for fiscal years 2014 through 2018, <cato:funds-and-year amount="1000000" year="2014, 2015, 2016, 2017, 2018">$1,000,000 is authorized to be appropriated for each such fiscal year</cato:funds-and-year> <cato:property name="purpose">to carry out the provisions of <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="113 HR 301" proposed="true">this Act</cato:entity-ref>
            </cato:property>.</cato:entity>
        </text> </subsection>
<subsection id="HD307A1E556E44885AE8D0E0323A6F79B">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Funding offset</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To offset the costs to
			 be incurred by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Department of State</cato:entity-ref> to carry out the provisions of this Act
			 for fiscal years 2014 through 2018, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref> shall eliminate such
			 positions within the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Department of State</cato:entity-ref>, unless otherwise authorized or
			 required by law, as the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> determines to be necessary to fully offset
			 such costs.</text> </subsection>
<subsection id="HB9648079934448AD9EE04610B6C9400A">
        <enum>(c)</enum>
        <header>Limitation</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No additional funds are authorized to be appropriated for <term>Diplomatic and Consular Programs</term> to carry out the provisions of this Act.</text> </subsection>
    </section>
<section id="H6F71A46F42D74B108F132F8A0A2F1FB1">
      <enum>7.</enum>
      <header>Sunset</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act shall cease to be effective beginning on October 1, 2018.</text> </section>
</legis-body> <attestation>
    <attestation-group>
      <attestation-date date="20130918" chamber="House">Passed the House of Representatives September 18, 2013.</attestation-date>
      <attestor display="no">Karen L. Haas,</attestor>
      <role>Clerk.</role>
    </attestation-group>
  </attestation>
<endorsement display="yes"/>
</bill>
</doc>