<doc>
  <docmeta id="113hr3624ih">
    <bill congress="113" type="hr" number="3624" version="ih"/>
    <revision size="4279" annotations="0" status="complete" id="3" commit-time="2013-12-09T01:58:24Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113hr3624ih/3.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H72F23A0F95DF425FBE9DEFDED306907F" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata>
<dublinCore>
<dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">113 HR 3624 IH: Trans Fat Truth in Labeling Act of 2013</dc:title>
<dc:publisher xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">2013-11-22</dc:date>
<dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>113th CONGRESS</congress>
<session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. R. 3624</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20131122">November 22, 2013</action-date> 
<action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="I000057">Mr. Israel</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>
      </action-desc>
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To direct the Commissioner of Food and Drugs to revise the Federal regulations applicable to the declaration of the trans fat content of a food on the label and in the labeling of the food when such content is less than 0.5 gram.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H8AD044181F5C46CDBE53A959A7FE0FA1" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H1D664CD16DC9462E804F2C06D11D2E7B" section-type="section-one">
      <enum>1.</enum>
      <header>Short title</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote>
          <short-title>Trans Fat Truth in Labeling Act of 2013</short-title>
        </quote>.</text>
    </section> 
<section id="H6E786DB5AA0A44D8BEC4AEF838CBB4CD">
      <enum>2.</enum>
      <header>Findings</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> finds the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="HEC0CA00CE4DB473D839DB5FE9B88E21B">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text>The Institute of Medicine of the National Academies advises the United States Government on nutritional science for use in the formation of public policy, including product labeling programs.</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDE0B12D7725A4E42B753C31F0C7DB961">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text>In 2002, the Institute of Medicine—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H0AADF34513F14968B200159AF57DCC08">
          <enum>(A)</enum>
          <text>issued recommended dietary reference intake amounts for energy, carbohydrates, fiber, fat, fatty acids, cholesterol, protein, and amino acids; and</text>
        </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5266FF052BA34373B9CAE5F562A36A92">
          <enum>(B)</enum>
          <text>made recommendations regarding consumption of trans fat.</text>
        </subparagraph>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H09FEC8F7785748DEBEE2C1217842A247">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <text>These recommendations included the following statement: <quote>trans fatty acids are not essential and provide no known benefit to human health</quote>.</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA7F896C84C3B42298591052A544E94C6">
        <enum>(4)</enum>
        <text>The Institute of Medicine concluded that—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H6252B55366794E03A144C32B52A3D21A">
          <enum>(A)</enum>
          <text>both saturated and trans fats increase levels of LDL cholesterol; and</text>
        </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H07AB35FFE6294D20BE23F71DEF9A9D46">
          <enum>(B)</enum>
          <text>trans fats may also lower levels of HDL cholesterol.</text>
        </subparagraph>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFFA88788F4EB4F0F8645B0DE568A8E1B">
        <enum>(5)</enum>
        <text>A 2006 New England Journal of Medicine scientific review stated that <quote>from a nutritional standpoint, the consumption of trans fatty acids results in considerable potential harm but no apparent benefit</quote>.</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8AD000F37DAD450CA190E6ED9C5F6758">
        <enum>(6)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline"> Based on this overwhelming scientific evidence, in 2013, the Food and Drug Administration issued a preliminary determination that partially hydrogenated oils, which are the primary dietary source of artificial trans fats, are not <quote>generally recognized as safe</quote> for use as an ingredient in food. </text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0EB72DE4CD7F4143982D95123217BE8C">
        <enum>(7)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding such preliminary determination, certain foods will still contain a certain level of naturally-occurring trans fats, and current laws and regulations, which only require that the labeling of food containing a certain threshold amount of trans fats bear that fact, will remain in effect.</text>
      </paragraph>
    </section> 
<section id="HA2120CE1098D4CBBA17AD665311E9817">
      <enum>3.</enum>
      <header>Declaration of trans fat content of less than 0.5 gram per serving on the label or in the labeling of food</header> 
<subsection id="HB5B4CEDC3BBC40A9BB9BC9BA99CE3135">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Requirement</header>
        <text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7524">Commissioner of Food and Drugs</cato:entity-ref> shall promulgate a final regulation, revising <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/101">section 101.9(c)(2)(ii)</external-xref> of title 21 of the Code of Federal Regulations and such other regulatory provisions as may be necessary, to—</text> 
<paragraph id="HE43DC935940D4FBA82D7CCCED9903054">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>require that the nutrition information on the label or labeling on an applicable food contain an asterisk or another similar notation and a note to indicate that the food has a low trans fat content per serving; and</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDA874D37DA0E40B78C08E5FDEF165404">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>prohibit the label or labeling on an applicable food from indicating that trans fat content per serving is zero.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="H1557BD0C132042C6AF796A060C0AEC9B">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Applicable food</header>
        <text>For purposes of this section, the term <term>applicable food</term> means a food for which—</text> 
<paragraph id="HD5B0F2F65B044940821C603DDD796C37">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>the trans fat content of a serving of the food is less than 0.5 gram and greater than 0.0 gram; and</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2C853EFFF0984F14ABC8186C30ED0602">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>the trans fat content of a serving of the food is declared in the nutrition information on the label or in the labeling of the food.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="H33A7C403E34A4B37896C1911DB2E6CAB">
        <enum>(c)</enum>
        <header>Effective date</header>
        <text>The regulation promulgated under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Trans Fat Truth in Labeling Act of 2013/s:3/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref> shall take effect on the date that is 18 months after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
      </subsection>
    </section> 
</legis-body> 
</bill>
</doc>