<doc>
  <docmeta id="113hjres96ih">
    <bill congress="113" type="hjres" number="96" version="ih"/>
    <revision size="4429" annotations="0" status="complete" id="3" commit-time="2013-10-22T21:38:03Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113hjres96ih/3.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <resolution xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" dms-id="HF2F42D4939F443A8B00BC09C8F937EF7" key="H" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" resolution-type="house-joint" star-print="no-star-print">
  <metadata>
<dublinCore>
<title>113 HJ 96 IH: Making continuing appropriations for fossil energy research and development of the Department of Energy for fiscal year 2014, and for other purposes.</title>
<publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</publisher>
<date>2013-10-15</date>
<format>text/xml</format>
<language>EN</language>
<rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IA</distribution-code>
    <congress display="yes">113th CONGRESS</congress>
    <session display="yes">1st Session</session>
    <legis-num>H. J. RES. 96</legis-num>
    <current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
    <action display="yes">
      <action-date date="20131015">October 15, 2013</action-date>
      <action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="M001180">Mr. McKinley</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="R000011">Mr. Rahall</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001047">Mrs. Capito</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="J000292">Mr. Johnson of Ohio</cosponsor>) introduced the following joint resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAP00">Committee on Appropriations</committee-name>
      </action-desc>
    </action>
    <legis-type>JOINT RESOLUTION</legis-type>
    <official-title display="yes">Making continuing appropriations for fossil energy research and development of the Department of Energy for fiscal year 2014, and for other purposes.</official-title>
  </form>
  <resolution-body id="HCF4746AE07A14E00B7A9D83972768148" style="traditional">
    <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H1C5A8324087D43CAABD27F09BD4371DF" section-type="undesignated-section">
      <enum/>
      <text>That the following sums are hereby appropriated, out of any money in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, and out of applicable corporate or other revenues, receipts, and funds, for the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="8900">Department of Energy</cato:entity-ref> for fiscal year 2014, and for other purposes, namely:</text>
    </section>
    <section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB287E78FAAEC4F5CBC7EEC27DC71898B">
      <enum>101.</enum>
      <subsection commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HCE55A77F93194C9580D6A5B7F4301C9A">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">
          <cato:entity entity-type="auth-approp">
            <cato:funds-and-year amount="indefinite" year="2014">Such amounts as may be necessary</cato:funds-and-year>, at a rate for operations as provided for fiscal year 2013 under the <cato:entity entity-type="law-citation">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Energy and Water Development and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2012">Energy and Water Development and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2012</cato:entity-ref> (<cato:entity-ref entity-type="public-law" value="public-law/112/74/d:B">division B of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/112/74">Public Law 112–74</external-xref>
              </cato:entity-ref>)</cato:entity> and under the authority and conditions provided in such Act, <cato:property name="purpose">for continuing projects or activities (including the costs of direct loans and loan guarantees) that are not otherwise specifically provided for in this joint resolution, that were conducted in fiscal year 2013, and for which appropriations, funds, or other authority were made available by such Act under the heading <term>Fossil Energy Research and Development</term>
            </cato:property>.</cato:entity>
        </text>
      </subsection>
      <subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2DB82FBCF127470A80B7850B929C02A9">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The rate for operations provided by <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="113 HJRES 96/s:101/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref> for each account shall be calculated to reflect the full amount of any reduction required in fiscal year 2013 pursuant to—</text>
        <paragraph id="HBC0D9C1EC1BA43CF94ED6BE4C0212DEA">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any provision of <cato:entity entity-type="law-citation">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Consolidated and Further Continuing Appropriations Act, 2013/d:G">division G of the Consolidated and Further Continuing Appropriations Act, 2013</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/113/6">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="public-law" value="public-law/113/6">Public Law 113–6</cato:entity-ref>
              </external-xref>)</cato:entity>, including <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Consolidated and Further Continuing Appropriations Act, 2013/s:3004">section 3004</cato:entity-ref>; and</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H079281D356494936A9A57D44BC050B44">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Presidential sequestration order dated March 1, 2013, except as attributable to budget authority made available by the <cato:entity entity-type="law-citation">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Disaster Relief Appropriations Act, 2013">Disaster Relief Appropriations Act, 2013</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/113/2">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="public-law" value="public-law/113/2">Public Law 113–2</cato:entity-ref>
              </external-xref>)</cato:entity>.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
    </section>
    <section id="HA11E9EE6A73047A79F6A8300856CCE96" indent="down1">
      <enum>102.</enum>
      <text>Appropriations made by <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="113 HJRES 96/s:101" proposed="true">section 101</cato:entity-ref> shall be available to the extent and in the manner that would be provided by the pertinent appropriations Act.</text>
    </section>
    <section id="HFBC3EDC7CC754E89BB356B197D520BB1" indent="down1">
      <enum>103.</enum>
      <text>Unless otherwise provided for in this joint resolution or in the applicable appropriations Act for fiscal year 2014, appropriations and funds made available and authority granted pursuant to this joint resolution shall be available until whichever of the following first occurs: (1) the enactment into law of an appropriation for any project or activity provided for in this joint resolution; (2) the enactment into law of the applicable appropriations Act for fiscal year 2014 without any provision for such project or activity; or (3) September 30, 2014.</text>
    </section>
    <section id="H9452E53AEF404E8980E89D6B1B51BD39" indent="down1">
      <enum>104.</enum>
      <text>Expenditures made pursuant to this joint resolution shall be charged to the applicable appropriation, fund, or authorization whenever a bill in which such applicable appropriation, fund, or authorization is contained is enacted into law.</text>
    </section>
    <section commented="no" id="H7EDB6A4949354E0587F6F49B532C68C0" indent="down1">
      <enum>105.</enum>
      <text>This joint resolution shall be implemented so that only the most limited funding action of that permitted in the joint resolution shall be taken in order to provide for continuation of projects and activities.</text>
    </section>
    <section commented="no" id="H2A4094C2CD2F4FAF92D433906679B04D" indent="down1">
      <enum>106.</enum>
      <text>Amounts made available under <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="113 HJRES 96/s:101" proposed="true">section 101</cato:entity-ref> for civilian personnel compensation and benefits in each department and agency may be apportioned up to the rate for operations necessary to avoid furloughs within such department or agency, consistent with the applicable appropriations Act for fiscal year 2013, except that such authority provided under this section shall not be used until after the department or agency has taken all necessary actions to reduce or defer non-personnel-related administrative expenses.</text>
    </section>
  </resolution-body>
</resolution>
</doc>