<doc>
  <docmeta id="113hr1566ih">
    <bill congress="113" type="hr" number="1566" version="ih"/>
    <revision size="51820" annotations="0" id="6" commit-time="2013-05-03T15:25:09+00:00" committer="favila" doc="113hr1566ih/6.xml" status="complete">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HB305D877432D48779C894B6C911A7179" public-private="public">
	<metadata>
<dublinCore>
<title>113 HR 1566 IH: Consumer Credit Access, Innovation, and Modernization Act</title>
<publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</publisher>
<date>2013-04-15</date>
<format>text/xml</format>
<language>EN</language>
<rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>113th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 1566</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20130415">April 15, 2013</action-date>
			<action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="L000569">Mr. Luetkemeyer</sponsor> (for
			 himself and <cosponsor name-id="M001137">Mr. Meeks</cosponsor>) introduced the
			 following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial
			 Services</committee-name>
      </action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To create a Federal charter for Internet consumer credit
		  corporations, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H7150F2462E3B45CEA45809F139470CBE" style="OLC">
		<section id="HAFB2FC1BC4AE43ADBDD2E0A7D78780B0" section-type="section-one">
      <enum>1.</enum>
      <header>Short title</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the
			 <quote>
          <short-title>Consumer Credit Access, Innovation,
			 and Modernization Act</short-title>
        </quote>.</text>
		</section>
    <section id="H92FA133DFA3D4B9B8869696F881E7314">
      <enum>2.</enum>
      <header>Findings;
			 purpose; and intent</header>
			<subsection id="H56B899B689B743398EEC12314B98F11B">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Findings</header>
        <text>
          <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref>
			 finds the following:</text>
				<paragraph id="HC84EC5FFC68B4C9693DED45CCF5EB034">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>Studies by the
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="5100">Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation</cato:entity-ref> (FDIC), National Bureau of Economic
			 Research, FINRA Investor Education Foundation, and other credible parties have
			 shown that roughly half of all American families, including not only lower and
			 moderate income families but also a large segment of middle and higher income
			 families who have poor credit scores and limited disposable incomes, are
			 literally living paycheck-to-paycheck, lacking adequate savings and other
			 resources to cover unplanned expenses that frequently arise in every
			 household.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HE467A23863F5451785076410B9AAA79E">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>These consumers
			 (in this Act referred to as <quote>underserved consumers</quote>) include those
			 who are <quote>unbanked</quote>, having neither a checking or savings account
			 at a depository institution, and those who are <quote>underbanked</quote>,
			 having such an account and frequently having higher incomes but credit
			 impairments, while nonetheless needing to rely on nondepository financial
			 institutions for short-term, small loans and other credit products and
			 financial services they desperately need, but generally cannot obtain from
			 traditional banking institutions.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H1D580B27C3474E09AFFC80E65D4256DB">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <text>Credit
			 alternatives for underserved consumers generally are limited and often not well
			 suited to their particular needs and in some instances lack any statutory
			 consumer protections.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HA134B0F4A8C24683990B5339C4DE02D1">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
          <text>Programs by the
			 FDIC and other parties to expand access to small loans and other financial
			 products or services for underserved consumers through banking institutions
			 have had very limited success because banks, which typically have relatively
			 high operating costs, generally have been unable to make affordable small
			 personal loans on a widespread, commercially viable basis to these higher risk
			 consumers, most of whom may not even qualify for a loan under the high-credit
			 standards regulators necessarily require insured depositories to
			 maintain.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HC9E5E412A29D498EB98D7F56B2CC83FD">
          <enum>(5)</enum>
          <text>To the extent that
			 depository institutions offer underserved consumers affordable small loans and
			 other financial products or services on a commercially viable basis, they
			 should be encouraged to do so, but it must be recognized that overcoming the
			 practical business obstacles for depositories to offer such products or
			 services appears to be quite difficult at best for most depositories, and given
			 the massive scope of the short-term credit needs of such consumers,
			 depositories most likely will be unable to provide affordable small loans and
			 other financial products or services for a significant number of them.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HB04ECE07B8154E2E95B25CE4034516C3">
          <enum>(6)</enum>
          <text>Efforts of
			 governmental, nonprofit, and private sector institutions to help underserved
			 consumers manage their personal finances more effectively through financial
			 education and counseling programs also are important and must continue, but
			 given the tremendous number of consumers who face significant ongoing financial
			 challenges, most such underserved consumers are likely to be unable to overcome
			 their financial difficulties through such efforts.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H780D8C2CF0A04DBBB0977F5D28784580">
          <enum>(7)</enum>
          <text>Nondepository
			 creditors historically have been primarily State-regulated, are not federally
			 insured, generally pose little or no systemic or taxpayer risk, typically have
			 lower operating costs and can employ less restrictive credit standards than
			 depositories, and are a major source of small loans and financial products or
			 services for underserved consumers, providing such consumers annually with
			 billions of dollars in credit.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HEB56259ADC824565B73B1AEDB20E1951">
          <enum>(8)</enum>
          <text>A
			 number of nondepository creditors have developed advanced proprietary loan
			 underwriting and servicing procedures and cutting-edge technologies allowing
			 them to offer credit to more underserved consumers, but such creditors lack the
			 authority available to national banks to operate on a multistate or nationwide
			 basis using a single lending charter and subject to strong, uniform Federal
			 regulation that would enable them to maximize their capacities to operate more
			 innovatively and efficiently.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H0A013BB76EFA4FA899B544AE8E0CF959">
          <enum>(9)</enum>
          <text>Nondepository
			 creditors are instead subject to widely differing State licensing laws that
			 impose substantial cost and compliance burdens, and, more significantly, laws
			 that severely limit the types of financial products or services that may be
			 offered, prevent loans from being provided on a commercially viable basis,
			 stifle innovation, reduce competition, and leave underserved consumers with a
			 limited choice of products or services that in many cases are not well suited
			 to their personal needs and cost significantly more because of these
			 conflicting and outdated restrictive State laws.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H62F87ECFD1DE4BFD8DA3497C427D9EBB">
          <enum>(10)</enum>
          <text>It is in the
			 national interest and will greatly benefit the millions of underserved
			 consumers who have pressing needs for additional credit alternatives for
			 Congress to adopt legislation to authorize creditors the option of receiving a
			 Federal charter under which they can provide such consumers loans and other
			 financial products and services through the Internet and electronic devices and
			 not traditional brick-and-mortar storefront locations, allowing them to operate
			 more innovatively and efficiently on a nationwide basis.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H85954E11F817494196AE63BA063A6AB2">
          <enum>(11)</enum>
          <text>An Internet
			 consumer credit corporation chartered under this Act will be adequately
			 regulated under Federal laws and regulations prescribed by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2046">Comptroller of
			 the Currency</cato:entity-ref> and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Consumer Financial Protection Bureau">Director of the Consumer Financial Protection Bureau</cato:entity-ref>, and
			 such laws and regulations shall be enforced in accordance with this Act without
			 such corporation being subjected to duplicative and conflicting State laws that
			 in many cases severely and unnecessarily restrict product innovation and choice
			 and raise the cost of the limited credit choices now available to underserved
			 consumers.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H7E9ECFEEAAB14F4BBB3B9B8993714626">
          <enum>(12)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Allowing such federally regulated lending
			 by Internet creditors as authorized by this Act through the Internet and by
			 electronic devices, but not through traditional storefront, brick-and-mortar
			 locations, on a nationwide basis, is consistent with the fact that consumers’
			 borrowing habits are shifting rapidly to seeking more financial product and
			 service choices with the convenience, ease of credit access, and more
			 alternatives provided by computers, mobile phones, and other electronic
			 devices, and millions of underserved consumers will be able to secure credit
			 from Internet consumer credit corporations that are subject to applicable State
			 and Federal laws.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HE7D882D55BEA4F0DAB29C75883E7D2A4">
          <enum>(13)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Small businesses, which are vital to job
			 creation and the health of the Nation’s economy, also have a continuing need
			 for additional credit alternatives, and allowing Internet consumer credit
			 corporations to offer certain financial products and services to small
			 businesses through the Internet and by electronic devices will be in the
			 national interest.</text>
				</paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="H1728D4DD6F5743FD8FBAEE16D90C47BA">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Purpose and
			 intent</header>
        <text>The purpose and intent of this Act is to—</text>
				<paragraph id="H79DB4A88966C4530B86B3C57955B0C28">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>provide
			 underserved consumers greater access to innovative, affordable, commercially
			 viable, and better suited financial products and services;</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H27E0361D71FD43A29545DD006B419B1F">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>create a Federal
			 charter for creditors that offer financial products or services through the
			 Internet and electronic devices and not traditional brick-and-mortar storefront
			 locations and focus their business primarily on meeting the credit needs of
			 underserved consumers and small businesses, enabling such Internet creditors to
			 provide more innovative, affordable, and appropriate credit options, subject to
			 uniform Federal lending standards rather than operating under the widely
			 varying, often conflicting, overly restrictive, and unnecessarily costly system
			 of State lending laws that currently prevent nondepository creditors from
			 offering underserved consumers and small businesses the credit options they
			 need;</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H09F983A107C54F72A848EDE449319A48">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">clarify that <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> understands that even
			 with the more innovative and efficient lending authorized by this Act and
			 reasonable pricing by Internet consumer credit corporations, the cost of
			 commercially viable, short-term, small-dollar credit for higher risk
			 underserved consumers typically will be considerably higher than the cost for
			 other consumers who have no credit impairments and that when the cost of such
			 credit is expressed in terms of an annual percentage rate, in most cases such
			 rate will be much higher than such rate for larger, longer term loans,
			 especially those made to consumers with unimpaired credit records, and
			 therefore it should not be presumed or necessarily concluded that such credit
			 extensions to underserved consumers are unfair or abusive, provided full
			 disclosure of the cost of such credit is made as required by this Act and such
			 corporation has a reasonable basis for determining that an underserved consumer
			 can repay, therefore indicating that the credit is affordable;</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H8AF5E9029EB044789AA502D170117072">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">require that the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2046">Comptroller</cato:entity-ref> exercise his
			 or her authorities to administer, enforce, and implement the provisions of this
			 Act and regulations prescribed pursuant to this Act to provide for ongoing
			 prudential regulatory oversight of Internet consumer credit corporations and to
			 promptly adopt reasonable and flexible policies and procedures to ensure the
			 approval of Federal charters for qualified applicants, while also promoting the
			 offering of innovative, affordable, and commercially viable financial products
			 or services; and</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H2E47CB0C94624B9AA07C63EF46179CF4">
          <enum>(5)</enum>
          <text>require that the
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Consumer Financial Protection Bureau">Director</cato:entity-ref> exercise his or her authorities to administer, enforce, and implement
			 the provisions of Federal consumer financial laws and applicable provisions of
			 this Act and regulations prescribed pursuant to this Act to ensure that
			 underserved consumers receive effective consumer financial protections, while
			 also promoting the offering of innovative, affordable, and commercially viable
			 financial products or services.</text>
				</paragraph>
      </subsection>
    </section>
    <section id="H464B716A9C924F21B2647DE7CC4BA00C">
      <enum>3.</enum>
      <header>Internet Consumer
			 Credit Corporations</header>
			<subsection id="HB996F8B1CBDB44B98A5D0A91FFAC6FFB">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Federal
			 charter</header>
        <text>In accordance with the provisions of this Act, and
			 regulations prescribed pursuant to this Act, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2046">Comptroller</cato:entity-ref> shall charter
			 creditors which shall become Internet consumer credit corporations (hereinafter
			 referred to as <quote>Internet creditors</quote>) to offer financial products
			 or services primarily to underserved consumers and small businesses as provided
			 for in this Act.</text>
			</subsection>
      <subsection id="HEAD4A7CB66054337A14703C95A82352E">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Application
			 required</header>
				<paragraph id="HAD2300441A2047589367CDF0100E11DA">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>In
			 general</header>
          <text>A person that desires to obtain a Federal charter under
			 this Act shall submit an application to the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2046">Comptroller</cato:entity-ref> at such time, in such
			 manner, and accompanied by such information as the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2046">Comptroller</cato:entity-ref> may
			 require.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HEC66F172D55A479889EE9CEEC75513FB">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Expeditious
			 determination</header>
          <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2046">Comptroller</cato:entity-ref> shall make a determination as to
			 whether an application submitted under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Consumer Credit Access, Innovation, and Modernization Act/s:3/ss:b/p:1" proposed="true">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref> is approved or denied
			 expeditiously.</text>
				</paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="HF37B8DD8D3C84AA18B6FA2380E1F3F29">
        <enum>(c)</enum>
        <header>Requirements</header>
        <text>In
			 seeking a Federal charter under this Act, an applicant shall meet the following
			 requirements:</text>
				<paragraph id="H19BCCE2A797C4C05BABC2D2A0A5DF200">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>A
			 business plan shall be established covering at least the initial 3-year period
			 of operation as a commercially viable entity with its primary business
			 activities being to serve the needs of underserved consumers and small
			 businesses for credit and related financial services through the Internet and
			 electronic devices and not through brick-and-mortar locations, and such plan
			 shall—</text>
					<subparagraph id="HC54AD664D0884BE9B3587AF3757D5D5E">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>realistically
			 forecast market demand, the intended customer base, competition, economic
			 conditions, financial projections, and business risks;</text>
					</subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H4384963BCAE843C58EB7B8BF3435B337">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>include a
			 marketing plan that describes the types of financial products or services such
			 creditor intends to offer, how it will market them, and how such products or
			 services are expected to be affordable for underserved consumers and small
			 businesses and commercially viable for the creditor; and</text>
					</subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H1DE69143AA2F44D58379A16BFA17BD74">
            <enum>(C)</enum>
            <text>contain an
			 acceptable plan for—</text>
						<clause id="HAB9B90DCF4C348DAB832BBDE77BC2710">
              <enum>(i)</enum>
              <text>ensuring
			 compliance with all applicable laws and regulations; and</text>
						</clause>
            <clause id="H97CD2E4B6C5246C7A74B414478ABBE0F">
              <enum>(ii)</enum>
              <text>for
			 promptly addressing complaints from underserved consumers and small
			 businesses.</text>
						</clause>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H1A69555F86DC4955B9EA43BB25B939C5">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>A
			 competent and experienced management team of good moral character with
			 expertise in and a commitment to serving the credit needs of underserved
			 consumers, experience in offering financial services products to consumers
			 through the Internet or electronic devices, and awareness and understanding of
			 applicable legal requirements shall be established.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H2BE72494D66C4F709BE50FEAE08DF94C">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <text>Adequate capital
			 structure relative to the operational and financial assumptions and business
			 plans of the applicant, including the cost of utilizing advanced technology and
			 information management systems for its operating and compliance needs, shall be
			 established.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HC000676571334853A70136854634D7B4">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
          <text>No Internet
			 creditor shall be directly or indirectly owned or controlled by any person
			 unless—</text>
					<subparagraph id="HEE0B126F944F4CBF9B568150DBE04AE2">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>the person is an
			 individual, a Federal- or State-chartered depository institution, a bank
			 holding company (as defined in <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Bank Holding Company Act of 1956/s:2/ss:a">section 2(a) of the Bank Holding Company Act of
			 1956</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1841">
                  <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/12/1841/a">12 U.S.C. 1841(a)</cato:entity-ref>
                </external-xref>)</cato:entity>), a savings and loan holding company (as defined in
			 <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Home Owners’ Loan Act/s:10/ss:a/p:1/sp:D">section 10(a)(1)(D) of the Home Owners’ Loan Act</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1467a">
                  <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/12/1467a/a/1/D">12 U.S.C. 1467a(a)(1)(D)</cato:entity-ref>
                </external-xref>)</cato:entity>),
			 or a nonprofit corporation; or</text>
					</subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H2DA20C55DA694C24BA2FCEE7564A8711">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>the primary
			 business activity of the person involves—</text>
						<clause id="H97F3001155C4411C8600A7D20BBC84BB">
              <enum>(i)</enum>
              <text>providing
			 financial products or services to consumers; or</text>
						</clause>
            <clause id="H9D6818D554C540CC9FAD674448523C20">
              <enum>(ii)</enum>
              <text>owning or
			 controlling persons whose primary business activity is providing financial
			 products or services to consumers.</text>
						</clause>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HD56A8CAE190A4543B3DB02A959507D07">
          <enum>(5)</enum>
          <text>Any other
			 requirements provided for under this Act or in regulations prescribed by the
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2046">Comptroller</cato:entity-ref> consistent with the purposes of this Act.</text>
				</paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="H19396A5F7F5A4AFF8EB259BBCF5C09FB">
        <enum>(d)</enum>
        <header>Authority of
			 Internet Creditors</header>
        <text>Upon receiving a Federal charter pursuant to
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Consumer Credit Access, Innovation, and Modernization Act/s:3/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref>, an Internet creditor shall become, as from the date of the
			 execution of its charter, a body corporate, and, as such, an Internet consumer
			 credit corporation, and in the name designated in the charter it is authorized
			 to—</text>
				<paragraph id="H10DADCBDB9D7443583EC24F5285B0D94">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>adopt and use a
			 corporate seal;</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HAEA5022B1F6B4761A2B427489042B4E8">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>have succession
			 from the date its charter is issued until such time as it be dissolved by the
			 act of its shareholders owning two-thirds of its stock, or until its charter is
			 revoked by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2046">Comptroller</cato:entity-ref>, or until terminated by an Act of <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref>, or until
			 its affairs are placed in the hands of a receiver and finally wound up by the
			 receiver in accordance with <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc/11">title 11, United States Code</cato:entity-ref>, or other applicable
			 law;</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HDF2BC0481B14444CBCD5E5F480A00424">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <text>borrow money,
			 issue stock, and enter into contracts;</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H7EE46978FFB94D988D0D543ED2E318EB">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
          <text>sue and be sued
			 and complain and defend, in any court of law and equity of competent
			 jurisdiction, as fully as natural persons;</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H48F377BFB2484F738ECFD24D82C62CB1">
          <enum>(5)</enum>
          <text>elect or appoint
			 directors, and by its board of directors to appoint a president, vice
			 president, and other officers, define their duties, require bonds of them and
			 fix the penalty thereof, dismiss such officers or any of them at pleasure, and
			 appoint others to fill their places;</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H1A55FC2B963A477E82956FA0C9CF175E">
          <enum>(6)</enum>
          <text>prescribe, by its
			 board of directors, bylaws not inconsistent with law, regulating the manner in
			 which its stock shall be transferred, its directors elected or appointed, its
			 officers appointed, its property transferred, its general business conducted,
			 and the privileges granted to it by law exercised and enjoyed;</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H1A3DA44D46344266B68818561605DB6D">
          <enum>(7)</enum>
          <text>hire employees and
			 consultants and fix their compensation, define their duties, and give such
			 persons appropriate authority to carry on its business operations;</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HD7D65AE6F3934448A9421A1F6831495C">
          <enum>(8)</enum>
          <text>enter into joint
			 ventures and other business partnerships with other Internet creditors,
			 depository institutions, State-chartered or licensed nondepository creditors,
			 third-party service providers and vendors, and other parties to promote or
			 facilitate providing as herein authorized commercially viable financial
			 products or services to underserved consumers and small businesses;</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H8D90FB1616E5414FB1D0DA4F0065F796">
          <enum>(9)</enum>
          <text>contribute to
			 community funds, or to charitable, philanthropic, or benevolent
			 instrumentalities conducive to public welfare, such sums as its board of
			 directors may deem expedient and in the interests of the Internet
			 creditor;</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H7FB81699DF7F4B64B74198D497AC4F7C">
          <enum>(10)</enum>
          <text>invest in, or buy
			 or lease, real estate or tangible personal property, including vehicles,
			 equipment, furnishings and furniture, to be used by the Internet creditor in
			 conducting business related operations authorized under this Act;</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H2A4499BC52824BFA80C78AE1697E5982">
          <enum>(11)</enum>
          <text>provide loans and
			 other financial services only through the Internet and electronic devices as
			 its board of directors or duly authorized officers or agents may determine, in
			 accordance with this Act and regulations prescribed pursuant to this Act, are
			 appropriate for providing financial products or services to consumers,
			 including underserved consumers, and to small businesses in accordance with the
			 provisions of this Act and regulations prescribed pursuant to this Act;</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HDC2B07CC96A14E14B88ACF2B0A44D841">
          <enum>(12)</enum>
          <text>exercise by its
			 board of directors or duly authorized officers or agents, subject to law, all
			 such incidental, implied, or reasonably necessary powers as may be appropriate
			 to carry on its corporate operations and the business of providing commercially
			 viable financial products or services to consumers, including underserved
			 consumers and small businesses in accordance with the provisions of this Act
			 and regulations prescribed pursuant to this Act;</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HF2C1969A178D4A1FA843AC69F0CC9328">
          <enum>(13)</enum>
          <text>be affiliated
			 with, or owned by, an insured depository institution, nondepository creditor,
			 nonprofit organization, or other qualified entities unless otherwise limited by
			 this Act or regulations prescribed pursuant to this Act;</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H71FEE71A5AF34C4FA134447E95C62E78">
          <enum>(14)</enum>
          <text>acquire or merge
			 with other Internet creditors; and</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H18999E822E48403D9423866CE51ECD55">
          <enum>(15)</enum>
          <text>exercise such
			 other powers as may be reasonably necessary or appropriate to offer financial
			 products or services as provided for pursuant to this Act, or provided for
			 through regulations prescribed by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2046">Comptroller</cato:entity-ref> pursuant to the provisions of
			 this Act.</text>
				</paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="H6398BF30616545139A8EBD35E25040FC">
        <enum>(e)</enum>
        <header>Duties and
			 responsibilities</header>
				<paragraph id="HE5BE9CB3CBB442D1AD69969F6C45FDCF">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>Comptroller of
			 the Currency</header>
          <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2046">Comptroller</cato:entity-ref> shall—</text>
					<subparagraph id="H2627123371D54967B6498229665B0056">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>ensure that
			 Internet creditors only provide loans and other financial products or services
			 through the Internet and electronic devices and that, to the extent reasonably
			 possible, such creditors primarily focus their business operations on providing
			 underserved consumers a variety of affordable financial products or services
			 that are commercially viable for such creditors, including certain products or
			 services that contain features to facilitate personal savings and enhance the
			 credit record of such consumers;</text>
					</subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="HA2AC6FF4B9D249F1989C17D1C1A51F2B">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>encourage and
			 facilitate—</text>
						<clause id="H52FC9D568041498184866992F309AC83">
              <enum>(i)</enum>
              <text>innovation with
			 respect to the financial products or services offered to underserved consumers;
			 and</text>
						</clause>
            <clause id="H9BADEFFE9830429C96762CC3AF6E359F">
              <enum>(ii)</enum>
              <text>joint ventures
			 and other business partnerships among Internet creditors, insured depository
			 institutions, other nondepository creditors, third-party service providers and
			 vendors, nonprofit organizations, and other parties in order to ensure greater
			 credit access for underserved consumers and small businesses;</text>
						</clause>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H38E2A754ADBD46C0B7BD05D24D0A1459">
            <enum>(C)</enum>
            <text>provide, through
			 regulations, details on how Internet creditors should be organized,
			 incorporated, and operated in a prudential manner;</text>
					</subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H80A02FAD227546E3B3DD88F905B7D714">
            <enum>(D)</enum>
            <text>conduct
			 examination and supervisory activities of Internet creditors to—</text>
						<clause id="H5B28A294AA5F468389AAD56E20CB4650">
              <enum>(i)</enum>
              <text>access their
			 internal controls and management ability;</text>
						</clause>
            <clause id="H7F746819366E4E499A300901E1C667B0">
              <enum>(ii)</enum>
              <text>evaluate their
			 financial condition and risk profile;</text>
						</clause>
            <clause id="H6875730555844E34B2334C506508927D">
              <enum>(iii)</enum>
              <text>determine if
			 they are meeting the needs of underserved consumers and small businesses;
			 and</text>
						</clause>
            <clause id="H748B02D1073F4CBCAD3235AF95D44E51">
              <enum>(iv)</enum>
              <text>monitor their
			 compliance with this Act and other applicable laws and regulations that the
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2046">Comptroller</cato:entity-ref> may have administrative responsibly for, and identify areas in
			 which corrective action is needed;</text>
						</clause>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H10649DF57C944AF58EABE8F3558BEA3E">
            <enum>(E)</enum>
            <text>consult, cooperate
			 and coordinate, as appropriate, with the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Consumer Financial Protection Bureau">Director</cato:entity-ref> and with other Federal and
			 State regulatory agencies, including State bank supervisors, to promote much
			 greater availability of innovative, affordable, commercially viable credit for
			 underserved consumers, and consistent regulatory treatment of consumer and
			 small business financial products and services;</text>
					</subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H5F5FCE351DA94725B603F550CEF77620">
            <enum>(F)</enum>
            <text>help ensure that
			 the supervisory activities, including examination schedules, of Internet
			 creditors and affiliated companies are conducted in a coordinated and efficient
			 manner; and</text>
					</subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H6DFE7A1AAE784EE5860251C8313E4B73">
            <enum>(G)</enum>
            <text>adopt adequate
			 safeguards to ensure appropriate privacy and confidentiality protections with
			 respect to individually identifiable personal data and proprietary corporate
			 data.</text>
					</subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H0E7472879DCF42BE88E89AD8AD8EE2A8">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Director of the
			 Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection</header>
          <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Consumer Financial Protection Bureau">Director</cato:entity-ref>
			 shall—</text>
					<subparagraph id="H71F74E223B754A0BBFB04972E26C6CBB">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">regulate the offering and provision of
			 consumer financial products or services by Internet creditors under the Federal
			 consumer financial laws pursuant to its authorities under the <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Dodd-Frank Wall Street Reform and Consumer Protection Act">Dodd-Frank Wall
			 Street Reform and Consumer Protection Act</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/5301">
                  <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/12/5301/etseq">12 U.S.C. 5301 et seq.</cato:entity-ref>
                </external-xref>)</cato:entity>, this Act,
			 and regulations prescribed pursuant to this Act;</text>
					</subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="HF738B24104C0423D81A792CB43C2F46C">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>consult,
			 cooperate, and coordinate, as appropriate, with the Comptroller and with other
			 Federal and State regulatory agencies, including State bank supervisors, to
			 promote—</text>
						<clause id="H7AB42B7EE9E141C48C1416F5E7AEBF22">
              <enum>(i)</enum>
              <text>much
			 greater availability of innovative, affordable, commercially viable credit for
			 underserved consumers and small businesses; and</text>
						</clause>
            <clause id="H48648F118B544EC2B4C987EF646C9B6C">
              <enum>(ii)</enum>
              <text>consistent
			 regulatory treatment of consumer and small business financial products or
			 services;</text>
						</clause>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H8984C54CFDA2420D8A6E9517CB4D0371">
            <enum>(C)</enum>
            <text>help ensure that
			 the supervisory activities, including examination schedules, of Internet
			 creditors and affiliated companies are conducted in a coordinated and efficient
			 manner; and</text>
					</subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H6D6F9D47479E46AE8D41E03BAF2359A0">
            <enum>(D)</enum>
            <text>adopt adequate
			 safeguards to ensure appropriate privacy and confidentially protections with
			 respect to individually identifiable personal data and proprietary corporate
			 data.</text>
					</subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H55712E935B544BD8B89A256F8D40E9E9">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <header>Internet
			 Creditors</header>
          <text>Each Internet creditor shall—</text>
					<subparagraph id="H25387CC17D4C4BACAF263CB296BE29A0">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>make financial
			 education information available to each consumer it offers a financial product
			 or service, including information on how a consumer may obtain financial
			 counseling services, the benefits of following a regular personal savings
			 program, and how consumers can improve their credit ratings;</text>
					</subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H26D19C990FB94E7DB8F662DDB98103C9">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>comply with all
			 applicable Federal laws and regulations, including Federal consumer financial
			 protection law requirements and such State laws, regulations, and enforcement
			 actions as are authorized under the provisions of this Act;</text>
					</subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="HD3EFE163C58E40A088556EE9165DDC19">
            <enum>(C)</enum>
            <text>provide account
			 access to its customers through the Internet and a toll-free telephone
			 number;</text>
					</subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="HE57AC09FBE2B48E48994F040DFDF66C7">
            <enum>(D)</enum>
            <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide, in accordance with regulations
			 prescribed pursuant to this Act, to all consumers who are extended credit with
			 a repayment term of 1 year or less by the Internet creditor a clear and
			 conspicuous statement in the loan agreement that discloses the true cost of the
			 loan, including all interest, fees, and other loan-related charges, as a dollar
			 amount and as a percentage of the principal amount of the loan in lieu of the
			 annual percentage rate disclosure that otherwise would be required under the
			 <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Truth in Lending Act">Truth in Lending Act</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/1601">
                  <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/15/1601/etseq">15 U.S.C. 1601 et seq.</cato:entity-ref>
                </external-xref>)</cato:entity> or regulations prescribed
			 pursuant to such Act;</text>
					</subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H3137D30B19C1469F97D288344516D549">
            <enum>(E)</enum>
            <text>report to the
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2046">Comptroller</cato:entity-ref> or <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Consumer Financial Protection Bureau">Director</cato:entity-ref> such data as either may require regarding its
			 activities, including the types of financial products or services provided to
			 underserved consumers and small businesses, and data demonstrating that its
			 business activities are focused primarily on serving underserved consumers and
			 small businesses as required by this Act;</text>
					</subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H70D9F4B135F540B7800D58FD0966642F">
            <enum>(F)</enum>
            <text>offer—</text>
						<clause id="HC027F8F297974664BF23377E5A4BD7A0">
              <enum>(i)</enum>
              <text>an
			 underserved consumer who is unable to repay an extension of credit by an
			 Internet creditor that has a loan repayment term of less than 120 days, an
			 extended repayment plan, at no cost to the consumer, at least once in a
			 12-month period; and</text>
						</clause>
            <clause id="H98531B5AE30B498D9A33F533D206BB64">
              <enum>(ii)</enum>
              <text>to
			 the extent reasonably possible, certain financial products or services that
			 contain features to facilitate personal savings that could help underserved
			 consumers enhance their credit records if such consumers fully comply with the
			 terms and conditions of such products or services; and</text>
						</clause>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="HB81089F037214855A14EDDA50C49BD11">
            <enum>(G)</enum>
            <text>not—</text>
						<clause id="H8F4C87E7BFA74CD8803196B68B8FA3FA">
              <enum>(i)</enum>
              <text>accept consumer or
			 commercial deposits;</text>
						</clause>
            <clause id="HA1C81000730B44708E5E798BF6198504">
              <enum>(ii)</enum>
              <text>make commercial
			 loans, except to the extent allowed by the provisions of this Act and
			 regulations prescribed pursuant to this Act, with respect to small
			 businesses;</text>
						</clause>
            <clause id="H864B559A279B4722B04326B9FC241DA4">
              <enum>(iii)</enum>
              <text>make a consumer
			 loan with a term of 30 days or less;</text>
						</clause>
            <clause id="H2A9FBC2B820E46948F4835100E0CAC13">
              <enum>(iv)</enum>
              <text>make a loan that
			 requires a consumer to repay the loan balance in one lump-sum payment;
			 or</text>
						</clause>
            <clause id="HB1AAB2958A7A42B183ECC2575F9528A2">
              <enum>(v)</enum>
              <text>extend credit to a
			 consumer—</text>
							<subclause id="H72196F62AD7B46BE8EE2F5D2B7530014">
                <enum>(I)</enum>
                <text>unless the
			 Internet creditor has a reasonable basis for believing that the consumer will
			 have the ability to repay the credit extension;</text>
							</subclause>
              <subclause id="HE2397AFD083A4F28AE0FB3A155E406B6">
                <enum>(II)</enum>
                <text>if the maximum
			 principal amount of the credit outstanding from all financial products or
			 services authorized by the Internet creditor to such consumer, in the case of
			 an unsecured credit transaction, exceeds $5,000, or in the case of a secured
			 credit transaction, $25,000, unless a higher amount is authorized by
			 regulations prescribed by the Comptroller; or</text>
							</subclause>
              <subclause id="H7C323907173949769483B65166D604F0">
                <enum>(III)</enum>
                <text>if the loan
			 terms include a prepayment penalty; or</text>
							</subclause>
            </clause>
            <clause id="HAF3275C008AF426BAA5EC08DF191C2CA">
              <enum>(vi)</enum>
              <text>extend credit to
			 a small business in excess of $25,000.</text>
						</clause>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="H3B3E842F7D0B475FA82EA08082E9BBBE">
        <enum>(f)</enum>
        <header>Additional
			 product or service offerings</header>
        <text>Financial products or services that
			 may be offered to underserved consumers pursuant to this subsection for
			 underserved consumers and certain small businesses may also be offered to other
			 consumers and businesses.</text>
			</subsection>
      <subsection id="H0E00E996148E4C40AE21870E7F851401">
        <enum>(g)</enum>
        <header>Rule of
			 construction</header>
        <text>Nothing in this Act is intended to provide the
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2046">Comptroller</cato:entity-ref> or the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Consumer Financial Protection Bureau">Director</cato:entity-ref> with the authority to—</text>
				<paragraph id="H1E4C2943FD524493B203457C20DE5D23">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">regulate financial products or services
			 that are provided or offered by an affiliate company or another entity that the
			 Internet creditor has a business relationship with, but the Internet creditor
			 does not provide or offer to underserved consumers or small businesses in
			 accordance with this Act;</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H192BD3289865495D814C21DF7C59E08B">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">determine, directly or indirectly, pricing
			 applicable to an extension of credit offered by an Internet creditor to a
			 consumer or small business pursuant to this Act through a usury limit, a cap on
			 the rate of interest, fees, or other charges, or otherwise;</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HCBC1E23118DD4D39A4F803788B3BC8A9">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">prohibit, directly or indirectly, the
			 offering of a financial product or service to underserved consumers or small
			 businesses by an Internet creditor pursuant to this Act unless a determination
			 is made by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2046">Comptroller</cato:entity-ref> or <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Consumer Financial Protection Bureau">Director</cato:entity-ref>, based on a fair and reasonable
			 determination of the facts and circumstances regarding the financial product or
			 service, that offering such a product or service will seriously harm the
			 financial interests of underserved consumers or small businesses; or</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HFB781A5B76574967A5170012A0722301">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">presume or conclude that a credit extension
			 offered to underserved consumers by an Internet creditor under the provisions
			 of this Act, regulations prescribed by this Act, and such other statutes and
			 regulations as either may have administrative and enforcement authority for is
			 unfair, abusive, or otherwise inappropriate solely on the basis that the
			 interest rates and other charges to such consumers, who typically pose
			 relatively high credit risks, are significantly higher than those on credit
			 extensions offered to other consumers who do not pose such high credit
			 risks.</text>
				</paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="H1B6126202467405A981DC08AE4466F98">
        <enum>(h)</enum>
        <header>Internet
			 Creditor regulatory fee</header>
        <text>Each Internet creditor shall pay to the
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2046">Comptroller</cato:entity-ref> an annual fee in a reasonable amount that the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2046">Comptroller</cato:entity-ref>
			 determines is sufficient, in the aggregate of all such fees paid by Internet
			 creditors, to offset the cost to the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2046">Comptroller</cato:entity-ref> of carrying out the provisions
			 of this Act.</text>
			</subsection>
      <subsection id="H4B9B14B41A6B493A9C514AF28252CD22">
        <enum>(i)</enum>
        <header>Charter
			 suspension or revocation</header>
        <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2046">Comptroller</cato:entity-ref>, pursuant to procedures
			 established in regulations prescribed by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2046">Comptroller</cato:entity-ref>, may suspend or revoke
			 the charter of an Internet creditor if there has been a material failure by the
			 Internet creditor to comply with the requirements set forth in the charter,
			 provisions of this Act, or other applicable statutes, regulations, or
			 orders.</text>
			</subsection>
      <subsection id="H7B95179ADEA740C3B1D8A8BBDD291CDA">
        <enum>(j)</enum>
        <header>Relationship to
			 other Federal and State laws</header>
				<paragraph id="H0E4DBB9571564CA9B1B6AFA47A6F0CA5">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>Federal
			 law</header>
          <text>An Internet creditor is subject to—</text>
					<subparagraph id="H59EA8170307A442C8CCF4DD699C4F980">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>all otherwise
			 applicable provisions of Federal statutes and regulations, including the
			 consumer financial laws listed under <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Consumer Financial Protection Act of 2010/s:1002/p:14">section 1002(14) of the Consumer Financial
			 Protection Act of 2010</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/5481">
                  <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/12/5481//14">12 U.S.C. 5481(14)</cato:entity-ref>
                </external-xref>)</cato:entity>, <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc/10/987">
                <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/10/987">section 987</external-xref> of title 10, United
			 States Code</cato:entity-ref> (relating to consumer credit extended to servicemembers and
			 dependents), and the provisions of this Act and regulations established
			 pursuant to this Act; and</text>
					</subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H094A8E07EAF9432A8FDF45733236CA6F">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>the administration
			 and enforcement of such statutes and regulations by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2046">Comptroller</cato:entity-ref>, the
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Consumer Financial Protection Bureau">Director</cato:entity-ref>, any other Federal agency, or State attorney general (or the
			 equivalent thereof) having enforcement authority.</text>
					</subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H6896A24BB89A4D7A859BC549FAB18C1B">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>State
			 law</header>
          <text>An Internet creditor, or an employee, agent, or other
			 business partner of an Internet creditor, shall not be subject to—</text>
					<subparagraph id="H8FEEE6FA71034E1284FB6FBB79CC9F1F">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>State laws that
			 relate to office location, licensing, education, or training that apply to the
			 operations of an Internet creditor, or its employees, agents, or other business
			 partners to the extent that these operations relate to the exercise of its
			 powers or authorities under this Act and implementing regulations to provide
			 financial products or services to underserved consumers and small businesses;
			 or</text>
					</subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="HC0AB5F4ACA6840A285DA522545E6B228">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>other State laws
			 that—</text>
						<clause id="HD834E6C0A84D4210A552758DC603EFDF">
              <enum>(i)</enum>
              <text>have
			 a discriminatory effect on an Internet creditor compared to the effect of such
			 laws on any other depository or nondepository creditor chartered or licensed in
			 that State;</text>
						</clause>
            <clause id="H53A3F9594DD34CF08D3833830227F3EC">
              <enum>(ii)</enum>
              <text>consistent with
			 the legal standard for preemption in the decision of the Supreme Court of the
			 United States in Barnett Bank of Marion County, N.A. v. Nelson, Florida
			 Insurance Commissioner, et al., 517 U.S. 25 (1996), prevent or significantly
			 interfere with the exercise by an Internet creditor of its powers and
			 authorities as set forth in this Act; or</text>
						</clause>
            <clause id="HC26F3DA0EDD548D8935C7C471B137BB4">
              <enum>(iii)</enum>
              <text>are preempted by
			 any provision of Federal law.</text>
						</clause>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H2C565BB5B1F74277B313BCBF1D78634A">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <header>Determination of
			 preemption</header>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An Internet
			 creditor may challenge the applicability of a State law as preventing or
			 significantly interfering with the exercise of such creditor’s powers under
			 this Act, or for violating any provision of <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Consumer Credit Access, Innovation, and Modernization Act/s:3/ss:j/p:2" proposed="true">paragraph (2)</cato:entity-ref>, in any court of
			 competent jurisdiction, and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2046">Comptroller</cato:entity-ref> or <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Consumer Financial Protection Bureau">Director</cato:entity-ref>, by regulation or
			 order, or any court of competent jurisdiction may make a determination, on a
			 case-by-case basis, that a State law prevents or significantly interferes with
			 the exercise of an Internet creditor’s powers under this Act, or violates a
			 provision of <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Consumer Credit Access, Innovation, and Modernization Act/s:3/ss:j/p:2" proposed="true">paragraph (2)</cato:entity-ref>, in accordance with applicable law.</text>
				</paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="H83809CA2F31B47DB98ED61D11EE33F36">
        <enum>(k)</enum>
        <header>Enforcement</header>
				<paragraph id="H943235102DD74C60AF9631184671FD16">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>In
			 general</header>
          <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2046">Comptroller</cato:entity-ref> or the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Consumer Financial Protection Bureau">Director</cato:entity-ref> may enforce in any court
			 of competent jurisdiction the provisions of this Act, regulations prescribed
			 pursuant to this Act relating to their respective regulatory authority in this
			 Act, and their respective cease and desist or other orders or regulatory
			 requirements.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H25B86447D09A4A3BB00FDFE81BE39949">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Action by
			 State</header>
          <text>The attorney general (or the equivalent thereof) of any
			 State shall have the power to investigate violations of this Act and may bring
			 a civil enforcement action in the name of such State against an Internet
			 creditor in any district court of the United States or in State court that has
			 jurisdiction over the Internet creditor and to secure civil penalties and such
			 other remedies under provisions of this Act or otherwise provided under other
			 applicable law.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HC6C61ED661C340FE96056DBAFC4DE127">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <header>Consultation
			 required</header>
					<subparagraph id="H31468BB008B54A4A8E1C25CF51C26245">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <header>Notice</header>
						<clause id="H8CBBE617A7C14919AE129F8B7DC088E8">
              <enum>(i)</enum>
              <header>In
			 general</header>
              <text>When initiating any action in a court or other
			 administrative or regulatory proceeding against any Internet creditor as
			 authorized by this Act to enforce any provision of this Act, including any
			 regulation pursuant to this Act, a copy of the complete complaint filed or to
			 be filed and written notice describing such action or proceeding shall be
			 provided to the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2046">Comptroller</cato:entity-ref> and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Consumer Financial Protection Bureau">Director</cato:entity-ref> by the State attorney general (or
			 the equivalent thereof) prior to or immediately upon instituting the action or
			 proceeding.</text>
						</clause>
            <clause id="H8A73CD973BF34B959D20604BBB94D820">
              <enum>(ii)</enum>
              <header>Contents of
			 notice</header>
              <text>The notification required under this paragraph shall, at a
			 minimum, describe—</text>
							<subclause id="H3768A545C95C4B4E93BEB7A4529FAE1B">
                <enum>(I)</enum>
                <text>the identity of
			 the parties;</text>
							</subclause>
              <subclause id="H676D8F5BCC264272B59F920B95298629">
                <enum>(II)</enum>
                <text>the alleged facts
			 underlying the proceeding; and</text>
							</subclause>
              <subclause id="HBA6A3834EC47457CB7BD7991B4E29213">
                <enum>(III)</enum>
                <text>whether there
			 may be a need to coordinate the prosecution of the proceeding so as not to
			 interfere with any action, including any rulemaking, undertaken by the
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2046">Comptroller</cato:entity-ref> or the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Consumer Financial Protection Bureau">Director</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
							</subclause>
            </clause>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H1803B108ECA3429D9BD6DF7D7DF24BDE">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <header>Comptroller and
			 Director response</header>
            <text>In any action brought by a State attorney
			 general (or equivalent thereof), the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2046">Comptroller</cato:entity-ref> and <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Consumer Financial Protection Bureau">Director</cato:entity-ref> may—</text>
						<clause id="H2586EBB3FE1A4E2D8A85FEE4BF20921E">
              <enum>(i)</enum>
              <text>intervene in the
			 action as a party; and</text>
						</clause>
            <clause id="HD70FA3E3967646949944BFFF58F073BA">
              <enum>(ii)</enum>
              <text>upon
			 intervening—</text>
							<subclause id="HB7596B1350BC49CC97C4CECD4B44D505">
                <enum>(I)</enum>
                <text>remove the action
			 to the appropriate United States district court, if the action was not
			 originally brought there;</text>
							</subclause>
              <subclause id="H84953B13F6CF466895688D9ABA852A6E">
                <enum>(II)</enum>
                <text>be heard on all
			 matters arising in the action; and</text>
							</subclause>
              <subclause id="HDED13C63C38A4BE9BB34AD4070FBD223">
                <enum>(III)</enum>
                <text>appeal any order
			 or judgment, to the same extent as any other party in the proceeding
			 may.</text>
							</subclause>
            </clause>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H5F7E933236FA40379E446048B42E4130">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
          <header>Regulations</header>
          <text>The
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2046">Comptroller</cato:entity-ref> and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Consumer Financial Protection Bureau">Director</cato:entity-ref> shall jointly prescribe regulations to implement
			 the requirements of this subsection and, from time to time, consult with State
			 attorneys general (or the equivalent thereof) in order to develop appropriate
			 protocols to coordinate actions with the State attorneys general and other
			 appropriate regulators.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H2D8B747931BC4700A8605551C4D46EE4">
          <enum>(5)</enum>
          <header>Preservation of
			 State authority</header>
          <text>No provision of this Act shall be construed as
			 modifying, limiting, or superseding the operation of any provision of any
			 Federal consumer financial protection law or regulations prescribed pursuant to
			 such laws that relates to the authority of a State attorney general (or the
			 equivalent thereof) to enforce such Federal law and regulations.</text>
				</paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="H0BE131FDEE414AC0AAFA756FC51E544B">
        <enum>(l)</enum>
        <header>Penalties for
			 violations</header>
        <text>The relief available for violations of provisions of
			 this Act, regulations prescribed pursuant to this Act, or orders or supervisory
			 mandates, including cease and desist orders, with respect to proceedings
			 involving Internet creditors by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2046">Comptroller</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Consumer Financial Protection Bureau">Director</cato:entity-ref>, or State
			 attorneys general (or the equivalent thereof) shall be the same as or
			 equivalent to that provided with respect to actions by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Consumer Financial Protection Bureau">Director</cato:entity-ref> in <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Dodd-Frank Wall Street Reform and Consumer Protection Act/s:1055">section
			 1055 of the Dodd-Frank Wall Street Reform and Consumer Protection Act</cato:entity-ref> (<cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/12/5565">12
			 U.S.C. 5565</cato:entity-ref>)</cato:entity>.</text>
			</subsection>
      <subsection id="H442DC30A682F449B94FC04E756B32595">
        <enum>(m)</enum>
        <header>Reports to
			 congress</header>
        <text>Not later than 180 days after the effective date of this
			 Act, and annually for 5 years thereafter, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2046">Comptroller</cato:entity-ref> and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Consumer Financial Protection Bureau">Director</cato:entity-ref>
			 shall submit to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> a joint report on their activities and progress in
			 helping to expand access to innovative and affordable credit for underserved
			 consumers and small businesses, and such reports shall include—</text>
				<paragraph id="H37B1CAF74C6F4C528112654D2B97AD65">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>a
			 descriptive summary of the actions of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2046">Comptroller</cato:entity-ref> and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Consumer Financial Protection Bureau">Director</cato:entity-ref> during
			 the reporting period to carry out the purposes of this Act;</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HECD6BDA7147747E3B5E07EB3562EC799">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>the number of
			 charter applications received by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2046">Comptroller</cato:entity-ref>;</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H44E028FCADA4499EB4B498A4808C5BC7">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <text>the number of
			 charter applications that were approved, disapproved, conditionally approved,
			 or are pending and a detailed explanation of each disapproval or conditional
			 approval;</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HB20AED5615F8427B9A02C6BB330C4DDC">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
          <text>a
			 description of any further actions the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2046">Comptroller</cato:entity-ref> or the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Consumer Financial Protection Bureau">Director</cato:entity-ref> believes
			 should be undertaken to—</text>
					<subparagraph id="HC41A49720941434884130F3D31B0D006">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>facilitate the
			 chartering of qualified nondepository institutions; and</text>
					</subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H5F013EDA47E9494599DD7FE11AEB3B5F">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>increase the
			 number of financial products that are available to help increase competition
			 and consumer choice for underserved consumers; and</text>
					</subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H0705837880924B0AA51E1B247433A3D4">
          <enum>(5)</enum>
          <text>any
			 recommendations the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2046">Comptroller</cato:entity-ref> or the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Consumer Financial Protection Bureau">Director</cato:entity-ref> may have regarding other
			 legislative measures that would improve the ability of an Internet creditor to
			 provide additional financial products or services to underserved consumers or
			 small businesses.</text>
				</paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="HAAB775CC7CD54E54BAAB27AF6EE81BC0">
        <enum>(n)</enum>
        <header>Regulations</header>
        <text>The
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2046">Comptroller</cato:entity-ref> and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Consumer Financial Protection Bureau">Director</cato:entity-ref> shall consult and prescribe joint regulations
			 implementing the provisions of this Act not later than 180 days after the
			 effective date of this Act.</text>
			</subsection>
    </section>
    <section id="HA5E5319424074ABA8D7C9D9F59AB4A72">
      <enum>4.</enum>
      <header>Definitions</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text>
			<paragraph id="HA660AD6BFFDD47D8BA5B1B07A128F99D">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <header>Affiliate</header>
        <text>The
			 term <quote>affiliate</quote> means any person that controls, is controlled by,
			 or is under common control with another person.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H9D77EDA6CC1D48989DBB51744655677F">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <header>Affordable</header>
        <text>The
			 term <quote>affordable</quote> means that a creditor has a reasonable
			 expectation that a consumer or small business will be able to repay an
			 extension of credit.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HEC668B1DC8464DA9A103C81EE7F05D8E">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <header>Commercially
			 viable</header>
        <text>The term <quote>commercially viable</quote> means that a
			 reasonable economic profit is expected to be made when a financial product or
			 service is provided to a consumer or small business.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HC8768C39BCF2439CA73B3AFF695049E1">
        <enum>(4)</enum>
        <header>Comptroller</header>
        <text>The
			 term <quote>Comptroller</quote> means the Comptroller of the Currency.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H6D4720FB7EEA45BD82102C7686A2732A">
        <enum>(5)</enum>
        <header>Consumer</header>
        <text>The
			 term <quote>consumer</quote> means an individual or agent, trustee, or
			 representative acting on behalf of an individual.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H7CCB6468F4184D409D25262806229685">
        <enum>(6)</enum>
        <header>Control and
			 controlled by</header>
        <text>The terms <quote>control</quote> and
			 <quote>controlled by</quote> mean that—</text>
				<subparagraph id="H9EFB3DADD8674F438DCA1F51A948E1F5">
          <enum>(A)</enum>
          <text>a person directly
			 or indirectly or acting through 1 or more other persons owns, controls, or has
			 power to vote 25 percent or more of any class of voting stock of a
			 company;</text>
				</subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="H355A0385A51E435D9C052CACDE51D33F">
          <enum>(B)</enum>
          <text>a person controls
			 in any manner the election of a majority of the directors or trustees of a
			 company; or</text>
				</subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="HAC288093B7CF483BB69B6323BAA44626">
          <enum>(C)</enum>
          <text>the Comptroller
			 makes a determination, after notice and opportunity for hearing, that a person
			 directly or indirectly exercises a controlling influence over the management or
			 policies of a company.</text>
				</subparagraph>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H457E7F6B690C4A5C9BEFF75D8F62220A">
        <enum>(7)</enum>
        <header>Credit</header>
        <text>The
			 term <quote>credit</quote> means the right granted by a person to a consumer or
			 a small business to defer payment of a debt, incur debt and defer its payment,
			 or purchase property or services and defer payment for such purchase.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H40B8166428E44C118EB021E0ADA1DDDD">
        <enum>(8)</enum>
        <header>Creditor</header>
        <text>The
			 term <quote>creditor</quote> has the same meaning as is given such term in
			 <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Truth in Lending Act/s:103/ss:g">section 103(g) of the Truth in Lending Act</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/1602">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/15/1602/g">15 U.S.C. 1602(g)</cato:entity-ref>
            </external-xref>)</cato:entity>, and for
			 purposes of this Act, shall include a person who extends credit to a small
			 business pursuant to the provisions of this Act.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HD8F5238217D945E79D7F8F01C1028BF1">
        <enum>(9)</enum>
        <header>Director</header>
        <text>The
			 term <quote>Director</quote> means the Director of the Bureau of Consumer
			 Financial Protection.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H2FD65507ECBE47C197C154B459B27F99">
        <enum>(10)</enum>
        <header>Electronic
			 device</header>
        <text>The term <quote>electronic device</quote> means an
			 electronic device that communicates by any transfer of signs, signals, writing,
			 images, sounds, data, or intelligence of any nature transmitted in whole or in
			 part by a wire, radio, electromagnetic, photoelectronic, or photo-optical
			 system that affects interstate or foreign commerce.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HC0AA9D9EC8864C088E74E97B5AC4BDEF">
        <enum>(11)</enum>
        <header>Extended
			 repayment plan</header>
        <text>The term <quote>extended repayment plan</quote>
			 means an installment plan under which a consumer who is unable to repay a
			 credit extension on a loan with a term of less than 120 days on the date due,
			 and who complies with applicable requirements established in regulations
			 pursuant to this Act, may repay a creditor the outstanding balance of the loan
			 in at least 4 substantially equal payments without being charged any additional
			 interest, fees, or other charges.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H4D40A238F2944BF8934CEBBC1FA5888A">
        <enum>(12)</enum>
        <header>Federal
			 consumer financial laws</header>
        <text>The term <quote>Federal consumer
			 financial laws</quote> has the same meaning as is given to that term in <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Consumer Financial Protection Act of 2010/s:1002/p:14">section
			 1002(14) of the Consumer Financial Protection Act of 2010</cato:entity-ref> (<cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/12/5481//14">12 U.S.C.
			 5481(14)</cato:entity-ref>)</cato:entity>.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H2D872017918F47F7A28C997DDBFA04DD">
        <enum>(13)</enum>
        <header>Financial
			 product or service</header>
        <text>The term <quote>financial product or
			 service</quote> has the same meaning as is given the term <quote>consumer
			 financial product or service</quote> in <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Consumer Financial Protection Act of 2010/s:1002/p:5">section 1002(5) of the Consumer
			 Financial Protection Act of 2010</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/5481">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/12/5481//5">12 U.S.C. 5481(5)</cato:entity-ref>
            </external-xref>)</cato:entity>, and for purposes of this
			 Act, shall also include a financial product or service provided to a small
			 business.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HCEFCD5A82FB64DFABA3C89AC3F70B127">
        <enum>(14)</enum>
        <header>Insured
			 depository institution and depository institution</header>
        <text>The terms
			 <quote>insured depository institution</quote> and <quote>depository
			 institution</quote> (also referred to herein as <quote>depositories</quote>)
			 have the same meanings as are given such terms under <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Federal Deposit Insurance Act/s:3/ss:c">section 3(c) of the
			 Federal Deposit Insurance Act</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1813">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/12/1813/c">12 U.S.C. 1813(c)</cato:entity-ref>
            </external-xref>)</cato:entity>, and for purposes of this
			 Act, also includes an <quote>insured credit union</quote> as such term is
			 defined under <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Federal Credit Union Act/s:101/p:7">section 101(7) of the Federal Credit Union Act</cato:entity-ref> (<cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/12/1752//7">12 U.S.C.
			 1752(7)</cato:entity-ref>)</cato:entity>.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HE72360668EA8421B8E58987B3646EA06">
        <enum>(15)</enum>
        <header>Internet</header>
        <text>The
			 term <quote>Internet</quote> means the international computer network of
			 interoperable packet-switched data networks.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H89A43D076D504E399F2718DC38B0A292">
        <enum>(16)</enum>
        <header>Nondepository
			 creditor</header>
        <text>The term <quote>nondepository creditor</quote> means an
			 entity that is chartered or licensed by a State and offers personal loans or
			 other financial products or services to consumers or small businesses, but does
			 not accept consumer or commercial deposits.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H645BFF18CC4942C38800F9A297107F7A">
        <enum>(17)</enum>
        <header>Person</header>
        <text>The
			 term <quote>person</quote> means an individual, partnership, company,
			 corporation, association (incorporated or unincorporated), trust, estate,
			 cooperative organization, or any other entity.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HE9A4CEFE0A4B4FB2B8024A39BB67A3CB">
        <enum>(18)</enum>
        <header>Primary
			 business activities</header>
        <text>The term <quote>primary business
			 activities</quote> means that the business activities of an Internet creditor
			 predominately involve providing financial products and services to underserved
			 consumers and small businesses.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H6216FC9751114EF889F71356D2A7F0A9">
        <enum>(19)</enum>
        <header>Secured credit
			 transaction</header>
        <text>The term <quote>secured credit transaction</quote>
			 means—</text>
				<subparagraph id="H50E0CD912EE54D5194CA15A124F77972">
          <enum>(A)</enum>
          <text>a consumer credit
			 transaction where the performance of the credit obligation is secured by an
			 interest in property; and</text>
				</subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="H1A44FB99A3874BF88D5FE0E2E55C9DA1">
          <enum>(B)</enum>
          <text>such transaction
			 is recognized as secured by State or Federal law, provided, however, a
			 consumer’s authorization for an electronic fund transfer as a payment on a
			 financial product or service shall not be considered, for purposes of this Act,
			 as security on a credit transaction.</text>
				</subparagraph>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H88E43428AAF844C1ACEA355C01B927D6">
        <enum>(20)</enum>
        <header>Small
			 business</header>
        <text>The term <quote>small business</quote> means a business
			 entity, including a sole proprietorship, that has less than 500 full-time
			 employees.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H24BEBC69982B4FAD9DD8C9976FE878B0">
        <enum>(21)</enum>
        <header>State</header>
        <text>The
			 term <quote>State</quote> means—</text>
				<subparagraph id="H3458FB5EFEFD4648B59C05E6F1B33218">
          <enum>(A)</enum>
          <text>a State,
			 territory, or possession of the United States, the District of Columbia, the
			 Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands,
			 Guam, American Samoa, and the United States Virgin Islands.</text>
				</subparagraph>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H647E9B8DB8834AC89ED48F0F5266CF2E">
        <enum>(22)</enum>
        <header>Underserved
			 consumer</header>
        <text>The term <quote>underserved consumer</quote> means a
			 natural person who—</text>
				<subparagraph id="H847FA4EEF729457B96B98A7B3A3AA56B">
          <enum>(A)</enum>
          <text>does not have a
			 checking or savings account with an insured depository institution; or</text>
				</subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="HBE9B382541334022BDED3DC5F48FC065">
          <enum>(B)</enum>
          <text>has a deposit
			 account with an insured depository institution, but has limited or no ability
			 to obtain small personal loans or other nondepository financial products or
			 services from an insured depository institution.</text>
				</subparagraph>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H835F6FB6A5294D5796091AEB2D5E7815">
        <enum>(23)</enum>
        <header>Unsecured
			 credit transaction</header>
        <text>The term <quote>unsecured credit
			 transaction</quote> means a consumer credit transaction where the performance
			 of the credit obligation is not secured by an interest in property or where the
			 security interest is not recognized by State or Federal law.</text>
			</paragraph>
    </section>
    <section id="H820D4E78A6694E89939E6B8F01EEAC25">
      <enum>5.</enum>
      <header>Conforming
			 amendment to TILA</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">
        <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
          <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Truth in Lending Act/s:104">Section 104
			 of the Truth in Lending Act</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/1603">15 U.S.C. 1603</external-xref>)</cato:entity> is amended by adding at the end
			 the following:</text>
			<quoted-block id="H1253F73A0BA6472F80EB753CA0CF1167" style="OLC">
				<paragraph id="H755EF4B026DA4EE6B2416FCF5585EBA5">
          <enum>(8)</enum>
          <text>Credit
				transactions involving extensions of credit with a term of 1 year or less in
				which the creditor provides consumers in all such credit transactions with a
				clear and conspicuous statement in the loan agreement that discloses the true
				cost of the loan, including all interest, fees, and other loan related charges,
				as a dollar amount and as a percentage of the principal amount of the
				loan.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
      </quoted-block>
		</section>
    <section id="H534CA943DEF44078BDAAB34FE3A13A1B">
      <enum>6.</enum>
      <header>Effective
			 date</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act shall be
			 effective 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
		</section>
  </legis-body>
</bill>
</doc>