<doc>
  <docmeta id="113hres344ih">
    <bill congress="113" type="hres" number="344" version="ih"/>
    <revision size="3882" annotations="0" status="complete" id="3" commit-time="2013-09-15T20:19:47Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113hres344ih/3.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <resolution xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" dms-id="H69956E59450748318B36074BA30EAD8B" key="H" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>113 HRES 344 IH: Directing the Speaker of the House of Representatives to direct, for the purpose of interpreting Office of Personnel Management (OPM) guidance with respect to the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act, that the definition of congressional staff employed by an official office shall include all committee staff, all joint committee staff, and all staff employed by leadership offices of the House of Representatives.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2013-09-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">113th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session display="yes">1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. RES. 344</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20130912">September 12, 2013</action-date>
			<action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="G000552">Mr. Gohmert</sponsor> submitted
			 the following resolution; which was referred to the
			 <committee-name committee-id="HHA00">Committee on House
			 Administration</committee-name>
      </action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">Directing the Speaker of the House of
		  Representatives to direct, for the purpose of interpreting Office of Personnel
		  Management (OPM) guidance with respect to the Patient Protection and Affordable
		  Care Act, that the definition of <term>congressional staff</term> employed by
		  an <term>official office</term> shall include all committee staff, all joint
		  committee staff, and all staff employed by leadership offices of the House of
		  Representatives.</official-title>
	</form>
	<preamble>
		<whereas>
      <text>Whereas on March 23, 2010, the <cato:entity entity-type="law-citation">
          <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act">Patient Protection and
			 Affordable Care Act</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/148">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="public-law" value="public-law/111/148">Public Law 111–148</cato:entity-ref>
          </external-xref>)</cato:entity>, was signed into law;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas there is a requirement in the Act that
			 <term>Members of Congress</term> and <term>congressional staff</term> who wish
			 to purchase health insurance through their employer purchase health plans
			 <quote>offered through an Exchange established under</quote> the Act starting
			 in 2014;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the Act defines congressional staff as <quote>all
			 full-time and part-time employees employed by the official office of a Member
			 of Congress, whether in Washington, DC or outside of Washington,
			 DC</quote>;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas <term>official office</term> is not defined under
			 current statutory or regulatory laws;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas according to the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2400">Office of Personnel Management</cato:entity-ref>
			 (OPM), “[b]ecause there is not an existing statutory or regulatory definition
			 of official office,” <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2400">OPM</cato:entity-ref> defers to the <term>employing office of the Member of
			 Congress</term> to determine <quote>whether an employed individual meets the
			 statutory definition</quote> of congressional staff for purposes of the
			 Act;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas currently <term>congressional employee</term>, as
			 defined in accordance with <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/5/8901">
          <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/5/8901">section 8901</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code</cato:entity-ref> (the
			 statute determining eligibility for enrollment in the Federal Employees Health
			 Benefits (FEHBP) Program), includes each Member’s respective personal staffs,
			 staffs of House and Senate leadership offices, other committee staff, and
			 administrative office staff;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act">Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act</cato:entity-ref>
			 does not amend <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/5/8901">
          <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/5/8901">section 8901</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code</cato:entity-ref>, and therefore does
			 not change the current definition of <term>congressional employee</term>;
			 and</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas because the committee staff, joint committee
			 staff, and staff employed by leadership offices do not meet the definition of
			 congressional employee under the Act, they are excluded from the requirement:
			 Now, therefore, be it</text>
		</whereas>
  </preamble>
	<resolution-body id="H84BD64E7F30F445CB5AA4345246E5ADA" style="traditional">
		<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HCFDE9409CFAA479C9573C36486FF8DA1" section-type="undesignated-section">
      <enum/>
      <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" value="Speaker of the House of Representatives" entity-parent-id="0050">Speaker of the House of
			 Representatives</cato:entity-ref> shall direct, for the purpose of interpreting <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2400">Office of
			 Personnel Management</cato:entity-ref> (OPM) guidance with respect to the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act">Patient Protection and
			 Affordable Care Act</cato:entity-ref>, that the definition of <term>congressional staff</term>
			 employed by an <term>official office</term> shall include all committee staff,
			 all joint committee staff, and all staff employed by leadership offices of the
			 <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0050">House of Representatives</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
		</section>
  </resolution-body>
</resolution>
</doc>