<doc>
  <docmeta id="113hr1151pcs">
    <bill congress="113" type="hr" number="1151" version="pcs"/>
    <revision size="9943" annotations="0" status="complete" id="6" commit-time="2014-01-24T15:05:06Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113hr1151pcs/6.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <bill bill-stage="Placed-on-Calendar-Senate" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H17942661BA894CC5811857E73CFEF1FA" key="G" public-private="public" stage-count="1">
	<metadata>
<dublinCore>
<dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">113 HR 1151 PCS: To direct the Secretary of State to develop a strategy to obtain observer status for Taiwan at the triennial International Civil Aviation Organization Assembly, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"/>
<dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
		<calendar>Calendar No. 90</calendar>
		<congress>113th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 1151</legis-num>
		<current-chamber display="yes">IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED
		  STATES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date>June 19, 2013</action-date>
			<action-desc>Received; read twice and placed on the
			 calendar</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of State to develop
		  a strategy to obtain observer status for Taiwan at the triennial International
		  Civil Aviation Organization Assembly, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H7C1940EBBB5C4A13BAF1671464796A50" style="OLC">
		<section id="HF8D420ECAE4045F89FC1B7CC6C076C3A" section-type="section-one">
      <enum>1.</enum>
      <header>Concerning the participation
			 of Taiwan in the International Civil Aviation Organization</header>
			<subsection id="H51AB4F010B9B4745853865A93F6038EE">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Findings</header>
        <text>
          <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref>
			 makes the following findings:</text>
				<paragraph id="HA11C28CB52C54AF88B125A2CD2EE961F">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>Safe, secure, and
			 economical international air navigation and transport is important to every
			 citizen of the world, and safe skies are ensured through uniform aviation
			 standards, harmonization of security protocols, and expeditious dissemination
			 of information regarding new regulations and other relevant matters.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H7EB578B2F4BF403491352626097CCB23">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>Direct and
			 unobstructed participation in international civil aviation forums and programs
			 is beneficial for all nations and their civil aviation authorities. Civil
			 aviation is vital to all due to the international transit and commerce it makes
			 possible, but must also be closely regulated due to the possible use of
			 aircraft as weapons of mass destruction or to transport biological, chemical,
			 and nuclear weapons or other dangerous materials.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H7C501769B9B8410488D95C9B7D777E4C">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <text>The Convention on
			 International Civil Aviation, signed in Chicago, Illinois, on December 7, 1944,
			 and entered into force April 4, 1947, established the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="19UA">International Civil
			 Aviation Organization</cato:entity-ref> (ICAO), stating <quote>The aims and objectives of the
			 Organization are to develop the principles and techniques of international air
			 navigation and to foster the planning and development of international air
			 transport so as to . . . meet the needs of the peoples of the world for safe,
			 regular, efficient and economical air transport.</quote>.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HDB5D5BAA44714DA3BD608E5A7030BD0A">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
          <text>The terrorist
			 attacks of September 11, 2001, demonstrated that the global civil aviation
			 network is subject to vulnerabilities that can be exploited in one country to
			 harm another. The ability of civil aviation authorities to coordinate, preempt
			 and act swiftly and in unison is an essential element of crisis prevention and
			 response.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HD405E280D7D3440F80034919C0B145E0">
          <enum>(5)</enum>
          <text>Following the
			 terrorist attacks of September 11, 2001, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="19UA">ICAO</cato:entity-ref> convened a high-level
			 Ministerial Conference on Aviation Security that endorsed a global strategy for
			 strengthening aviation security worldwide and issued a public declaration that
			 <quote>a uniform approach in a global system is essential to ensure aviation
			 security throughout the world and that deficiencies in any part of the system
			 constitute a threat to the entire global system,</quote> and that there should
			 be a commitment to <quote>foster international cooperation in the field of
			 aviation security and harmonize the implementation of security
			 measures</quote>.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HA209DBDCFAFD4AD1B348426516EB5D58">
          <enum>(6)</enum>
          <text>The Taipei Flight
			 Information Region, under the jurisdiction of Taiwan, covers 180,000 square
			 nautical miles of airspace and provides air traffic control services to over
			 1.2 million flights annually, with the Taiwan Taoyuan International Airport
			 recognized as the 10th and 19th largest airport by international cargo volume
			 and number of international passengers, respectively in 2011.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H717257BD5AE949219A06157941BC4C6D">
          <enum>(7)</enum>
          <text>Despite the
			 established international consensus regarding a uniform approach to aviation
			 security that fosters international cooperation, exclusion from the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="19UA">ICAO</cato:entity-ref> since
			 1971 has impeded the efforts of the Government of Taiwan to maintain civil
			 aviation practices that comport with evolving international standards, due to
			 its inability to contact the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="19UA">ICAO</cato:entity-ref> for up-to-date information on aviation
			 standards and norms, secure amendments to the organization’s regulations in a
			 timely manner, obtain sufficient and timely information needed to prepare for
			 the implementation of new systems and procedures set forth by the ICAO, receive
			 technical assistance in implementing new regulations, and participate in
			 technical and academic seminars hosted by the ICAO.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H7C87D7BA9C6E4445B44895EE3E8C232A">
          <enum>(8)</enum>
          <text>On October 8,
			 2010, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Department of State</cato:entity-ref> praised the 37th ICAO Assembly on its adoption of
			 a Declaration on Aviation Security, but noted that <quote>because every airport
			 offers a potential entry point into this global system, every nation faces the
			 threat from gaps in aviation security throughout the world—and all nations must
			 share the responsibility for securing that system</quote>.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H58B61067CE00432086315B7C87D1A408">
          <enum>(9)</enum>
          <text>On October 2,
			 2012, Taiwan became the 37th participant to join the United States Visa Waiver
			 program, which is expected to stimulate tourism and commerce that will rely
			 increasingly on international commercial aviation.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HF04560F6D1E34B4681C6D2F877350615">
          <enum>(10)</enum>
          <text>The Government of
			 Taiwan’s exclusion from the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="19UA">ICAO</cato:entity-ref> constitutes a serious gap in global standards
			 that should be addressed at the earliest opportunity in advance of the 38th
			 ICAO Assembly in September 2013.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H4FDCB5944D254A3DAA35D7F19BF1D5E9">
          <enum>(11)</enum>
          <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="6920">Federal
			 Aviation Administration</cato:entity-ref> and its counterpart agencies in Taiwan have enjoyed
			 close collaboration on a wide range of issues related to innovation and
			 technology, civil engineering, safety and security, and navigation.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HFAE9153CD9AB47F987AA66EBC3E9A442">
          <enum>(12)</enum>
          <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="19UA">ICAO</cato:entity-ref> has
			 allowed a wide range of observers to participate in the activities of the
			 organization.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H5F3644EF89D24D55972F6B12E51F1996">
          <enum>(13)</enum>
          <text>The United
			 States, in the 1994 Taiwan Policy Review, declared its intention to support
			 Taiwan’s participation in appropriate international organizations and has
			 consistently reiterated that support.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H1297D889A27E489ABB1119AC17C64FA1">
          <enum>(14)</enum>
          <text>Senate Concurrent
			 Resolution 17, agreed to on September 11, 2012, affirmed the sense of Congress
			 that—</text>
					<subparagraph id="HF170329C1CCE4A0EA454AA4051F359C5">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>meaningful
			 participation by the Government of Taiwan as an observer in the meetings and
			 activities of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="19UA">ICAO</cato:entity-ref> will contribute both to the fulfillment of the ICAO’s
			 overarching mission and to the success of a global strategy to address aviation
			 security threats based on effective international cooperation; and</text>
					</subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H7FD255520EFD40F88E7ED9D502410993">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>the United States
			 Government should take a leading role in garnering international support for
			 the granting of observer status to Taiwan in the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="19UA">ICAO</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
					</subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H28975E61F67E4A0985BEC12068868E0D">
          <enum>(15)</enum>
          <text>Following the
			 enactment of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/108/235">
              <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="public-law" value="public-law/108/235">Public Law 108–235</cato:entity-ref>
            </external-xref>, a law
			 authorizing the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref> to initiate and implement a plan to endorse
			 and obtain observer status for Taiwan at the annual summit of the World Health
			 Assembly and subsequent advocacy by the United States, Taiwan was granted
			 observer status to the World Health Assembly for four consecutive years since
			 2009. Both prior to and in its capacity as an observer, Taiwan has contributed
			 significantly to the international community’s collective efforts in pandemic
			 control, monitoring, early warning, and other related matters.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H005798AA78E24AADBB9569DABEF6F853">
          <enum>(16)</enum>
          <text>
            <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="19UA">ICAO</cato:entity-ref> rules and
			 existing practices allow for the meaningful participation of non-contracting
			 countries as well as other bodies in its meetings and activities through
			 granting of observer status.</text>
				</paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="HC6100A5A9A3D40FC8F14537ACB337265">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Taiwan’s
			 Participation at ICAO</header>
        <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref> shall—</text>
				<paragraph id="H0E4111B2B0174B34879C8DC2F170270D">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>develop a strategy
			 to obtain observer status for Taiwan at the triennial ICAO Assembly—next held
			 in September 2013 in Montreal, Canada—and other related meetings, activities,
			 and mechanisms thereafter; and</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HDBC645E360E94B9781EFF1F1656657C7">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">instruct the United States Mission to the
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="19UA">ICAO</cato:entity-ref> to officially request observer status for Taiwan at the triennial ICAO
			 Assembly and other related meetings, activities, and mechanisms thereafter and
			 to actively urge ICAO member states to support such observer status and
			 participation for Taiwan.</text>
				</paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="H0B27F0D26F0E4B1FA6E9E4AB022CCB46">
        <enum>(c)</enum>
        <header>Report
			 concerning observer status for Taiwan at the ICAO assembly</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 30 days after the date of
			 the enactment of this Act, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref> shall submit to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> a
			 report, in unclassified form, describing the United States strategy to endorse
			 and obtain observer status for Taiwan at the triennial ICAO Assembly and at
			 subsequent ICAO Assemblies and at other related meetings, activities, and
			 mechanisms thereafter. The report shall include the following:</text>
				<paragraph id="H4FD80560CF77486498FF31F95A3CFEF4">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>A
			 description of the efforts the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref> has made to encourage ICAO
			 member states to promote Taiwan’s bid to obtain observer status.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H36A3B692908648388C8F99B09D481F83">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>The steps the
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref> will take to endorse and obtain observer status for Taiwan
			 in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="19UA">ICAO</cato:entity-ref> and at other related meetings, activities, and mechanisms
			 thereafter.</text>
				</paragraph>
      </subsection>
    </section>
  </legis-body>
	<attestation>
		<attestation-group>
			<attestation-date chamber="House" date="20130618">Passed the House of
			 Representatives June 18, 2013.</attestation-date>
			<attestor display="yes">Karen L. Haas,</attestor>
			<role>Clerk</role>
		</attestation-group>
	</attestation>
	<endorsement display="yes">
		<action-date>June 19, 2013</action-date>
		<action-desc>Received; read twice and placed on the
		  calendar</action-desc>
	</endorsement>
</bill>
</doc>