<doc>
  <docmeta id="113hr3912ih">
    <bill congress="113" type="hr" number="3912" version="ih"/>
    <revision size="3624" annotations="0" status="complete" id="3" commit-time="2014-01-27T23:27:29Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113hr3912ih/3.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H3A509F19E37C4BC380EA7DA75D6AFEE9" public-private="public">
  <metadata>
<dublinCore>
<dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">113 HR 3912 IH: Recruiting Individuals to Drive Our Elders Act of 2014</dc:title>
<dc:publisher xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">2014-01-16</dc:date>
<dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
    <congress>113th CONGRESS</congress>
    <session>2d Session</session>
    <legis-num>H. R. 3912</legis-num>
    <current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
    <action>
      <action-date date="20140116">January 16, 2014</action-date>
      <action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="D000617">Ms. DelBene</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="K000188">Mr. Kind</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="P000597">Ms. Pingree of Maine</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>
      </action-desc>
    </action>
    <legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
    <official-title>To provide reimbursement under the Medicaid program to individuals and entities that provide voluntary non-emergency medical transportation to Medicaid beneficiaries for expenses related to no-load travel.</official-title>
  </form>
  <legis-body id="H44DDA7AC186849699DE679BFD49F49A3" style="OLC">
    <section id="HFF1E943ECA6546429DD1C6172E90C3E5" section-type="section-one">
      <enum>1.</enum>
      <header>Short title</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote>
          <short-title>Recruiting Individuals to Drive Our Elders Act of 2014</short-title>
        </quote> or the <quote>
          <short-title>RIDE Act of 2014</short-title>
        </quote>.</text>
    </section>
    <section id="H49BDE48C21FB429183337CD8F630D768">
      <enum>2.</enum>
      <header>Reimbursement for no-load travel costs incurred by volunteers providing non-emergency medical transportation to Medicaid beneficiaries</header>
      <subsection id="HC677B3911E5F4415B7C7CD5B83BB103F">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>In general</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary of Health and Human Services</cato:entity-ref> shall publish an interim final rule to revise the Medicaid transportation regulations at sections <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/431">431.53</external-xref> and <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/440">440.170</external-xref> of title 42, Code of Federal Regulations, as necessary, to allow a State plan for medical assistance under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Social Security Act/t:XIX">title XIX of the Social Security Act</cato:entity-ref> to provide, at the option of the State, reimbursement for costs attributable to providing no-load volunteer travel services to individuals eligible for medical assistance under the State plan who require transportation to receive non-emergency medical treatment.</text>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="HF7F2096A2D474E94AFF3694400008278">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>No-Load volunteer travel service</header>
        <text>For purposes of <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Recruiting Individuals to Drive Our Elders Act of 2014/s:2/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref>, the term <term>no-load volunteer travel service</term> means travel services that—</text>
        <paragraph id="H8D062EADE68F426FA00E60AF390AFA43">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>are provided by a person who, as determined by a State, local, or tribal government, provides such services on a volunteer basis (referred to in this subsection as a <term>volunteer</term>); and</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H8A9792B2501D4425AFE07C0A3E0AC4AE">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>are necessary for the volunteer to—</text>
          <subparagraph id="HBE4BA8386D144E06833C1DEF80C81898">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>travel from the originating location of the volunteer to the location of an individual who is eligible for medical assistance under the State Medicaid plan and requires transportation to receive non-emergency medical treatment (including, for purposes of an individual who requested transportation to receive non-emergency medical treatment and subsequently refused such transportation or was not present at the requested pick-up location, any travel that is necessary for the volunteer to return to their originating location);</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="HAA2AB03C9F6A4D97AF624278B9B8CF7C">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>for purposes of an individual who has been provided transportation by the volunteer to receive non-emergency medical treatment and is required to remain at the treatment location overnight or for an extended period of time (as determined appropriate by a State, local, or tribal government), return to the originating location of the volunteer and, following the completion of such treatment, travel back to the treatment location; and</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="HADCA13BAE8FE41349A6B9C7AEED097B6">
            <enum>(C)</enum>
            <text>following any transportation that is necessary to return an individual who has received non-emergency medical treatment to their pick-up location, return to the originating location of the volunteer.</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
    </section>
  </legis-body>
</bill>
</doc>