<doc>
  <docmeta id="113hr4820ih">
    <bill congress="113" type="hr" number="4820" version="ih"/>
    <revision size="5810" annotations="0" status="complete" id="4" commit-time="2014-06-12T16:33:49Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113hr4820ih/4.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H93372FAAC97F4D8CB539B4CCBFF681AC" public-private="public">
	<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>113th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>2d Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 4820</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20140609">June 9, 2014</action-date>
			<action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>
      </action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To amend the Public Health Service Act to provide for a national program to conduct and support
			 activities toward the goal of significantly reducing the number of cases
			 of overweight and obesity among individuals in the United States.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H3FCAF09D48354060B6B5A304108FBCA2" style="OLC">
		<section id="H7C9DDCBF8EF341449E2EAE63A5A669C0" section-type="section-one">
      <enum>1.</enum>
      <header>Short title</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote>
          <short-title>
            <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Promoting Healthier Lifelong Improvements in Food and Exercise Act" proposed="true">Promoting Healthier Lifelong Improvements in Food and Exercise Act</cato:entity-ref>
          </short-title>
        </quote> or the <quote>
          <short-title>LIFE Act</short-title>
        </quote>.</text>
		</section>
    <section id="HF983FB84FAED4C2F913636C0960E6E34" section-type="subsequent-section">
      <enum>2.</enum>
      <header>Findings</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Congress finds as follows:</text>
			<paragraph id="H5830BBCB3F9C40CCAA022EB2C9B03191">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text>Currently, 64.5 percent of adults in the United States, age 20 years and older, are overweight and
			 72 million (more than one-third of the adult population in the United
			 States) are obese.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HE80003D8D97C4A1F9DBD147A5583C8A5">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text>Data from two National Health and Nutrition Examination Surveys show that among adults who are 20
			 to 74 years of age the prevalence of obesity increased from 15.0 percent
			 in the 1976–1980 survey to 34.9 percent in the 2011–2012 survey.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H08373E654509407799FA1B56D435963E">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <text>In 2011 and 2012, of children and adolescents 2 to 19 years of age more than 12,500,000 (or 17
			 percent) were overweight, and of adults more than 66,000,000 (or 34.9
			 percent) were obese. Almost 6 percent of adults were extremely obese.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H49921731FC0B46BE927E370BEDE61726">
        <enum>(4)</enum>
        <text>The percentage of children who are obese has more than doubled, and among adolescents the
			 percentage has more than tripled, since 1980 the obesity rate for
			 adolescents increased from 5 percent to 21 percent.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H2772F2D4C1DE4674A4F54D90C480278B">
        <enum>(5)</enum>
        <text>More than <fraction>1/3</fraction> of adults in the United States do not get enough physical activity and national data
			 have shown an increase in the calorie consumption of adults.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H106C6BD75BF64F008848568DE4E3EBC8">
        <enum>(6)</enum>
        <text>The rising rates of obesity portend greater disease and health conditions including hypertension,
			 high total cholesterol, Type 2 diabetes, coronary heart disease, stroke,
			 gallbladder disease, osteoporosis, sleep apnea, and respiratory problems,
			 and some cancers, such as endometrial, breast, and colon cancer.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HCC65FE4CFFD9416BA20AE9B41567BD01">
        <enum>(7)</enum>
        <text>Many underlying factors have been linked to the increase in obesity, such as increasing portion
			 sizes, eating out more often, increased consumption of sugar-sweetened
			 drinks, increasing television, computer, and electronic gaming time,
			 changing labor markets, and fear of crime, which prevents outdoor
			 exercise.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HC1C21BD493C444A0AAB75112229FF918">
        <enum>(8)</enum>
        <text>Chronic diseases account for 1.7 million, or 70 percent, of all deaths in the United States each
			 year. Although chronic diseases are among the most common and costly
			 health problems, they are also among the most preventable. Adopting a
			 healthy lifestyle such as eating nutritious foods and engaging in physical
			 activity, can prevent or control the devastating effects of these
			 diseases. Although chronic diseases are among the most common and costly
			 health problems, they are also among the most preventable.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HFC6A30886D9D46519E105415518F45DB">
        <enum>(9)</enum>
        <text>In 2008, overall medical costs related to obesity for United States adults were estimated to be as
			 high as $147 billion. People who were obese had medical costs that were on
			 average $1,429 higher than the cost for people of normal body weight.</text>
			</paragraph>
    </section>
    <section id="HF3511FE5D64D4AFAB85C687B452DFD09">
      <enum>3.</enum>
      <header>Reduction in prevalence of obesity; program for lifelong improvements in food and exercise</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">
        <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
          <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Public Health Service Act/t:III/pt:B">Part B of title III of the Public Health Service Act</cato:entity-ref> (<cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/42/243/etseq">42 U.S.C. 243 et seq.</cato:entity-ref>)</cato:entity> is amended by
			 inserting after <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Public Health Service Act/s:317T">section 317T</cato:entity-ref> the following section:</text>
			<quoted-block id="H6827EF506B79417DB8B73DD39843B6E5" style="OLC">
				<section id="H8727273534E94EB586C8B0B27B2897E0">
          <enum>317U.</enum>
          <header>Reduction in prevalence of obesity</header>
					<subsection id="HE9653FDBCD124035BB98CA97AC48D2B0">
            <enum>(a)</enum>
            <header>In general</header>
            <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref>, acting through the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="7523" entity-type="federal-body">Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention</cato:entity-ref>, shall
			 carry out a national program to conduct and support activities regarding
			 individuals who are overweight or obese in order to make progress toward
			 the goal of significantly reducing the number of cases of obesity among
			 individuals in the United States.</text>
					</subsection>
          <subsection id="HA3BE6E90E30C478B9C1F718F98343200">
            <enum>(b)</enum>
            <header>Certain activities</header>
            <text>In carrying out <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Public Health Service Act/s:317U/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall (directly or through grants or contracts) carry
			 out the following with respect to individuals who are overweight:</text>
						<paragraph id="H7A8E19FAA7D54FA69621C7296799A1F1">
              <enum>(1)</enum>
              <text>Activities to train health professionals to recognize that patients are overweight and to recommend
			 prevention activities regarding such condition, including educating
			 patients on the relationship between such condition and cardiovascular
			 disease, diabetes, and other health conditions, and on proper nutrition
			 and regular physical activities.</text>
						</paragraph>
            <paragraph id="H8B8F140224CF4DE8B321A75BD0ACE37E">
              <enum>(2)</enum>
              <text>Activities to educate the public with respect to the condition of being overweight, including the
			 development of a strategy for a public awareness campaign.</text>
						</paragraph>
            <paragraph id="HB5FFE3A7A9F64BAA9FA01C3E0D8C60D9">
              <enum>(3)</enum>
              <text>The development and demonstration of intervention strategies for use at worksites and in community
			 settings such as hospitals and community health centers.</text>
						</paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection id="H7156F1A0DF6C49A88899A5A1F32CB234">
            <enum>(c)</enum>
            <header>Authorization of appropriations</header>
            <text>
              <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="auth-auth-approp">
                <cato:property name="purpose">For the purpose of carrying out <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Public Health Service Act/s:317U" proposed="true">this section</cato:entity-ref>
                </cato:property>, there are authorized to be appropriated <cato:funds-and-year amount="25000000" year="2015">$25,000,000
			 for fiscal year 2015</cato:funds-and-year>, and <cato:funds-and-year amount="indefinite" year="2016, 2017, 2018">such sums as may be necessary for each of the
			 fiscal years 2016 through 2018</cato:funds-and-year>.</cato:entity>
            </text>
          </subsection>
        </section>
        <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
      </quoted-block>
		</section>
  </legis-body>
</bill>
</doc>