<doc>
  <docmeta id="113hconres67ih">
    <bill congress="113" type="hconres" number="67" version="ih"/>
    <revision size="5486" annotations="0" status="complete" id="4" commit-time="2014-01-02T23:36:43Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113hconres67ih/4.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <resolution xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" dms-id="H40E4C123DB2B4769BEEEAA37C60B112E" key="H" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" resolution-type="house-concurrent" star-print="no-star-print">
  <metadata>
<dublinCore>
<dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">113 HCON 67 IH: Recognizing the need to improve physical access to many United States postal facilities for all people in the United States in particular disabled citizens.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">2013-11-21</dc:date>
<dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code>
    <congress display="yes">113th CONGRESS</congress>
    <session display="yes">1st Session</session>
    <legis-num>H. CON. RES. 67</legis-num>
    <current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
    <action display="yes">
      <action-date date="20131121">November 21, 2013</action-date>
      <action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="E000293">Ms. Esty</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="C001069">Mr. Courtney</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000216">Ms. DeLauro</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001047">Mr. Himes</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="L000557">Mr. Larson of Connecticut</cosponsor>) submitted the following concurrent resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Education and the Workforce</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
    </action>
    <legis-type>CONCURRENT RESOLUTION</legis-type>
    <official-title display="yes">Recognizing the need to improve physical access to many United States postal facilities for all people in the United States in particular disabled citizens.</official-title>
  </form>
  <preamble>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas, in 2012, 12 percent of the civilian population in the United States reported having a disability;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas, in 2012, 16 percent of veterans, amounting to more than 3,500,000 people, received service-related disability benefits;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas, in 2011, the percentage of working-age people in the United States who reported having a work limitation due to a disability was 7 percent, which is a 20-year high;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the <cato:entity entity-type="law-citation">Act entitled <quote>
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Architectural Barriers Act of 1968" official-title="true">An Act to insure that certain buildings financed with Federal funds are so designed and constructed as to be accessible to the physically handicapped</cato:entity-ref>
          </quote>, approved August 12, 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4151">
          <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/42/4151/etseq">42 U.S.C. 4151 et seq</cato:entity-ref>.</external-xref>) (referred to in this preamble as the <quote>
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Architectural Barriers Act of 1968">Architectural Barriers Act of 1968</cato:entity-ref>
          </quote>)</cato:entity>, was enacted to ensure that certain federally funded facilities are designed and constructed to be accessible to people with disabilities and requires that physically handicapped people have ready access to, and use of, post offices and other Federal facilities;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas automatic doors, though not mandated by either the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Architectural Barriers Act of 1968">Architectural Barriers Act of 1968</cato:entity-ref> or the <cato:entity entity-type="law-citation">
          <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990">Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12101">
          <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/42/12101/etseq">42 U.S.C. 12101 et seq</cato:entity-ref>.</external-xref>)</cato:entity>, provide a greater degree of self-sufficiency and dignity for people with disabilities and the elderly, who may have limited strength to open a manually operated door;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas a report commissioned by the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="9532">Architectural and Transportation Barriers Compliance Board</cato:entity-ref> (referred to in this preamble as the <quote>Access Board</quote>), an independent Federal agency created to ensure access to federally funded facilities for people with disabilities, recommends that all new buildings for use by the public should have at least one automated door at an accessible entrance, except for small buildings where adding such doors may be a financial hardship for the owners of the buildings;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas States and municipalities have begun to recognize the importance of automatic doors in improving accessibility;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the laws of the State of Connecticut require automatic doors in certain shopping malls and retail businesses, the laws of the State of Delaware require automatic doors or calling devices for newly constructed places of accommodation, and the laws of the District of Columbia have a similar requirement;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the Facilities Standards for the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="4740">Public Buildings Service</cato:entity-ref>, published by the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="4700">General Services Administration</cato:entity-ref>, requires automation of at least one exterior door for all newly constructed or renovated facilities managed by the General Services Administration, including post offices;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas from 2006 to 2011, 71 percent of the complaints received by the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="9532">Access Board</cato:entity-ref> regarding the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Architectural Barriers Act of 1968">Architectural Barriers Act of 1968</cato:entity-ref> concerned a post office or other facility of the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1800">United States Postal Service</cato:entity-ref>;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1800">United States Postal Service</cato:entity-ref> employs approximately 522,000 people, making it the second-largest civilian employer in the United States;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas approximately 3,200,000 people visit 1 of the 31,857 post offices in the United States each day; and</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the United States was founded on principles of equality and freedom, and these principles require that all people, including people with disabilities, are able to engage as equal members of society: Now, therefore, be it</text>
    </whereas>
  </preamble>
  <resolution-body id="H99377BEB12AC4D7D8C51DDE4803F339D" style="traditional">
    <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HBAB7E6997D1C423B8ADDB7AEDFDAD3E1" section-type="undesignated-section">
      <enum/>
      <text>That <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref>—</text>
      <paragraph id="H042D48B581BB40F39D65734682AC2621">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recognizes the immense hardships that disabled United States citizens must overcome every day;</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H2EB3240146BA4D61A13E54AE09FD3E7B">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text>reaffirms its support of the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Architectural Barriers Act">Architectural Barriers Act</cato:entity-ref> and the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Americans with Disabilities Act">Americans with Disabilities Act</cato:entity-ref> and full compliance of the laws;</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H6189C3455D564C5CA3B8A6475AAD9241">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <text>recommends that the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1800">United States Postal Service</cato:entity-ref> and other public agencies install power-assisted doors to ensure equal access to all citizens; and</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H3991511656A94E4DB52C4EDB7020EDF3">
        <enum>(4)</enum>
        <text>pledges to continue to work to identify and rectify the barriers that are preventing all United States citizens from having equal access to the services provided by the Federal Government.</text>
      </paragraph>
    </section>
  </resolution-body>
</resolution>
</doc>