<doc>
  <docmeta id="113hres401ih">
    <bill congress="113" type="hres" number="401" version="ih"/>
    <revision size="3986" annotations="0" status="complete" id="3" commit-time="2013-11-13T18:09:11Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113hres401ih/3.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <resolution xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" dms-id="HA96ADA4E5C1E47A48973CBD73D4E5055" key="H" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print">
  <metadata>
<dublinCore>
<dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">113 HRES 401 IH: Expressing support for designation of the third Tuesday of November as National Entrepreneurs Day.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">2013-10-30</dc:date>
<dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code>
    <congress display="yes">113th CONGRESS</congress>
    <session display="yes">1st Session</session>
    <legis-num>H. RES. 401</legis-num>
    <current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
    <action display="yes">
      <action-date date="20131030">October 30, 2013</action-date>
      <action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="P000608">Mr. Peters of California</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="G000569">Mr. Grimm</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001191">Mr. Murphy of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001097">Mr. Cárdenas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001245">Ms. Bordallo</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001084">Mr. Cicilline</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000130">Mr. Vargas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000382">Ms. Kuster</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000597">Mr. Rice of South Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000598">Mrs. Davis of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000617">Ms. DelBene</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000293">Ms. Esty</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000565">Mr. Loebsack</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000595">Mr. Peters of Michigan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000604">Mr. Payne</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000579">Mr. Lowenthal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000187">Mrs. Negrete McLeod</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001080">Ms. Chu</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000598">Mr. Polis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000215">Ms. Eshoo</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001034">Mr. Honda</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000381">Mr. Kilmer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000560">Mr. Larsen of Washington</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000188">Mr. Kind</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001064">Mr. Heck of Washington</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000454">Mr. Foster</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="B001280">Mr. Bentivolio</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>
      </action-desc>
    </action>
    <legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
    <official-title display="yes">Expressing support for designation of the third Tuesday of November as <term>National Entrepreneurs Day</term>.</official-title>
  </form>
  <preamble>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas since our Nation’s beginning, innovation, creativity, industriousness, and entrepreneurship have formed the economic fiber of the United States;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas entrepreneurs’ willingness to evaluate risk has resulted in unparalleled contributions to this country’s growth and development;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas entrepreneurship is the stimulus for strengthening the economy, advancing innovation, improving productivity, and creating new jobs;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas research conveys that innovation has been responsible for approximately two-thirds of our country’s economic growth since World War II;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas more than half-a-million new businesses are created in the United States every month and small business openings have accounted for 40 percent of new jobs in the last two decades;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas despite economic instability, 56 percent of adults were confident that they could start a business and 82 percent of entrepreneurs in 2012 used their own savings for startup cash, indicating that the American entrepreneurial spirit remains strong;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas collaboration and cooperation amidst a broad coalition of organizations, including nonprofit entrepreneurial incubators, angel investors, venture capitalists, crowd-funding initiatives, and other early-stage investors, catalyze entrepreneurial ventures;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas entrepreneurial literacy skills serve as one of the 21st-century content areas critical to success in communities and workplaces;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas more than 70 percent of young Americans envision starting a business or doing something entrepreneurial as adults;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas positive outcomes for youth who participate in entrepreneurship education programs include improved academic performance, increased critical thinking skills, and heightened occupational aspirations;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas to maintain our position as a world economic leader, the government, entrepreneurs, universities, and small and large businesses of this country must be united in a comprehensive effort to welcome and cultivate entrepreneurial savvy;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas entrepreneurship is America’s best offense for economic progress and its finest defense against the status quo; and</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the third Tuesday of November would be an appropriate date to designate as <term>National Entrepreneurs Day</term>: Now, therefore, be it</text>
    </whereas>
  </preamble>
  <resolution-body id="H74AE367B878A412587525226B44BDF9D" style="traditional">
    <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HE53B009E28F245A0BB212CC435364D89" section-type="undesignated-section">
      <enum/>
      <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0050">House of Representatives</cato:entity-ref>—</text>
      <paragraph id="HBDE62C9D3F734BF2803A0CF34496B0DC">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">supports the designation of <term>National Entrepreneurs Day</term>;</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HF4BC53D72C0B436F8DADA316E9CD802E">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recognizes the considerable contributions of entrepreneurs to the United States of America; and</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H6C28352720C7420C997BCCB4284C3BBA">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <text>honors those entrepreneurs who ignite innovation and inspire the next generation.</text>
      </paragraph>
    </section>
  </resolution-body>
</resolution>
</doc>