<doc>
  <docmeta id="113hres322eh">
    <bill congress="113" type="hres" number="322" version="eh"/>
    <revision size="8243" annotations="0" status="complete" id="4" commit-time="2014-02-13T21:38:06Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113hres322eh/4.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <resolution xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" dms-id="H7b9e0b26-2911-4d21-bbfc-8397d0039808" key="H" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Engrossed-in-House" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" stage-count="1"> 
<metadata>
<dublinCore>
<dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">113 HRES 322 EH: Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 367) to amend <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/8">chapter 8</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, to provide that major rules of the executive branch shall have no force or effect unless a joint resolution of approval is enacted into law; providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 2009) to prohibit the Secretary of the Treasury from enforcing the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act and the Health Care and Education Reconciliation Act of 2010; providing for proceedings during the period from August 3, 2013, through September 6, 2013; and providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 2879) to provide limitations on bonuses for Federal employees during sequestration, to provide for investigative leave requirements for members of the Senior Executive Service, to establish certain procedures for conducting in-person or telephonic interactions by Executive branch employees with individuals, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">2013-08-01</dc:date>
<dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="no">IV</distribution-code> 
<congress display="no">113th CONGRESS</congress> 
<session display="no">1st Session</session> 
<legis-num>H. RES. 322</legis-num> 
<current-chamber display="yes">In the House of Representatives, U. S.,</current-chamber>
<action>
<action-date date="20130801">August 1, 2013</action-date>
</action> 
<legis-type display="yes">RESOLUTION</legis-type> 
<official-title display="no">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 367) to amend <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/8">chapter 8</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, to provide that major rules of the executive branch shall have no force or effect unless a joint resolution of approval is enacted into law; providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 2009) to prohibit the Secretary of the Treasury from enforcing the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act and the Health Care and Education Reconciliation Act of 2010; providing for proceedings during the period from August 3, 2013, through September 6, 2013; and providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 2879) to provide limitations on bonuses for Federal employees during sequestration, to provide for investigative leave requirements for members of the Senior Executive Service, to establish certain procedures for conducting in-person or telephonic interactions by Executive branch employees with individuals, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<resolution-body id="H06a0e4f1-ae39-4f1e-888c-2e39f165027a" style="traditional"> 
<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H86a692bd-272d-450a-bd5b-beab17ff535d" section-type="undesignated-section">
      <enum/>
      <text>That at any time after the adoption
			 of this resolution the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" value="Speaker of the House of Representatives">Speaker</cato:entity-ref> may, pursuant to clause 2(b) of rule XVIII,
			 declare the House resolved into the Committee of the Whole House on the state
			 of the Union for consideration of the bill (<cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="113 HR 367" proposed="true">H.R. 367</cato:entity-ref>) to amend <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc-chapter/5/8">chapter 8 of
			 title 5, United States Code</cato:entity-ref>, to provide that major rules of the executive
			 branch shall have no force or effect unless a joint resolution of approval is
			 enacted into law. The first reading of the bill shall be dispensed with. All
			 points of order against consideration of the bill are waived. General debate
			 shall be confined to the bill and shall not exceed one hour equally divided and
			 controlled by the chair and ranking minority member of the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="committee" entity-id="HJU00">Committee on the
			 Judiciary</cato:entity-ref>. After general debate the bill shall be considered for amendment
			 under the five-minute rule. It shall be in order to consider as an original
			 bill for the purpose of amendment under the five-minute rule the amendment in
			 the nature of a substitute recommended by the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="committee" entity-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</cato:entity-ref> now
			 printed in the bill modified by the amendment printed in part A of the report
			 of the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="committee" entity-id="HRU00">Committee on Rules</cato:entity-ref> accompanying this resolution. That amendment in the
			 nature of a substitute shall be considered as read. All points of order against
			 that amendment in the nature of a substitute are waived. No amendment to that
			 amendment in the nature of a substitute shall be in order except those printed
			 in part B of the report of the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="committee" entity-id="HRU00">Committee on Rules</cato:entity-ref>. Each such amendment may be
			 offered only in the order printed in the report, may be offered only by a
			 Member designated in the report, shall be considered as read, shall be
			 debatable for the time specified in the report equally divided and controlled
			 by the proponent and an opponent, shall not be subject to amendment, and shall
			 not be subject to a demand for division of the question in the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0050">House</cato:entity-ref> or in the
			 Committee of the Whole. All points of order against such amendments are waived.
			 At the conclusion of consideration of the bill for amendment the Committee
			 shall rise and report the bill to the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0050">House</cato:entity-ref> with such amendments as may have
			 been adopted. Any Member may demand a separate vote in the House on any
			 amendment adopted in the Committee of the Whole to the bill or to the amendment
			 in the nature of a substitute made in order as original text. The previous
			 question shall be considered as ordered on the bill and amendments thereto to
			 final passage without intervening motion except one motion to recommit with or
			 without instructions.</text> </section>
<section id="H3DB2AA5251F345F7A3EBC798C18F13AE">
      <enum>2.</enum>
      <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon the adoption of this resolution it
			 shall be in order to consider in the House the bill (<cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="113 HR 2009" proposed="true">H.R. 2009</cato:entity-ref>) to prohibit the
			 <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary of the Treasury</cato:entity-ref> from enforcing the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act">Patient Protection and Affordable
			 Care Act</cato:entity-ref> and the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Health Care and Education Reconciliation Act of 2010">Health Care and Education Reconciliation Act of 2010</cato:entity-ref>. All
			 points of order against consideration of the bill are waived. The bill shall be
			 considered as read. All points of order against provisions in the bill are
			 waived. The previous question shall be considered as ordered on the bill and on
			 any amendment thereto to final passage without intervening motion except: (1)
			 one hour of debate equally divided and controlled by the chair and ranking
			 minority member of the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="committee" entity-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</cato:entity-ref>; and (2) one motion to
			 recommit.</text> </section>
<section id="H52FE20C1FCEA42EB9F96D648C9381953">
      <enum>3.</enum>
      <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">
        <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="113 HRES 292" proposed="true">House Resolution 292</cato:entity-ref> is laid on the
			 table.</text> </section>
<section id="H89BE645A561349199CA7771DADCD4A76">
      <enum>4.</enum>
      <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">On any legislative day during the period from August 3, 2013, through September 6, 2013, —</text> 
<subsection id="H792B46363664447785CDB7EB1B84E382">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Journal of the proceedings of the previous day shall be considered as approved;</text> </subsection>
<subsection id="H2C41CAF76EF94F789F90263601CA8DDE">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <text>the Chair may at any time declare the House adjourned to meet at a date and time, within the limits of clause 4, section 5, article I of the Constitution, to be announced by the Chair in declaring the adjournment; and</text> </subsection>
<subsection id="HB14135F90D364983B82DD5976E3A6EF7">
        <enum>(c)</enum>
        <text>bills and resolutions introduced during the period addressed by this section shall be numbered, listed in the Congressional Record, and when printed shall bear the date of introduction, but may be referred by the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" value="Speaker of the House of Representatives" entity-parent-id="0050">Speaker</cato:entity-ref> at a later time.</text> </subsection>
    </section>
<section id="H0F9899C21C9D4262BF8873A065D3DFAA">
      <enum>5.</enum>
      <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" value="Speaker of the House of Representatives" entity-parent-id="0050">Speaker</cato:entity-ref> may appoint Members to perform the duties of the Chair for the duration of the period addressed by <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="113 HRES 322/s:4" proposed="true">section 4 of this resolution</cato:entity-ref> as though under clause 8(a) of rule I.</text> </section>
<section id="H91CF36B9247C4D89BA0F68A1DB20B20A">
      <enum>6.</enum>
      <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each day during the period addressed by <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="113 HRES 322/s:4" proposed="true">section 4 of this resolution</cato:entity-ref> shall not constitute a calendar day for purposes of <cato:entity entity-type="law-citation">
          <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="War Powers Resolution/s:7">section 7 of the War Powers Resolution</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1546">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/50/1546">50 U.S.C. 1546</cato:entity-ref>
          </external-xref>)</cato:entity>.</text> </section>
<section id="H5D8EE2F5CE3D46CEAE6E2D2576FACFD6">
      <enum>7.</enum>
      <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each day during the period addressed by
			 <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="113 HRES 322/s:4" proposed="true">section 4 of this resolution</cato:entity-ref> shall not constitute a legislative day for
			 purposes of clause 7 of rule XIII.</text> </section>
<section id="H464805521F9049F3B2E438F182322A12">
      <enum>8.</enum>
      <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon the adoption of this resolution it
			 shall be in order to consider in the House the bill (<cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="113 HR 2879" proposed="true">H.R. 2879</cato:entity-ref>) to provide
			 limitations on bonuses for Federal employees during sequestration, to provide
			 for investigative leave requirements for members of the Senior Executive
			 Service, to establish certain procedures for conducting in-person or telephonic
			 interactions by Executive branch employees with individuals, and for other
			 purposes. All points of order against consideration of the bill are waived. The
			 bill shall be considered as read. All points of order against provisions in the
			 bill are waived. The previous question shall be considered as ordered on the
			 bill and on any amendment thereto to final passage without intervening motion
			 except: (1) one hour of debate equally divided and controlled by the chair and
			 ranking minority member of the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="committee" entity-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</cato:entity-ref>;
			 and (2) one motion to recommit.</text> </section>
<section id="H88177F4D5DB14E5E8660A9E96F441174">
      <enum>9.</enum>
      <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon passage of <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="113 HR 2879" proposed="true">H.R. 2879</cato:entity-ref>, the following
			 bills shall be laid on the table: <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="113 HR 1541" proposed="true">H.R. 1541</cato:entity-ref>, <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="113 HR 2579" proposed="true">H.R. 2579</cato:entity-ref>, and <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="113 HR 2711" proposed="true">H.R. 2711</cato:entity-ref>.</text> </section>
</resolution-body> 
<attestation>
    <attestation-group>
      <attestor display="no">Karen L. Haas,</attestor>
      <role>Clerk.</role>
    </attestation-group>
  </attestation>
</resolution>
</doc>