<doc>
  <docmeta id="113hr5590ih">
    <bill congress="113" type="hr" number="5590" version="ih"/>
    <revision size="7374" annotations="0" status="complete" id="4" commit-time="2014-10-10T14:35:56Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113hr5590ih/4.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H5CDADA58DDC64E24A2B542F54CC402D3" public-private="public">
	<metadata>
<dublinCore>
<dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">113 HR 5590 IH: Go to High School, Go to College Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">2014-09-18</dc:date>
<dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>113th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>2d Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 5590</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20140918">September 18, 2014</action-date>
			<action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="F000455">Ms. Fudge</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="G000564">Mr. Gibson</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and the Workforce</committee-name>
      </action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To amend the Higher Education Act of 1965 to allow the Secretary of Education to award Early
			 College Federal Pell Grants.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="HFB5DBF9605934A228F378BA9A420EE2F" style="OLC">
		<section id="H67F8C512E04A402EA724CAA1D5974C8F" section-type="section-one">
      <enum>1.</enum>
      <header>Short title</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote>
          <short-title>
            <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Go to High School, Go to College Act" proposed="true">Go to High School, Go to College Act</cato:entity-ref>
          </short-title>
        </quote>.</text>
		</section>
    <section id="HF7E211DCE85C47D0989124C7A24EB093">
      <enum>2.</enum>
      <header>Early college Federal Pell Grant</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">
        <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
          <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Higher Education Act of 1965/s:401">Section 401 of the Higher Education Act of 1965</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1070a">
          <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/20/1070a">20 U.S.C. 1070a</cato:entity-ref>
        </external-xref>)</cato:entity> is amended by adding at the end
			 the following:</text>
			<quoted-block id="HA25F5E84B9004568B912A7AFDA5EF2A8" style="OLC">
				<subsection id="H9BD6C4FE419D484DAFE81F3A650EF518">
          <enum>(k)</enum>
          <header>Early College Federal Pell Grants</header>
					<paragraph id="H2EA95468B1164DB6A7928D235F6D4D69">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <header>In general</header>
            <text>Notwithstanding the requirement under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Higher Education Act of 1965/s:484/ss:a/p:1">section 484(a)(1)</cato:entity-ref> that a student not been enrolled in an
			 elementary or secondary school to be eligible to receive a Federal Pell
			 Grant under this section, for the award years beginning on July 1, 2014,
			 and ending on June 30, 2020, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="9100">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall carry out a program to
			 award Early College Federal Pell Grants to eligible students to support
			 enrollment in, and completion of, postsecondary courses offered through an
			 early college high school.</text>
					</paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H89771F4B52DC48B7B7AA783985481EF7">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <header>Maximum period for Early College Federal Pell Grants</header>
            <text>An eligible student may receive an Early College Federal Pell Grant under this subsection in an
			 amount equal to the cost of not more than 4 full-time postsecondary
			 semesters, or the equivalent of 4 full-time postsecondary semesters, as
			 determined by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="9100">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> by regulation, while enrolled in postsecondary
			 courses offered by an early college high school.</text>
					</paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H94322A8B3DB24F7B90154FB5FAC0FC07">
            <enum>(3)</enum>
            <header>Counting of awards for purposes of Federal Pell Grants</header>
						<subparagraph id="H6415A19CDFF64348B9AC2C4C62016BDB">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <header>In general</header>
              <text>An Early College Federal Pell Grant received under this subsection shall be counted toward the
			 maximum period for which a student may receive Federal Pell Grants under
			 this section, as provided under subsection (c)(5).</text>
						</subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H440A18FC6FD34C61825A106EC3F8F5CB">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <header>Waiver</header>
              <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="9100">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> may waive the requirement under subparagraph (A) on a case-by-case basis for any
			 student demonstrating evidence of a credible disruption or redirection in
			 course of study necessitating additional time to complete a postsecondary
			 degree or credential.</text>
						</subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H322CCC27BD9A42E5A894F58EA6744443">
            <enum>(4)</enum>
            <header>Terms and conditions</header>
						<subparagraph id="H012D540DCB374344B3DA55B6C4057401">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <header>In general</header>
              <text>Except as provided in this subsection, an Early College Federal Pell Grant received under this
			 subsection shall have the same terms and conditions, and be awarded in the
			 same manner, as Federal Pell Grants awarded under this section.</text>
						</subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="HD806780AF0A747A893F0F3A3656C1CE7">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <header>Minimum completion</header>
              <text>An eligible student may only receive an Early College Federal Pell Grant under this subsection upon
			 completion of a full-time postsecondary semester, or the equivalent of a
			 full-time postsecondary semester, as determined by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="9100">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> by
			 regulation.</text>
						</subparagraph>
            <subparagraph commented="no" id="HF32B204349BC466FB440CBE79F3086F0">
              <enum>(C)</enum>
              <header>Amount</header>
              <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="9100">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall pay an eligible institution that is engaged in a partnership as part of an
			 early college high school an amount equal to the cost of tuition, fees,
			 and books for each postsecondary course (including with respect to the
			 postsecondary courses completed to satisfy the requirement under
			 subparagraph (B)) an eligible student completes through such early college
			 high school, provided such eligible student satisfies the requirement
			 under subparagraph (B).</text>
						</subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="HB120A54066ED4AD7BB3A9533635B75EE">
            <enum>(5)</enum>
            <header>Reporting</header>
            <text>Each early college high school shall annually submit to the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="9100">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> a report on the program of
			 postsecondary courses provided to eligible students that includes the
			 following information:</text>
						<subparagraph id="HC572B4AD6DD4441E871114D23E077DDE">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>Total number and percentage of eligible students who enroll in and subsequently complete the
			 program at the early college high school.</text>
						</subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H3C18F0E24D994CE3934AD23DB795271B">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>The number of postsecondary credits earned by eligible students while enrolled in the early college
			 high school that may be applied toward a postsecondary degree or
			 credential program.</text>
						</subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H9659D27F788E46C88B7652A1D7125F12">
              <enum>(C)</enum>
              <text>The percentage of eligible students enrolled in the early college high school who concurrently earn
			 a secondary school diploma and an associate degree or equivalent.</text>
						</subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="HC27CBCE64CFD4FA6A3C3EAB4309D5A9C">
              <enum>(D)</enum>
              <text>The percentage of early college high school graduates completing the program who enroll in a
			 postsecondary institution.</text>
						</subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H506416C176BF48B0AE19EA55925037EB">
              <enum>(E)</enum>
              <text>The total amount of Early College Federal Pell Grants awarded to eligible students served by the
			 early college high school.</text>
						</subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="HB669A1BBBC9B4A209C01566D3B4CE9C2">
            <enum>(6)</enum>
            <header>Definitions</header>
            <text>In this subsection:</text>
						<subparagraph id="HC3345F43D9DA42FABFEDDC92D067D819">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <header>Early college high school</header>
              <text>The term <quote>early college high school</quote> means a partnership between a public secondary school and at least one eligible institution—</text>
							<clause id="H535A96E8E0684930819223EE89CB6924">
                <enum>(i)</enum>
                <text>that enables a student enrolled at such secondary school to simultaneously earn a secondary school
			 diploma and postsecondary credits that are transferable to such eligible
			 institution as part of an organized course of study toward a postsecondary
			 degree or credential at no cost to the student or the family of the
			 student;</text>
							</clause>
              <clause id="H8778A5E347DF4497AAACECAD2C27A37E">
                <enum>(ii)</enum>
                <text>that offers students enrolled at such secondary school postsecondary courses provided by an
			 eligible institution as part of a State-approved program of study that
			 leads to a postsecondary degree, certificate, or general education core
			 that is transferable to such eligible institution;</text>
							</clause>
              <clause id="H7EDBF6CCD71D4AD9ADA1D6BBD1D3604C">
                <enum>(iii)</enum>
                <text>that provides such students the opportunity to earn not less than 12 credit hours in such
			 postsecondary courses; and</text>
							</clause>
              <clause id="H54B8EE31DF7C480AA7926BCC56CF483D">
                <enum>(iv)</enum>
                <text>that provides support, placement test prep strategies, tutoring, or comparable strategies to ensure
			 student preparation for and success in college courses.</text>
							</clause>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H15821506069F47C0A0DE05DACC7DEDAB">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <header>Eligible student</header>
              <text>The term <quote>eligible student</quote> means a student enrolled at an early college high school who, if such student met the requirements
			 of <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Higher Education Act of 1965/s:484">section 484</cato:entity-ref> for eligibility for a Federal Pell Grant, would be awarded
			 a Federal Pell Grant after the determination of the expected family
			 contribution for such student.</text>
						</subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
      </quoted-block>
		</section>
  </legis-body>
</bill>
</doc>