<doc>
  <docmeta id="113hr4503ih">
    <bill congress="113" type="hr" number="4503" version="ih"/>
    <revision size="23770" annotations="0" status="complete" id="4" commit-time="2014-05-08T20:22:19Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113hr4503ih/4.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H98663E52CD45444F9394BADC493B213C" public-private="public">
	<metadata>
<dublinCore>
<dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">113 HR 4503 IH: Fair Playing Field Act of 2014</dc:title>
<dc:publisher xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">2014-04-28</dc:date>
<dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>113th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>2d Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 4503</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20140428">April 28, 2014</action-date>
			<action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="M000404">Mr. McDermott</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name>
      </action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to permit the Secretary of the Treasury to issue
			 prospective guidance clarifying the employment status of individuals for
			 purposes of employment taxes and to prevent retroactive assessments with
			 respect to such clarifications.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="HD09BADD9F33F4B3394E3197FE3954B9E" style="OLC">
		<section id="HEC38D02D130B421988DF82937695193D" section-type="section-one">
      <enum>1.</enum>
      <header>Short title; findings; purposes</header>
			<subsection id="HAE61A3227E2C4FA58540619C33C2FAC4">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Short title</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote>
            <short-title>
              <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Fair Playing Field Act of 2014" proposed="true">Fair Playing Field Act of 2014</cato:entity-ref>
            </short-title>
          </quote>.</text>
			</subsection>
      <subsection id="H0C22F83BDD5D48C28C6728EF333C7ADC">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Findings</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">
          <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> makes the following findings:</text>
				<paragraph id="H431F077DEAC249CDA533155A4E9D14C3">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In 1978, <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> was concerned that lack of clarity as to the proper classification of some
			 workers, increased <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="2050" entity-type="federal-body">IRS</cato:entity-ref> enforcement activity, and retroactive application
			 by <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="2050" entity-type="federal-body">IRS</cato:entity-ref> of interpretations that were arguably new had caused hardships for
			 some small businesses and other taxpayers and confusion as to the
			 applicable rules.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HE6171FCAAADE449483C6C7EF5BA8DDFF">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>To allow time to develop a comprehensive approach to the problem, <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> enacted <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Revenue Act of 1978/s:530">section 530 of
			 the Revenue Act of 1978</cato:entity-ref> as an interim measure protecting taxpayers from
			 liability for misclassification if the taxpayer has a reasonable basis for
			 classifying a worker as an independent contractor and meets certain other
			 conditions. In addition, the Act prohibited the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="2000" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of the Treasury</cato:entity-ref>
			 from publishing regulations or revenue rulings on workers’ employment tax
			 status pending the expected near-term enactment of clarifying legislation.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H1159CE3DB40F40B2BA2A3F14AFB0A87C">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <text>During the ensuing 33 years, <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> made <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Revenue Act of 1978/s:530">section 530 of the Revenue Act of 1978</cato:entity-ref> permanent,
			 however, changes in working relationships and the continued prohibition on
			 new guidance have increased the uncertainty as to the proper
			 classification of workers.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H4A9EF09F42824907B423E7BA5C40A43F">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
          <text>Many workers are properly classified as independent contractors. In other instances, workers who
			 are employees are being treated as independent contractors. Such
			 misclassification for tax purposes contributes to inequities in the
			 competitive positions of businesses and to the Federal and State tax gap,
			 and may also result in misclassification for other purposes, such as
			 denial of unemployment benefits, workplace health and safety protections,
			 and retirement or other benefits or protections available to employees.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H620DC180635D48E790CE3A87449C9A52">
          <enum>(5)</enum>
          <text>Workers, businesses, and other taxpayers will benefit from clear guidance regarding employment tax
			 status. In the interest of fairness and in view of many service
			 recipients’ reliance on current <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Revenue Act of 1978/s:530">section 530</cato:entity-ref>, such guidance should apply
			 only prospectively.</text>
				</paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="HA027F7EFDA6A4D6A925291CE16D70623">
        <enum>(c)</enum>
        <header>Purposes</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The purposes of this Act are to permit the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="2000" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of the Treasury</cato:entity-ref> to provide guidance allowing
			 workers and businesses to clearly understand the proper Federal tax
			 classification of workers and to provide relief allowing an orderly
			 transition to new rules designed to increase certainty and uniformity of
			 treatment.</text>
			</subsection>
    </section>
    <section id="H50666E3EBAAE4E1FA37F94B6CE653BBB">
      <enum>2.</enum>
      <header>Authority to issue guidance clarifying employment status for purposes of employment taxes</header>
			<subsection id="H6939C066427D4EAEBB004BFB9A61BA4A">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>In general</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">
          <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/ch:25">
            <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/25">Chapter 25</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986</cato:entity-ref> is amended by adding at the end the following new
			 section:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBF6B1246AF774092B21F681A32CF1867" style="OLC">
					<section id="HA53091843331475CB07119A9A6C86450">
            <enum>3511.</enum>
            <header>Authority to issue guidance clarifying employment status</header>
						<subsection id="HB154169388E14D8F868516DE3DB1ED4A">
              <enum>(a)</enum>
              <header>In general</header>
              <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall issue such regulations or other guidance as the Secretary determines to be
			 necessary or appropriate to clarify the proper employment status of
			 individuals for purposes of any tax imposed by this subtitle.</text>
						</subsection>
            <subsection id="HCA573EC46B5C47E0B24DA06675766F13">
              <enum>(b)</enum>
              <header>Prohibition on retroactive assessments</header>
							<paragraph id="H94C2EC2DA3444AF69AF822BEB8AA3F20">
                <enum>(1)</enum>
                <header>In general</header>
                <text>If—</text>
								<subparagraph id="H0329B152FA114F9FA9EEDBB80FC4EC7C">
                  <enum>(A)</enum>
                  <text>for purposes of any tax imposed by this subtitle, the taxpayer did not treat an individual as an
			 employee for any period before the reclassification date with respect to
			 such individual, and</text>
								</subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="H437C3060980641548461AF8C44D5F96D">
                  <enum>(B)</enum>
                  <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of periods after December 31, 1978, and before such reclassification date, all Federal
			 tax returns (including information returns) required to be filed by the
			 taxpayer with respect to such individual for such period are filed on a
			 basis consistent with the taxpayer’s treatment of such individual as not
			 being an employee,</text>
                </subparagraph>
                <continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph">then, for purposes of applying such taxes for periods before such reclassification date with
			 respect to the taxpayer, the individual shall be deemed not to be an
			 employee unless the taxpayer had no reasonable basis for not treating such
			 individual as an employee.</continuation-text>
              </paragraph>
              <paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H95C49B994DEF4C73BBEF70FBF58AA0B5">
                <enum>(2)</enum>
                <header>Statutory standards providing one method of satisfying the requirements of paragraph (1)</header>
                <text>For purposes of <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:3511/ss:b/p:1" proposed="true">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref>, a taxpayer shall in any case be treated as having a reasonable basis
			 for not treating an individual as an employee for a period if the
			 taxpayer’s treatment of such individual for such period was in reasonable
			 reliance on any of the following:</text>
								<subparagraph id="H4CB34135B9DB48F2AD752CDCC1161C9D">
                  <enum>(A)</enum>
                  <text>Judicial precedent, published rulings, technical advice with respect to the taxpayer, or a letter
			 ruling to the taxpayer.</text>
								</subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="HDE0A1B60BBB042C79BF4A612749B8E2D">
                  <enum>(B)</enum>
                  <text>A past <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="2050" entity-type="federal-body">Internal Revenue Service</cato:entity-ref> audit of the taxpayer in which there was no assessment attributable
			 to the treatment (for purposes of any tax imposed by this subtitle) of the
			 individuals holding positions substantially similar to the position held
			 by such individual.</text>
								</subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="HFC23309598D64A12946BC063BF2E7975">
                  <enum>(C)</enum>
                  <text>Long-standing recognized practice of a significant segment of the industry in which such individual
			 was engaged.</text>
								</subparagraph>
              </paragraph>
              <paragraph id="HAC4392DF2B4641D1ABF9231A517F25C8">
                <enum>(3)</enum>
                <header>Consistency required in the case of prior tax treatment</header>
                <text>
                  <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:3511/ss:b/p:1" proposed="true">Paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref> shall not apply with respect to the treatment of any individual (hereafter in this
			 paragraph referred to as the reclassified individual) for purposes of any
			 tax imposed by this subtitle for any period ending after December 31,
			 1978, if the taxpayer (or a predecessor) has treated any individual
			 holding a substantially similar position as an employee for purposes of
			 any tax imposed by this subtitle for any period beginning after December
			 31, 1977, and ending before the reclassification date with respect to such
			 reclassified individual.</text>
							</paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="H80DDA77F8B634B17BB261CA13C8A7BD6">
              <enum>(c)</enum>
              <header>Definitions</header>
              <text>For purposes of this section—</text>
							<paragraph id="HDE0E49FE65B343BAB9A0C7C873D2C420">
                <enum>(1)</enum>
                <header>Reclassification date</header>
								<subparagraph id="H7C2160FD03C94EB69F7B96BCD2764DCF">
                  <enum>(A)</enum>
                  <header>In general</header>
                  <text>The term <term>reclassification date</term> means, with respect to any individual, the earlier of—</text>
									<clause id="H0164416918CC498E909A850FFEBB7390">
                    <enum>(i)</enum>
                    <text>the first day of the first calendar quarter beginning more than 180 days after the date of an
			 employee classification determination with respect to such individual, or</text>
									</clause>
                  <clause id="H94BBF9A77A224F9C83CA5C1BB51619C2">
                    <enum>(ii)</enum>
                    <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the effective date of the first applicable final regulation issued by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> under
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:3511/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref> with respect to such individual (or, if later, the first
			 day of the first calendar quarter beginning more than 180 days after such
			 regulation is issued).</text>
									</clause>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="H7EEF04A5721A4A9EB3070193C16CF1F7">
                  <enum>(B)</enum>
                  <header>Employee classification determination</header>
                  <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>employee classification determination</term> means, with respect to any individual, a determination by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary</cato:entity-ref>, in connection with an
			 audit of the taxpayer which is described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:7436">section 7436</cato:entity-ref> and which
			 commences after the date which is 1 year after the date of the enactment
			 of this section, that a class of individuals holding positions with such
			 taxpayer which are substantially similar to the position held by such
			 individual are employees.</text>
								</subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="H6608D4991DAB4EC5BB41B43175813B20">
                  <enum>(C)</enum>
                  <header>First applicable final regulation</header>
                  <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>first applicable final regulation</term> means, with respect to any individual, the first final regulation (or other guidance of general
			 applicability) which sets forth the factors for determining the employment
			 status of a class of individuals holding positions substantially similar
			 to the position held by such individual.</text>
								</subparagraph>
              </paragraph>
              <paragraph id="H23085CF896C0490480F73DB75C0DF172">
                <enum>(2)</enum>
                <header>Employment status</header>
                <text>The term <term>employment status</term> means the status of an individual, under the usual common law rules applicable in determining the
			 employer-employee relationship, as an employee or as an independent
			 contractor (or other individual who is not an employee).</text>
							</paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="H9B6F603BDC8447DA9A446DBC3A88246B">
              <enum>(d)</enum>
              <header>Continuation of certain special rules</header>
							<paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDF4474A946BC489F8D037465F1EDC408">
                <enum>(1)</enum>
                <header>Exception for certain skilled workers</header>
                <text>
                  <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:3511/ss:b" proposed="true">Subsection (b)</cato:entity-ref> shall not apply in the case of an individual who, pursuant to an arrangement between
			 the taxpayer and another person, provides services for such other person
			 as an engineer, designer, drafter, computer programmer, systems analyst,
			 or other similarly skilled worker engaged in a similar line of work.</text>
							</paragraph>
              <paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE0F94FFC32CE459FB0487062C3F7C273">
                <enum>(2)</enum>
                <header>Notice of availability of section</header>
                <text>An officer or employee of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="2050" entity-type="federal-body">Internal Revenue Service</cato:entity-ref> shall, before or at the commencement of any
			 audit inquiry relating to the employment status of one or more individuals
			 who perform services for the taxpayer, provide the taxpayer with a written
			 notice of the provisions of this section.</text>
							</paragraph>
              <paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H25EA8CA3D3E9419D94EF14A22CB1430C">
                <enum>(3)</enum>
                <header>Rules relating to statutory standards</header>
                <text>For purposes of <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:3511/ss:b/p:2" proposed="true">subsection (b)(2)</cato:entity-ref>—</text>
								<subparagraph id="HE497724D59CC4AD98052C9EDD3397127">
                  <enum>(A)</enum>
                  <text>a taxpayer may not rely on an audit commenced after December 31, 1996, for purposes of <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:3511/ss:b/p:2/sp:B" proposed="true">subparagraph
			 (B) thereof</cato:entity-ref> unless such audit included an examination for purposes of any
			 tax imposed by this subtitle whether the individual involved (or any
			 individual holding a position substantially similar to the position held
			 by the individual involved) should be treated as an employee of the
			 taxpayer,</text>
								</subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="H92BE7F35E185462695DB5666DCA4E0A4">
                  <enum>(B)</enum>
                  <text>in no event shall the significant segment requirement of <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:3511/ss:b/p:2/sp:C" proposed="true">subparagraph (C) thereof</cato:entity-ref> be construed to
			 require a reasonable showing of the practice of more than 25 percent of
			 the industry (determined by not taking into account the taxpayer), and</text>
								</subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="H144257D2FC82468FB2DEE6255DD7FFDC">
                  <enum>(C)</enum>
                  <text>in applying the long-standing recognized practice requirement of <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:3511/ss:b/p:2/sp:C" proposed="true">subparagraph (C) thereof</cato:entity-ref>—</text>
									<clause id="H772AE28AF17A47009543CDD2F7E4F78C">
                    <enum>(i)</enum>
                    <text>such requirement shall not be construed as requiring the practice to have continued for more than
			 10 years, and</text>
									</clause>
                  <clause id="H146E464F89E745D6B6EBAB14792C8E34">
                    <enum>(ii)</enum>
                    <text>a practice shall not fail to be treated as long-standing merely because such practice began after
			 1978.</text>
									</clause>
                </subparagraph>
              </paragraph>
              <paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0226DC77E203455E867C1BC4075470FD">
                <enum>(4)</enum>
                <header>Availability of safe harbors</header>
                <text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to provide that <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:3511/ss:b" proposed="true">subsection (b)</cato:entity-ref> only applies where the
			 individual involved is otherwise an employee of the taxpayer.</text>
							</paragraph>
              <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H584934AA7902404DB6031779312798DC">
                <enum>(5)</enum>
                <header>Burden of proof</header>
								<subparagraph commented="no" id="H22C1467C814042598696E3AD588D8865">
                  <enum>(A)</enum>
                  <header>In general</header>
                  <text>If—</text>
									<clause commented="no" id="H1741DE169CCE42338F64FA59C46AB62A">
                    <enum>(i)</enum>
                    <text>a taxpayer establishes a prima facie case that it was reasonable not to treat an individual as an
			 employee for purposes of <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:3511/ss:b" proposed="true">subsection (b)</cato:entity-ref>, and</text>
									</clause>
                  <clause commented="no" id="H4DD98F29C8FD4F459FF56166FDDDF8A0">
                    <enum>(ii)</enum>
                    <text>the taxpayer has fully cooperated with reasonable requests from the Secretary,</text>
                  </clause>
                  <continuation-text commented="no" continuation-text-level="subparagraph">then the burden of proof with respect to such treatment shall be on the Secretary.</continuation-text>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph commented="no" id="H36BE240DEFBB4194B572B59DB8539294">
                  <enum>(B)</enum>
                  <header>Exception for other reasonable basis</header>
                  <text>In the case of any issue involving whether the taxpayer had a reasonable basis not to treat an
			 individual as an employee for purposes of <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:3511/ss:b" proposed="true">subsection (b)</cato:entity-ref>, <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:3511/ss:d/p:5/sp:A" proposed="true">subparagraph (A)</cato:entity-ref>
			 shall only apply for purposes of determining whether the taxpayer meets
			 the requirements of <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:3511/ss:b/p:2/sp:A" proposed="true">subparagraph (A)</cato:entity-ref>, <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:3511/ss:b/p:2/sp:B" proposed="true">(B)</cato:entity-ref>, or <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:3511/ss:b/p:2/sp:C" proposed="true">(C) of subsection (b)(2)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
								</subparagraph>
              </paragraph>
              <paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF202F18F238E467B80694378CCA64DF7">
                <enum>(6)</enum>
                <header>Preservation of prior period safe harbor</header>
                <text>If—</text>
								<subparagraph id="H5F4450B3DB5648C59D2501BC302B5825">
                  <enum>(A)</enum>
                  <text>an individual would (but for the treatment referred to in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:3511/ss:d/p:6/sp:B" proposed="true">subparagraph (B)</cato:entity-ref>) be deemed not to be an
			 employee of the taxpayer under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:3511/ss:b" proposed="true">subsection (b)</cato:entity-ref> for any prior period, and</text>
								</subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="H38185E0856D74298AAB6E5B5D7F3CE02">
                  <enum>(B)</enum>
                  <text>such individual is treated by the taxpayer as an employee for purposes of the taxes imposed by this
			 subtitle for any subsequent period,</text>
                </subparagraph>
                <continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph">then, for purposes of applying such taxes for such prior period with respect to the taxpayer, the
			 individual shall be deemed not to be an employee.</continuation-text>
              </paragraph>
              <paragraph id="H850FE42F9A0144ED9F512C65198344E5">
                <enum>(7)</enum>
                <header>Substantially similar position</header>
                <text>For purposes of <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:3511/ss:b" proposed="true">subsection (b)</cato:entity-ref> and this subsection, the determination as to whether an individual
			 holds a position substantially similar to a position held by another
			 individual shall include consideration of the relationship between the
			 taxpayer and such individuals.</text>
							</paragraph>
              <paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9F5EA87EA70B4060850D67B4E65A3359">
                <enum>(8)</enum>
                <header>Treatment of test room supervisors and proctors who assist in the administration of college
			 entrance and placement exams</header>
								<subparagraph id="H8319E67D896845F982D4CD6995DE1A2B">
                  <enum>(A)</enum>
                  <header>In general</header>
                  <text>In the case of an individual described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:3511/ss:d/p:8/sp:B" proposed="true">subparagraph (B)</cato:entity-ref> who is providing services as a test
			 proctor or room supervisor by assisting in the administration of college
			 entrance or placement examinations, <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:3511/ss:b" proposed="true">subsection (b)</cato:entity-ref> shall be applied to
			 such services performed after December 31, 2006 (and remuneration paid for
			 such services), without regard to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:3511/ss:b/p:3" proposed="true">paragraph (3) thereof</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
								</subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="HDD1B7F8E4B914CCC9DDDAFF8E286B650">
                  <enum>(B)</enum>
                  <header>Applicability</header>
                  <text>An individual is described in this subparagraph if the individual—</text>
									<clause id="HC4AFEC31AD2C42D9BA67EEF79ECF3966">
                    <enum>(i)</enum>
                    <text>is providing the services described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:3511/ss:b" proposed="true">subsection (b)</cato:entity-ref> to an organization described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:501/ss:c">section
			 501(c)</cato:entity-ref> and exempt from tax under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:501/ss:a">section 501(a)</cato:entity-ref>, and</text>
									</clause>
                  <clause id="HF24955E50F5A451D9D5A0B3DA64B257F">
                    <enum>(ii)</enum>
                    <text>is not otherwise treated as an employee of such organization for purposes of this subtitle.</text>
									</clause>
                </subparagraph>
              </paragraph>
              <paragraph id="H7A0DDA21F91840EA9CF27195D4B51143">
                <enum>(9)</enum>
                <header>Treatment of securities broker dealers</header>
                <text>In determining for purposes of this title whether a registered representative of a securities
			 broker-dealer is an employee (as defined in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:3121/ss:d">section 3121(d)</cato:entity-ref>), no weight
			 shall be given to instructions from the service recipient which are
			 imposed only in compliance with investor protection standards imposed by
			 the Federal Government, any State government, or a governing body pursuant
			 to a delegation by a Federal or State agency.</text>
							</paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="HD9E9682916814CAEA4F424835E744B77">
              <enum>(e)</enum>
              <header>Statements to independent contractors</header>
							<paragraph id="HBCAFF9A72D384BEC8C05DFE846D15326">
                <enum>(1)</enum>
                <header>In general</header>
                <text>Each person who contracts for the services of an independent contractor on a regular and ongoing
			 basis, within the scope of such person’s trade or business, shall provide
			 a written statement to such independent contractor notifying such
			 independent contractor of the Federal tax obligations of an independent
			 contractor, the labor and employment law protections that do not apply to
			 independent contractors, and the right of such independent contractor to
			 seek a status determination from the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="2050" entity-type="federal-body">Internal Revenue Service</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
							</paragraph>
              <paragraph id="H9F65C368ED0B411DBB873E5515373E49">
                <enum>(2)</enum>
                <header>Independent contractor</header>
                <text>For purposes of this subsection, the term <term>independent contractor</term> means any individual who is not treated as an employee by the person receiving the services
			 referred to in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:3511/ss:e/p:1" proposed="true">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
							</paragraph>
              <paragraph id="HDF0CCFD7C00D4B03B1197D72E942D8EB">
                <enum>(3)</enum>
                <header>Timing of statement</header>
                <text>Except as otherwise provided by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary</cato:entity-ref>, the statement required under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:3511/ss:e/p:1" proposed="true">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref> shall be
			 provided within a reasonable period of entering into the contract referred
			 to in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:3511/ss:e/p:1" proposed="true">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
							</paragraph>
              <paragraph id="H4067F7D047034F9DB1BB2B8BD1B9D11E">
                <enum>(4)</enum>
                <header>Development of model statement</header>
                <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall develop model materials for providing the statement required under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:3511/ss:e/p:1" proposed="true">paragraph
			 (1)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
              </paragraph>
            </subsection>
          </section>
          <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
        </quoted-block>
			</subsection>
      <subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1F5D8EB9BFD6410EB399B1B5384C6ED5">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Reduced penalty not applicable in cases of noncompliance with guidance without reasonable basis</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">
          <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:3509/ss:c">Subsection (c) of section 3509 of such Code</cato:entity-ref> is amended—</text>
				<paragraph id="HA348B88788BF4D0D8B249EC3FCBD7D27">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>by striking <quote>if such liability</quote> and inserting</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HC4ED0457270D4266AE0C8CB271C0AF23" style="OLC">
            <text>if—</text>
            <paragraph id="H756CC463A25A444EBA81FCE86C2E49B8">
              <enum>(1)</enum>
              <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such liability</text>
            </paragraph>
            <after-quoted-block>, and</after-quoted-block>
          </quoted-block>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H0D0113FFEB57440EB87984B655A6BA59">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>by striking the period at the end and inserting</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H88C8D4C9DAA04513A1587B2981CF2AC0" style="OLC">
            <text>, or</text>
            <paragraph id="H02AAEEEF8FCA4E0080C84970E7333C1F">
              <enum>(2)</enum>
              <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such liability relates to an individual who is treated as an employee under regulations or other
			 guidance issued by the Secretary under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:3511/ss:a" proposed="true">section 3511(a)</cato:entity-ref> and the taxpayer
			 lacks a reasonable basis for treating the individual as other than an
			 employee.</text>
						</paragraph>
            <quoted-block-continuation-text quoted-block-continuation-text-level="subsection">In the case of a taxpayer which has received a final written determination from the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2050">Internal
			 Revenue Service</cato:entity-ref> holding that the individual referred to in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:3509/ss:c/p:2" proposed="true">paragraph (2)</cato:entity-ref>
			 (or another individual who holds a position with the taxpayer
			 substantially similar to the position held by such individual) is an
			 employee, such taxpayer shall be treated for purposes of <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:3509/ss:c/p:2" proposed="true">paragraph (2)</cato:entity-ref> as
			 lacking a reasonable basis for treating such individual as other than an
			 employee with respect to periods beginning on and after the first day of
			 the first calendar quarter beginning more than 180 days after the date of
			 such written determination unless the taxpayer establishes by clear and
			 convincing evidence that the taxpayer has a reasonable basis for such
			 treatment.</quoted-block-continuation-text>
            <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
          </quoted-block>
				</paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7CB252BC4840439DA04FB6DD1C0BFD6A">
        <enum>(c)</enum>
        <header>Conforming amendments</header>
				<paragraph id="H05B52DA0D640446DA2482D2C7FF50F33">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>
            <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:6724/ss:d/p:2">Paragraph (2) of section 6724(d) of such Code</cato:entity-ref> is amended by striking <quote>or</quote> at the end of <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:6724/ss:d/p:2/sp:GG">subparagraph (GG)</cato:entity-ref>, by striking the period at the end of <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:6724/ss:d/p:2/sp:HH">subparagraph (HH)</cato:entity-ref> and
			 inserting <quote>, or</quote>, and by inserting after <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:6724/ss:d/p:2/sp:HH">subparagraph (HH)</cato:entity-ref> the following new subparagraph:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBE8DD538D2D9452CBAAEAB3D1FA32111" style="OLC">
						<subparagraph id="H9716E2CCBF2F43F59D5C069AA5EE0885">
              <enum>(II)</enum>
              <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">
                <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:3511/ss:e" proposed="true">section 3511(e)</cato:entity-ref> (relating to statements to independent contractors).</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
          </quoted-block>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HE763BE1BEECB47B5A43E8C8937D78A0C">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>
            <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:7436/ss:a/p:2">Paragraph (2) of section 7436(a) of such Code</cato:entity-ref> is amended by striking <quote>subsection (a) of section 530 of the Revenue Act of 1978</quote> and inserting <quote>
              <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:3511/ss:b" proposed="true">section 3511(b)</cato:entity-ref>
            </quote>.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H8B2E91154BC44E5BB03F5E01B6FFC56F">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <text>The table of sections for <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/ch:25">chapter 25 of such Code</cato:entity-ref> is amended by adding at the end the following new
			 item:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0BF83482B13C43B3BAF4E4FEDDC70EFD" style="OLC">
						<toc container-level="quoted-block-container" idref="HBF6B1246AF774092B21F681A32CF1867" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded" lowest-level="section" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" regeneration="yes-regeneration">
							<toc-entry idref="HA53091843331475CB07119A9A6C86450" level="section">Sec. 3511. Authority to issue guidance clarifying employment status.</toc-entry>
            </toc>
            <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
          </quoted-block>
				</paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="H717A498F8109401A83B1962531B9A56F">
        <enum>(d)</enum>
        <header>Termination of section 530 of the Revenue Act of 1978</header>
        <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Revenue Act of 1978">Revenue Act of 1978</cato:entity-ref> is amended by striking <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Revenue Act of 1978/s:530">section 530</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
			</subsection>
      <subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFF0323B7DFD347E4AD5C4D87A296863D">
        <enum>(e)</enum>
        <header>Reports on worker misclassification</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Beginning with the first fiscal year beginning after the date the first regulation or other
			 guidance is issued for public comment under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:3511/ss:a" proposed="true">section 3511(a) of the
			 Internal Revenue Code of 1986</cato:entity-ref> (as added by this section):</text>
				<paragraph id="HB11887C08D7349099323AC6507E7E4E7">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>A report each fiscal year on worker classification which shall include the total number of
			 examinations of employers initiated because of suspected worker
			 classification issues, the total number of examinations that included
			 determinations on worker classification issues, the amount of additional
			 tax liabilities associated with worker classification enforcement actions,
			 the number of workers reclassified as a result of these actions, the
			 number of requests for Determination of Worker Status (Form SS–8), and
			 technical guidance on how to understand the data provided in the report.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H8CB4A30C5D2D44119BD728B4485E077D">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>A report each fiscal year in which new statistically valid data is compiled and interpreted on
			 worker classification, prepared on the basis of information gathered
			 during an Employment Tax Study conducted by the National Research Program
			 (NRP) of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="2050" entity-type="federal-body">Internal Revenue Service</cato:entity-ref>. Such report shall provide
			 statistical estimates of the number of employers misclassifying workers,
			 the number of workers misclassified, the industries involved, data
			 interpretations and conclusions, and a description of the impact of
			 improper worker classification on the employment tax gap.</text>
				</paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="HA6BA6F0CFD0940149FCA9923C5D8F87D">
        <enum>(f)</enum>
        <header>Effective dates</header>
				<paragraph id="HDA0EF0EF3D254B37893DE24036972F48">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>Delayed effective date of regulations and guidance</header>
          <text>Except as provided in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Fair Playing Field Act of 2014/s:2/ss:f/p:2" proposed="true">paragraph (2)</cato:entity-ref>, any regulation or other guidance issued under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:3511/ss:a" proposed="true">section 3511(a)
			 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986</cato:entity-ref>, as added by this section, shall not
			 apply to services rendered before the date which is 1 year after the date
			 of the enactment of this Act.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H2F4D61E9AB4A416493E1F26DAFDBFE49">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Treatment of securities broker dealers</header>
          <text>
            <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:3511/ss:d/p:9" proposed="true">Paragraph (9) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/3511">section 3511(d)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986</cato:entity-ref>, as added by this section,
			 shall apply to services performed after December 31, 1997.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H98074398D4594B8E80B9A868FEEB1EF3">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <header>Authority to issue regulations and guidance immediately</header>
          <text>So much of the amendment made by <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Fair Playing Field Act of 2014/s:2/ss:d" proposed="true">subsection (d)</cato:entity-ref> as relates to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Revenue Act of 1978/s:530/ss:b">subsection (b) of section 530 of the
			 Revenue Act of 1978</cato:entity-ref> shall take effect on the date of the enactment of this
			 Act.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HC093342A958148A4B5DA5276D0745EEF">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
          <header>Delayed termination of remainder of Section 530 of the Revenue Act of 1978</header>
          <text>Except as provided in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Fair Playing Field Act of 2014/s:2/ss:f/p:3" proposed="true">paragraph (3)</cato:entity-ref>, the amendments made by <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Fair Playing Field Act of 2014/s:2/ss:c/p:1" proposed="true">subsections (c)(1)</cato:entity-ref> and <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Fair Playing Field Act of 2014/s:2/ss:d" proposed="true">(d)</cato:entity-ref> shall apply
			 to services rendered on or after the date which is 1 year after the date
			 of the enactment of this Act.</text>
				</paragraph>
      </subsection>
    </section>
  </legis-body>
</bill>
</doc>