<doc>
  <docmeta id="113hres712ih">
    <bill congress="113" type="hres" number="712" version="ih"/>
    <revision size="3255" annotations="0" status="complete" id="7" commit-time="2014-08-08T15:29:25Z" committer="zwilliams" doc="113hres712ih/7.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <resolution xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" dms-id="H9556715634694181AD966E79E5449C82" key="H" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print">
	<metadata>
<dublinCore>
<dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">113 HRES 712 IH: Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives that the United States should initiate negotiations to enter into a bilateral free trade agreement with the Republic of South Africa.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">2014-08-01</dc:date>
<dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">113th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session display="yes">2d Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. RES. 712</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20140801">August 1, 2014</action-date>
			<action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="R000515">Mr. Rush</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name>
      </action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives that the United States should initiate
			 negotiations to enter into a bilateral free trade agreement with the
			 Republic of South Africa.</official-title>
	</form>
	<preamble>
		<whereas>
      <text>Whereas South Africa is the 34th largest economy in the world and is a member of the Group of
			 Twenty (G–20) and in a <quote>enhanced engagement</quote> partnership with the Organisation for Economic Co-operation and Development (OECD);</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas South Africa has signed 12 trade agreements with several countries and the European Free
			 Trade Association, 4 of which are free trade agreements;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas South Africa has concluded two trade agreements with the United States as well as
			 successfully participated in the Generalized System of Preferences (GSP)
			 and the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="African Growth and Opportunity Act">African Growth and Opportunity Act</cato:entity-ref> (AGOA);</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas United States exports to South Africa totaled $10 billion in 2012;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas South Africa is currently the United States 38th largest trading partner for goods with
			 $15.8 billion in total trade in goods in 2013;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas South Africa was the United States 36th largest export market for goods in 2013;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the amount of United States exports of goods to South Africa in 2013 was $7.3 billion, an
			 increase of 159 percent from 2003;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas United States exports of agricultural products to South Africa totaled $295 million in 2013
			 with leading categories including dairy products, wheat, planting seeds,
			 and poultry;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the amount of United States exports of private commercial services (excluding military and
			 government) to South Africa was $2.7 billion in 2012, an increase of 115
			 percent from 2002 levels;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas South Africa is a democratic, secular, unitary, constitutional republic, with a proud
			 heritage that shares many of the fundamental values of the United States;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas South Africa is the largest, most diversified, highly industrialized economy in Africa;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the average per capita income in South Africa is among the highest of African countries;
			 and</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas closer relations with South Africa through free trade agreements would encourage further
			 privatization in South Africa’s economy: Now, therefore, be it</text>
    </whereas>
  </preamble>
	<resolution-body id="H9532F82721764C9D90DD4B38146C42B3" style="traditional">
		<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H6199A5FE585C43F5BE6C5EF9F06B8E9B" section-type="undesignated-section">
      <enum/>
      <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That it is the sense of the <cato:entity-ref entity-id="0050" entity-type="federal-body">
          <cato:entity-ref entity-id="0050" entity-type="federal-body">House of Representatives</cato:entity-ref>
        </cato:entity-ref> that the United States should initiate
			 negotiations to enter into a bilateral free trade agreement with the
			 Republic of South Africa.</text>
		</section>
  </resolution-body>
</resolution>
</doc>