<doc>
  <docmeta id="113hr1872ih">
    <bill congress="113" type="hr" number="1872" version="ih"/>
    <revision size="35560" annotations="0" status="complete" id="5" commit-time="2013-06-26T21:19:57Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113hr1872ih/5.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HD066B89D02EA401B8D77F97C76A0E7F9" public-private="public">
	<metadata>
<dublinCore>
<title>113 HR 1872 IH: Budget and Accounting Transparency Act of 2013</title>
<publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</publisher>
<date>2013-05-08</date>
<format>text/xml</format>
<language>EN</language>
<rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>113th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 1872</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20130508">May 8, 2013</action-date>
			<action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="G000548">Mr. Garrett</sponsor> (for
			 himself, <cosponsor name-id="R000570">Mr. Ryan of Wisconsin</cosponsor>,
			 <cosponsor name-id="D000615">Mr. Duncan of South Carolina</cosponsor>,
			 <cosponsor name-id="F000461">Mr. Flores</cosponsor>,
			 <cosponsor name-id="M001182">Mr. Mulvaney</cosponsor>,
			 <cosponsor name-id="W000796">Mr. Westmoreland</cosponsor>,
			 <cosponsor name-id="A000367">Mr. Amash</cosponsor>, and
			 <cosponsor name-id="H001036">Mr. Hensarling</cosponsor>) introduced the
			 following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBU00">Committee on the Budget</committee-name>, and in addition
			 to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Oversight and
			 Government Reform</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined
			 by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall
			 within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To amend the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit
		  Control Act of 1985 to increase transparency in Federal budgeting, and for
		  other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="HCC11AB06C0DF462DB3D6C2D682ECB534" style="OLC">
		<section id="H42BBB4A3C9B4412F95F6181B41A92343" section-type="section-one">
      <enum>1.</enum>
      <header>Short title</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the
			 <quote>
          <short-title>Budget and Accounting Transparency Act
			 of 2013</short-title>
        </quote>.</text>
		</section>
    <title id="H4121B6A38FA04A8AA20A5DFB585F7312">
      <enum>I</enum>
      <header>Fair
			 value estimates</header>
			<section id="H742D5FFA75E446199E32A68BAB814AEA">
        <enum>101.</enum>
        <header>Credit
			 reform</header>
				<subsection id="HAF05DFBC94364E1C99F72F606B73720C">
          <enum>(a)</enum>
          <header>In
			 general</header>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">
            <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Congressional Budget Act of 1974/t:V">Title V of the
			 Congressional Budget Act of 1974</cato:entity-ref> is amended to read as follows:</text>
					<quoted-block id="H4C65D2AF17654846B2DC1E2E9F4D61FD" style="OLC">
						<title id="HB25F95EA0B124395AAF73E11FD53CC10">
              <enum>V</enum>
              <header>Fair
				value</header>
							<section id="HD106482FE8F24B7EA131C59A59EBD835">
                <enum>501.</enum>
                <header>Purposes</header>
                <text display-inline="no-display-inline">The purposes of this title are to—</text>
								<paragraph id="HF037B002DB414C7A82EE3547E99D477F">
                  <enum>(1)</enum>
                  <text>measure more
				accurately the costs of Federal credit programs by accounting for them on a
				fair value basis;</text>
								</paragraph>
                <paragraph id="H483A5FDE500542A8BE6B79CA9FD9ACFA">
                  <enum>(2)</enum>
                  <text>place the cost of
				credit programs on a budgetary basis equivalent to other Federal
				spending;</text>
								</paragraph>
                <paragraph id="HD3CF3FA3A62A4B08A9F2A73DC8F4A1A4">
                  <enum>(3)</enum>
                  <text>encourage the
				delivery of benefits in the form most appropriate to the needs of
				beneficiaries; and</text>
								</paragraph>
                <paragraph id="H84388CEC8AEF4418A52C474074878711">
                  <enum>(4)</enum>
                  <text>improve the
				allocation of resources among Federal programs.</text>
								</paragraph>
              </section>
              <section id="H626F59337C614D00A8B47B119E8C8CD0">
                <enum>502.</enum>
                <header>Definitions</header>
                <text display-inline="no-display-inline">For purposes of this title:</text>
								<paragraph id="H3ECEA686CF4B4140879244CE8C198F03">
                  <enum>(1)</enum>
                  <text>The term
				<term>direct loan</term> means a disbursement of funds by the Government to a
				non-Federal borrower under a contract that requires the repayment of such funds
				with or without interest. The term includes the purchase of, or participation
				in, a loan made by another lender and financing arrangements that defer payment
				for more than 90 days, including the sale of a Government asset on credit
				terms. The term does not include the acquisition of a federally guaranteed loan
				in satisfaction of default claims or the price support loans of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1260">Commodity
				Credit Corporation</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
								</paragraph>
                <paragraph id="H332C64FC37C64E51A5309DBBA2034E42">
                  <enum>(2)</enum>
                  <text>The term
				<term>direct loan obligation</term> means a binding agreement by a Federal
				agency to make a direct loan when specified conditions are fulfilled by the
				borrower.</text>
								</paragraph>
                <paragraph id="H54976AC876664B38A3EDB10B7BE1251D">
                  <enum>(3)</enum>
                  <text>The term
				<term>loan guarantee</term> means any guarantee, insurance, or other pledge
				with respect to the payment of all or a part of the principal or interest on
				any debt obligation of a non-Federal borrower to a non-Federal lender, but does
				not include the insurance of deposits, shares, or other withdrawable accounts
				in financial institutions.</text>
								</paragraph>
                <paragraph id="H4B429143D2144149ADBCAC139102FC76">
                  <enum>(4)</enum>
                  <text>The term
				<term>loan guarantee commitment</term> means a binding agreement by a Federal
				agency to make a loan guarantee when specified conditions are fulfilled by the
				borrower, the lender, or any other party to the guarantee agreement.</text>
								</paragraph>
                <paragraph id="HC9020BC5F9804F4287C0401F3B488E60">
                  <enum>(5)</enum>
                  <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H4EDF25EAA431462E88CB404CF9A6B7A6">
                    <enum>(A)</enum>
                    <text>The term
				<term>cost</term> means the sum of the Treasury discounting component and the
				risk component of a direct loan or loan guarantee, or a modification
				thereof.</text>
									</subparagraph>
                  <subparagraph id="H4E85766B58E441F08A29E83EB850CA31" indent="up1">
                    <enum>(B)</enum>
                    <text>The Treasury discounting component
				shall be the estimated long-term cost to the Government of a direct loan or
				loan guarantee, or modification thereof, calculated on a net present value
				basis, excluding administrative costs and any incidental effects on
				governmental receipts or outlays.</text>
									</subparagraph>
                  <subparagraph id="H3E7E3D8D9A5847B19B519136EB4C91E5" indent="up1">
                    <enum>(C)</enum>
                    <text>The risk component shall be an amount
				equal to the difference between—</text>
										<clause id="H11D9A944D00A4D1EB32BB8D5A44E7E9B">
                      <enum>(i)</enum>
                      <text>the estimated long-term cost to the
				Government of a direct loan or loan guarantee, or modification thereof,
				estimated on a fair value basis, applying the guidelines set forth by the
				Financial Accounting Standards Board in Financial Accounting Standards #157, or
				a successor thereto, excluding administrative costs and any incidental effects
				on governmental receipts or outlays; and</text>
										</clause>
                    <clause id="HDBD720FC050247739B7F1958F345BF49">
                      <enum>(ii)</enum>
                      <text>the Treasury discounting component
				of such direct loan or loan guarantee, or modification thereof.</text>
										</clause>
                  </subparagraph>
                  <subparagraph id="H21067C70E8D1417A8E497EB34DEF8170" indent="up1">
                    <enum>(D)</enum>
                    <text>The Treasury discounting component of
				a direct loan shall be the net present value, at the time when the direct loan
				is disbursed, of the following estimated cash flows:</text>
										<clause id="HF245407AD9B74D1AB5ECDF9BB67822FE">
                      <enum>(i)</enum>
                      <text>Loan disbursements.</text>
										</clause>
                    <clause id="H41DF9F82BBCB4DAE9063DCCE031C0218">
                      <enum>(ii)</enum>
                      <text>Repayments of principal.</text>
										</clause>
                    <clause id="H82A5B4D0B8D64C9A91AF1EB47FCD49A9">
                      <enum>(iii)</enum>
                      <text>Essential preservation expenses,
				payments of interest and other payments by or to the Government over the life
				of the loan after adjusting for estimated defaults, prepayments, fees,
				penalties, and other recoveries, including the effects of changes in loan terms
				resulting from the exercise by the borrower of an option included in the loan
				contract.</text>
										</clause>
                  </subparagraph>
                  <subparagraph id="H1140E84FF0B74E33B119EC1B8C224601" indent="up1">
                    <enum>(E)</enum>
                    <text>The Treasury discounting component of
				a loan guarantee shall be the net present value, at the time when the
				guaranteed loan is disbursed, of the following estimated cash flows:</text>
										<clause id="H51E0D9F190314C79A388B7C07A07ABB6">
                      <enum>(i)</enum>
                      <text>Payments by the Government to cover
				defaults and delinquencies, interest subsidies, essential preservation
				expenses, or other payments.</text>
										</clause>
                    <clause id="H242677A5712A42DB990576471A5D078B">
                      <enum>(ii)</enum>
                      <text>Payments to the Government
				including origination and other fees, penalties, and recoveries, including the
				effects of changes in loan terms resulting from the exercise by the guaranteed
				lender of an option included in the loan guarantee contract, or by the borrower
				of an option included in the guaranteed loan contract.</text>
										</clause>
                  </subparagraph>
                  <subparagraph id="HEDB21B6C77674F668FFF58E2E3E49F2C" indent="up1">
                    <enum>(F)</enum>
                    <text>The cost of a modification is the sum
				of—</text>
										<clause id="HD2F40FCA6AAE4624BDB9BA49359CB5AE">
                      <enum>(i)</enum>
                      <text>the difference between the current
				estimate of the Treasury discounting component of the remaining cash flows
				under the terms of a direct loan or loan guarantee and the current estimate of
				the Treasury discounting component of the remaining cash flows under the terms
				of the contract, as modified; and</text>
										</clause>
                    <clause id="HAB8FF1B43DCE4D7382380E26C05D9070">
                      <enum>(ii)</enum>
                      <text>the difference between the current
				estimate of the risk component of the remaining cash flows under the terms of a
				direct loan or loan guarantee and the current estimate of the risk component of
				the remaining cash flows under the terms of the contract as modified.</text>
										</clause>
                  </subparagraph>
                  <subparagraph id="HDF54F2F408934FE0BDD026136412E709" indent="up1">
                    <enum>(G)</enum>
                    <text>In estimating Treasury discounting
				components, the discount rate shall be the average interest rate on marketable
				Treasury securities of similar duration to the cash flows of the direct loan or
				loan guarantee for which the estimate is being made.</text>
									</subparagraph>
                  <subparagraph id="H0593E88535FA4C018F960C239642BF1E" indent="up1">
                    <enum>(H)</enum>
                    <text>When funds are obligated for a direct
				loan or loan guarantee, the estimated cost shall be based on the current
				assumptions, adjusted to incorporate the terms of the loan contract, for the
				fiscal year in which the funds are obligated.</text>
									</subparagraph>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="HD509F679041B41E485DA342362AB5B49">
                  <enum>(6)</enum>
                  <text>The term
				<term>program account</term> means the budget account into which an
				appropriation to cover the cost of a direct loan or loan guarantee program is
				made and from which such cost is disbursed to the financing account.</text>
								</paragraph>
                <paragraph id="H4F2D47CDCD1B43DB87E838CF981FA103">
                  <enum>(7)</enum>
                  <text>The term
				<term>financing account</term> means the nonbudget account or accounts
				associated with each program account which holds balances, receives the cost
				payment from the program account, and also includes all other cash flows to and
				from the Government resulting from direct loan obligations or loan guarantee
				commitments made on or after October 1, 1991.</text>
								</paragraph>
                <paragraph id="H61C244D84FA24331B91EC39B773DA6C7">
                  <enum>(8)</enum>
                  <text>The term
				<term>liquidating account</term> means the budget account that includes all
				cash flows to and from the Government resulting from direct loan obligations or
				loan guarantee commitments made prior to October 1, 1991. These accounts shall
				be shown in the budget on a cash basis.</text>
								</paragraph>
                <paragraph id="H4A03F680766A4B3CB48414869646AF9A">
                  <enum>(9)</enum>
                  <text>The term
				<term>modification</term> means any Government action that alters the estimated
				cost of an outstanding direct loan (or direct loan obligation) or an
				outstanding loan guarantee (or loan guarantee commitment) from the current
				estimate of cash flows. This includes the sale of loan assets, with or without
				recourse, and the purchase of guaranteed loans (or direct loan obligations) or
				loan guarantees (or loan guarantee commitments) such as a change in collection
				procedures.</text>
								</paragraph>
                <paragraph id="HFE69DD67118345AE963B5219D20E32B4">
                  <enum>(10)</enum>
                  <text>The term
				<term>current</term> has the same meaning as in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985/s:250/ss:c/p:9">section 250(c)(9) of the
				Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
								</paragraph>
                <paragraph id="HBF9282427E93465CB00629037A2020B8">
                  <enum>(11)</enum>
                  <text>The term
				<term>Director</term> means the Director of the Office of Management and
				Budget.</text>
								</paragraph>
                <paragraph id="HD57798D9F5464AB59E32918C6D559F1E">
                  <enum>(12)</enum>
                  <text>The term
				<term>administrative costs</term> means costs related to program management
				activities, but does not include essential preservation expenses.</text>
								</paragraph>
                <paragraph id="HE09F525F09164A3FB9C138F58B244705">
                  <enum>(13)</enum>
                  <text>The term
				<term>essential preservation expenses</term> means servicing and other costs
				that are essential to preserve the value of loan assets or collateral.</text>
								</paragraph>
              </section>
              <section id="HE099B56BD9A6405E9C31E6684AA7BB44">
                <enum>503.</enum>
                <header>OMB and CBO
				analysis, coordination, and review</header>
								<subsection id="H6C4DC7199EF141A2905B5199CDE3F85F">
                  <enum>(a)</enum>
                  <header>In
				general</header>
                  <text>For the executive branch, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1103">Director</cato:entity-ref> shall be
				responsible for coordinating the estimates required by this title. The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1103">Director</cato:entity-ref>
				shall consult with the agencies that administer direct loan or loan guarantee
				programs.</text>
								</subsection>
                <subsection id="H3B6F2CDF40514E0FB4FD0A1CED342908">
                  <enum>(b)</enum>
                  <header>Delegation</header>
                  <text>The
				<cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1103">Director</cato:entity-ref> may delegate to agencies authority to make estimates of costs. The
				delegation of authority shall be based upon written guidelines, regulations, or
				criteria consistent with the definitions in this title.</text>
								</subsection>
                <subsection id="HD57C6D895A0D4E49A45A22012CFCC42F">
                  <enum>(c)</enum>
                  <header>Coordination
				with the Congressional Budget Office</header>
                  <text>In developing estimation
				guidelines, regulations, or criteria to be used by Federal agencies, the
				<cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1103">Director</cato:entity-ref> shall consult with the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0800">Director of the Congressional Budget
				Office</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
								</subsection>
                <subsection id="HAE5152A8E9F740588FCE3672805A97FD">
                  <enum>(d)</enum>
                  <header>Improving cost
				estimates</header>
                  <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1103">Director</cato:entity-ref> and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0800">Director of the Congressional
				Budget Office</cato:entity-ref> shall coordinate the development of more accurate data on
				historical performance and prospective risk of direct loan and loan guarantee
				programs. They shall annually review the performance of outstanding direct
				loans and loan guarantees to improve estimates of costs. The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1103">Office of
				Management and Budget</cato:entity-ref> and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0800">Congressional Budget Office</cato:entity-ref> shall have access to
				all agency data that may facilitate the development and improvement of
				estimates of costs.</text>
								</subsection>
                <subsection id="H3F1C4DC507634188BF74017B929C64C3">
                  <enum>(e)</enum>
                  <header>Historical
				credit programs costs</header>
                  <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1103">Director</cato:entity-ref> shall review, to the extent
				possible, historical data and develop the best possible estimates of
				adjustments that would convert aggregate historical budget data to credit
				reform accounting.</text>
								</subsection>
              </section>
              <section id="H8AEA5C89126549EEAB19BD8C5FFFC3C3">
                <enum>504.</enum>
                <header>Budgetary
				treatment</header>
								<subsection id="H010C6453C4394172926D0EA058CF6C86">
                  <enum>(a)</enum>
                  <header>President’s
				budget</header>
                  <text>Beginning with fiscal year 1992, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President’s</cato:entity-ref> budget
				shall reflect the Treasury discounting component of direct loan and loan
				guarantee programs. Beginning with fiscal year 2015, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President’s</cato:entity-ref> budget
				shall reflect the costs of direct loan and loan guarantee programs. The budget
				shall also include the planned level of new direct loan obligations or loan
				guarantee commitments associated with each appropriations request.</text>
								</subsection>
                <subsection id="H74E2349B079B4FE1966E869C026B7338">
                  <enum>(b)</enum>
                  <header>Appropriations
				required</header>
                  <text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, new direct
				loan obligations may be incurred and new loan guarantee commitments may be made
				for fiscal year 1992 and thereafter only to the extent that—</text>
									<paragraph id="H8CCF47534F7A43A5A6AD766C24FE9E49">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
                    <text>new budget
				authority to cover their costs is provided in advance in an appropriation
				Act;</text>
									</paragraph>
                  <paragraph id="HC5E49F1737AD45DF97778F25ECE89337">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
                    <text>a limitation on
				the use of funds otherwise available for the cost of a direct loan or loan
				guarantee program has been provided in advance in an appropriation Act;
				or</text>
									</paragraph>
                  <paragraph id="H083E8FB0ACF94C8F85587AE73A6756A4">
                    <enum>(3)</enum>
                    <text>authority is
				otherwise provided in appropriation Acts.</text>
									</paragraph>
                </subsection>
                <subsection id="HFD171569614F4F39A9A3D4FC3A3B459B">
                  <enum>(c)</enum>
                  <header>Exemption for
				direct spending programs</header>
                  <text>
                    <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Congressional Budget Act of 1974/s:504/ss:b" proposed="true">Subsections (b)</cato:entity-ref> and <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Congressional Budget Act of 1974/s:504/ss:e" proposed="true">(e)</cato:entity-ref> shall not apply
				to—</text>
									<paragraph id="H542F61A5A7F94FAEBE0E920B7B6462F2">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
                    <text>any direct loan or
				loan guarantee program that constitutes an entitlement (such as the guaranteed
				student loan program or the veteran’s home loan guaranty program);</text>
									</paragraph>
                  <paragraph id="H295B213538364DD09585F6C2AF9A4B6D">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
                    <text>the credit
				programs of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1260">Commodity Credit Corporation</cato:entity-ref> existing on the date of enactment
				of this title; or</text>
									</paragraph>
                  <paragraph id="H649572449D294611AA9A56A6DEC3A46C">
                    <enum>(3)</enum>
                    <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any direct loan (or direct loan obligation)
				or loan guarantee (or loan guarantee commitment) made by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="8681">Federal National
				Mortgage Association</cato:entity-ref> or the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="8683">Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
									</paragraph>
                </subsection>
                <subsection id="HEA13CBA9FEF64077A651394C3A3D9503">
                  <enum>(d)</enum>
                  <header>Budget
				accounting</header>
									<paragraph id="H204048825F37417B8B021B432CBD72E4">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
                    <text>The authority to
				incur new direct loan obligations, make new loan guarantee commitments, or
				modify outstanding direct loans (or direct loan obligations) or loan guarantees
				(or loan guarantee commitments) shall constitute new budget authority in an
				amount equal to the cost of the direct loan or loan guarantee in the fiscal
				year in which definite authority becomes available or indefinite authority is
				used. Such budget authority shall constitute an obligation of the program
				account to pay to the financing account.</text>
									</paragraph>
                  <paragraph id="H10749FA12EBC4ABCB5A0BF75EE5312AE">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
                    <text>The outlays
				resulting from new budget authority for the cost of direct loans or loan
				guarantees described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Congressional Budget Act of 1974/s:504/ss:d/p:1" proposed="true">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref> shall be paid from the program account
				into the financing account and recorded in the fiscal year in which the direct
				loan or the guaranteed loan is disbursed or its costs altered.</text>
									</paragraph>
                  <paragraph id="H9DBBC237F895421D8ACAD6C34246A274">
                    <enum>(3)</enum>
                    <text>All collections
				and payments of the financing accounts shall be a means of financing.</text>
									</paragraph>
                </subsection>
                <subsection id="HEF27AF974E9A455EA6C881DCB74B46E0">
                  <enum>(e)</enum>
                  <header>Modifications</header>
                  <text>An
				outstanding direct loan (or direct loan obligation) or loan guarantee (or loan
				guarantee commitment) shall not be modified in a manner that increases its
				costs unless budget authority for the additional cost has been provided in
				advance in an appropriation Act.</text>
								</subsection>
                <subsection id="H1E9822704C944291885A1871C227D340">
                  <enum>(f)</enum>
                  <header>Reestimates</header>
                  <text>When
				the estimated cost for a group of direct loans or loan guarantees for a given
				program made in a single fiscal year is re-estimated in a subsequent year, the
				difference between the reestimated cost and the previous cost estimate shall be
				displayed as a distinct and separately identified subaccount in the program
				account as a change in program costs and a change in net interest. There is
				hereby provided permanent indefinite authority for these re-estimates.</text>
								</subsection>
                <subsection id="HFCF7B1C54F034BDF88D5C7ABBD59244A">
                  <enum>(g)</enum>
                  <header>Administrative
				expenses</header>
                  <text>All funding for an agency’s administrative costs
				associated with a direct loan or loan guarantee program shall be displayed as
				distinct and separately identified subaccounts within the same budget account
				as the program’s cost.</text>
								</subsection>
              </section>
              <section id="H80F4ADCC1E2C443B83A1F0C974072B94">
                <enum>505.</enum>
                <header>Authorizations</header>
								<subsection id="H2903E6EEA0CE41598478E9F83AFF0BF2">
                  <enum>(a)</enum>
                  <header>Authorization
				for financing accounts</header>
                  <text>In order to implement the accounting
				required by this title, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> is authorized to establish such
				non-budgetary accounts as may be appropriate.</text>
								</subsection>
                <subsection id="HA6406F76F3E2452A974C20E295972C06">
                  <enum>(b)</enum>
                  <header>Treasury
				transactions with the financing accounts</header>
									<paragraph id="HA44A81654F0A41899FDAAC2F3F61C869">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
                    <header>In
				general</header>
                    <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary of the Treasury</cato:entity-ref> shall borrow from, receive
				from, lend to, or pay to the financing accounts such amounts as may be
				appropriate. The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary of the Treasury</cato:entity-ref> may prescribe forms and
				denominations, maturities, and terms and conditions for the transactions
				described in the preceding sentence, except that the rate of interest charged
				by the Secretary on lending to financing accounts (including amounts treated as
				lending to financing accounts by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2061">Federal Financing Bank</cato:entity-ref> (hereinafter in
				this subsection referred to as the <term>Bank</term>) pursuant to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Congressional Budget Act of 1974/s:405/ss:b">section
				405(b)</cato:entity-ref>) and the rate of interest paid to financing accounts on uninvested
				balances in financing accounts shall be the same as the rate determined
				pursuant to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Congressional Budget Act of 1974/s:502/p:5/sp:G">section 502(5)(G)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
									</paragraph>
                  <paragraph id="H7CB29257825E4A73A1E7BBBD1E059391">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
                    <header>Loans</header>
                    <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For guaranteed loans financed by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2061">Bank</cato:entity-ref>
				and treated as direct loans by a Federal agency pursuant to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Congressional Budget Act of 1974/s:406/ss:b/p:1">section 406(b)(1)</cato:entity-ref>,
				any fee or interest surcharge (the amount by which the interest rate charged
				exceeds the rate determined pursuant to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Congressional Budget Act of 1974/s:502/p:5/sp:G">section 502(5)(G)</cato:entity-ref> that the Bank charges
				to a private borrower pursuant to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Federal Financing Bank Act of 1973/s:6/ss:c">section 6(c) of the Federal Financing Bank
				Act of 1973</cato:entity-ref> shall be considered a cash flow to the Government for the purposes
				of determining the cost of the direct loan pursuant to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Congressional Budget Act of 1974/s:502/p:5" proposed="true">section 502(5)</cato:entity-ref>. All such
				amounts shall be credited to the appropriate financing account.</text>
									</paragraph>
                  <paragraph id="H5C8299C0ED3040EDAD337B72BFC05F62">
                    <enum>(3)</enum>
                    <header>Reimbursement</header>
                    <text>The
				Bank is authorized to require reimbursement from a Federal agency to cover the
				administrative expenses of the Bank that are attributable to the direct loans
				financed for that agency. All such payments by an agency shall be considered
				administrative expenses subject to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Congressional Budget Act of 1990/s:504/ss:g" proposed="true">section 504(g)</cato:entity-ref>. This subsection shall apply
				to transactions related to direct loan obligations or loan guarantee
				commitments made on or after October 1, 1991.</text>
									</paragraph>
                  <paragraph id="HEB5B46CA28994D60AEFF38D3D8CB91A7">
                    <enum>(4)</enum>
                    <header>Authority</header>
                    <text>The
				authorities provided in this subsection shall not be construed to supersede or
				override the authority of the head of a Federal agency to administer and
				operate a direct loan or loan guarantee program.</text>
									</paragraph>
                  <paragraph id="HE231351B41EC403BA7F2A6B0F3185723">
                    <enum>(5)</enum>
                    <header>Title
				31</header>
                    <text>All of the transactions provided in the subsection shall be
				subject to the provisions of <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc-chapter/31/15/II">subchapter II of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/31/15">chapter 15</external-xref> of title 31, United
				States Code</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
									</paragraph>
                  <paragraph id="HF3DA270858BF4C4FB594C81C86A94802">
                    <enum>(6)</enum>
                    <header>Treatment of
				cash balances</header>
                    <text>Cash balances of the financing accounts in excess
				of current requirements shall be maintained in a form of uninvested funds and
				the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary of the Treasury</cato:entity-ref> shall pay interest on these funds. The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary
				of the Treasury</cato:entity-ref> shall charge (or pay if the amount is negative) financing
				accounts an amount equal to the risk component for a direct loan or loan
				guarantee, or modification thereof. Such amount received by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary of
				the Treasury</cato:entity-ref> shall be a means of financing and shall not be considered a cash
				flow of the Government for the purposes of <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Congressional Budget Act of 1974/s:502/p:5" proposed="true">section 502(5)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
									</paragraph>
                </subsection>
                <subsection id="H939B5CA5EA0E46EEA01DF88E79255150">
                  <enum>(c)</enum>
                  <header>Authorization
				for liquidating accounts</header>
                  <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H9605CD3B8490474AAAF960C76283DA2B">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
                    <text>Amounts in liquidating
				accounts shall be available only for payments resulting from direct loan
				obligations or loan guarantee commitments made prior to October 1, 1991,
				for—</text>
										<subparagraph id="H6567E76490E443CCB5F6C4F1078A9107" indent="up1">
                      <enum>(A)</enum>
                      <text>interest payments and principal
				repayments to the Treasury or the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2061">Federal Financing Bank</cato:entity-ref> for amounts
				borrowed;</text>
										</subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="HCAF7C7022D9F4454B2D1F4D2EAA7C2A7" indent="up1">
                      <enum>(B)</enum>
                      <text>disbursements of loans;</text>
										</subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="H3190DF586584441D94DFD06D7DAA9A88" indent="up1">
                      <enum>(C)</enum>
                      <text>default and other guarantee claim
				payments;</text>
										</subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="H44BE6389ECC743158FE99DD50DBE3DD4" indent="up1">
                      <enum>(D)</enum>
                      <text>interest supplement payments;</text>
										</subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="HC13A7CF18A684A63A27B1757188A7211" indent="up1">
                      <enum>(E)</enum>
                      <text>payments for the costs of foreclosing,
				managing, and selling collateral that are capitalized or routinely deducted
				from the proceeds of sales;</text>
										</subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="H57B4EF254E174F66B323070690DD3F67" indent="up1">
                      <enum>(F)</enum>
                      <text>payments to financing accounts when
				required for modifications;</text>
										</subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="H4009E4BEB9D643EBA655CABFD7FA1302" indent="up1">
                      <enum>(G)</enum>
                      <text>administrative costs and essential
				preservation expenses, if—</text>
											<clause id="H8ED9E72644C4431F95B1FBEC4852159F">
                        <enum>(i)</enum>
                        <text>amounts credited to the liquidating
				account would have been available for administrative costs and essential
				preservation expenses under a provision of law in effect prior to October 1,
				1991; and</text>
											</clause>
                      <clause id="H92931C70936D447581AB1BD90C412CCA">
                        <enum>(ii)</enum>
                        <text>no direct loan obligation or loan
				guarantee commitment has been made, or any modification of a direct loan or
				loan guarantee has been made, since September 30, 1991; or</text>
											</clause>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="HA7CE264A2E2E4F7EBBB85E000251E078" indent="up1">
                      <enum>(H)</enum>
                      <text>such other payments as are necessary
				for the liquidation of such direct loan obligations and loan guarantee
				commitments.</text>
										</subparagraph>
                  </paragraph>
                  <paragraph id="H26FED22068614FC7B5F5F605B6DE8C4E" indent="up1">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
                    <text>Amounts credited to liquidating
				accounts in any year shall be available only for payments required in that
				year. Any unobligated balances in liquidating accounts at the end of a fiscal
				year shall be transferred to miscellaneous receipts as soon as practicable
				after the end of the fiscal year.</text>
									</paragraph>
                  <paragraph id="H0545C109103A4F7182DE0780401207BD" indent="up1">
                    <enum>(3)</enum>
                    <text>If funds in liquidating accounts are
				insufficient to satisfy obligations and commitments of such accounts, there is
				hereby provided permanent, indefinite authority to make any payments required
				to be made on such obligations and commitments.</text>
									</paragraph>
                </subsection>
                <subsection id="HB10D2AE8780B4A3AA9B6940BF4386E98">
                  <enum>(d)</enum>
                  <header>Reinsurance</header>
                  <text>Nothing
				in this title shall be construed as authorizing or requiring the purchase of
				insurance or reinsurance on a direct loan or loan guarantee from private
				insurers. If any such reinsurance for a direct loan or loan guarantee is
				authorized, the cost of such insurance and any recoveries to the Government
				shall be included in the calculation of the cost.</text>
								</subsection>
                <subsection id="H046ED74358124448A6A3775DBEF96404">
                  <enum>(e)</enum>
                  <header>Eligibility and
				assistance</header>
                  <text>Nothing in this title shall be construed to change the
				authority or the responsibility of a Federal agency to determine the terms and
				conditions of eligibility for, or the amount of assistance provided by a direct
				loan or a loan guarantee.</text>
								</subsection>
              </section>
              <section id="H332D696860104C36AF9310A129037AEB">
                <enum>506.</enum>
                <header>Treatment of
				deposit insurance and agencies and other insurance programs</header>
                <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This title shall not apply to the credit or
				insurance activities of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="5100">Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation</cato:entity-ref>, <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2500">National
				Credit Union Administration</cato:entity-ref>, Resolution Trust Corporation, <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1665">Pension Benefit
				Guaranty Corporation</cato:entity-ref>, National Flood Insurance, National Insurance Development
				Fund, <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1263">Crop Insurance</cato:entity-ref>, or <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="6400">Tennessee Valley Authority</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
							</section>
              <section id="H8D0E5C29AC7F4E36B93AEB31AAE27A47">
                <enum>507.</enum>
                <header>Effect on other
				laws</header>
								<subsection id="H74B921C676F741EC84DD9669C2FF415D">
                  <enum>(a)</enum>
                  <header>Effect on other
				laws</header>
                  <text>This title shall supersede, modify, or repeal any provision
				of law enacted prior to the date of enactment of this title to the extent such
				provision is inconsistent with this title. Nothing in this title shall be
				construed to establish a credit limitation on any Federal loan or loan
				guarantee program.</text>
								</subsection>
                <subsection id="H325440A1F04F484D9ADDF59D5A14261A">
                  <enum>(b)</enum>
                  <header>Crediting of
				collections</header>
                  <text>Collections resulting from direct loans obligated or
				loan guarantees committed prior to October 1, 1991, shall be credited to the
				liquidating accounts of Federal agencies. Amounts so credited shall be
				available, to the same extent that they were available prior to the date of
				enactment of this title, to liquidate obligations arising from such direct
				loans obligated or loan guarantees committed prior to October 1, 1991,
				including repayment of any obligations held by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary of the Treasury</cato:entity-ref> or
				the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2061">Federal Financing Bank</cato:entity-ref>. The unobligated balances of such accounts that are
				in excess of current needs shall be transferred to the general fund of the
				Treasury. Such transfers shall be made from time to time but, at least once
				each
				year.</text>
								</subsection>
              </section>
            </title>
            <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
          </quoted-block>
				</subsection>
        <subsection id="H365986E1A8F1498EB98DD09F95DEEA6E">
          <enum>(b)</enum>
          <header>Conforming
			 amendment</header>
          <text>The table of contents set forth in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Congressional Budget and Impoundment Control Act of 1974/s:1/ss:b">section 1(b) of the
			 Congressional Budget and Impoundment Control Act of 1974</cato:entity-ref> is amended by striking
			 the items relating to title V and inserting the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFD7CA657A9EC4C7DA8AD718496BF7913" style="OLC">
						<toc regeneration="yes-regeneration">
							<toc-entry idref="HB25F95EA0B124395AAF73E11FD53CC10" level="title">Title V—Fair Value</toc-entry>
							<toc-entry idref="HD106482FE8F24B7EA131C59A59EBD835" level="section">Sec. 501. Purposes.</toc-entry>
							<toc-entry idref="H626F59337C614D00A8B47B119E8C8CD0" level="section">Sec. 502. Definitions.</toc-entry>
							<toc-entry idref="HE099B56BD9A6405E9C31E6684AA7BB44" level="section">Sec. 503. OMB and CBO analysis, coordination, and
				review.</toc-entry>
							<toc-entry idref="H8AEA5C89126549EEAB19BD8C5FFFC3C3" level="section">Sec. 504. Budgetary treatment.</toc-entry>
							<toc-entry idref="H80F4ADCC1E2C443B83A1F0C974072B94" level="section">Sec. 505. Authorizations.</toc-entry>
							<toc-entry idref="H332D696860104C36AF9310A129037AEB" level="section">Sec. 506. Treatment of deposit insurance and agencies and other
				insurance programs.</toc-entry>
							<toc-entry idref="H8D0E5C29AC7F4E36B93AEB31AAE27A47" level="section">Sec. 507. Effect on other
				laws.</toc-entry>
						</toc>
						<after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
          </quoted-block>
				</subsection>
      </section>
      <section commented="no" id="HEF688824169B42D992B0229521B8F7D9">
        <enum>102.</enum>
        <header>Effective
			 date</header>
        <text display-inline="no-display-inline">The amendment made by
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Budget and Accounting Transparency Act of 2013/s:101" proposed="true">section 101</cato:entity-ref> shall take effect beginning with fiscal year 2015.</text>
			</section>
      <section id="HFF0C252ED0C644BAA45E8869FDA123EC">
        <enum>103.</enum>
        <header>Budgetary
			 adjustment</header>
				<subsection id="HC7C4296EB45F4F9D931C22BE85566DC1">
          <enum>(a)</enum>
          <header>In
			 general</header>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">
            <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985/s:251/ss:b/p:1">Section 251(b)(1) of
			 the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985</cato:entity-ref> is amended by
			 adding at the end the following new sentence: <quote>A change in discretionary
			 spending solely as a result of the amendment to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Congressional Budget Act of 1974/t:V">title V of the Congressional
			 Budget Act of 1974</cato:entity-ref> made by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Budget and Accounting Transparency Act of 2013" proposed="true">Budget and Accounting Transparency Act of 2013</cato:entity-ref>
			 shall be treated as a change of concept under this paragraph.</quote>.</text>
				</subsection>
        <subsection id="H017E6B339B4249909F44CD849741AAFE">
          <enum>(b)</enum>
          <header>Report</header>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Before adjusting the discretionary caps
			 pursuant to the authority provided in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Budget and Accounting Transparency Act of 2013/s:103/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1103">Office of Management
			 and Budget</cato:entity-ref> shall report to the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="committee" entity-id="HBU00">Committees on the Budget of the House of
			 Representatives</cato:entity-ref> and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="committee" entity-id="SSBU00">Senate</cato:entity-ref> on the amount of that adjustment, the
			 methodology used in determining the size of that adjustment, and a
			 program-by-program itemization of the components of that adjustment.</text>
				</subsection>
        <subsection id="H9AEEDA4CD17645C4B371B8606AE1C8E6">
          <enum>(c)</enum>
          <header>Schedule</header>
          <text>The
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1103">Office of Management and Budget</cato:entity-ref> shall not make an adjustment pursuant to the
			 authority provided in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Budget and Accounting Transparency Act of 2013/s:103/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref> sooner than 60 days after providing the
			 report required in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Budget and Accounting Transparency Act of 2013/s:103/ss:b" proposed="true">subsection (b)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
				</subsection>
      </section>
    </title>
    <title commented="no" id="H1E287136C47D47D19029907274C31BC1">
      <enum>II</enum>
      <header>Budgetary
			 treatment</header>
			<section commented="no" id="HC4DCCEEC76AF4D189A4C4B97B7D40B45">
        <enum>201.</enum>
        <header>CBO and OMB
			 studies respecting budgeting for costs of Federal insurance
			 programs</header>
        <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 1 year
			 after the date of enactment of this Act, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0800">Directors of the Congressional
			 Budget Office</cato:entity-ref> and of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1103">Office of Management and Budget</cato:entity-ref> shall each prepare a
			 study and make recommendations to the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="committee" entity-id="HBU00">Committees on the Budget of the House of
			 Representatives</cato:entity-ref> and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="committee" entity-id="SSBU00">Senate</cato:entity-ref> as to the feasability of applying fair value
			 concepts to budgeting for the costs of Federal insurance programs.</text>
			</section>
      <section commented="no" id="H45407E70594340F5BD7297E2278CCB7A" section-type="subsequent-section">
        <enum>202.</enum>
        <header>On-budget status of
			 Fannie Mae and Freddie Mac</header>
        <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law,
			 the receipts and disbursements, including the administrative expenses, of the
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="8681">Federal National Mortgage Association</cato:entity-ref> and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="8683">Federal Home Loan Mortgage
			 Corporation</cato:entity-ref> shall be counted as new budget authority, outlays, receipts, or
			 deficit or surplus for purposes of—</text>
				<paragraph commented="no" id="HA920C7EA8A3649F8B717552FB2971C64">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>the budget of the
			 United States Government as submitted by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref>;</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph commented="no" id="H1B680B9F722B45A3870D5258B905605A">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>the congressional
			 budget; and</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph commented="no" id="H793626427DA2420180DF5C3F4023F8A4">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <text>the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985">Balanced
			 Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
				</paragraph>
      </section>
      <section commented="no" id="HDAEAA7DC28E44298A566B6487E4DCA23">
        <enum>203.</enum>
        <header>Effective
			 date</header>
        <text display-inline="no-display-inline">
          <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Budget and Accounting Transparency Act of 2013/s:202" proposed="true">Section 202</cato:entity-ref> shall not
			 apply with respect to an enterprise (as such term is defined in <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Federal Housing Enterprises Financial Safety and Soundness Act of 1992/s:1303">section 1303 of
			 the Federal Housing Enterprises Financial Safety and Soundness Act of 1992</cato:entity-ref> (<cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/12/4502">12
			 U.S.C. 4502</cato:entity-ref>)</cato:entity>) after the date that all of the following have occurred:</text>
				<paragraph commented="no" id="H8D59B7D7E5AD40B69B885895E9801E33">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>The
			 conservatorship for such enterprise under <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Federal Housing Enterprises Financial Safety and Soundness Act of 1992/s:1367">section 1367 of such Act</cato:entity-ref> (<cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/12/4617">12 U.S.C.
			 4617</cato:entity-ref>)</cato:entity> has been terminated.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph commented="no" id="H4CC6216E70774295B89ACAD746492479">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="9540">Director of the Federal Housing Finance
			 Agency</cato:entity-ref> has certified in writing that such enterprise has repaid to the Federal
			 Government the maximum amount consistent with minimizing total cost to the
			 Federal Government of the financial assistance provided to the enterprise by
			 the Federal Government pursuant to the amendments made by <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Housing and Economic Recovery Act of 2008/s:1117">section 1117 of the
			 Housing and Economic Recovery Act of 2008</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/110/289">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="public-law" value="public-law/110/289">Public Law 110–289</cato:entity-ref>
              </external-xref>; <cato:entity-ref entity-type="statute-at-large" value="statute-at-large/122/2683">122 Stat. 2683</cato:entity-ref>)</cato:entity>
			 or otherwise.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph commented="no" id="H89A972C3EB59485C9B1B3B00D2494CC3">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <text>The charter for
			 the enterprise has been revoked, annulled, or terminated and the authorizing
			 statute (as such term is defined in such <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Federal Housing Enterprises Financial Safety and Soundness Act of 1992/s:1303">section 1303</cato:entity-ref>) with respect to the
			 enterprise has been repealed.</text>
				</paragraph>
      </section>
    </title>
    <title id="H6D765FF0E43844AE8E103231B4E77FB5">
      <enum>III</enum>
      <header>Budget review
			 and analysis</header>
			<section commented="no" id="HBA948A9EA1ED4A03B29B59C5A5D6B7FF">
        <enum>301.</enum>
        <header>CBO and OMB
			 review and recommendations respecting receipts and collections</header>
        <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of
			 enactment of this Act, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1103">Director of the Office of Management and Budget</cato:entity-ref>
			 shall prepare a study of the history of offsetting collections against
			 expenditures and the amount of receipts collected annually, the historical
			 application of the budgetary terms <quote>revenue</quote>, <quote>offsetting
			 collections</quote>, and <quote>offsetting receipts</quote>, and review the
			 application of those terms and make recommendations to the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="committee" entity-id="HBU00">Committees on the
			 Budget of the House of Representatives</cato:entity-ref> and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="committee" entity-id="SSBU00">Senate</cato:entity-ref> of whether such usage
			 should be continued or modified. The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0800">Director of the Congressional Budget
			 Office</cato:entity-ref> shall review the history and recommendations prepared by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1103">Director of
			 the Office of Management and Budget</cato:entity-ref> and shall submit comments and
			 recommendations to such Committees.</text>
			</section>
      <section commented="no" id="H46D6C51B354647748076471534B910A6">
        <enum>302.</enum>
        <header>Agency budget
			 justifications</header>
        <text display-inline="no-display-inline">
          <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc/31/1108">Section 1108 of
			 title 31, United States Code</cato:entity-ref>, is amended by inserting at the end the following
			 new subsection:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE0BD053D38E745C6AA5817D596993C5B" style="USC">
					<subsection id="HF0211446ADCD428791C85E212833BD4C">
            <enum>(h)</enum>
            <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H17BA7FAA1FC44121946A1203E6DC5F03">
              <enum>(1)</enum>
              <text>Whenever any agency
				prepares and submits written budget justification materials for any committee
				of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0050">House of Representatives</cato:entity-ref> or the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0010">Senate</cato:entity-ref>, such agency shall post such
				budget justification on the same day of such submission on the
				<term>open</term> page of the public website of the agency, and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1103">Office of
				Management and Budget</cato:entity-ref> shall post such budget justification in a centralized
				location on its website, in the format developed under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc/31/1108/h/2" proposed="true">paragraph (2)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
						</paragraph>
            <paragraph id="H1FEAE17605D44B29BD0A39FEBF87AAEC" indent="up1">
              <enum>(2)</enum>
              <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1103">Office of Management and Budget</cato:entity-ref>, in
				consultation with the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0800">Congressional Budget Office</cato:entity-ref> and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0500">Government
				Accountability Office</cato:entity-ref>, shall develop and notify each agency of the format in
				which to post a budget justification under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc/31/1108/h/1" proposed="true">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref>. Such format shall be
				designed to ensure that posted budget justifications for all agencies—</text>
							<subparagraph id="HF40F13DB33C943148A5A7038C125D37E">
                <enum>(A)</enum>
                <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">are searchable, sortable, and downloadable
				by the public;</text>
							</subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="HA9234193D2934910B9BE6E7F24F70553">
                <enum>(B)</enum>
                <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">are consistent with generally accepted
				standards and practices for machine-discoverability;</text>
							</subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="H338B993F0FFD4489B94B604504E98F38">
                <enum>(C)</enum>
                <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">are organized uniformly, in a logical
				manner that makes clear the contents of a budget justification and
				relationships between data elements within the budget justification and among
				similar documents; and</text>
							</subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="H0CB135AF62934E988AAC819949760BD5">
                <enum>(D)</enum>
                <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">use uniform identifiers, including for
				agencies, bureaus, programs, and
				projects.</text>
							</subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
        </quoted-block>
			</section>
    </title>
  </legis-body>
</bill>
</doc>