<doc>
  <docmeta id="113hres502ih">
    <bill congress="113" type="hres" number="502" version="ih"/>
    <revision size="3996" annotations="0" status="complete" id="4" commit-time="2014-07-30T18:54:53Z" committer="zwilliams" doc="113hres502ih/4.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <resolution xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" dms-id="HB67AF4F03C424D13BA137928DA89953F" key="H" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print">
	<metadata>
<dublinCore>
<dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">113 HRES 502 IH: Congratulating the Minority Business Development Agency on its 45th anniversary and commending its achievements in fostering the establishment and growth of minority businesses in the United States.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">2014-03-05</dc:date>
<dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">113th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session display="yes">2d Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. RES. 502</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20140305">March 5, 2014</action-date>
			<action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="R000515">Mr. Rush</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HSM00">Small Business</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">Congratulating the Minority Business Development Agency on its 45th anniversary and commending its
			 achievements in fostering the establishment and growth of minority
			 businesses in the United States.</official-title>
	</form>
	<preamble>
		<whereas>
      <text>Whereas the success of minority businesses is a critical component of a robust economy in the
			 United States;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas minority businesses employ 5,800,000 people and generate $1 trillion to the economy of the
			 United States;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas minority businesses are supporting the global competitiveness of the United States by
			 utilizing the most effective export capabilities of any segment of the
			 United States economy;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas minority businesses are more likely to generate revenue through exports compared to
			 non-minority businesses due to language capabilities, cultural competence,
			 ancestral ties, and business agility;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas, in 1969, there were 322,000 minority businesses with $11,000,000,000 in gross receipts and
			 the number of minority businesses has continued to increase to nearly
			 6,000,000 as estimated by the <cato:entity-ref entity-id="1323" entity-type="federal-body">United States Census Bureau</cato:entity-ref>;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the <cato:entity-ref entity-id="1352" entity-type="federal-body">Minority Business Development Agency</cato:entity-ref> was established by Executive Order 11458 on March
			 5, 1969;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the <cato:entity-ref entity-id="1352" entity-type="federal-body">Minority Business Development Agency</cato:entity-ref> has operated for 45 years as the only Federal
			 agency created specifically to serve and foster the growth of minority
			 entrepreneurs;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the <cato:entity-ref entity-id="1352" entity-type="federal-body">Minority Business Development Agency</cato:entity-ref> operates a nationwide network of MBDA Business
			 Centers to assist with the expansion and competitiveness of the rapidly
			 growing minority business community;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas, in fiscal year 2013, the <cato:entity-ref entity-id="1352" entity-type="federal-body">Minority Business Development Agency</cato:entity-ref> helped minority businesses
			 gain access to over $4,800,000,000 in contracts and capital, which
			 contributed in excess of 25,000 American jobs created or retained;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas, since 1969, the <cato:entity-ref entity-id="1352" entity-type="federal-body">Minority Business Development Agency</cato:entity-ref> has served nearly 660,000 minority
			 businesses and assisted in securing more than $25,000,000,000 in contracts
			 and capital for these minority businesses; and</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the long-term strategic direction of the <cato:entity-ref entity-id="1352" entity-type="federal-body">Minority Business Development Agency</cato:entity-ref> is to achieve
			 entrepreneurial parity so that the number of businesses that are minority
			 businesses is proportional to the minority population: Now, therefore, be
			 it</text>
    </whereas>
  </preamble>
	<resolution-body id="H61DFB17702C44FB99CDA638F0D51BA73" style="traditional">
		<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HDB76FF82504F45869511CE2EA9141AB2" section-type="undesignated-section">
      <enum/>
      <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the <cato:entity-ref entity-id="0050" entity-type="federal-body">House of Representatives</cato:entity-ref>—</text>
			<paragraph id="HEB1E084C5D734DCCA36FAE4521BF3A0C">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text>congratulates the <cato:entity-ref entity-id="1352" entity-type="federal-body">Minority Business Development Agency</cato:entity-ref> on its 45th anniversary;</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H17F66E61EB604473A975678AFEB74E12">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text>commends the <cato:entity-ref entity-id="1352" entity-type="federal-body">Minority Business Development Agency</cato:entity-ref> for its achievements in fostering the
			 establishment and growth of minority businesses; and</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H4E6D24D2B0D24478A30431B8DC0492E1">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">encourages the <cato:entity-ref entity-id="1352" entity-type="federal-body">Minority Business Development Agency</cato:entity-ref> to continue its efforts to assist minority
			 businesses as minority businesses continue to strengthen communities,
			 create jobs, and contribute to the health of the economy of the United
			 States.</text>
			</paragraph>
    </section>
  </resolution-body>
</resolution>
</doc>