<doc>
  <docmeta id="113hr3769ih">
    <bill congress="113" type="hr" number="3769" version="ih"/>
    <revision size="3789" annotations="0" status="complete" id="3" commit-time="2014-01-02T20:54:28Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113hr3769ih/3.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H68C35652DC464377A2643FB0D56968D4" public-private="public">
  <metadata>
<dublinCore>
<dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">113 HR 3769 IH: To extend the nonenforcement instruction for the Medicare direct supervision requirement for therapeutic hospital outpatient services insofar as it applies to critical access hospitals and rural hospitals, to require a study of the impact on critical access hospitals and rural hospitals of a failure to extend such instruction, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">2013-12-12</dc:date>
<dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
    <congress>113th CONGRESS</congress>
    <session>1st Session</session>
    <legis-num>H. R. 3769</legis-num>
    <current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
    <action>
      <action-date date="20131212">December 12, 2013</action-date>
      <action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="S001172">Mr. Smith of Nebraska</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="J000290">Ms. Jenkins</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
    </action>
    <legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
    <official-title>To extend the nonenforcement instruction for the Medicare direct supervision requirement for therapeutic hospital outpatient services insofar as it applies to critical access hospitals and rural hospitals, to require a study of the impact on critical access hospitals and rural hospitals of a failure to extend such instruction, and for other purposes.</official-title>
  </form>
  <legis-body id="HAA9E822E62D7426F890E7329B6E31982" style="OLC">
    <section id="HFB77DB07A3B64B4E92AC87AE729538E1" section-type="section-one">
      <enum>1.</enum>
      <header>Extension of nonenforcement instruction for the Medicare direct supervision requirement for therapeutic hospital outpatient services for critical access hospitals and rural hospitals; study of impact of failure to extend such instruction</header>
      <subsection id="H39761D94F89344CC8848B801C99B6557">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Extension of therapy supervision nonenforcement instruction</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary of Health and Human Services</cato:entity-ref> shall, during the extension period, extend the therapy supervision nonenforcement instruction.</text>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="HEC2D3AC2DD6C42C98ED21F736F799F6C">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Definitions</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text>
        <paragraph id="HB86F6414575A49089AD97DA0AC47959D">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>Therapy supervision nonenforcement instruction</header>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>therapy supervision nonenforcement instruction</quote> means the enforcement instruction on supervision requirements for outpatient therapeutic services in critical access and small rural hospitals, as extended for calendar year 2013 by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7530">Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services</cato:entity-ref> (released as of November 1, 2012).</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HD118BAB45C2E4A0D903ADAA3317A8992">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Critical access hospital; small rural hospital</header>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The terms <quote>critical access hospital</quote> and <quote>small rural hospital</quote> have the meanings given such terms for purposes of the therapy supervision nonenforcement instruction.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HED005C9C6A6146968760DC4CBF69F7B2">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <header>Extension period</header>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>extension period</quote> means calendar year 2014, and includes a subsequent calendar year unless the report under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="113 HR 3769/s:1/ss:c/p:2" proposed="true">subsection (c)(2)</cato:entity-ref> has been submitted at least 90 days before the end of the previous calendar year.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="H4888FDE558A54ADDAD6C27AD1E71F61A">
        <enum>(c)</enum>
        <header>Study and report on impact of failure To extend therapy supervision nonenforcement instruction</header>
        <paragraph id="HF35D37FCD3A24F938D4943E7F371FF32">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>Study</header>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary of Health and Human Services</cato:entity-ref> shall conduct a study on the impact (including the economic impact and the impact upon hospital staffing needs, if any) on critical access hospitals and small rural hospitals of not extending the therapy supervision nonenforcement instruction.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H127DCD6E961F42A187EBEB1F4E24DAC4">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Report</header>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary of Health and Human Services</cato:entity-ref> shall submit to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> a report on the findings of the study conducted under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="113 HR 3769/s:1/ss:c/p:1" proposed="true">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref>, including recommendations regarding on whether the therapy supervision nonenforcement instruction should be extended or made permanent.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
    </section>
  </legis-body>
</bill>
</doc>