<doc>
  <docmeta id="113hr4790ih">
    <bill congress="113" type="hr" number="4790" version="ih"/>
    <revision size="7167" annotations="0" status="complete" id="6" commit-time="2014-06-13T16:20:27Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113hr4790ih/6.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H4957F2119C1A49B8BB53EA52FAC1DFF7" public-private="public">
	<metadata>
<dublinCore>
<dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">113 HR 4790 IH: Highways Bettering the Economy and Environment Pollinator Protection Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">2014-05-30</dc:date>
<dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>113th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>2d Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 4790</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20140530">May 30, 2014</action-date>
			<action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="H000324">Mr. Hastings of Florida</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="D000612">Mr. Denham</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>
      </action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To amend title 23, United States Code, to encourage and facilitate efforts by States and other
			 transportation rights-of-way managers to adopt integrated vegetation
			 management practices, including enhancing plantings of native forbs and
			 grasses that provide habitats and forage for Monarch butterflies and other
			 native pollinators and honey bees, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="HB8BF4A08C9CF48BCA87FA9DA82172D7D" style="OLC">
		<section id="HB49BAF0E8EDE4DC386C876301B954D63" section-type="section-one">
      <enum>1.</enum>
      <header>Short title</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote>
          <short-title>
            <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Highways Bettering the Economy and Environment Pollinator Protection Act" proposed="true">Highways Bettering the Economy and Environment Pollinator Protection Act</cato:entity-ref>
          </short-title>
        </quote>.</text>
		</section>
    <section id="HEADBEF0F24F94A18B721ECABF9648EF3">
      <enum>2.</enum>
      <header>Findings</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">
        <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> finds the following:</text>
			<paragraph id="H803741DC2C864E528FF01368E0900097">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text>The roadside vegetation management practices of both State governments and the Federal Government
			 aim to secure motorist safety, reduce the presence of noxious weeds, and
			 stabilize the soil.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HC092E6B8DE3444DEB82EF7BF22B666AF">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text>Federal and State highway departments are facing severe budget shortfalls.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H03B949EF1FFA4AB28255B4E9A9FAA845">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <text>Native forbs and grasses are less likely to encroach onto roads than invasive species, such as
			 kudzu.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H3E833539D8A946E9A88D3124CF309E74">
        <enum>(4)</enum>
        <text>Integrated vegetation management practices will reduce the cost of maintaining roadside vegetation.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H912BC84DDCF24C5EB76D87A374284B2E">
        <enum>(5)</enum>
        <text>Native forbs and grasses are best adapted to local conditions and thus require less active
			 management, reducing the need to replant, weed, and mow the areas adjacent
			 to the road.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H0F76B25083154D81AEC616E4674D81D4">
        <enum>(6)</enum>
        <text>Pollinators, such as native bees, honey bees, birds, bats, Monarch butterflies, and other
			 butterflies, are suffering drastic population loss due in part to loss of
			 habitat and forage.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H74A668344CC84497ACA967A5F7EA3599">
        <enum>(7)</enum>
        <text>Pollinators are vital for American agriculture. Responsible for 1 out of every 3 bites of food we
			 eat, a diverse pollinator population is necessary for maintaining the
			 diversity of our plant life and food supply.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H4C9B9B9219BE45EDB680112863504FCC">
        <enum>(8)</enum>
        <text>Studies have shown supporting native forbs and grasses along the roadside can be beneficial to the
			 pollinator population by providing migratory corridors and habitat and
			 forage connectivity and by helping such populations adapt to climate
			 change.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H1C6CE5DFA0974B238C4E65DBF4A2FCF5">
        <enum>(9)</enum>
        <text>Plantings of noninvasive, locally appropriate milkweed species can create migratory way stations
			 for the endangered Monarch butterfly and to facilitate migrations of other
			 pollinators.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HD8812C488DD74FD694AC863E7AD11B5A">
        <enum>(10)</enum>
        <text>Enhancing pollinator populations on rights-of-way can result in improved pollination services for
			 neighboring lands, including agriculture and wildlife ecosystems.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HEE667EE3C3FE4E95B26DD4B8FA6FB7DC">
        <enum>(11)</enum>
        <text>Highway rights-of-way managed by States represent 17 million acres of pollinator habitat
			 conservation opportunity, and similar opportunities and benefits exist on
			 other transportation rights-of-way.</text>
			</paragraph>
    </section>
    <section id="H7EA4193BDF094A4E9D7EEB0285A2DAD7">
      <enum>3.</enum>
      <header>Administrative provisions to encourage pollinator habitat and forage on transportation
			 rights-of-way</header>
			<subsection id="H45D55ED603F24D2094BB06CFBFD5CAF8">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>In general</header>
        <text>
          <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc/23/319">
            <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/23/319">Section 319</external-xref> of title 23, United States Code</cato:entity-ref>, is amended—</text>
				<paragraph id="H95E48DCD4DE94109802C1A27D67E6DAB">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc/23/319/a">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref> by striking <quote>beauty adjacent</quote> and inserting <quote>beauty (including the enhancement of habitat and forage for pollinators) adjacent</quote>; and</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HFE1DC4A247F842FD9E24C2CF11A48128">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>by adding at the end the following:</text>
					<quoted-block id="HD1405D1BA6A246E981D8188547325CC7" style="OLC">
						<subsection id="HC8EBF1CE0BDD4430887CC7C87826A78B">
              <enum>(c)</enum>
              <header>Encouragement of pollinator habitat and forage development and protection on transportation
			 rights-of-Way</header>
              <text>In carrying out any program administered by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="6900">Secretary</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="6900">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall, in conjunction with
			 willing States, as appropriate—</text>
							<paragraph id="H18CF14BF85BB41B2B6833815CF04F73F">
                <enum>(1)</enum>
                <text>conduct or encourage integrated vegetation management practices on roadsides and other
			 transportation rights-of-way, including reduced mowing;</text>
							</paragraph>
              <paragraph id="HC03BA567FA874CBB91630D79C811F118">
                <enum>(2)</enum>
                <text>enhance the development of habitat and forage for Monarch butterflies, other native pollinators,
			 and honey bees through plantings of native forbs and grasses, including
			 noninvasive, native milkweed species that can serve as migratory way
			 stations for the endangered Monarch butterfly and to facilitate migrations
			 of other pollinators.</text>
							</paragraph>
              <paragraph id="H9BBC623799DA48628204931F1D6845BA">
                <enum>(3)</enum>
                <text>encourage leveraging through partnerships and coordination with stakeholders in support of
			 pollinators and plantings of native forbs and grasses, such as
			 environmental groups, research institutions, other agencies, businesses,
			 and community organizations; and</text>
							</paragraph>
              <paragraph id="H5AED285863A84372AEA12765DE74AF0C">
                <enum>(4)</enum>
                <text>conduct or facilitate research and demonstration projects on the economic and environmental
			 benefits and best practices for integrated vegetation management, reduced
			 mowing, and plantings of native forbs and grasses for pollinator habitat,
			 forage, and migratory way stations for Monarch butterflies and other
			 migrating pollinators.</text>
              </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
          </quoted-block>
				</paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="H63CC80884B3D419F97EDC97698933175">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Report</header>
        <text>Not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of this Act, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="6900" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of Transportation</cato:entity-ref>
			 shall transmit to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> a report that includes—</text>
				<paragraph id="H594C367B718E49A48EEDC9A00E657B72">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>an analysis of current programs and authorities available to carry out <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc/23/319/c">
              <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/23/319">section 319(c)</external-xref> of title 23,
			 United States Code</cato:entity-ref>;</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H3836E4A49C47460CA13C03B33C148CD7">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>a summary of programs and authorities being used to implement such section;</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H72F68E9989B34B2F83E6C6F2ACED6FCB">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <text>an assessment of actions being taken by willing State transportation departments and other managers
			 of transportation rights-of-way to implement integrated vegetation
			 management practices, reduce mowing, and enhance habitat and forage for
			 Monarch butterflies, other native pollinators, and honey bees through
			 plantings of native forbs and grasses and migratory way stations for
			 Monarch butterflies and other migrating pollinators; and</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HA9EF5573BD14484B99D5794D201BCE0C">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
          <text>any recommendations for further action.</text>
				</paragraph>
      </subsection>
    </section>
    <section id="HC616569AA1BE425396D6227C3B7AD07B">
      <enum>4.</enum>
      <header>Provision of habitat, forage, and migratory way stations for monarch butterflies, other native
			 pollinators, and honey bees</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">
        <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc/23/329/a/1">
          <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/23/329">Section 329(a)(1)</external-xref> of title 23, United States Code</cato:entity-ref>, is amended by inserting <quote>provision of habitat, forage, and migratory way stations for Monarch butterflies, other native
			 pollinators, and honey bees,</quote> before <quote>and aesthetic enhancement</quote>.</text>
		</section>
  </legis-body>
</bill>
</doc>