<doc>
  <docmeta id="113hres266eh">
    <bill congress="113" type="hres" number="266" version="eh"/>
    <revision size="3143" annotations="0" status="complete" id="3" commit-time="2013-08-05T18:18:40Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113hres266eh/3.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <resolution xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" dms-id="Hc1aaeade-9ff2-499a-826c-df4e4d72efd4" key="H" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Engrossed-in-House" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" stage-count="1"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>113 HRES 266 EH: Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 1947) to provide for the reform and continuation of agricultural and other programs of the Department of Agriculture through fiscal year 2018, and for other purposes; and providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 1797) to amend title 18, United States Code, to protect pain-capable unborn children in the District of Columbia, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2013-06-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="no">IV</distribution-code> 
<congress display="no">113th CONGRESS</congress> 
<session display="no">1st Session</session> 
<legis-num>H. RES. 266</legis-num> 
<current-chamber display="yes">In the House of Representatives, U. S.,</current-chamber>
<action>
<action-date date="20130618">June 18, 2013</action-date>
</action> 
<legis-type display="yes">RESOLUTION</legis-type> 
<official-title display="no">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 1947) to provide for the reform and continuation of agricultural and other programs of the Department of Agriculture through fiscal year 2018, and for other purposes; and providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 1797) to amend title 18, United States Code, to protect pain-capable unborn children in the District of Columbia, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<resolution-body id="H97b199f7-a9da-4a75-a6ed-f975b5c43e53" style="traditional"> 
<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="Hafaaad9f-b7cb-4ac4-9f69-4895fadeeb12" section-type="undesignated-section">
      <enum/>
      <text>That at any time after the adoption of this resolution the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" value="Speaker of the House of Representatives" entity-parent-id="0050">Speaker</cato:entity-ref> may, pursuant to clause 2(b) of rule XVIII, declare the House resolved into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for consideration of the bill (<cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="113 HR 1947" proposed="true">H.R. 1947</cato:entity-ref>) to provide for the reform and continuation of agricultural and other programs of the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1200">Department of Agriculture</cato:entity-ref> through fiscal year 2018, and for other purposes. The first reading of the bill shall be dispensed with. All points of order against consideration of the bill are waived. General debate shall be confined to the bill and shall not exceed one hour equally divided and controlled by the chair and ranking minority member of the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="committee" entity-id="HAG00">Committee on Agriculture</cato:entity-ref>. After general debate, the Committee of the Whole shall rise without motion. No further consideration of the bill shall be in order except pursuant to a subsequent order of the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0050">House</cato:entity-ref>.</text> </section>
<section id="H7C9429943FDD4FBB85363EDDEA1068D4">
      <enum>2.</enum>
      <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon the adoption of this resolution it shall be in order to consider in the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0050">House</cato:entity-ref> the bill (<cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="113 HR 1797" proposed="true">H.R. 1797</cato:entity-ref>) to amend <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/18">title 18, United States Code</cato:entity-ref>, to protect pain-capable unborn children in the District of Columbia, and for other purposes. All points of order against consideration of the bill are waived. In lieu of the amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="committee" entity-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</cato:entity-ref> now printed in the bill, an amendment in the nature of a substitute consisting of the text of Rules Committee Print 113–15 shall be considered as adopted. The bill, as amended, shall be considered as read. All points of order against provisions in the bill, as amended, are waived. The previous question shall be considered as ordered on the bill, as amended, and on any amendment thereto to final passage without intervening motion except: (1) one hour of debate equally divided and controlled by the chair and ranking minority member of the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="committee" entity-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</cato:entity-ref>; and (2) one motion to recommit with or without instructions.</text> </section>
</resolution-body> 
<attestation>
    <attestation-group>
      <attestor display="no">Karen L. Haas,</attestor>
      <role>Clerk.</role>
    </attestation-group>
  </attestation>
</resolution>
</doc>