<doc>
  <docmeta id="113hres276ih">
    <bill congress="113" type="hres" number="276" version="ih"/>
    <revision size="4595" annotations="0" status="complete" id="3" commit-time="2013-08-05T18:31:02Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113hres276ih/3.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <resolution xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" dms-id="HB3B4C3CF80264FAF85DCDB006CE058E8" key="H" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print">
	<metadata>
<dublinCore>
<title>113 HRES 276 IH: Supporting the goals and ideals of National Science Week and the biennial USA Science ? Engineering Festival in Washington, D.C., and inviting State and local governments to recognize the last week in April as a National Science Week.</title>
<publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</publisher>
<date>2013-06-25</date>
<format>text/xml</format>
<language>EN</language>
<rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">113th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session display="yes">1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. RES. 276</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20130625">June 25, 2013</action-date>
			<action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="H001059">Mr. Hultgren</sponsor> (for
			 himself and <cosponsor name-id="K000379">Mr. Kennedy</cosponsor>) submitted the
			 following resolution; which was referred to the
			 <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Committee on Science, Space, and
			 Technology</committee-name>
      </action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">Supporting the goals and ideals of National
		  Science Week and the biennial USA Science &amp; Engineering Festival in
		  Washington, D.C., and inviting State and local governments to recognize the
		  last week in April as a National Science Week.</official-title>
	</form>
	<preamble>
		<whereas>
      <text>Whereas science, technology, engineering and mathematics
			 are an essential element of the future competitiveness in the world of the
			 United States;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas advances in technology have resulted in
			 significant improvement in the daily lives of people in the United
			 States;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the global economy of the future will require a
			 workforce which is educated in science and engineering specialties;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas a new generation of Americans educated in STEM is
			 crucial to ensure continued economic growth;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas scientific discoveries are critical to curing
			 diseases, solving global challenges, and expanding our understanding of our
			 world;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas invigorating the interest of the next generation
			 of Americans in STEM education is necessary to maintain the global
			 competitiveness of the United States;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas nations around the world have held science
			 festivals which have brought together hundreds of thousands of visitors
			 celebrating science;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas science and engineering festivals have attracted
			 millions of participants and inspired a national effort to promote science and
			 engineering;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas thousands of universities, museums and science
			 centers, STEM professional societies, educational societies, government
			 agencies and laboratories, community organizations, elementary and secondary
			 schools, volunteers, corporate and private sponsors, and nonprofit
			 organizations, have come together to produce the USA Science &amp; Engineering
			 Festival on a nationwide scale in Washington, D.C., in April 2014;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the USA Science &amp; Engineering Festival will
			 highlight the important contributions of science and engineering to the
			 competitiveness of the United States through exhibits on such topics as human
			 spaceflight, medicine, engineering, biotechnology, weather forecasting,
			 physics, and astronomy; and</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas scientific research is essential to the
			 competitiveness of the United States and events like the USA Science &amp;
			 Engineering Festival promote the importance of scientific research and
			 development to the future of America: Now, therefore, be it</text>
		</whereas>
  </preamble>
	<resolution-body id="HBB33A55C79584B829C312C7C97ADC39C" style="traditional">
		<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H0D1A2059A7DB4F8D806E36CB01052928" section-type="undesignated-section">
      <enum/>
      <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0050">House of Representatives</cato:entity-ref>—</text>
			<paragraph id="H325A0AA0728B47EBB6F11681290E3769">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text>expresses its
			 support for the goals and ideals of the USA Science &amp; Engineering Festival
			 to promote science scholarship and an interest in scientific research and
			 development as the cornerstones of innovation and competition in the United
			 States;</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H8339980B041C4E6E96E0D81480F81C7A">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text>supports festivals
			 such as the USA Science &amp; Engineering Festival which focus on the
			 importance of science and engineering to our everyday lives through exhibits in
			 such topics as human spaceflight, weather forecasting, satellite technology,
			 and telescopes;</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HE74DF6F8B56343CEAC05D988F0FCA74B">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <text>congratulates all
			 the individuals and organizations whose efforts will make the USA Science &amp;
			 Engineering Festival highlighting American accomplishments in science and
			 engineering possible;</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HDC8C5F9B4C954ACBB029D9333FD91E37">
        <enum>(4)</enum>
        <text>encourages
			 families and their children to participate in the activities and exhibits that
			 will occur in the Washington Convention Center and across the United States as
			 satellite events to the USA Science &amp; Engineering Festival; and</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HDC3A1BEF6EF3489AB6F04196FFE68481">
        <enum>(5)</enum>
        <text>invites State and
			 local governments to recognize a National Science Week.</text>
			</paragraph>
    </section>
  </resolution-body>
</resolution>
</doc>