<doc>
  <docmeta id="113hr3050ih">
    <bill congress="113" type="hr" number="3050" version="ih"/>
    <revision size="9959" annotations="0" status="complete" id="3" commit-time="2013-08-26T18:39:43Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113hr3050ih/3.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HE4177D657B864E27BC7FA94EB3397B2F" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata>
<dublinCore>
<title>113 HR 3050 IH: Social Security Equality Act of 2013</title>
<publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</publisher>
<date>2013-08-02</date>
<format>text/xml</format>
<language>EN</language>
<rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>113th CONGRESS</congress>
<session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. R. 3050</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20130802">August 2, 2013</action-date> 
<action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="S001156">Ms. Linda T. Sánchez of California</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001162">Ms. Schwartz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001038">Mr. Higgins</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001227">Mr. Brady of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001047">Mr. Himes</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000933">Mr. Moran</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001050">Ms. Hanabusa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000551">Mr. Grijalva</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001145">Ms. Schakowsky</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001080">Ms. Chu</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000465">Ms. Tsongas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000197">Ms. DeGette</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000288">Mr. Ellison</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001036">Mrs. Capps</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000087">Mrs. Carolyn B. Maloney of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001150">Mr. Schiff</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Q000023">Mr. Quigley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000551">Ms. Lee of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001037">Mr. Capuano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000597">Ms. Pingree of Maine</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000559">Mr. Langevin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000797">Ms. Wasserman Schultz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001066">Ms. Castor of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000382">Ms. Kuster</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000248">Mr. Serrano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H000324">Mr. Hastings of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000397">Ms. Lofgren</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000510">Mr. Smith of Washington</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001034">Mr. Honda</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000191">Mr. DeFazio</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001032">Mr. Holt</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000170">Mr. O’Rourke</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000598">Mrs. Davis of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000472">Mr. Takano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001193">Mr. Swalwell of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001084">Mr. Cicilline</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000598">Mr. Polis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000312">Mr. McGovern</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000800">Mr. Welch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000610">Mr. Deutch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000263">Mr. Levin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001242">Mr. Bishop of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001049">Mr. Clay</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000579">Mr. Lowenthal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000130">Mr. Vargas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001063">Ms. Hahn</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000030">Mr. Farr</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001175">Ms. Speier</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000215">Ms. Eshoo</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000607">Mr. Pocan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001090">Mr. Cartwright</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001068">Mr. Huffman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000557">Mr. Larson of Connecticut</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000293">Ms. Esty</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001097">Mr. Cárdenas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001190">Mr. Schneider</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000375">Mr. Keating</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="I000057">Mr. Israel</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001285">Ms. Brownley of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C000714">Mr. Conyers</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000096">Mr. Pascrell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000287">Mr. Lewis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001160">Ms. Moore</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000034">Mr. Pallone</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001278">Ms. Bonamici</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001149">Mr. Michaud</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000216">Ms. DeLauro</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001163">Ms. Matsui</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000725">Mr. George Miller of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001191">Ms. Sinema</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000808">Ms. Wilson of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001143">Ms. McCollum</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000469">Mr. Tonko</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000593">Mr. Perlmutter</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000379">Mr. Kennedy</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000053">Mr. Rangel</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001191">Mr. Murphy of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000179">Mr. Engel</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000562">Mr. Lynch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000179">Mrs. Napolitano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000215">Mr. Waxman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000482">Mr. Doyle</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H000636">Mr. Hinojosa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001170">Ms. Shea-Porter</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000608">Mr. Peters of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000580">Ms. Michelle Lujan Grisham of New Mexico</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000468">Ms. Titus</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000081">Ms. Velázquez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000574">Mr. Blumenauer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001067">Ms. Clarke</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001168">Mr. Sarbanes</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000355">Mr. Dingell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000486">Ms. Roybal-Allard</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000577">Mr. Ryan of Ohio</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Y000062">Mr. Yarmuth</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000462">Ms. Frankel of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000622">Ms. Duckworth</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000131">Mr. Veasey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000553">Mr. Al Green of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000559">Mr. Garamendi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000556">Mr. Grayson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001137">Mr. Meeks</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000404">Mr. McDermott</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000381">Mr. Kilmer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000515">Mr. Rush</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000015">Mr. Neal</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="F000454">Mr. Foster</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name>
      </action-desc>
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To amend title II of the Social Security Act to provide for treatment of permanent partnerships between individuals of the same gender as marriage for purposes of determining entitlement to benefits under such title.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H5185F0F8B3BD4DD2B2FADD2E25A20145" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H675837F46DCF4026B9753361A6F55886" section-type="section-one">
      <enum>1.</enum>
      <header>Short title</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote>
          <short-title>Social Security Equality Act of 2013</short-title>
        </quote>.</text>
    </section>
<section id="H29CE46996DB44AF8AC5790B77750A8C1">
      <enum>2.</enum>
      <header>Treatment of permanent partnerships under title II of the Social Security Act</header>
<subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCFB652BF58F84B018EB6F25AA07A6E2B">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>In general</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">
          <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Social Security Act/s:216">Section 216 of the Social Security Act</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/416">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/42/416">42 U.S.C. 416</cato:entity-ref>
            </external-xref>)</cato:entity> is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text>
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC14129A449454DDB8499A19EFC65AA2F" other-style="archaic" style="other">
<subsection id="HC445B7D167754574A867BF991246CABF">
            <enum>(m)</enum>
            <header>Permanent partnership</header>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H6F2015106B32462CBAB178D6FA95B592">
              <enum>(1)</enum>
              <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of this title and under regulations of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2800">Commissioner of Social Security</cato:entity-ref> prescribed as required under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Social Security Act/s:216/ss:m/p:3" proposed="true">paragraph (3)</cato:entity-ref>:</text>
<subparagraph id="H9FF78C3013504B0B80822E62FB779E49" indent="up1">
                <enum>(A)</enum>
                <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In any case in which the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2800">Commissioner</cato:entity-ref> determines, in connection with the application by (or on behalf of) an individual for a benefit under this title, that a current or former marriage between the applicant and another individual, or between 2 other individuals, is a prerequisite for entitlement of the applicant to such benefit and the application designates, for treatment as such a marriage for purposes of such application, an arrangement between 2 individuals of the same gender—</text>
<clause id="HFC00B2E3450B417CBDCAB6D14CDD0771">
                  <enum>(i)</enum>
                  <text>if the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2800">Commissioner</cato:entity-ref> determines that such arrangement is (or was) a permanent partnership within the meaning of <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Social Security Act/s:216/ss:m/p:2" proposed="true">paragraph (2)</cato:entity-ref>, such arrangement shall be treated for purposes of this title as a marriage of such individuals; and</text>
                </clause>
<clause id="HC68276F53B2A4B92B54A5D968BBAB302">
                  <enum>(ii)</enum>
                  <text>each female party to such arrangement shall be treated as a wife with respect to such arrangement (referencing the other party as such individual’s spouse in connection with such arrangement) and each male party to such arrangement shall be treated as a husband with respect to such arrangement (referencing the other party as such individual’s spouse in connection with such arrangement).</text>
                </clause>
              </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H40BD1A4902D64F49A4367CEB4F0269CB" indent="up1">
                <enum>(B)</enum>
                <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An arrangement between individuals of the same gender shall be treated as a former marriage under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Social Security Act/s:216/ss:m/p:1/sp:A" proposed="true">subparagraph (A)</cato:entity-ref> in connection with an application for benefits under this title only if the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2800">Commissioner</cato:entity-ref> determines that such arrangement has been dissolved under the laws of the State of domicile of the applicant. In any case in which the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2800">Commissioner</cato:entity-ref> determines that such an arrangement has been so dissolved—</text>
<clause id="HE0E2D5A28A464F608AFFC4BD6A9CE066">
                  <enum>(i)</enum>
                  <text>the dissolution of such arrangement shall be treated as a divorce with respect to such arrangement; and</text>
                </clause>
<clause id="HA7320FA178D94DE7992E317B26AF7AE8">
                  <enum>(ii)</enum>
                  <text>each female individual who was a party to such arrangement shall be treated as a divorced wife with respect to such arrangement (referencing the other party as such individual’s divorced spouse in connection with such arrangement) and each male individual who was a party to such arrangement shall be treated as a divorced husband with respect to such arrangement (referencing the other party as the applicant’s divorced spouse in connection with such arrangement).</text>
                </clause>
              </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HF4A882F45A7949B9ACB22334EAFE3485" indent="up1">
                <enum>(C)</enum>
                <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In any case in which the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2800">Commissioner</cato:entity-ref> determines that, after an individual entitled to a monthly insurance benefit under section 202 became so entitled, such individual and another individual of the same gender have entered into an arrangement that constitutes a permanent partnership, such arrangement shall be treated as a marriage of such individuals for purposes of any provision of such section providing for termination of such entitlement upon marriage or remarriage.</text>
              </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H90DCF65650C446629AE73A7D1F3977B0" indent="up1">
                <enum>(D)</enum>
                <text>Upon receipt by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2800">Commissioner</cato:entity-ref> of an application by (or on behalf of) an individual for a benefit under this title containing certification by (or on behalf of) the applicant, submitted in such form and manner as shall be prescribed in such regulations, that the applicant is a stepchild or adopted child of an individual who is or was a party to an arrangement consisting of a permanent partnership, if such arrangement is treated as a marriage under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Social Security Act/s:216/ss:m/p:1/sp:A" proposed="true">subparagraph (A)</cato:entity-ref> and, under the laws of the domicile of the applicant, the applicant is, at the time of such application, treated as a stepchild or adopted child of such party to such arrangement, the applicant shall be treated as such a stepchild or adopted child of such party (referencing such party as a parent of the applicant).</text>
              </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H5A81A941AD464100AD3A203151DB3944" indent="up1">
                <enum>(E)</enum>
                <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon receipt by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2800">Commissioner</cato:entity-ref> of an application by (or on behalf of) an individual for a benefit under this title containing certification by (or on behalf of) the applicant, submitted in such form and manner as shall be prescribed in such regulations, that the applicant is or was a party to an arrangement consisting of a permanent partnership and that the applicant is a parent of an individual who is a stepchild or adopted child of the applicant with respect to such arrangement, if such arrangement is treated as a marriage under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Social Security Act/s:216/ss:m/p:1/sp:A" proposed="true">subparagraph (A)</cato:entity-ref> and, under the laws of the domicile of the applicant, the applicant is, at the time of such application, treated as a parent of such individual with respect to such arrangement, the applicant shall be treated as such a parent of such individual (referencing such individual as a stepchild or adopted child of the applicant).</text>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H1FB43EB0EFA54C68A2FD970DC971E0BA" indent="up1">
              <enum>(2)</enum>
              <text>For purposes of this subsection, the term <term>permanent partnership</term> means, in connection with any individual, a committed, intimate arrangement which is between such individual and another individual who have both attained 18 years of age and which has been recognized and certified as legally valid by the State of domicile of the applicant, in any case in which—</text>
<subparagraph id="H52854A691C25408BA247788F2E14A916">
                <enum>(A)</enum>
                <text>each such individual intends a lifelong commitment to the other;</text>
              </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HF72EEBCAF6694F429219A777A16C635D">
                <enum>(B)</enum>
                <text>such individuals are financially interdependent;</text>
              </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H2DD37D150B5B4838B3D2DE137F6AACE5">
                <enum>(C)</enum>
                <text>such individuals are unable to contract with each other a marriage cognizable under this title (other than as provided in this subsection);</text>
              </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H02A70DAA15774FA5A5C032ED287D3497">
                <enum>(D)</enum>
                <text>each such individual is not a first, second, or third degree blood relation of the other individual; and</text>
              </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HB8FFB91DF14C4A7184356ACF43493651">
                <enum>(E)</enum>
                <text>each such individual is neither married (within the meaning of this title other than as provided in this subsection) to, nor in a relationship described in the preceding provisions of this paragraph with, any third individual.</text>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H85195362719642B6921E6D885B93D5AC" indent="up1">
              <enum>(3)</enum>
              <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2800">Commissioner</cato:entity-ref> shall prescribe such regulations as are necessary to carry out the provisions of this subsection. In prescribing such regulations, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2800">Commissioner</cato:entity-ref> shall take into account the laws of the State of domicile of an applicant for benefits under this title so as to ensure that such provisions, together with the other provisions of this title as applied in accordance with this subsection, are appropriately coordinated with each other and with the laws of such State.</text>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
        </quoted-block>
      </subsection>
<subsection id="HCD80CD353020461C85BE8166472E8070">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Effective date</header>
        <text>The amendment made by this section shall apply with respect to monthly insurance benefits for months after November 2013 for which applications are filed after December 31, 2013, and with respect to lump-sum death payments in connection with deaths occurring after such date.</text>
      </subsection>
    </section> 
</legis-body> 
</bill>
</doc>