<doc>
  <docmeta id="113hr2052eh">
    <bill congress="113" type="hr" number="2052" version="eh"/>
    <revision size="9268" annotations="0" status="complete" id="4" commit-time="2014-01-27T23:01:26Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113hr2052eh/4.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <bill bill-stage="Engrossed-in-House" dms-id="HE7AB00FBE083436CAD71196878DF91D4" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc" stage-count="1"> 
<metadata>
<dublinCore>
<dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">113 HR 2052 EH: Global Investment in American Jobs Act of 2013</dc:title>
<dc:publisher xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"/>
<dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="no">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>113th CONGRESS</congress> <session>1st Session</session> 
<legis-num>H. R. 2052</legis-num> 
<current-chamber display="no">IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type> 
<official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Commerce, in coordination with the heads of other relevant Federal departments and agencies, to conduct an interagency review of and report to Congress on ways to increase the global competitiveness of the United States in attracting foreign direct investment.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H8618619BA12D4D36981AB1E31BFAC845" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HBC25319E47414E569E04664D8639A0DE" section-type="section-one">
      <enum>1.</enum>
      <header>Short title</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote>
          <short-title>Global Investment in American Jobs Act of 2013</short-title>
        </quote>.</text>
    </section> 
<section id="H0BD5030FCCDC4E6192258E203C9D0DB0">
      <enum>2.</enum>
      <header>Findings</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">
        <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> finds the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H46057AA935C04081ADB9638934651327">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text>It remains an urgent national priority to improve economic growth and create new jobs.</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6D75808AFD7E40EEA4C4A846739DD781">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text>National security requires economic strength and global engagement.</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H10A8F03B55174EC5B15373DDA799AB34">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <text>Businesses today have a wide array of choices when considering where to invest, expand, or establish new operations.</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H36195E11CB714BD1AC5D243E5DAA2E72">
        <enum>(4)</enum>
        <text>Administrations of both parties have consistently reaffirmed the need to promote an open investment climate as a key to domestic economic prosperity and security.</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H009BC6916C3F4A78A0D99004EE3DCD36">
        <enum>(5)</enum>
        <text>The United States has historically been the largest worldwide recipient of foreign direct investment but has seen its share decline in recent years.</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1CE6339C9E79457D85339C980015928A">
        <enum>(6)</enum>
        <text>The United States faces increasing competition from other countries as it works to recruit investment from global companies.</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB4360DE69E1D4529BA793D9B4A35D796">
        <enum>(7)</enum>
        <text>Foreign direct investment can benefit the economy and workforce of every State and Commonwealth in the United States.</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H10BF26EE6F574748B9AE07E074D3EBF2">
        <enum>(8)</enum>
        <text>According to the latest Federal statistics, the United States subsidiaries of companies headquartered abroad contribute to the United States economy in a variety of important ways, including by—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H4C298544579D4E7E8C417AB137B92DC3">
          <enum>(A)</enum>
          <text>providing jobs for an estimated 5,600,000 Americans, with compensation that is often higher than the national private-sector average, as many of these jobs are in high-skilled, high-paying industries;</text>
        </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9332E53987FD4A52A05E6C262ADC107F">
          <enum>(B)</enum>
          <text>strengthening the United States industrial base and employing nearly 15 percent of the United States manufacturing sector workforce;</text>
        </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9EAF3E33F2DB49C6BF7FD6B0FDED5A00">
          <enum>(C)</enum>
          <text>establishing operations in the United States from which to sell goods and services around the world, thereby producing nearly 18 percent of United States exports;</text>
        </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HECB54998008E404FA9E6C8CEB31538F3">
          <enum>(D)</enum>
          <text>promoting innovation with more than $41,000,000,000 in annual United States research and development activities;</text>
        </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H0E52BA0893334D70A2F66505486B1437">
          <enum>(E)</enum>
          <text>paying nearly 14 percent of United States corporate income taxes; and</text>
        </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H3C4FCB6A4445473C9B2E7B1DA06E3D35">
          <enum>(F)</enum>
          <text>purchasing goods and services from local suppliers and small businesses worth hundreds of billions of dollars annually.</text>
        </subparagraph>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H544244F67A6E4E4995CCDF8ED014D4CE">
        <enum>(9)</enum>
        <text>These companies account for 5.8 percent of United States private sector gross domestic product.</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFD4ED6B990A540029C4C9B09F7B20436">
        <enum>(10)</enum>
        <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1300">Department of
			 Commerce</cato:entity-ref> has initiatives in place to increase foreign direct investment.</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8D705E49C939446FA68971BF0EE0C686">
        <enum>(11)</enum>
        <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref>
			 issued a statement in 2011 reaffirming the longstanding open investment policy
			 of the United States and encouraged all countries to pursue such a
			 policy.</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCD824F903D7A4F69BB3B040FD60FFF35">
        <enum>(12)</enum>
        <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref>
			 signed an Executive order in 2011 to establish the SelectUSA initiative and
			 expanded its resources and activities in 2012, so as to promote greater levels
			 of business investment in the United States.</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H310D90267651499EAE41D11A99733686">
        <enum>(13)</enum>
        <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President’s</cato:entity-ref>
			 Council on Jobs and Competitiveness in 2011 recommended the establishment of a
			 National Investment Initiative to attract $1,000,000,000,000 in foreign direct
			 investment over five years.</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC810B1F4518E437598A4AA9900120BC0">
        <enum>(14)</enum>
        <text>Sound transportation infrastructure, a well-educated and healthy workforce, safe food and water, stable financial institutions, a fair and equitable justice system, and transparent and accountable administrative procedures are important factors that contribute to United States global competitiveness.</text>
      </paragraph>
    </section> 
<section id="H46C87BF64F2445AA8EB9C076B29C5715">
      <enum>3.</enum>
      <header>Sense of congress</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> that—</text> 
<paragraph id="HE351FD72D39241F2A0155EF19BCBEFF0">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text>the ability of the United States to attract foreign direct investment is directly linked to the long-term economic prosperity, global competitiveness, and security of the United States;</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9A54A69636624A3297DEAF0E2DCB4A49">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text>it is a top national priority to enhance the global competitiveness, prosperity, and security of the United States by—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H2F354A9F6556423984F199A5BD138AC2">
          <enum>(A)</enum>
          <text>removing unnecessary barriers to foreign direct investment and the jobs that it creates throughout the United States; and</text>
        </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HFEFF2E3BE6734BD6852E2AB60B9DD8B0">
          <enum>(B)</enum>
          <text>promoting policies to ensure the United States remains the premier global destination in which to invest, hire, innovate, and manufacture products; </text>
        </subparagraph>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9D26CB7418284A3B91BA672F8E75780A">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <text>maintaining the United States’ commitment to open investment policy encourages other countries to reciprocate and enables the United States to open new markets abroad for United States companies and their products;</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2C8DD6CFD6E94FFB8ED88C6525B740F8">
        <enum>(4)</enum>
        <text>while foreign direct investment can enhance the Nation’s economic strength, policies regarding foreign direct investment should reflect national security interests and should not disadvantage domestic investors or companies; and</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD1BCBB8327474FFE894CC416E3A72D73">
        <enum>(5)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">United States efforts to attract foreign direct investment should be consistent with efforts to maintain and improve the domestic standard of living.</text>
      </paragraph>
    </section> 
<section id="H648E4E9982C64135AA9C76F4D8792D12">
      <enum>4.</enum>
      <header>Foreign direct investment review</header> 
<subsection id="H242FDB795FC245BD8D47EC913DEE456A">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Review</header>
        <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1300">Secretary of Commerce</cato:entity-ref>, in coordination with the Federal Interagency Investment Working Group and the heads of other relevant Federal departments and agencies, shall conduct an interagency review of the global competitiveness of the United States in attracting foreign direct investment.</text>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="H51B20315747344D7A7453AB6E4523E77">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Specific matters to be included</header>
        <text>The review conducted pursuant to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Global Investment in American Jobs Act of 2013/s:4/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref> shall include a review of—</text> 
<paragraph id="H58B7656CF1BA4C52BD4B5C0D0FF46B51">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>the current economic impact of foreign direct investment in the United States, with particular focus on manufacturing, research and development, trade, and jobs;</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFEB17812F0D0400DA2A5668CDD9F3613">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>trends in global cross-border investment flows and the underlying factors for such trends;</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2613324A6FBC42CF8331B55ED41D6B53">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <text>Federal Government policies that are closely linked to the ability of the United States to attract and retain foreign direct investment;</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H469FB618330F4CE0A8056BF718A66A98">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
          <text>foreign direct investment as compared to direct investment by domestic entities;</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0DB8AC8443B5469E8E63B743A742FB27">
          <enum>(5)</enum>
          <text>foreign direct investment that takes the form of greenfield investment as compared to foreign direct investment reflecting merger and acquisition activity;</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA4F2C0D8B559422BABB5082D055FF0C4">
          <enum>(6)</enum>
          <text>the unique challenges posed by foreign direct investment by state-owned enterprises;</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5BC6F21D255E42DAB7922C27AF232C1C">
          <enum>(7)</enum>
          <text>ongoing Federal Government efforts to improve the investment climate and facilitate greater levels of foreign direct investment in the United States;</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD7F0386D2E834764BEAFE242D113B563">
          <enum>(8)</enum>
          <text>innovative and noteworthy State, regional, and local government initiatives to attract foreign investment; and</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2711E3E74D26431CA2F608B331345AF5">
          <enum>(9)</enum>
          <text>initiatives by other countries in order to identify best practices for increasing global competitiveness in attracting foreign direct investment.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="HD17E369D37D94975B1B39416094E1B33">
        <enum>(c)</enum>
        <header>Limitation</header>
        <text>The
			 review conducted pursuant to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Global Investment in American Jobs Act of 2013/s:4/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref> shall not address laws or policies
			 relating to the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Committee on Foreign Investment in the United States" entity-parent-id="2000">Committee on Foreign Investment in the United States</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="H91B40FB19BBF4FFDA67138A497431186">
        <enum>(d)</enum>
        <header>Public comment</header>
        <text>Prior to—</text> 
<paragraph id="HBD57EE0A629844719BBFD6B110308A0A">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>conducting the review under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Global Investment in American Jobs Act of 2013/s:4/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1300">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall publish notice of the review in the Federal Register and shall provide an opportunity for public comment on the matters to be covered by the review; and</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE8BE27862D6445D88C7237372F1D108F">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>reporting pursuant to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Global Investment in American Jobs Act of 2013/s:4/ss:e" proposed="true">subsection (e)</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1300">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall publish the proposed findings and recommendations to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> in the Federal Register and shall provide an opportunity for public comment.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="HBFB94F3EA52248CB82744C5FB8D9289E">
        <enum>(e)</enum>
        <header>Report to congress</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of enactment of this Act, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1300">Secretary of Commerce</cato:entity-ref>, in coordination with the Federal Interagency Investment Working Group and the heads of other relevant Federal departments and agencies, shall report to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> the findings of the review required under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Global Investment in American Jobs Act of 2013/s:4/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref> and submit recommendations for increasing the global competitiveness of the United States in attracting foreign direct investment without weakening labor, consumer, financial, or environmental protections.</text>
      </subsection>
    </section> 
</legis-body> <attestation>
    <attestation-group>
      <attestation-date date="20130909" chamber="House">Passed the House of Representatives September 9, 2013.</attestation-date>
      <attestor display="no">Karen L. Haas,</attestor>
      <role>Clerk.</role>
    </attestation-group>
  </attestation>
<endorsement display="yes"/>
</bill>
</doc>