<doc>
  <docmeta id="113hres339rh">
    <bill congress="113" type="hres" number="339" version="rh"/>
    <revision size="2431" annotations="0" status="complete" id="3" commit-time="2013-09-12T19:40:47Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113hres339rh/3.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <resolution xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" dms-id="Ha3d6c514-6590-4725-9ca8-af40cdb7989c" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Reported-in-House" key="H"> 
<metadata>
<dublinCore>
<title>113 HRES 339 RH: Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 2775) to condition the provision of premium and cost-sharing subsidies under the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act upon a certification that a program to verify household income and other qualifications for such subsidies is operational, and for other purposes.</title>
<publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</publisher>
<date>2013-09-10</date>
<format>text/xml</format>
<language>EN</language>
<rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code>
<calendar display="yes">House Calendar No. 51</calendar>
<congress display="yes">113th CONGRESS</congress>
<session display="yes">1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. RES. 339</legis-num>
<associated-doc role="report" display="yes">[Report No. 113–206]</associated-doc>
<current-chamber display="yes">IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20130910">September 10, 2013</action-date>
<action-desc>
        <cosponsor name-id="B001248">Mr. Burgess</cosponsor>, from the <committee-name committee-id="HRU00">Committee on Rules</committee-name>, reported the following resolution; which was referred to the House Calendar and ordered to be printed</action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 2775) to condition the provision of premium and cost-sharing subsidies under the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act upon a certification that a program to verify household income and other qualifications for such subsidies is operational, and for other purposes.</official-title>
</form>
<resolution-body style="traditional" id="H60cc8f6e-a8fc-4ae4-983b-37ffb2fbdc51">
<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="Ha97cc762-2914-4495-9135-3af65fb8a1d4">
      <text>That upon the adoption of this resolution it shall be in order to consider in the House the bill (<cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="113 HR 2775" proposed="true">H.R. 2775</cato:entity-ref>) to condition the provision of premium and cost-sharing subsidies under the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act">Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act</cato:entity-ref> upon a certification that a program to verify household income and other qualifications for such subsidies is operational, and for other purposes. All points of order against consideration of the bill are waived. The amendment printed in the report of the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="committee" entity-id="HRU00">Committee on Rules</cato:entity-ref> accompanying this resolution shall be considered as adopted. The bill, as amended, shall be considered as read. All points of order against provisions in the bill, as amended, are waived. The previous question shall be considered as ordered on the bill, as amended, and on any amendment thereto to final passage without intervening motion except: (1) one hour of debate, with 40 minutes equally divided and controlled by the chair and ranking minority member of the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="committee" entity-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</cato:entity-ref> and 20 minutes equally divided and controlled by the chair and ranking minority member of the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="committee" entity-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</cato:entity-ref>; and (2) one motion to recommit with or without instructions.</text>
    </section>
</resolution-body>
<endorsement>
<action-date date="20130910">September 10, 2013</action-date>
<action-desc>Referred to the House Calendar and ordered to be printed</action-desc>
  </endorsement>
</resolution>
</doc>