<doc>
  <docmeta id="113hr3405ih">
    <bill congress="113" type="hr" number="3405" version="ih"/>
    <revision size="9520" annotations="0" status="complete" id="4" commit-time="2013-11-08T18:55:20Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113hr3405ih/4.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H06FC26C4E7354C748A65CDDBB67FD880" public-private="public">
<metadata>
<dublinCore>
<dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">113 HR 3405 IH: United We Stand to Hire Veterans Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">2013-10-30</dc:date>
<dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
<congress>113th CONGRESS</congress>
    <session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. R. 3405</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<action>
<action-date date="20131030">October 30, 2013</action-date>
<action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="D000612">Mr. Denham</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="W000799">Mr. Walz</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Veterans’ Affairs</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
<official-title>To better connect current and former members of the Armed Forces with employment opportunities by consolidating duplicative Federal Government Internet websites into a single portal, to conserve resources by merging redundant and competing programs, and for other purposes.</official-title>
</form>
<legis-body id="HC3C60075B0E04152B568E8C49FD390C2" style="OLC">
<section id="HD957BD97B3E445E7890DE805208C9194" section-type="section-one">
      <enum>1.</enum>
      <header>Short title</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote>
          <short-title>United We Stand to Hire Veterans Act</short-title>
        </quote>.</text>
    </section>
<section id="HB083D73693E949C6BCC5B755BAF6F21B">
      <enum>2.</enum>
      <header>Consolidated and coordinated Federal Government Internet portal to connect current and former members of the Armed Forces with employers seeking employees with skills and experience developed through military service</header>
<subsection id="HFE4EEA7DC4114330A2B9688C987FF0DE">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Findings</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">
          <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> makes the following findings:</text>
<paragraph id="H474AFD206E4046C19B23F3F41ABD93D4">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>Although significant progress has been made, unemployment among veterans remains stubbornly high.</text>
        </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HD0C967A7715C4357AE3C875E821BC7EA">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>The unemployment rate among younger veterans, ages 18 to 24, remains well above the national average.</text>
        </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HB50E97B627E54E4A971608151E9B5BE4">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <text>This problem impacts the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="9700">Department of Defense</cato:entity-ref> budget. Over the past 10 years, the Federal Government has expended more than $9,600,000,000 on unemployment compensation benefits for former members of the Armed Forces.</text>
        </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H5FE09FEAC86A465FBBD64C547EC71889">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
          <text>The Department makes significant investments in members of the Armed Forces including specialized technical training in skills that are easily transferrable to civilian career fields.</text>
        </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H0230E086694048FEB4848D111579D953">
          <enum>(5)</enum>
          <text>Beyond specific technical training, veterans gain unique leadership, organizational, and other skills that make them valued employees in the private sector.</text>
        </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H361AB8D3C451419F908FAEE03C94DFCE">
          <enum>(6)</enum>
          <text>Government agencies, private sector entities, and nonprofit organizations are responding to the issue of unemployment among veterans.</text>
        </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H4EACCA0183884404848BFCAA6CD05FF1">
          <enum>(7)</enum>
          <text>There are now so many programs to assist veterans in finding employment, many within the Government, that veterans may not know where to turn to find assistance in finding employment. While these programs are well intentioned, many are duplicative in nature, and compete for scarce resources.</text>
        </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H6D8A645D0833481D9F2F1DB6C14B7783">
          <enum>(8)</enum>
          <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1600">Department of Labor</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="3600">Department of Veterans Affairs</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="9700">Department of Defense</cato:entity-ref>, and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2400">Office of Personnel Management</cato:entity-ref> are currently working to consolidate the veterans employment initiatives of the Government into a single, consolidated Internet portal with the goal of connecting veterans who are seeking employment with employers who want to employ them.</text>
        </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HD740E2636F7F42AEB9E70A27851F175F">
          <enum>(9)</enum>
          <text>The consolidated portal would prevent Federal Government agencies from competing with each other to accomplish the same goal, and will save the Federal Government money while providing a comprehensive, coordinated tool for employers and veterans seeking employment.</text>
        </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H9B3BE7D456A3446D94810C53E2812C49">
          <enum>(10)</enum>
          <text>The Federal Government can accomplish this by leveraging the best practices of current programs.</text>
        </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HBCF15F190DFA4EA581CFA6CEBD661707">
          <enum>(11)</enum>
          <text>While progress has been made, there is no statutory requirement to streamline these Government programs and coordinate the resources that are all intended to achieve the same goal.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
<subsection id="H9466898EA1614392AC19A9FEA99066FD">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Consolidated Internet portal required</header>
        <text>Commencing not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1600">Secretary of Labor</cato:entity-ref> shall, in conjunction with the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="9700">Secretary of Defense</cato:entity-ref> and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="3600">Secretary of Veterans Affairs</cato:entity-ref>, consolidate Internet portals of the Federal Government on employment for current and former members of the Armed Forces into a comprehensive consolidated Internet portal for the purposes of connecting current and former members of the Armed Forces who are seeking employment with employers who want to employ them.</text>
      </subsection>
<subsection id="HD102B0BE71F54589983A796040DDBAE7">
        <enum>(c)</enum>
        <header>Elements</header>
<paragraph id="H4EBD659DF8394F0B874308EA7CE01243">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>In general</header>
          <text>The consolidated Internet portal under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="United We Stand to Hire Veterans Act/s:2/ss:b" proposed="true">subsection (b)</cato:entity-ref> should include the following:</text>
<subparagraph id="H891D95B68F6849A8A3DBD9418CD4A1CC">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>A means through which current and former members of the Armed Forces may connect for employment purposes with employers seeking the experience and skills developed during service in the Armed Forces, including a means of presenting a profile of each member or former member to employers that includes, at a minimum—</text>
<clause id="H5D9702F6E61949ABAA9873AB1BE983E6">
              <enum>(i)</enum>
              <text>the skills obtained by such member or former member during service in the Armed Forces and additional skills such member or former member is interested in pursuing; and</text>
            </clause>
<clause id="H942F546EB03F4B7C952DD30FA84FE069">
              <enum>(ii)</enum>
              <text>the current or intended residence of such member or former member (including an option for members or former members who are willing to reside in various locations).</text>
            </clause>
          </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H26057E9073CC419EAA5BA7AF8B7F44F6">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>A means of permitting qualified prospective employers to post employment openings and seek contact with members or former members based on their profile for the purposes of requesting the initiation of arrangements or negotiations concerning potential employment.</text>
          </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HF810010F4C4E4153AD6024A07AEBDBB6">
            <enum>(C)</enum>
            <text>A means of presenting other employment resources, including resume preparation, to members or former members seeking employment.</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H503691D9204C40298B60FE575530B291">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Matters considered</header>
          <text>In developing the consolidated Internet portal, the Secretaries referred to in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="United We Stand to Hire Veterans Act/s:2/ss:b" proposed="true">subsection (b)</cato:entity-ref> should consider, at a minimum, the following:</text>
<subparagraph id="H750A861C638044E2891AE3CDAB77C70F">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>Public and private sector resources on matters relating to the portal.</text>
          </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H2CF1629CF434417DBE75D5CA91BA2B4D">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>Opportunities to incorporate local employment networks into the portal.</text>
          </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H88172641AA6D4A6DB5AF3F01745372EE">
            <enum>(C)</enum>
            <text>Methodologies to determine the most effective employment resources and programs to be incorporated into the portal.</text>
          </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H4F23094A04AA494384C3D8D414E5ACDF">
            <enum>(D)</enum>
            <text>Means for streamlining processes through the portal for employers to find and employ former members of the Armed Forces.</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
<subsection id="H0C2F585A11734CFBA15D9D7993CD40A2">
        <enum>(d)</enum>
        <header>Member participation</header>
        <text>Participation by a member or former member of the Armed Force in the consolidated Internet portal under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="United We Stand to Hire Veterans Act/s:2/ss:b" proposed="true">subsection (b)</cato:entity-ref> shall be voluntary. A member or former member participating in the portal may cease participation in the portal at any time.</text>
      </subsection>
<subsection id="H2E153B44DBBF4E1AA132AC0E2BA407FA">
        <enum>(e)</enum>
        <header>Pilot project authority</header>
<paragraph id="H02C5DDBF0FF548D39A9069B9838E0530">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>In general</header>
          <text>In order to expedite implementation of the consolidated Internet portal under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="United We Stand to Hire Veterans Act/s:2/ss:b" proposed="true">subsection (b)</cato:entity-ref>, the Secretaries may carry out one or more pilot projects to evaluate the feasibility and advisability of various options for the portal. Any such pilot project may only be a continuation or modification of an existing program.</text>
        </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HF18AFB3EE4244B709BF8B7A5C56A90E0">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Sunset</header>
          <text>The authority to carry out pilot projects under this subsection shall expire on the date that is five years after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
<subsection id="HC748ED562FCF403682C0878EAA042759">
        <enum>(f)</enum>
        <header>Reports</header>
<paragraph id="H1AF78C9DB5394E1FB97E8A37DFA8288C">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>Preliminary report</header>
          <text>Not later than six months after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretaries shall submit to the appropriate committees of <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> a report on the consolidated Internet portal under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="United We Stand to Hire Veterans Act/s:2/ss:b" proposed="true">subsection (b)</cato:entity-ref>. The report shall include the following:</text>
<subparagraph id="HD738452435D04EC382278C57AD2B02D7">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>A list of the Internet portals of the Federal Government that are redundant to, or duplicative of, the consolidated Internet portal.</text>
          </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H88CD4B0DA2B84A21916AB77B2F1F8271">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>An estimate of the cost savings to be achieved by the Federal Government through the consolidated Internet portal, including through the elimination or consolidation into the consolidated Internet portal of the Internet portals listed under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="United We Stand to Hire Veterans Act/s:2/ss:f/p:1/sp:A" proposed="true">subparagraph (A)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H05CF695A94CD437690A4FD505D04C580">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Report following implementation of portal</header>
          <text>Not later than one year after the date of the implementation of the portal under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="United We Stand to Hire Veterans Act/s:2/ss:b" proposed="true">subsection (b)</cato:entity-ref>, the Secretaries shall submit to the appropriate committees of <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> a report on the portal.</text>
        </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H4CA920F00D5445C08E773EE0512AF965">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <header>Elements</header>
          <text>Each report under this subsection shall include a description of the portal and such other information on the portal as the Secretaries consider appropriate.</text>
        </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HF10C028FBCEC4908B84FC18405146857">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
          <header>Appropriate committees of Congress defined</header>
          <text>In this subsection, the term <term>appropriate committees of Congress</term> means—</text>
<subparagraph id="HA17679FD342B4E3B8EA54DEAF94E8907">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="committee" entity-id="SSAS00">Committee on Armed Services</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="committee" entity-id="SSHR00">Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="committee" entity-id="SSVA00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</cato:entity-ref>, and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="committee" entity-id="SSAP00">Committee on Appropriations of the Senate</cato:entity-ref>; and</text>
          </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H182204F7A856490CA530569E2AFACA08">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="committee" entity-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="committee" entity-id="HED00">Committee on Education and the Workforce</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="committee" entity-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</cato:entity-ref>, and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="committee" entity-id="HAP00">Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
    </section>
</legis-body>
</bill>
</doc>