<doc>
  <docmeta id="113hr5547ih">
    <bill congress="113" type="hr" number="5547" version="ih"/>
    <revision size="18416" annotations="0" status="complete" id="6" commit-time="2014-10-20T16:20:55Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113hr5547ih/6.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HCD738B7B8F91401CA2E52896B1685E63" public-private="public">
	<metadata>
<dublinCore>
<dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">113 HR 5547 IH: Community Integration Act of 2014</dc:title>
<dc:publisher xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">2014-09-18</dc:date>
<dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>113th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>2d Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 5547</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20140918">September 18, 2014</action-date>
			<action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="C001090">Mr. Cartwright</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="M001149">Mr. Michaud</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>
      </action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To ensure that Medicaid beneficiaries have the opportunity to receive care in a home and
			 community-based setting.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="HD56EF7E2A1D845E18E732A55C6242030" style="OLC">
		<section id="H65E8793F26AA48F3A9589516D3BA1CE8" section-type="section-one">
      <enum>1.</enum>
      <header>Short title</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote>
          <short-title>
            <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Community Integration Act of 2014" proposed="true">Community Integration Act of 2014</cato:entity-ref>
          </short-title>
        </quote>.</text>
		</section>
    <section id="H4497E03BCDEB45E3A9DC5ACFE5BBFBB6">
      <enum>2.</enum>
      <header>Findings</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text>
			<paragraph id="HEA5F842D13334E96AAE04E3B326FB39A">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text>The Supreme Court's 1999 decision in Olmstead v. L.C., 527 U.S. 581 (1999), held that the
			 unnecessary segregation of individuals with disabilities is a violation of
			 the <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990">Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12101">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/42/12101/etseq">42 U.S.C. 12101 et seq.</cato:entity-ref>
          </external-xref>)</cato:entity>.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H566C2460F1C942AA8AAF84D78058D343">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text>Under Olmstead, individuals generally have the right to receive their supports and services in home
			 and community-based settings, rather than in institutional settings, if
			 they so choose.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HA63ADC04597144868CAC46B202D01BC8">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <text>Olmstead envisioned that States would provide appropriate long-term services and supports to
			 individuals with disabilities through home and community-based services
			 and end forced segregation in nursing homes and other institutions.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HE4143B884BF7466FBD00F5986FFD4D4F">
        <enum>(4)</enum>
        <text>While there has been progress in rebalancing State spending on individuals with disabilities in
			 institutions as compared to home and community-based settings, more than
			 75 percent of States continue to spend the majority of their long-term
			 care dollars on nursing homes and other institutional settings, and the
			 number of individuals with disabilities under age 65 in nursing homes
			 increased between 2008 and 2012.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HDD75AE12938947A8B33CE349CFB6A326">
        <enum>(5)</enum>
        <text>As of June 2013, there were more than 200,000 individuals younger than age 65 in nursing
			 homes—almost 16 percent of the total nursing home population.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H8A1FA102CEA44FD9B92E4489B6B735C2">
        <enum>(6)</enum>
        <text>Thirty-eight studies published from 2005 to 2012 concluded that providing services in home and
			 community-based settings is less costly than providing care in a nursing
			 home or other institutional setting.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H7AEB5AED99494AF38F006472AAAA8C1B">
        <enum>(7)</enum>
        <text>No clear or centralized reporting system exists to compare how effectively States are meeting the
			 Olmstead mandate.</text>
			</paragraph>
    </section>
    <section id="H9FDF9722D82B44A0950EAEEA031C4560">
      <enum>3.</enum>
      <header>Ensuring Medicaid beneficiaries may elect to receive care in a home and community-based setting</header>
			<subsection id="H2C0FE7A0E7A74316B440A60FC3503182">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>In general</header>
        <text>
          <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Social Security Act/s:1902/ss:a">Section 1902(a) of the Social Security Act</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396a">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/42/1396a/a">42 U.S.C. 1396a(a)</cato:entity-ref>
          </external-xref>)</cato:entity> is amended—</text>
				<paragraph id="HBB527D86D6104923813AF1CA453CCF54">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>in paragraph (80), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H4A13350C1F9E4500A5EAD8E398FF7E1A">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>in paragraph (81), by striking the period and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H1A4D5280C11940049004C7F0DBFD521C">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <text>by inserting after paragraph (81) the following new paragraph:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6C08417A21664FE98339BEF4D1DC4112" style="OLC">
						<paragraph id="HD681D44DB71D42C9A1F0593F87DB9B08">
              <enum>(82)</enum>
              <text>in the case of any individual with respect to whom there has been a determination that the
			 individual requires the level of care provided in a nursing facility,
			 intermediate care facility for the mentally retarded, institution for
			 mental disease, or other similarly restrictive or institutional setting—</text>
							<subparagraph id="HCC15F1A764F14728B8AACAFC6D719C4B">
                <enum>(A)</enum>
                <text>provide the individual with the choice and opportunity to receive such care in a home and
			 community-based setting, including rehabilitative services, assistance and
			 support in accomplishing activities of daily living, instrumental
			 activities of daily living, and health-related tasks, and assistance in
			 acquiring, maintaining, or enhancing skills necessary to accomplish such
			 activities, tasks, or services;</text>
							</subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="H4F9A2E0221EF41A5896FDAFCB5ACE582">
                <enum>(B)</enum>
                <text>ensure that each such individual has an equal opportunity (when compared to the receipt and
			 availability of nursing facility services) to receive care in a home and
			 community-based setting, if the individual so chooses, by ensuring that
			 the provision of such care in a home and community-based setting is widely
			 available on a statewide basis for all such individuals within the State;
			 and</text>
							</subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="H78710D75707349FF8946CB67ABDCD3E9">
                <enum>(C)</enum>
                <text>meet the requirements of <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Social Security Act/s:1904A" proposed="true">section 1904A</cato:entity-ref> (relating to the provision of care in a home and
			 community-based setting).</text>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
          </quoted-block>
				</paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="H97AFB60F9E224B46995ECDA6B084A738">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Requirements for community care options</header>
        <text>
          <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Social Security Act/t:XIX">Title XIX of the Social Security Act</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/42/1396/etseq">42 U.S.C. 1396 et seq.</cato:entity-ref>
          </external-xref>)</cato:entity> is amended by inserting after <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Social Security Act/s:1904">section
			 1904</cato:entity-ref> the following new section:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCBDA9BAF0F0F4DBF87E61E3A8C8CAA4B" style="traditional">
					<section id="H51A746EBC96B40288B99AAD2C6CE29E4">
            <enum>1904A.</enum>
            <header>Provisions related to home and community-based care</header>
            <subsection commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HDC8D907829104E68ABA5CCD8A654B2CE">
              <enum>(a)</enum>
              <header>Definitions</header>
              <text>For purposes of this section, <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Social Security Act/s:1902/ss:a/p:82" proposed="true">section 1902(a)(82)</cato:entity-ref>, and <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Social Security Act/s:1905/ss:a/p:4/sp:A">section 1905(a)(4)(A)</cato:entity-ref>:</text>
							<paragraph id="HECC4868E0C86466E95FB310625C6C738">
                <enum>(1)</enum>
                <header>Activities of daily living</header>
                <text>The term <term>activities of daily living</term> includes, but is not limited to, tasks such as eating, toileting, grooming, dressing, bathing, and
			 transferring.</text>
							</paragraph>
              <paragraph id="H1FC3043D5FD5433A80077B7641517BD9">
                <enum>(2)</enum>
                <header>Health-related tasks</header>
                <text>The term <term>health-related tasks</term> means specific tasks related to the needs of an individual, including, but not limited to, bowel
			 or bladder care, wound care, use and care of ventilators and feeding
			 tubes, and the administration of medications and injections, which, in the
			 opinion of the individual's physician, can be delegated to be performed by
			 an attendant.</text>
							</paragraph>
              <paragraph id="HD2864D6F95FA45A289971C2EDAC9169D">
                <enum>(3)</enum>
                <header>Home and community-based setting</header>
                <text>The term <term>home and community-based setting</term> means, with respect to an individual who requires a level of care provided in a nursing facility,
			 intermediate care facility for the mentally retarded, institution for
			 mental disease, or other similarly restrictive or institutional setting, a
			 setting that—</text>
								<subparagraph id="HE0FDBC96495C48928F7B973F14CF3FAD">
                  <enum>(A)</enum>
                  <text>includes a house, apartment, townhouse, condominium, or similar public or private housing where the
			 individual resides that—</text>
									<clause id="H4FE613C1508B4231BFD72102EE4A67C3">
                    <enum>(i)</enum>
                    <text>is owned or leased by the individual or a member of the individual’s family;</text>
									</clause>
                  <clause id="HE81C518F91FD43D4A1A9E0F210DACEDE">
                    <enum>(ii)</enum>
                    <text>ensures the individual’s privacy, dignity, respect, and freedom from coercion; and</text>
									</clause>
                  <clause id="H24CCC53D8E4C4D03BB904FA30B57FC14">
                    <enum>(iii)</enum>
                    <text>maximizes the individual’s autonomy and independence;</text>
									</clause>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="H8976E0E719D24EAE90408AB9269BD7BE">
                  <enum>(B)</enum>
                  <text>is integrated in, and provides access to, the general community in which the setting is located so
			 that the individual has access to the community and opportunities to seek
			 employment and work in competitive integrated settings, participate in
			 community life, control and utilize personal resources, benefit from
			 community services, and participate in the community in an overall manner
			 that is comparable to that available to individuals who are not
			 individuals with disabilities; and</text>
								</subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="H312B97CCB5754F8CA8152148C77C62DC">
                  <enum>(C)</enum>
                  <text>has the services and supports that the individual needs in order to live as independently as
			 possible.</text>
								</subparagraph>
              </paragraph>
              <paragraph id="HA247BB0EADC243B0A9E0F098B253819D">
                <enum>(4)</enum>
                <header>Instrumental activities of daily living</header>
                <text>The term <term>instrumental activities of daily living</term> means activities related to living independently in the community and includes, but is not limited
			 to, meal planning and preparation, managing finances, shopping for food,
			 clothing, and other items, performing household chores, communicating by
			 phone or other media, and traveling around and participating in the
			 community.</text>
							</paragraph>
              <paragraph id="H5501C17D33E6493F984BD4CA366D3905">
                <enum>(5)</enum>
                <header>Public entity</header>
                <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>public entity</term> means a public entity as defined in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990/s:201/p:1/sp:A">subparagraphs (A)</cato:entity-ref> and <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990/s:201/p:1/sp:B">(B) of section 201(1) of the Americans
			 with Disabilities Act of 1990</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
							</paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="H6B9D6B6BC77045AE8CCE1CD88063EB5A">
              <enum>(b)</enum>
              <header>Requirements for providing services in home and community-Based settings</header>
              <text>With respect to the availability and provision of services under the State plan under this title,
			 or under any waiver of State plan requirements (subject to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Community Integration Act of 2014/s:3/ss:d" proposed="true">section 3(d) of
			 the <short-title>Community Integration Act of 2014</short-title>
                </cato:entity-ref>), in a home and community-based setting to any individual who requires a level of care provided in
			 a nursing facility, intermediate care facility for the mentally retarded,
			 institution for mental disease, or other similarly restrictive or
			 institutional setting, any public entity that receives payment under the
			 State plan or waiver for providing services to such an individual shall
			 not—</text>
							<paragraph id="H5A0260146FE845669C66DD3C83465F32">
                <enum>(1)</enum>
                <text>impose or utilize policies, practices, or procedures, such as unnecessary requirements or arbitrary
			 service or cost caps, that limit the availability of services in home and
			 community-based settings to an individual with a disability (including
			 individuals with the most significant disabilities) who need such
			 services;</text>
							</paragraph>
              <paragraph id="H1765B9D027264A8E8A89AD3E40EB0E7D">
                <enum>(2)</enum>
                <text>impose or utilize policies, practices, or procedures that limit the availability of services in a
			 home and community-based setting (including assistance and support in
			 accomplishing activities of daily living, instrumental activities of daily
			 living, health-related tasks, and rehabilitative services) based on the
			 specific disability of an otherwise eligible individual;</text>
							</paragraph>
              <paragraph id="H3EF8308622F441A682DE83B81EE97503">
                <enum>(3)</enum>
                <text>impose or utilize policies, practices, or procedures that arbitrarily restrict an individual with a
			 disability from full and meaningful participation in community life;</text>
							</paragraph>
              <paragraph id="H6CACC73C7F8F4F439041CD29C13E7AC8">
                <enum>(4)</enum>
                <text>impose or utilize policies, practices, or procedures that unnecessarily delay or restrict the
			 provision of services in a home and community-based setting to any
			 individual who requires such services;</text>
							</paragraph>
              <paragraph id="H523035DB72E0484D94AE0A6FA62255AD">
                <enum>(5)</enum>
                <text>fail to establish and utilize adequate payment structures to maintain a sufficient workforce to
			 provide services in home and community-based settings to any individual
			 who requires such services;</text>
							</paragraph>
              <paragraph id="H1570F65A6F6F436490CEE72A158871A5">
                <enum>(6)</enum>
                <text>fail to provide information, on an ongoing basis, to help any individual who receives care in a
			 nursing facility, intermediate care facility for the mentally retarded,
			 institution for mental disease, or other similarly restrictive or
			 institutional setting, understand the individual's right to choose to
			 receive such care in a home and community-based setting; or</text>
							</paragraph>
              <paragraph id="H404AF60A439A4306996CDAB67EAA9F65">
                <enum>(7)</enum>
                <text>fail to provide information to help any individual that requires the level of care provided in a
			 nursing facility, intermediate care facility for the mentally retarded,
			 institution for mental disease, or other similarly restrictive or
			 institutional setting, prior to the individual's placement in such a
			 facility or institution, understand the individual's right to choose to
			 receive such care in a home and community-based setting.</text>
							</paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="H49253CD7B23043E0A5ACFBF36EDA63B4">
              <enum>(c)</enum>
              <header>Plan To increase affordable and accessible housing</header>
              <text>Not later than 180 days after the enactment of this section, each State shall develop a statewide
			 plan to increase the availability of affordable and accessible private and
			 public housing stock for individuals with disabilities (including
			 accessible housing for individuals with physical disabilities and those
			 using mobility devices).</text>
						</subsection>
            <subsection id="H4203E950148D46C6A2CB0C23CF7170DF">
              <enum>(d)</enum>
              <header>Availability of remedies and procedures</header>
							<paragraph id="H051C992D2F5845308ED80344CD5B697F">
                <enum>(1)</enum>
                <header>In general</header>
                <text>The remedies and procedures set forth in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990/s:203">sections 203</cato:entity-ref> and <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990/s:505">505 of the Americans with Disabilities
			 Act of 1990</cato:entity-ref> shall be available to any person aggrieved by the failure of—</text>
								<subparagraph id="HC2BEE743DF57496B8AC71E6836E087CD">
                  <enum>(A)</enum>
                  <text>a State to comply with this section or <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Social Security Act/s:1902/ss:a/p:82" proposed="true">section 1902(a)(82)</cato:entity-ref>; or</text>
								</subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="H1AB88D1905114D92AF40C26123289A83">
                  <enum>(B)</enum>
                  <text>a public entity (including a State) to comply with the requirements of subsection (b).</text>
								</subparagraph>
              </paragraph>
              <paragraph id="H1E4F322F55A84FC696403E0729A31678">
                <enum>(2)</enum>
                <header>Rule of construction</header>
                <text>Nothing in paragraph (1) shall be construed to limit any remedy or right of action that otherwise
			 is available to an aggrieved person under this title.</text>
							</paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="HFC61A04D75DC44AEA1BAE30F3C45DF2E">
              <enum>(e)</enum>
              <header>Enforcement by the Secretary</header>
							<paragraph id="HF33C6DE4A8504AC390D435382F778738">
                <enum>(1)</enum>
                <header>In general</header>
                <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> may reduce the Federal matching assistance percentage applicable to the State (as
			 determined under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Social Security Act/s:1905/ss:b">section 1905(b)</cato:entity-ref>) if the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> determines that the
			 State has violated the requirements of subsection (b).</text>
							</paragraph>
              <paragraph id="H92787CCD9C19462187A5955CE94D6833">
                <enum>(2)</enum>
                <header>Rule of construction</header>
                <text>Nothing in paragraph (1) shall be construed to limit any remedy or right of action that is
			 otherwise available to the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
							</paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="HDA29D7B6DC71499D8E5CC9A7B59B3861">
              <enum>(f)</enum>
              <header>Reporting requirements</header>
              <text>With respect to fiscal year 2016, and for each fiscal year thereafter, each State shall submit to
			 the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Administration for Community Living " entity-parent-id="7500">Administrator of the Administration for Community Living of the
			 Department of Health and Human Services</cato:entity-ref>, not later than April 1 of the
			 succeeding fiscal year, a report, in such form and manner as the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref>
			 shall require, that includes—</text>
							<paragraph id="H5849C08C0886492ABE86CB23D5B3D722">
                <enum>(1)</enum>
                <text>the total number of individuals enrolled in the State plan or under a waiver of the plan during
			 such fiscal year that required the level of care provided in a nursing
			 facility, intermediate care facility for the mentally retarded,
			 institution for mental disease, or other similarly restrictive or
			 institutional setting, disaggregated by the type of facility or setting;</text>
							</paragraph>
              <paragraph id="H11DEC12B1F6D4671B4D3D317637660AF">
                <enum>(2)</enum>
                <text>with respect to the total number described in paragraph (1), the total number of individuals
			 described in that paragraph who received care in a nursing facility,
			 intermediate care facility for the mentally retarded, institution for
			 mental disease, or other similarly restrictive or institutional setting,
			 disaggregated by the type of facility or setting; and</text>
							</paragraph>
              <paragraph id="H73D1A82E4E1148D6B8C6CFFA9A14724F">
                <enum>(3)</enum>
                <text>with respect to the total number described in paragraph (2), the total number of individuals
			 described in that paragraph who were transitioned from a nursing facility,
			 intermediate care facility for the mentally retarded, institution for
			 mental disease, or other similarly restrictive or institutional setting to
			 a home and community-based setting, dis­ag­gre­gated by the type of home
			 and community-based setting.</text>
              </paragraph>
            </subsection>
          </section>
          <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
        </quoted-block>
			</subsection>
      <subsection id="H72D32EB1DECA4CC8A123B2BA267737B1">
        <enum>(c)</enum>
        <header>Inclusion as a mandatory service</header>
        <text>
          <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Social Security Act/s:1905/ss:a/p:4/sp:A">Section 1905(a)(4)(A) of the Social Security Act</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396d">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/42/1396d/a/4/A">42 U.S.C. 1396d(a)(4)(A)</cato:entity-ref>
          </external-xref>)</cato:entity> is amended by striking <quote>other than</quote> and inserting <quote>including similar services such as rehabilitative services and assistance and support in
			 accomplishing activities of daily living, instrumental activities of daily
			 living, and health-related tasks, that are provided, at the individual's
			 option, in a home and community-based setting (as defined in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Social Security Act/s:1904A/ss:a/p:3" proposed="true">section
			 1904A(a)(3)</cato:entity-ref>), but not including</quote>.</text>
			</subsection>
      <subsection id="HC8C716B9F4244185892F6F0C5E60B065">
        <enum>(d)</enum>
        <header>Application to waivers</header>
        <text>Notwithstanding <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Social Security Act/s:1904A" proposed="true">section 1904A of the Social Security Act</cato:entity-ref> (as added by subsection (b)), such
			 section, and <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Social Security Act/s:1902/ss:a/p:82" proposed="true">sections 1902(a)(82)</cato:entity-ref>, and <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Social Security Act/s:1905/ss:a/p:4/sp:A">1905(a)(4)(A) of the Social
			 Security Act</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396">
            <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc/42/1396/etseq">42 U.S.C. 1396 et seq.</cato:entity-ref>
          </external-xref>), as amended by subsections (a) and
			 (c), respectively, shall not apply to any individuals who are eligible for
			 medical assistance for home and community-based services under a waiver
			 under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Social Security Act/s:1115">section 1115</cato:entity-ref> or <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Social Security Act/s:1915">1915 of the Social Security Act</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1315">
            <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc/42/1315">42 U.S.C. 1315</cato:entity-ref>
          </external-xref>,
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc/42/1396n">1396n</cato:entity-ref>) and who are receiving such services, to the extent such sections
			 (as so added or amended) are inconsistent with any such waiver.</text>
			</subsection>
      <subsection id="H78C22C774C844A469619C9AE00DBF1D9">
        <enum>(e)</enum>
        <header>Effective date</header>
				<paragraph id="H523C793D6577412D80AABA8186C6BFDF">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>In general</header>
          <text>Except as provided in paragraph (2), the amendments made by this section shall take effect on
			 October 1, 2014.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HEAEB470D3B414F03843056456439B4CE">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Delay permitted if State legislation required</header>
          <text>In the case of a State plan under <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Social Security Act/s:1902">section 1902 of the Social Security Act</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396a">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/42/1396a">42 U.S.C. 1396a</cato:entity-ref>
            </external-xref>)</cato:entity> which
			 the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="7500" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of Health and Human Services</cato:entity-ref> determines requires State
			 legislation (other than legislation appropriating funds) in order for the
			 plan to meet the additional requirements imposed by the amendments made by
			 this section, the State plan shall not be regarded as failing to comply
			 with the requirements of <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Social Security Act/s:1902">such section 1902</cato:entity-ref> solely on the basis of the
			 failure of the plan to meet such additional requirements before the 1st
			 day of the 1st calendar quarter beginning after the close of the 1st
			 regular session of the State legislature that begins after the date of
			 enactment of this Act. For purposes of the previous sentence, in the case
			 of a State that has a 2-year legislative session, each year of such
			 session shall be deemed to be a separate regular session of the State
			 legislature.</text>
				</paragraph>
      </subsection>
    </section>
  </legis-body>
</bill>
</doc>