<doc>
  <docmeta id="113hr2973ih">
    <bill congress="113" type="hr" number="2973" version="ih"/>
    <revision size="15189" annotations="0" status="complete" id="3" commit-time="2013-08-22T22:54:28Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113hr2973ih/3.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H2E8F644ADEC84F1C826727B211C77F55" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>113 HR 2973 IH: Hudson-Mohawk River Basin Act of 2013</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2013-08-01</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>113th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 2973</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20130801">August 1, 2013</action-date>
			<action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="T000469">Mr. Tonko</sponsor> introduced
			 the following bill; which was referred to the
			 <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural
			 Resources</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on
			 <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Transportation and
			 Infrastructure</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by
			 the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within
			 the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To authorize the Secretary of Interior to carry out
		  projects and conduct research on water resources in the Hudson-Mohawk River
		  Basin, to establish a Hudson-Mohawk River Basin Commission, and for other
		  purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H3AA300E9CBB1493FAA103C715FCF673B" style="OLC">
		<section id="H0DC8EB296B2E43EF800321B47710ABD5" section-type="section-one">
      <enum>1.</enum>
      <header>Short title</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the
			 <quote>
          <short-title>Hudson-Mohawk River Basin Act of
			 2013</short-title>
        </quote>.</text>
		</section>
    <section id="HAE3D5733BF7A485B97C546B4DB609624" section-type="subsequent-section">
      <enum>2.</enum>
      <header>Findings</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">
        <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> finds the following:</text>
			<paragraph id="H4FFC900AF5274FE7AF486A2ACC87C3BA">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Hudson-Mohawk River Basin together with
			 the Erie Canal connects the Great Lakes to the Atlantic Ocean and includes the
			 13,400 square mile area encompassing five large sub-basins: the Upper Hudson
			 River sub-basin, the Mohawk River sub-basin, the Lower Hudson River sub-basin,
			 the Passaic River sub-basin, and the Raritan River sub-basin.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H672C4D8F5E13468F965F2E1752905644">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text>The Hudson-Mohawk
			 River Basin played an essential role in the birth of our Nation and its
			 westward expansion. The water of the Hudson-Mohawk Basin is the ink used to
			 write the early United States history of European settlement and the American
			 Revolution. The Basin’s rivers served as a major transportation corridor
			 connecting the communities along it from the Atlantic Ocean to the Great
			 Lakes.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H4871D52656C24C26A2EFDF931D8C184A">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <text>The Hudson-Mohawk
			 River Basin includes the largest metropolitan area of the country: the New
			 York-New Jersey metropolitan area. This metropolitan area, together with the
			 many communities in the Upper Hudson, Mohawk, and Lower Hudson sub-basins,
			 makes the area one of the most densely and heavily populated river basins in
			 the country with over 15,000,000 people.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H317B0EBBAC0A4C81B897427FD65C3CDE">
        <enum>(4)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The water resources of the Hudson-Mohawk
			 River Basin are functionally interrelated and their uses are interdependent. A
			 single entity is essential to provide effective communication, coordination,
			 and cooperation among Federal, State, and local governments, non-governmental
			 organizations, and the private sector for this area.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HB11D5EBD85E2441690F5435CADF17A64">
        <enum>(5)</enum>
        <text>The New York-New
			 Jersey Harbor Estuary is a complex natural harbor at the junction of three
			 major water bodies, the New York Bight, the Hudson River and the Long Island
			 Sound. In addition, it receives freshwater inputs from the Raritan and Passaic
			 Rivers. The health and productivity of the New York Bight is affected directly
			 by the quality of the freshwater inputs to the estuary from the Hudson,
			 Passaic, and Raritan Rivers.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H00437F51FC4C4CE5BEC46092CC634832">
        <enum>(6)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The headwaters of the Hudson originate
			 within the Adirondack Mountains, a treasured northeastern wilderness area,
			 protected under the New York State constitution since 1894. The Hudson’s path
			 south through the Hudson River Highlands, and the Mohawk’s path south east to
			 its junction with the Hudson, provides the only natural break in the
			 Appalachian Mountain chain.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H83DF46D23CFC41E8838AFF3742DF6A6B">
        <enum>(7)</enum>
        <text>The Mohawk
			 Valley’s abundant natural resources, and fertile floodplain soils provided a
			 rich endowment that first supported the Mohawk nation and the Iroquois
			 Confederacy and later supported European settlement and the development of
			 industry and commerce.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H6A554D5E1C1E43C487B064DD9A1CB086">
        <enum>(8)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Mohawk River and its watershed drain
			 directly into the Hudson River providing the largest freshwater input to the
			 brackish water mix that characterizes the Hudson River Estuary and supports a
			 biologically rich and productive ecosystem.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H3B40F77A189D400DBF93436689DEFCE9">
        <enum>(9)</enum>
        <text>The Mohawk River
			 is integrated with the Erie Canal along much of its channel. Therefore, tying
			 the operation of the Canal system to the health of the Mohawk and the Hudson
			 Rivers.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HFFBDCAAD86A248D38A24E1D04A429592">
        <enum>(10)</enum>
        <text>Individuals in
			 many communities throughout the Basin have experienced devastating flooding
			 that led to tremendous costs for businesses, State, and local governments. A
			 holistic approach to river and stream monitoring, updated floodplain maps, and
			 development of floodplain management strategies based upon improved
			 understanding of the Basin’s hydrology would make communities safer and more
			 resistant and resilient to flood events.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H2A0DA7E62000454B8FDE713E072FB768">
        <enum>(11)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Climate change is occurring and, as a
			 result, sea level rise along the United States eastern coastline will increase
			 the vulnerability of coastal communities to storm surge and flooding in the New
			 York-New Jersey harbors and along the major rivers in the Basin.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H934CE9856A2947ABBC6089D7F7BCCDB3">
        <enum>(12)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each of the subwatersheds of the
			 Hudson-Mohawk River Basin receives support of programs administered by Federal,
			 State, regional, and local organizations.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HBDC11C4A56A1470A9749AEFA0CF9D5B5">
        <enum>(13)</enum>
        <text>There has been
			 little integration of planning and program implementation to address the
			 Hudson-Mohawk River Basin in a holistic manner.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H7BC82E850E1E4237B2BB9400A4FEF302">
        <enum>(14)</enum>
        <text>New York, New
			 Jersey, Vermont, Massachusetts, and Connecticut have a long history of
			 achievements working together on resource management issues through their
			 memberships in the Delaware River Basin Commission, the Susquehanna River Basin
			 Commission, the Appalachian Regional Commission, the New England Interstate
			 Water Pollution Control Commission, and the Lake Champlain Basin
			 Program.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HF9E96AE85D22412E892C872970004F72">
        <enum>(15)</enum>
        <text>The basin-wide
			 impacts experienced as a result of recent hurricanes and storms illustrate the
			 need for integrated, basin-wide planning to address water management challenges
			 and vulnerability to flooding.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H59CD80CD9C04462FB4C6A01C66BB9D1A">
        <enum>(16)</enum>
        <text>Protection and
			 restoration of wetlands, expanded use of green infrastructure, strengthening of
			 dams and levees, and upgrading of wastewater and water treatment infrastructure
			 will be necessary to reduce the impacts of extreme weather events and maintain
			 water quality and public health.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H960FBB8E9D2B47AC9610F116F88D03F2">
        <enum>(17)</enum>
        <text>Development and
			 implementation of projects to control flooding and improve water quality must
			 be done with the full participation of local communities and citizens, address
			 the needs they identify, and be conducted in a manner that respects private
			 property and is consistent with the authorities of state and local
			 jurisdictions.</text>
			</paragraph>
    </section>
    <section id="H384F68C06AFA43ADB498F89D966168F4">
      <enum>3.</enum>
      <header>Definitions</header>
			<subsection commented="no" id="H9DC87456450C4E93BD814BDC8CCD9BB7">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Hudson-Mohawk
			 river basin</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term
			 <term>Hudson-Mohawk River Basin</term> means the area of drainage of the
			 Hudson, Mohawk, Passaic and Raritan Rivers and their tributaries into the New
			 York-New Jersey Harbor Estuary. This includes areas in New York, New Jersey,
			 Vermont, Massachusetts, and Connecticut.</text>
			</subsection>
      <subsection id="HE051F1C0D3214FC886F34EB4F3F67B22">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Commission</header>
        <text>The
			 term <term>Commission</term> means the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Hudson-Mohawk River Basin Commission" proposed="true">Hudson-Mohawk River Basin Commission</cato:entity-ref>
			 established under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Hudson-Mohawk River Basin Act of 2013/s:4" proposed="true">section 4</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
			</subsection>
      <subsection id="HA8220093151D47A8B7F2B2E1F65A53A8">
        <enum>(c)</enum>
        <header>Water
			 resources</header>
        <text>The term <term>water resources</term> means all surface
			 waters and ground waters contained or otherwise originating within the
			 Hudson-Mohawk River Basin.</text>
			</subsection>
    </section>
    <section id="HDA1BE262E49C47609D1CDD725193DAD3">
      <enum>4.</enum>
      <header>Hudson-Mohawk
			 River Basin Commission</header>
			<subsection id="HCC95F12245544B41AA36891FB841622F">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Establishment</header>
        <text>The
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> shall—</text>
				<paragraph id="H5234C1E5B2364FB08EEE9E864409E0C6">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>establish the
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Hudson-Mohawk River Basin Commission" proposed="true">Hudson-Mohawk River Basin Commission</cato:entity-ref> in cooperation with the Governors of the
			 States included in the Hudson-Mohawk River Basin to coordinate activities being
			 undertaken by the States, advisory committees, local governments, institutions
			 of higher education, and non-governmental organizations to address
			 environmental, economic, and cultural issues associated with the management and
			 use of resources in the Hudson-Mohawk Watershed; and</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H423CDB9B25A64313990BC13DDD35FCA1">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>designate the
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1400">Secretary of Interior</cato:entity-ref> to serve as a member of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Hudson-Mohawk River Basin Commission" proposed="true">Commission</cato:entity-ref> and as coordinator
			 of participation of relevant Federal agencies in the activities of the
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Hudson-Mohawk River Basin Commission" proposed="true">Commission</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
				</paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="H701FC92862EF4ADF9595E59133F20F40">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Membership</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Hudson-Mohawk River Basin Commission" proposed="true">Commission</cato:entity-ref> shall include a Federal
			 representative designated by the President, and the Governors of the 5 States
			 whose territory is encompassed by the Hudson-Mohawk River Basin and its
			 associated ground waters: New York, New Jersey, Connecticut, Massachusetts, and
			 Vermont. The Governor of each of the 5 States shall appoint an alternate to act
			 on that Governor’s behalf, including attendance at meetings of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Hudson-Mohawk River Basin Commission" proposed="true">Commission</cato:entity-ref>
			 and with the power to vote in the absence of the member.</text>
			</subsection>
      <subsection id="H48839376B2424CC589740AB33C58CB5D">
        <enum>(c)</enum>
        <header>Duties of the
			 Commission</header>
        <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Hudson-Mohawk River Basin Commission" proposed="true">Commission</cato:entity-ref> shall—</text>
				<paragraph id="HB40B6EB86B7342DCB38D004DAF61E0D2">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">develop and implement plans, policies, and
			 projects relating to the water resources of the Hudson-Mohawk River
			 Basin;</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H7F586090EAC24E39A6B6DA7242FEF2EF">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">adopt and promote uniform and coordinated
			 policies for management and conservation of water resources in the
			 Hudson-Mohawk River Basin;</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HE5C93B89E08C434286928D3A28B1E870">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <text>adopt an annual
			 capital budget, including all projects the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Hudson-Mohawk River Basin Commission" proposed="true">Commission</cato:entity-ref> proposes to undertake or
			 continue during the budget period with a statement of the estimated cost of
			 each project and the method of financing the project; and</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HEFF50DF055E341998746C0A13FC6D0CD">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
          <text>coordinate and
			 direct the development, implementation, operation, and financing of water
			 resources projects consistent with its plans and policies.</text>
				</paragraph>
      </subsection>
    </section>
    <section id="HA22ED7C5343144EAA1413D3759C592E4">
      <enum>5.</enum>
      <header>Comprehensive
			 plan</header>
			<subsection id="HC700A6DF197D42EB918159BD9051CB79">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Plan
			 development</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 18
			 months after the date of the enactment of this Act, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Hudson-Mohawk River Basin Commission" proposed="true">Commission</cato:entity-ref> shall
			 develop and adopt a comprehensive plan for the development and use of water
			 resources of the Hudson-Mohawk River Basin. In developing the plan the
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Hudson-Mohawk River Basin Commission" proposed="true">Commission</cato:entity-ref> shall—</text>
				<paragraph id="H8CD407208D444081A5E137719EE54EDC">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>consult with State
			 and Federal agencies with jurisdiction over water resources, local governments,
			 non-governmental organizations, public utilities, water users, and other
			 interested parties;</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H7397192A5FF949639BF69D3124D4EB2A">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>prior to adoption
			 of the plan or any subsequent revision of the plan, publish a draft plan and
			 provide opportunity for public comment;</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H09DF075AB2CE48A9A6445FB861049FEA">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <text>ensure that the
			 plan addresses needs in each of the five sub-basins; and</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H36CBD9C7EEA545238A0ECE044E2FBD70">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
          <text>periodically
			 review and revise the plan.</text>
				</paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="HA675F309BDA841B7A067FD46DE29CB33">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Plan
			 contents</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The plan shall
			 address all projects and facilities required for development, conservation,
			 use, management, and control of the water resources of the Hudson-Mohawk River
			 Basin to meet present and future needs. The plan shall—</text>
				<paragraph id="HCE520145704E4836A92EB66F3F1E08D9">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">identify water resource needs in the
			 Hudson-Mohawk River Basin related to water supply, water quality, flooding,
			 ecosystems, fisheries, energy production, navigation, recreation, agriculture,
			 and economic development and establish goals for protection or enhancement of
			 water resources to address the identified needs;</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H86E7FAFE0F984C57A70CEBEDFCB8F8ED">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">inventory the historic and cultural
			 resources of the Hudson-Mohawk River Basin and identify projects to provide for
			 cultural enrichment, preservation of cultural resources, public education about
			 local heritage and historical significance of properties, canals, and other
			 historic sites within the Hudson-Mohawk River Basin;</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HEABA1AF6A3354C068ED62F56BD17F979">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide a comprehensive assessment of the
			 status of water resources in the Hudson-Mohawk River Basin and identify
			 additional research and information required to support management of water
			 resources in the Hudson-Mohawk River Basin; and</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HBBC83D784CD14965BA23E078A689707C">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide a mechanism to promote
			 communication and coordination among the organizations engaged in water
			 resource management activities to encourage efficient use of scarce resources,
			 avoid conflicts and inconsistencies, to promote consistent and fair treatment
			 of all water users, and to promote collaborative working relationships among
			 all entities working in the Hudson-Mohawk River Basin.</text>
				</paragraph>
      </subsection>
    </section>
    <section id="H364C5B89E876478593A402348B1A4830">
      <enum>6.</enum>
      <header>Water resources
			 program</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Hudson-Mohawk River Basin Commission" proposed="true">Commission</cato:entity-ref> shall
			 adopt a water resources program on an annual basis, based upon the
			 comprehensive plan, that identifies specific projects and facilities to be
			 undertaken by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Hudson-Mohawk River Basin Commission" proposed="true">Commission</cato:entity-ref>, other governmental and private entities,
			 educational institutions, non-governmental organizations, and individuals
			 during the immediate 5-year period in each of the five sub-basins. The water
			 resources program shall include a systematic presentation for each of the five
			 sub-basins of—</text>
			<paragraph id="H4854229B8D814AC8A4146ABA1B5A7401">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text>the specific needs
			 to be addressed by the water resources program;</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H530BBE942B544F36B6631101C21786EF">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text>the existing and
			 proposed projects, studies, and facilities required to satisfy the identified
			 needs;</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HE54AC28802A0449181EBE29581C6BA04">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <text>the subset of
			 projects and studies that will be undertaken by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Hudson-Mohawk River Basin Commission" proposed="true">Commission</cato:entity-ref> during such
			 period; and</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H37C6D828C1654BF996D7435159881342">
        <enum>(4)</enum>
        <text>the budget for the
			 identified projects and studies.</text>
			</paragraph>
    </section>
    <section id="HE9BCD532D0024A28B07E36695D3512DB">
      <enum>7.</enum>
      <header>Savings
			 provisions</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this Act
			 shall be construed to repeal, modify, or limit the authority of—</text>
			<paragraph id="H7ACC76C0EBAF451E910085C73BF38183">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text>the Federal
			 Government or the State government members of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Hudson-Mohawk River Basin Commission" proposed="true">Commission</cato:entity-ref> to enact
			 legislation or enforce any additional conditions or restrictions within their
			 jurisdictions; and</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HBE0E1E9C3CB24230B9293DA039026088">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text>local governments
			 to regulate land use as provided for by law or regulation.</text>
			</paragraph>
    </section>
    <section commented="no" id="HBF276D7E788C4007923F93A4810D3514">
      <enum>8.</enum>
      <header>Authorization of
			 appropriations</header>
			<subsection id="HFBF83F22341E40D4B600ABF1A6C12197">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Commission</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">
          <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="auth-auth-approp">There is authorized to be appropriated to
			 the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" value="Hudson-Mohawk River Basin Commission" proposed="true">Commission</cato:entity-ref> <cato:funds-and-year amount="500000" year="2014,..">$500,000 for each fiscal year</cato:funds-and-year> <cato:property name="purpose">to carry out the duties of the
			 <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" value="Hudson-Mohawk River Basin Commission" proposed="true">Commission</cato:entity-ref>
            </cato:property>.</cato:entity>
        </text>
			</subsection>
      <subsection id="HC509DF0810994965B25A785483E1E298">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Comprehensive
			 plan</header>
        <text>
          <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="auth-auth-approp">There is authorized to be appropriated to the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1400">Secretary of
			 Interior</cato:entity-ref> <cato:funds-and-year amount="25000000" year="2015, 2016, 2017, 2018, 2019, 2020, 2021">$25,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2015 through 2021</cato:funds-and-year> <cato:property name="purpose">to carry out
			 projects consistent with the comprehensive plan that are identified in the
			 annual Hudson-Mohawk Water Resources Program adopted by the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" value="Hudson-Mohawk River Basin Commission" proposed="true">Commission</cato:entity-ref> in
			 accordance with <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Hudson-Mohawk River Basin Act of 2013/s:6" proposed="true">section 6</cato:entity-ref>
            </cato:property>.</cato:entity>
        </text>
			</subsection>
    </section>
  </legis-body>
</bill>
</doc>