<doc>
  <docmeta id="113hres438eh">
    <bill congress="113" type="hres" number="438" version="eh"/>
    <revision size="6324" annotations="0" status="complete" id="5" commit-time="2014-01-02T23:19:53Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113hres438eh/5.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <resolution xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" dms-id="Hf56019d2-5ccb-4354-aa6b-604cb0509adc" key="H" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Engrossed-in-House" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" stage-count="1"> 
<metadata>
<dublinCore>
<dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">113 HRES 438 EH: Providing for consideration of the Senate amendment to the joint resolution (H.J. Res. 59) making continuing appropriations for fiscal year 2014, and for other purposes; providing for consideration of motions to suspend the rules; providing for proceedings during the period from December 14, 2013, through January 6, 2014; and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">2013-12-12</dc:date>
<dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="no">IV</distribution-code>
<congress display="no">113th CONGRESS</congress>
<session display="no">1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. RES. 438</legis-num>
<current-chamber display="yes">In the House of Representatives, U. S.,</current-chamber>
<action>
<action-date date="20131212">December 12, 2013</action-date>
</action>
<legis-type display="yes">RESOLUTION</legis-type>
<official-title display="no">Providing for consideration of the Senate amendment to the joint resolution (H.J. Res. 59) making continuing appropriations for fiscal year 2014, and for other purposes; providing for consideration of motions to suspend the rules; providing for proceedings during the period from December 14, 2013, through January 6, 2014; and for other purposes.</official-title>
</form>
<resolution-body id="H93e83310-12bf-44b7-b4bd-4d107280e2e6" style="traditional">
<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="Ha1d21eaa-5ce4-46fd-b9ac-ab080d518999" section-type="undesignated-section">
      <enum/>
      <text>That upon adoption of this resolution it shall be in order to take from the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" value="Speaker of the House of Representatives" entity-parent-id="0050">Speaker's</cato:entity-ref> table the joint resolution (<cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="113 HJRES 59" proposed="true">H.J. Res. 59</cato:entity-ref>) making continuing appropriations for fiscal year 2014, and for other purposes, with the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0050">House</cato:entity-ref> amendment to the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0010">Senate</cato:entity-ref> amendment thereto, and to consider in the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0050">House</cato:entity-ref>, without intervention of any point of order, a motion offered by the chair of the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="committee" entity-id="HBU00">Committee on the Budget</cato:entity-ref> or his designee that the House recede from its amendment and concur in the Senate amendment with the amendment printed in part A of the report of the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="committee" entity-id="HRU00">Committee on Rules</cato:entity-ref> accompanying this resolution modified by the amendment printed in part B of that report. The <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0010">Senate</cato:entity-ref> amendment and the motion shall be considered as read. The motion shall be debatable for 70 minutes, with 60 minutes equally divided and controlled by the chair and ranking minority member of the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="committee" entity-id="HBU00">Committee on the Budget</cato:entity-ref> and 10 minutes equally divided and controlled by the chair and ranking minority member of the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="committee" entity-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</cato:entity-ref>. The previous question shall be considered as ordered on the motion to its adoption without intervening motion or demand for division of the question.</text>
    </section>
<section id="H751DA549CC944FC8ABB6EE5C2FEDD4C2">
      <enum>2.</enum>
      <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The chair of the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="committee" entity-id="HBU00">Committee on the Budget</cato:entity-ref> may insert in the Congressional Record at any time during the remainder of the first session of the 113th Congress such material as he may deem explanatory of the motion specified in the first section of this resolution.</text>
    </section>
<section id="HBF5FF65A4E70486A877A271ECA805CB5">
      <enum>3.</enum>
      <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the engrossment of the House amendment to the Senate amendment to <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="113 HJRES 59" proposed="true">House Joint Resolution 59</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" value="Clerk of the House of Representatives" entity-parent-id="0050">Clerk</cato:entity-ref> may conform division, title, and section numbers and conform cross-references and provisions for short titles.</text>
    </section>
<section id="HA64198DA4CB64BA099F62FC53BBFE237">
      <enum>4.</enum>
      <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The chair of the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="committee" entity-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</cato:entity-ref> may insert in the Congressional Record at any time during the remainder of the first session of the 113th Congress such material as he may deem explanatory of defense authorization measures for the fiscal year 2014.</text>
    </section>
<section id="H38B649784E294736A14797D197AA8AB6">
      <enum>5.</enum>
      <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It shall be in order at any time on the legislative day of December 12, 2013, or December 13, 2013, for the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" value="Speaker of the House of Representatives" entity-parent-id="0050">Speaker</cato:entity-ref> to entertain motions that the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0050">House</cato:entity-ref> suspend the rules as though under clause 1 of rule XV. The <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" value="Speaker of the House of Representatives" entity-parent-id="0050">Speaker</cato:entity-ref> or his designee shall consult with the Minority Leader or her designee on the designation of any matter for consideration pursuant to this section.</text>
    </section>
<section id="H13B6FE9FCAD9486CA321BBDE3D78DFB0">
      <enum>6.</enum>
      <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">On any legislative day of the first session of the One Hundred Thirteenth Congress after December 13, 2013—</text>
<subsection id="H453DC60779A84C3DA29774265F77FDE9">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <text>the Journal of the proceedings of the previous day shall be considered as approved; and</text>
      </subsection>
<subsection id="H6B5406D9B27E43309B1B1A3EC189F53D">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <text>the Chair may at any time declare the House adjourned to meet at a date and time, within the limits of clause 4, section 5, article I of the Constitution, to be announced by the Chair in declaring the adjournment.</text>
      </subsection>
    </section>
<section id="HE3DF0218B8CA4FB2AF4CCCEE91005DCE">
      <enum>7.</enum>
      <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">On any legislative day of the second session of the One Hundred Thirteenth Congress before January 7, 2014—</text>
<subsection id="H55846ACE32744C76B66735FBACE25C65">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <text>the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" value="Speaker of the House of Representatives" entity-parent-id="0050">Speaker</cato:entity-ref> may dispense with organizational and legislative business;</text>
      </subsection>
<subsection id="H96958044B0F142F6A10987F2BFC039A0">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <text>the Journal of the proceedings of the previous day shall be considered as approved if applicable; and</text>
      </subsection>
<subsection id="H08ED4C08636E4615B934D906BF86B2EB">
        <enum>(c)</enum>
        <text>the Chair at any time may declare the House adjourned to meet at a date and time, within the limits of clause 4, section 5, article I of the Constitution, to be announced by the Chair in declaring the adjournment.</text>
      </subsection>
    </section>
<section id="H68D8FDAC38084F93B43A8A0BA3034080">
      <enum>8.</enum>
      <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" value="Speaker of the House of Representatives" entity-parent-id="0050">Speaker</cato:entity-ref> may appoint Members to perform the duties of the Chair for the duration of the period addressed by <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="113 HJRES 438/s:6" proposed="true">sections 6</cato:entity-ref> and <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="113 HJRES 438/s:7" proposed="true">7</cato:entity-ref> as though under clause 8(a) of rule I.</text>
    </section>
<section id="H1FA1D850AC0748A8947F25BE4CAF4EC0">
      <enum>9.</enum>
      <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each day during the period addressed by <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="113 HJRES 438/s:6" proposed="true">sections 6</cato:entity-ref> and <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="113 HJRES 438/s:7" proposed="true">7 of this resolution</cato:entity-ref> shall not constitute a calendar day for purposes of <cato:entity entity-type="law-citation">
          <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="War Powers Resolution/s:7">section 7 of the War Powers Resolution</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1546">
          <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/50/1546">50 U.S.C. 1546</cato:entity-ref>
        </external-xref>)</cato:entity>.</text>
    </section>
<section id="H6CD2E0019CDA4D6DA9C99F9DF16A820E">
      <enum>10.</enum>
      <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon adoption of this resolution it shall be in order to consider in the House the bill (<cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="113 HR 3695" proposed="true">H.R. 3695</cato:entity-ref>) to provide a temporary extension of the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Food, Conservation, and Energy Act of 2008">Food, Conservation, and Energy Act of 2008</cato:entity-ref> and amendments made by that Act, as previously extended and amended and with certain additional modifications and exceptions, to suspend permanent price support authorities, and for other purposes. All points of order against consideration of the bill are waived. The amendment printed in part C of the report of the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="committee" entity-id="HRU00">Committee on Rules</cato:entity-ref> accompanying this resolution shall be considered as adopted. The bill, as amended, shall be considered as read. All points of order against provisions in the bill, as amended, are waived. The previous question shall be considered as ordered on the bill, as amended, and on any amendment thereto to final passage without intervening motion except: (1) 40 minutes of debate equally divided and controlled by the chair and ranking minority member of the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="committee" entity-id="HAG00">Committee on Agriculture</cato:entity-ref>; and (2) one motion to recommit with or without instructions.</text>
    </section>
<section id="H41A1A5C25C1D447CA779E356042B40E0">
      <enum>11.</enum>
      <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The requirement of clause 6(a) of rule XIII for a two-thirds vote to consider a report from the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="committee" entity-id="HRU00">Committee on Rules</cato:entity-ref> on the same day it is presented to the House is waived with respect to any resolution reported through the legislative day of December 13, 2013.</text>
    </section>
</resolution-body>
<attestation>
    <attestation-group>
      <attestor display="no">Karen L. Haas,</attestor>
      <role>Clerk.</role>
    </attestation-group>
  </attestation>
</resolution>
</doc>