<doc>
  <docmeta id="113hres385eh">
    <bill congress="113" type="hres" number="385" version="eh"/>
    <revision size="4717" annotations="0" status="complete" id="4" commit-time="2014-02-13T21:35:26Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113hres385eh/4.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <resolution xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" dms-id="H63aa4ed9-c5f4-40ed-8f46-8081ecac0cbb" key="H" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Engrossed-in-House" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" stage-count="1"> 
<metadata>
<dublinCore>
<dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">113 HRES 385 EH: Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 3080) to provide for improvements to the rivers and harbors of the United States, to provide for the conservation and development of water and related resources, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">2013-10-23</dc:date>
<dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="no">IV</distribution-code>
<congress display="no">113th CONGRESS</congress>
<session display="no">1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. RES. 385</legis-num>
<current-chamber display="yes">In the House of Representatives, U. S.,</current-chamber>
<action>
<action-date date="20131023">October 23, 2013</action-date>
</action>
<legis-type display="yes">RESOLUTION</legis-type>
<official-title display="no">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 3080) to provide for improvements to the rivers and harbors of the United States, to provide for the conservation and development of water and related resources, and for other purposes.</official-title>
</form>
<resolution-body id="Hd8087ee2-172e-4cd9-8de8-9555af46b1b7" style="traditional">
<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H7b6a201f-41ef-4f4d-acd7-c7b5e1e50d40" section-type="undesignated-section">
      <enum/>
      <text>That at any time after the adoption of this resolution the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" value="Speaker of the House of Representatives" entity-parent-id="0050">Speaker</cato:entity-ref> may, pursuant to clause 2(b) of rule XVIII, declare the House resolved into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for consideration of the bill (<cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="113 HR 3080" proposed="true">H.R. 3080</cato:entity-ref>) to provide for improvements to the rivers and harbors of the United States, to provide for the conservation and development of water and related resources, and for other purposes. The first reading of the bill shall be dispensed with. All points of order against consideration of the bill are waived. General debate shall be confined to the bill and shall not exceed one hour equally divided and controlled by the chair and ranking minority member of the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="committee" entity-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</cato:entity-ref>. After general debate the bill shall be considered for amendment under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </section>
<section id="H3C765815696A423E92AED766A4B2408A">
      <enum>2.</enum>
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H6D1EB7BF87F84B39B37FC10ECA6CB849">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In lieu of the amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="committee" entity-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</cato:entity-ref> now printed in the bill, it shall be in order to consider as an original bill for the purpose of amendment under the five-minute rule an amendment in the nature of a substitute consisting of the text of Rules Committee Print 113–24. That amendment in the nature of a substitute shall be considered as read. All points of order against that amendment in the nature of a substitute are waived.</text>
      </subsection>
<subsection id="H1585B6420C3544F39893AD17E016B1A3">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <text>No amendment to the amendment in the nature of a substitute made in order as original text shall be in order except those printed in the report of the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="committee" entity-id="HRU00">Committee on Rules</cato:entity-ref> accompanying this resolution and amendments en bloc described in <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="113 HRES 395/s:3" proposed="true">section 3 of this resolution</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
      </subsection>
<subsection id="H704095F6F5EE45A28BA941CA302DF673">
        <enum>(c)</enum>
        <text>Each amendment printed in the report of the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="committee" entity-id="HRU00">Committee on Rules</cato:entity-ref> shall be considered only in the order printed in the report, may be offered only by a Member designated in the report, shall be considered as read, shall be debatable for the time specified in the report equally divided and controlled by the proponent and an opponent, shall not be subject to amendment, and shall not be subject to a demand for division of the question in the House or in the Committee of the Whole.</text>
      </subsection>
<subsection id="H645E5593D0B9482EACC168442EF1BC23">
        <enum>(d)</enum>
        <text>All points of order against amendments printed in the report of the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="committee" entity-id="HRU00">Committee on Rules</cato:entity-ref> or amendments en bloc described in <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="113 HRES 395/s:3" proposed="true">section 3</cato:entity-ref> of this resolution are waived.</text>
      </subsection>
    </section>
<section id="H44F9F70CC0BD41E8B96D1930265A80A5">
      <enum>3.</enum>
      <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It shall be in order at any time for the chair of the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="committee" entity-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</cato:entity-ref> or his designee to offer amendments en bloc consisting of amendments printed in the report of the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="committee" entity-id="HRU00">Committee on Rules</cato:entity-ref> accompanying this resolution not earlier disposed of. Amendments en bloc offered pursuant to this section shall be considered as read, shall be debatable for 10 minutes equally divided and controlled by the chair and ranking minority member of the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="committee" entity-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</cato:entity-ref> or their designees, shall not be subject to amendment, and shall not be subject to a demand for division of the question in the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0050">House</cato:entity-ref> or in the Committee of the Whole. The original proponent of an amendment included in such amendments en bloc may insert a statement in the Congressional Record immediately before the disposition of the amendments en bloc.</text>
    </section>
<section id="H077DB72ABA52487AB09086C31600DB9E">
      <enum>4.</enum>
      <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">At the conclusion of consideration of the bill for amendment the Committee shall rise and report the bill to the House with such amendments as may have been adopted. Any Member may demand a separate vote in the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0050">House</cato:entity-ref> on any amendment adopted in the Committee of the Whole to the bill or to the amendment in the nature of a substitute made in order as original text. The previous question shall be considered as ordered on the bill and amendments thereto to final passage without intervening motion except one motion to recommit with or without instructions.</text>
    </section>
</resolution-body>
<attestation>
    <attestation-group>
      <attestor display="no">Karen L. Haas,</attestor>
      <role>Clerk.</role>
    </attestation-group>
  </attestation>
</resolution>
</doc>