<doc>
  <docmeta id="113hr1144ih">
    <bill congress="113" type="hr" number="1144" version="ih"/>
    <revision size="9223" annotations="0" id="7" commit-time="2013-04-15T01:50:13+00:00" committer="favila" doc="113hr1144ih/7.xml" status="complete">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HD703DFEFF42D465D991AEC0E17C4E178" key="H" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>113 HR 1144 IH: Alabama-Coushatta Tribe of Texas Equal and Fair Opportunity Settlement Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date/>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>113th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 1144</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date>March 13, 2013</action-date>
			<action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="S000937">Mr. Stockman</sponsor>
			 introduced the following bill; which was referred to the
			 <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural
			 Resources</committee-name>
      </action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To restore an opportunity for tribal economic development
		  on terms that are equal and fair, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H9B9E693FC6F345B0876C4AE03C739AA1" style="OLC">
		<section id="H9A010D1A3C224019BD8807FE4A4A8A3A" section-type="section-one">
      <enum>1.</enum>
      <header>Short title</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the
			 <quote>
          <short-title>Alabama-Coushatta Tribe of Texas Equal
			 and Fair Opportunity Settlement Act</short-title>
        </quote>.</text>
		</section>
    <section id="H848A3B68C9294B498BF0339CB3C68546">
      <enum>2.</enum>
      <header>Congressional
			 findings and declaration of policy</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">
        <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> finds and declares that:</text>
			<subsection id="HDD13092DE5504AD288DC65C3C07F7636">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Findings and
			 declarations</header>
				<paragraph id="H8633B2823EAC477ABAC78D6569284236">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>It is the policy
			 of the United States to promote tribal self-determination and economic
			 self-sufficiency and to support the resolution of disputes over historical
			 claims.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HA0A34674B4D948AA95C01CA0FCEBEFE0">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>Sam Houston, as a
			 leader in the Texas Revolution and the President of the Republic of Texas,
			 established friendly relations with the tribes, expressed his personal
			 appreciation for the assistance of the tribes during the fight for Texas
			 independence, and endeavored to protect their lands and rights.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H3EECB80E42E34B38BE951290234C537B">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <text>The United States,
			 pursuant to Federal law and in accordance with several Federal court decisions,
			 has affirmed the rights of tribes, including the Alabama-Coushatta Tribe of
			 Texas (<term>Alabama-Coushatta Tribe</term>), to free and undisturbed use and
			 occupancy of its aboriginal lands, including the right to compensation when
			 those rights are violated.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="id06E9E81E9C584CA4ABD5AB11AFBAD259">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
          <text>The
			 Alabama-Coushatta Tribe holds aboriginal title to land in southeastern Texas
			 that has been subject to illegal trespass and use, depriving the
			 Alabama-Coushatta Tribe of critical economic development opportunities,
			 including valuable timber production and oil and gas leasing.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HD61682141F6D4789BAA85DB229D3D8A3">
          <enum>(5)</enum>
          <text>In June 2000, the
			 United States Court of Federal Claims ruled that the Alabama-Coushatta Tribe
			 retained aboriginal title to 5.5 million acres of land in southeastern Texas.
			 In its decision, the Court also ruled that the United States is responsible for
			 the Tribe's loss of use of more than 2.85 million acres.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HDDCE7271E7B14AA7931F7429CE16E8FA">
          <enum>(6)</enum>
          <text>In October 2002,
			 the United States Court of Federal Claims adopted the sum of Two Hundred
			 Seventy Million Six Hundred Thousand Dollars ($270,600,000) as the jointly
			 stipulated amount of economic damages to be recovered by the Alabama-Coushatta
			 Tribe from the United States.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H536B70E4FE1B4A5790319197A0C85F19">
          <enum>(7)</enum>
          <text>There is pending
			 before the United States District Court for the Eastern District of Texas a
			 lawsuit by the Alabama-Coushatta Tribe, seeking declaratory and injunctive
			 relief based on the United States failure to discharge its fiduciary duty to
			 the Tribe.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H2609CECE61844ECEB926DD375333F0F9">
          <enum>(8)</enum>
          <text>Despite the
			 Alabama-Coushatta Tribe's strongly held beliefs about the rights it possesses
			 regarding its aboriginal lands, the Tribe has decided to forego, relinquish,
			 waive, and otherwise disclaim any such rights, on the condition that Congress
			 authorize a restoration of its Federal status, as hereinafter described.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H3C7F2583752740F9B953E9EC765F0C9B">
          <enum>(9)</enum>
          <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref>
			 shares with the State of Texas and the parties to this litigation a desire to
			 empower the Alabama-Coushatta Tribe to govern its own economic future and
			 appreciates the Tribe's willingness to forego its aboriginal rights in exchange
			 for improved economic self-sufficiency.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HA4D3E39B4ED14BCCA63FC480D4FEE5D7">
          <enum>(10)</enum>
          <text>This legislation
			 represents a good faith effort on the part of <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> to provide the
			 Alabama-Coushatta Tribe with an economic development opportunity under the same
			 terms and conditions as other federally recognized Indian tribes, in exchange
			 for the Tribe's agreement to relinquish its rights as described above.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H7F540DC917E04ABD8A3329BE00A49F14">
          <enum>(11)</enum>
          <text>In the absence of
			 Congressional action, these land claims and related claims will be pursued
			 through the courts, a process which in all likelihood will consume many years
			 and thereby promote hostility and uncertainty in the State of Texas, to the
			 ultimate detriment of the Alabama-Coushatta Tribe, its members, and all other
			 citizens of the State of Texas.</text>
				</paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="HC045C56C67AD40B191D20762D64EA20C">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Purposes</header>
        <text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the purpose of this subchapter—</text>
				<paragraph id="HDB25A29F313D463DB38506DB92D84422">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>to recognize the
			 Alabama-Coushatta Tribe's loss of its aboriginal lands and the resulting loss
			 of any economically productive use of those lands for decades;</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H07C5BBBCE7694403BB5AC15D21809F36">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>to restore an
			 economic development opportunity to the Alabama-Coushatta Tribe on terms that
			 are equal and fair;</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H62A099DFB9F946009B5474DB8762E55D">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <text>to resolve
			 questions about the rights and obligations of those landowners in Texas that
			 hold title subject to the Tribe's aboriginal title; and</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HACD7C954186A4D138A383EDC5046F33F">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to insulate the Federal Government and
			 taxpayers from potentially greater and ongoing liability from these
			 claims.</text>
				</paragraph>
      </subsection>
    </section>
    <section id="H6692BC7D2DB14F428DDAEC390562B106">
      <enum>3.</enum>
      <header>Restoration Act
			 amendment</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">For the purpose of
			 restoring an economic development opportunity on terms that are equal and fair,
			 <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
          <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Alabama-Coushatta Tribes of Texas Restoration Act/s:207">Section 207 of the Alabama-Coushatta Tribes of Texas Restoration Act</cato:entity-ref>, <cato:entity-ref entity-type="public-law" value="public-law/100/89">Public
			 Law 100–89</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/737">25 U.S.C. 737</external-xref>)</cato:entity> is hereby deleted.</text>
		</section>
    <section id="H6C290D65677140E5A2F7B47A12717319">
      <enum>4.</enum>
      <header>Judgment and
			 dismissal of litigation</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not
			 later than six months after the date of enactment, the United States and the
			 Alabama-Coushatta Tribe of Texas shall execute and file with the United States
			 District Court for the Eastern District of Texas in the pending litigation a
			 motion for entry of final judgment in accordance with the terms of this
			 subchapter.</text>
		</section>
    <section id="HC502CD28AB244F2B8B4E0BEC9B73C9B1">
      <enum>5.</enum>
      <header>Approval of prior
			 transfers and extinguishment of claims and aboriginal title</header>
			<subsection id="HFE1288393BF045FE86988D230103069A">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Approval and
			 ratification of prior transfers</header>
        <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Any invalid transfer before the date of the
			 introduction of this legislation of land or natural resources located within
			 the State of Texas, including but not limited to transfers pursuant to a
			 statute or treaty of, or with, any State or the United States, from, by, or on
			 behalf of the Alabama-Coushatta Tribe of Texas, or any predecessor in interest
			 or any of its members, shall be deemed to have been made in compliance with the
			 Constitution and all laws of the United States. <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> hereby does approve
			 and ratify any such invalid transfer effective as of the date of said
			 transfer.</text>
			</subsection>
      <subsection id="H27DC2555D76E4A639B9B032835FB013B">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Extinguishment
			 of aboriginal title</header>
        <text display-inline="no-display-inline">By virtue
			 of the approval and ratification of a transfer of land or natural resources
			 effected by <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Alabama-Coushatta Tribe of Texas Equal and Fair Opportunity Settlement Act/s:5/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a) of this section</cato:entity-ref>, any aboriginal title held by the
			 Alabama-Coushatta Tribe of Texas, or any predecessor in interest or any of its
			 members, to any land or natural resources the transfer of which was approved
			 and ratified by <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Alabama-Coushatta Tribe of Texas Equal and Fair Opportunity Settlement Act/s:5/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a) of this section</cato:entity-ref> shall be regarded as
			 extinguished as of the date of such transfer.</text>
			</subsection>
      <subsection id="HA686DA68193948739657778E099CDDF1">
        <enum>(c)</enum>
        <header>Extinguishment
			 of claims</header>
        <text display-inline="no-display-inline">By virtue of the
			 approval and ratification of a transfer of land or natural resources effected
			 by this section, or the extinguishment of aboriginal title effected hereby, any
			 claim (including any claim for damages for trespass or for use and occupancy)
			 by, or on behalf of, the Alabama-Coushatta Tribe of Texas, or any predecessor
			 in interest or any of its members, against the United States or the State of
			 Texas which is based on—</text>
				<paragraph id="H1296A0A4D14145B594D2523ABB2F3E03">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>any interest in or
			 right involving any land or natural resources the transfer of which was
			 approved and ratified by <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Alabama-Coushatta Tribe of Texas Equal and Fair Opportunity Settlement Act/s:5/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a) of this section</cato:entity-ref>, or</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H37A6D49DA3CC4BE0BB3FDAA5F23E8884">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>any aboriginal
			 title to land or natural resources the extinguishment of which was effected by
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Alabama-Coushatta Tribe of Texas Equal and Fair Opportunity Settlement Act/s:5/ss:b" proposed="true">subsection (b) of this section</cato:entity-ref>,</text>
				</paragraph>
        <continuation-text continuation-text-level="subsection">shall be
			 regarded as extinguished as of the date of any such transfer.</continuation-text>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="HC02442AEF2C94180B7C728260F99E2B5">
        <enum>(d)</enum>
        <header>Savings
			 provisions</header>
				<paragraph id="H90ABC3ED644241BBA4BBAA7DCDA86F35">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>Nothing in this
			 section shall be construed to affect or eliminate the personal claim of an
			 individual Indian (except for a Federal common law fraud claim) which is
			 pursued under any law of general applicability that protects non-Indians as
			 well as Indians.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HB57E08511B994CAB963618565FEC919B">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>Nothing in this
			 subchapter is intended to alter the status of lands held in trust by the United
			 States on behalf of the Alabama-Coushatta Tribe of Texas.</text>
				</paragraph>
      </subsection>
    </section>
  </legis-body>
</bill>
</doc>