<doc>
  <docmeta id="113hr3661ih">
    <bill congress="113" type="hr" number="3661" version="ih"/>
    <revision size="5961" annotations="0" status="complete" id="3" commit-time="2013-12-10T22:32:19Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113hr3661ih/3.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H356F366CA071477E99F88CFBF9B4A2CE" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata>
<dublinCore>
<dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">113 HR 3661 IH: Public Access to Public Land Guarantee Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">2013-12-05</dc:date>
<dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>113th CONGRESS</congress>
<session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. R. 3661</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20131205">December 5, 2013</action-date> 
<action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="G000565">Mr. Gosar</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="K000368">Mrs. Kirkpatrick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000255">Mr. Jones</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001177">Mr. McClintock</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="F000448">Mr. Franks of Arizona</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Agriculture</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To authorize the Secretary of the Interior or the Secretary of Agriculture to enter into agreements with States and political subdivisions of States providing for the continued operation, in whole or in part, of public land, units of the National Park System, units of the National Wildlife Refuge System, and units of the National Forest System in the State during any period in which the Secretary of the Interior or the Secretary of Agriculture is unable to maintain normal level of operations at the units due to a lapse in appropriations, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="HA568D1A9B85B46EC9E3A9CFD7419AF58" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H7E1D6ADACF754ACD9E3D1EC821153539" section-type="section-one">
      <enum>1.</enum>
      <header>Short title</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote>
          <short-title>Public Access to Public Land Guarantee Act</short-title>
        </quote>.</text>
    </section> 
<section id="H2F77D59CCBEE4DD5BB5D50DCDED8645D">
      <enum>2.</enum>
      <header>Findings</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">
        <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> finds that—</text> 
<paragraph id="HA2E7D63C98234A30982C59997703B07B">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text>public land in the United States is managed and administered for the use and enjoyment of present and future generations;</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD0E146B347F243EF86D73B4815CE5DF9">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text>the National Park System (including National Parks, National Monuments, and National Recreation Areas) is managed for the benefit and inspiration of all the people of the United States;</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA27FC9C9A021482581A480CA8C65EDCE">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <text>the National Wildlife Refuge System is administered for the benefit of present and future generations of people in the United States, with priority consideration for compatible wildlife-dependent general public uses of the National Wildlife Refuge System;</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF9233CC6FD2C4998AF8A1C8E7FE75B77">
        <enum>(4)</enum>
        <text>the National Forest System is dedicated to the long-term benefit of present and future generations; and</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE6484F2931EB4272921B9227C366E5CA">
        <enum>(5)</enum>
        <text>the reopening and temporary operation and management of public land, the National Park System, the National Wildlife Refuge System, and the National Forest System using funds from States and political subdivisions of States during periods in which the Federal Government is unable to operate and manage the areas at normal levels due to a lapse in appropriations is consistent with the values and purposes for which those areas were established.</text>
      </paragraph>
    </section> 
<section id="HF4D91E3F7A2C4B1CBA700B9D999AC746">
      <enum>3.</enum>
      <header>Definitions</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> 
<paragraph id="H67F117C20B894683AD1852A606BC8E6A">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <header>Covered unit</header>
        <text>The term <term>covered unit</term> means—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HAE6082AD44AD42B78E351541F2561111">
          <enum>(A)</enum>
          <text>public land;</text>
        </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H4D74F14F98154C3395ED5DFE5EAFA5C3">
          <enum>(B)</enum>
          <text>units of the National Park System;</text>
        </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9928ED00A74241638CA42B9490919406">
          <enum>(C)</enum>
          <text>units of the National Wildlife Refuge System; or</text>
        </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H79BD48EC61264648826AA662E9197657">
          <enum>(D)</enum>
          <text>units of the National Forest System.</text>
        </subparagraph>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB1D18378801E434383CD5CAE187130C3">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <header>Public land</header>
        <text>The term <term>public land</term> has the meaning given the term <term>public lands</term> in <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976/s:103">section 103 of the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1702">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/43/1702">43 U.S.C. 1702</cato:entity-ref>
            </external-xref>)</cato:entity>.</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H37D555AE71F0466F821DAA398C1861B8">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <header>Secretary</header>
        <text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H0C304C9061714BF89CA529244F3A98A6">
          <enum>(A)</enum>
          <text>the Secretary of the Interior, with respect to land under the jurisdiction of the Secretary of the Interior; or</text>
        </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HAA62BD24359C4385A51C396B3EF1CDBC">
          <enum>(B)</enum>
          <text>the Secretary of Agriculture, with respect to land under the jurisdiction of the Secretary of Agriculture.</text>
        </subparagraph>
      </paragraph>
    </section> 
<section id="H5A911E5F910C4CE493179C9788CBEA36">
      <enum>4.</enum>
      <header>Agreement to keep public land open during a government shutdown</header> 
<subsection id="HC711E04B356E4B6E980295179998FC64">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>In general</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Public Access to Public Land Guarantee Act/s:4/ss:b" proposed="true">subsection (b)</cato:entity-ref>, if a State or political subdivision of the State offers, the Secretary shall enter into an agreement with the State or political subdivision of the State under which the United States may accept funds from the State or political subdivision of the State to reopen, in whole or in part, any covered unit within the State or political subdivision of the State during any period in which there is a lapse in available funds for the covered unit as a result of a failure to enact a regular appropriations bill or continuing resolution.</text>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="H4603CD6F08F74B2184C5A634A7E09C80">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Applicability</header>
        <text>The authority under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Public Access to Public Land Guarantee Act/s:4/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref> shall only be in effect during any period in which the Secretary is unable to operate and manage covered units at normal levels, as determined in accordance with the terms of agreement entered into under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Public Access to Public Land Guarantee Act/s:4/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="HD0352AEC795E4F0B98D4F3089D8DD5A9">
        <enum>(c)</enum>
        <header>Refund</header>
        <text>The Secretary shall refund to the State or political subdivision of the State all amounts provided to the United States under an agreement entered into under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Public Access to Public Land Guarantee Act/s:4/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref>—</text> 
<paragraph id="HC5F83E06EF45497D8F0D1827645D3450">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>on the date of enactment of an Act retroactively appropriating amounts sufficient to maintain normal operating levels at the covered unit reopened under an agreement entered into under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Public Access to Public Land Guarantee Act/s:4/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref>; or</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF00E95D30CEC42CC80CA01A2FA1D4A53">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>on the date on which the State or political subdivision establishes, in accordance with the terms of the agreement, that, during the period in which the agreement was in effect, fees for entrance to, or use of, the covered units were collected by the Secretary.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="HC5CBA4BD131D4862AF06AB0A20958A09">
        <enum>(d)</enum>
        <header>Voluntary reimbursement</header>
        <text>If the requirements for a refund under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Public Access to Public Land Guarantee Act/s:4/ss:c" proposed="true">subsection (c)</cato:entity-ref> are not met, the Secretary may, subject to the availability of appropriations, reimburse the State and political subdivision of the State for any amounts provided to the United States by the State or political subdivision under an agreement entered into under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Public Access to Public Land Guarantee Act/s:4/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
      </subsection>
    </section> 
</legis-body> 
</bill>
</doc>