<doc>
  <docmeta id="113hr3536ih">
    <bill congress="113" type="hr" number="3536" version="ih"/>
    <revision size="18449" annotations="0" status="complete" id="3" commit-time="2013-11-25T20:58:48Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113hr3536ih/3.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H6C2498B4775349BFB5E5D42A92B04002" public-private="public">
  <metadata>
<dublinCore>
<dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">113 HR 3536 IH: Support Our Students Act of 2013</dc:title>
<dc:publisher xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">2013-11-19</dc:date>
<dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
    <congress>113th CONGRESS</congress>
    <session>1st Session</session>
    <legis-num>H. R. 3536</legis-num>
    <current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
    <action>
      <action-date date="20131119">November 19, 2013</action-date>
      <action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="B001281">Mrs. Beatty</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001185">Ms. Sewell of Alabama</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000565">Mr. Loebsack</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001090">Mr. Cartwright</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and the Workforce</committee-name>
      </action-desc>
    </action>
    <legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
    <official-title>To amend the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to support teacher and school professional training on awareness of student mental health conditions and suicide prevention efforts.</official-title>
  </form>
  <legis-body id="H65896707685340B0B00E99EDE12977BB" style="OLC">
    <section id="HA5C94BF014C94E58842DA865F6EEDF90" section-type="section-one">
      <enum>1.</enum>
      <header>Short title</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote>
          <short-title>Support Our Students Act of 2013</short-title>
        </quote> or the <quote>
          <short-title>S.O.S. Act of 2013</short-title>
        </quote>.</text>
    </section>
    <section id="H21B920379A45421B96ABBCB772556737">
      <enum>2.</enum>
      <header>Findings</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">
        <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> finds the following:</text>
      <paragraph id="HE90DEA29E194475383E76B8249AC10E9">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text>Approximately 1 in 5 children have a diagnosable mental illness.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HD915E00AF2C74704AC051D7ADC62BF19">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Fifty percent of all lifetime cases of lived experience of mental illness begin by age 14, and 75 percent by age 24.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H9F6D60B4E01943D9BB5A726FAA67A8FC">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <text>Fifty percent of students with a mental illness, age 14 years and older, drop out of high school.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H7F4CDB5CEC6A4EA9994AA5E9FB20E659">
        <enum>(4)</enum>
        <text>One in 10 children and adolescents suffer from mental illness severe enough to cause some level of impairment, but only 1 in 5 of such children receive specialty mental health services.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H0F5582B571904D6093AFCBC0330E6089">
        <enum>(5)</enum>
        <text>For youth between the ages of 10 and 24, suicide is the third leading cause of death, and an estimated 90 percent have a diagnosable mental health condition.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H12474E85FC6A4A50AA4B7D743F1CF23B">
        <enum>(6)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Annually, approximately 4,600 youth die as a result of suicide and another 156,000 youth ages 10 to 24 are treated for self-inflicted injuries at emergency rooms.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H9BE0497572DA471D81CE844CD090762E">
        <enum>(7)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The overwhelming majority of individuals including teens, who attempt suicide, have one or more psychiatric or mental health conditions.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H407E362DEF7D4CC48AB2B0615AC31C3E">
        <enum>(8)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Suicide prevention and awareness efforts are key in combating this often preventable loss of life.</text>
      </paragraph>
    </section>
    <section id="HEC26ED569A534CEE8C3F555500487E76">
      <enum>3.</enum>
      <header>Training teachers and school professionals in understanding mental health conditions in children</header>
      <subsection id="HA28C1FD652D4416F957DBB3E4E158055">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>In general</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">
          <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965/t:IV/pt:A/spt:2">Subpart 2 of part A of title IV of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7131">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/20/7131/etseq">20 U.S.C. 7131 et seq.</cato:entity-ref>
            </external-xref>)</cato:entity> is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
        <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA6A81B5BC47340C884A0405F91DD503C" style="OLC">
          <section id="H7A9CCA991E8348CA9D6323F8C6512E38">
            <enum>4131.</enum>
            <header>Training teachers and school professionals in understanding mental health conditions in children</header>
            <subsection id="HBB2C335703B543C8A7C6E5BF056A2FDD">
              <enum>(a)</enum>
              <header>Program authorized</header>
              <paragraph id="HE3A1413964FB4D5E9E2D93746AAE41FD">
                <enum>(1)</enum>
                <header>In general</header>
                <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="9100">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall award grants to eligible State educational agencies to enable such agencies to award subgrants to eligible local educational agencies to support an existing, or develop a new, program that will educate teachers, school personnel, and specialized instructional support personnel on mental health conditions in children, including the causes, symptoms, and impact on learning.</text>
              </paragraph>
              <paragraph id="H4B751084F2534ACA8AC5235536CB8D1A">
                <enum>(2)</enum>
                <header>Definitions</header>
                <text>In this section:</text>
                <subparagraph id="HDFB6061E27624157A402E4BD7CCC8515">
                  <enum>(A)</enum>
                  <header>Eligible local educational agency</header>
                  <text>The term <term>eligible local educational agency</term> means a local educational agency or a local educational agency in partnership with a mental health organization, family advocacy organization, or community nonprofit organization.</text>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="H1FBEE8C4604447E7B81A2644DEC2C86C">
                  <enum>(B)</enum>
                  <header>Eligible state educational agency</header>
                  <text>The term <term>eligible State educational agency</term> means a State educational agency or a State educational agency in partnership with a mental health organization, family advocacy organization, or community nonprofit organization.</text>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="HF6FE874614A84324974144CAB600E851">
                  <enum>(C)</enum>
                  <header>School personnel</header>
                  <text>The term <term>school personnel</term> means administrators, administrative staff, custodial staff, cafeteria staff, transportation staff, and other school-employed staff who interact with students.</text>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="H718D76F152224D59834DF8D399483F35">
                  <enum>(D)</enum>
                  <header>Specialized instructional support personnel</header>
                  <text>The term <term>specialized instructional support personnel</term> means school counselors, school social workers, school psychologists, and other qualified professional personnel involved in providing assessment, diagnosis, counseling, educational, therapeutic, and other necessary services (including related services, as defined in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Individuals with Disabilities Education Act/s:602">section 602 of the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act</cato:entity-ref>) as part of comprehensive program to meet student needs.</text>
                </subparagraph>
              </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="HF5C8D12D1D35488DBA2AB1427FA8C621">
              <enum>(b)</enum>
              <header>Grants</header>
              <paragraph id="H8C9DD76A97AA4CC486F2FC5CD34A4EEC">
                <enum>(1)</enum>
                <header>Applications</header>
                <text>An eligible State educational agency that desires to receive a grant under this section shall submit an application to the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="9100">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> at such time, in such manner, and accompanied by such information as the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="9100">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> may require.</text>
              </paragraph>
              <paragraph id="HEC00C80309B944AC83F54A316AD940D4">
                <enum>(2)</enum>
                <header>Activities</header>
                <text>An eligible State educational agency that receives a grant under this section shall use the grant funds to award subgrants to eligible local educational agencies in accordance with <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965/s:4131/ss:c" proposed="true">subsection (c)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
              </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="HFA191A050CF34C3BB0BA5BB06A8C27FE">
              <enum>(c)</enum>
              <header>Subgrants</header>
              <paragraph id="H88C171DC5C1C4F8AA1D9AD43F41A7349">
                <enum>(1)</enum>
                <header>Application</header>
                <subparagraph id="H8393EE0FB2024B779CFA45586BB5A477">
                  <enum>(A)</enum>
                  <header>In general</header>
                  <text>An eligible local educational agency that desires to receive a subgrant under this section shall submit an application to the eligible State educational agency at such time, in such manner, and accompanied by such information as the eligible State educational agency may require.</text>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="HB2A8D74983C944F2A294385BC6A42459">
                  <enum>(B)</enum>
                  <header>Description of utilization</header>
                  <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An application submitted under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965/s:4131/ss:c/p:1/sp:A" proposed="true">subparagraph (A)</cato:entity-ref> shall include a description of how the local educational agency will utilize school counselors, school psychologists, school social workers, or community organizations with expertise in the lived experience of mental illness and suicide prevention efforts, in developing and conducting the training described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965/s:4131/ss:c/p:2" proposed="true">paragraph (2)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
                </subparagraph>
              </paragraph>
              <paragraph id="H400B33281D9D4F5A8BC8428FA4CE7240">
                <enum>(2)</enum>
                <header>Training</header>
                <subparagraph id="HE88E6D888E834ED89D52E70F23A1CEC7">
                  <enum>(A)</enum>
                  <header>In general</header>
                  <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An eligible local educational agency that receives a subgrant under this section shall support an existing training program developed by either the school or a community organization with expertise in the lived experience of mental illness and suicide prevention, or develop a new program, in which school counselors, school psychologists, and school social workers develop and provide training to teachers, school personnel, and specialized instructional support personnel in understanding the mental health needs of children. Such program shall include an annual in-service training program to enable such teachers, school personnel, and specialized instructional support personnel—</text>
                  <clause id="HE52B065025984E69B810A20B3DB4F7B3">
                    <enum>(i)</enum>
                    <text>to better understand mental health conditions and the early warning signs in children and adolescents;</text>
                  </clause>
                  <clause id="H1F31381310A7466D9BFFDA0804971489">
                    <enum>(ii)</enum>
                    <text>to best communicate with families about these concerns;</text>
                  </clause>
                  <clause id="HBE59EDC7EF0B42268D4C66493A95E05C">
                    <enum>(iii)</enum>
                    <text>to identify classroom strategies for working effectively with children with mental health conditions; and</text>
                  </clause>
                  <clause id="H9DBE6C09D1B74609B74CF2CD7617EED3">
                    <enum>(iv)</enum>
                    <text>to understand school specific information, including, as appropriate, how schools are—</text>
                    <subclause id="HD15A53364FFC4EC1ACC5180A643EB931">
                      <enum>(I)</enum>
                      <text>assisting in linking students to supports and services; and</text>
                    </subclause>
                    <subclause id="H406DD97C95524D779CEB79BE188A0A51">
                      <enum>(II)</enum>
                      <text>providing information on the school’s mental health services and supports, including school social work and psychological services, as well as the school’s referral process for additional school-linked services connecting to community mental health professionals.</text>
                    </subclause>
                  </clause>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="H60DBA611D379472BB60F6E62BD0C4235">
                  <enum>(B)</enum>
                  <header>Family perspective</header>
                  <text>A training program described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965/s:4131/ss:c/p:2/sp:A" proposed="true">subparagraph (A)</cato:entity-ref> shall incorporate family and parent perspectives.</text>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph commented="no" id="HE855E28624C44CA2BBE47607C5DD625D">
                  <enum>(C)</enum>
                  <header>Training program for all areas of the state and for personnel serving indian children</header>
                  <clause commented="no" id="H6F162331DAAF48C18FA934060CE564EC">
                    <enum>(i)</enum>
                    <header>Urban and rural areas</header>
                    <text>In awarding subgrants under this section, a State educational agency shall ensure training programs described under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965/s:4131/ss:c/p:2/sp:A" proposed="true">subparagraph (A)</cato:entity-ref> are available for teachers, school personnel, and specialized instructional support personnel in urban and rural areas across the State.</text>
                  </clause>
                  <clause commented="no" id="H02D0D5CB7C3546F8A5A147C9A87532E5">
                    <enum>(ii)</enum>
                    <header>Indian children</header>
                    <text>A State educational agency that receives a grant under this section shall award subgrants to eligible local educational agencies described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965/s:7112/ss:b/p:1">section 7112(b)(1)</cato:entity-ref> and Indian tribes described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965/s:7112/ss:c">section 7112(c)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
                  </clause>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph commented="no" id="HEDF6E862ADC548D9ABF654A1F16BBE16">
                  <enum>(D)</enum>
                  <header>School based mental health services providers</header>
                  <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A training program described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965/s:4131/ss:c/p:2/sp:A" proposed="true">subparagraph (A)</cato:entity-ref> shall include a school-based mental health service provider and a community organization with expertise in the lived experience of mental illness or suicide prevention, whenever possible, to maximize training outcomes and facilitate coordinated referrals when more intensive community services are needed.</text>
                </subparagraph>
              </paragraph>
              <paragraph id="H0DF1906A0CDD4E9B85D8673AC45FF759">
                <enum>(3)</enum>
                <header>Guidelines</header>
                <text>In carrying out a training program described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965/s:4131/ss:c/p:2" proposed="true">paragraph (2)</cato:entity-ref>, an eligible local educational agency may—</text>
                <subparagraph id="HC57835DF792141FF8C00DD1425B6E038">
                  <enum>(A)</enum>
                  <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">report to the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="9100">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> on the agency’s commitment to students with mental illness and suicide prevention efforts through innovative programs, resource development, and the development of a mental health curriculum and activities that focus on raising awareness within schools of early onset mental health conditions and linking students with effective mental health services and supports;</text>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="H7A61146C84664EF1B8E6BCF95DA81784">
                  <enum>(B)</enum>
                  <text>describe existing school-community partnerships that provide effective clinical services to students with severe mental health needs;</text>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="H9E6B5EC3730B4481BD208689D067FC37">
                  <enum>(C)</enum>
                  <text>describe how the agency will measure outcomes, as described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965/s:4131/ss:d" proposed="true">subsection (d)</cato:entity-ref>, specifically for students with serious mental health needs;</text>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="HDEE91282317E40EB959AD754D286BDBE">
                  <enum>(D)</enum>
                  <text>describe how the training program will be effective for teachers, school personnel, and specialized instructional support personnel in culturally and linguistically diverse school communities; and</text>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="H9198A321CE9E49BDAAEFEE9B41958767">
                  <enum>(E)</enum>
                  <text>describe any strong links to the community mental health system and community mental health providers through interagency collaboration, including documenting—</text>
                  <clause id="H472796B2B2F648FAA9E999A76F78A104">
                    <enum>(i)</enum>
                    <text>the extent of the interagency collaboration (including the engagement in joint activities); and</text>
                  </clause>
                  <clause id="H807FFD3AC41F44239EB955936A429F9E">
                    <enum>(ii)</enum>
                    <text>the dates during which the collaboration has been in effect and any outcomes that have been achieved as a result of this activity.</text>
                  </clause>
                </subparagraph>
              </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="H37A457C52D4F434E8A6EFF563A163CB6">
              <enum>(d)</enum>
              <header>Evaluations and measures of outcomes</header>
              <paragraph id="H016A442F3C4445128EB7CCB34D15CA00">
                <enum>(1)</enum>
                <header>In general</header>
                <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="9100">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall develop measures of outcomes for eligible local educational agencies that receive subgrants under this section, in order to evaluate the effectiveness of programs carried out under the subgrant.</text>
              </paragraph>
              <paragraph id="H933823B8F97A4B7AADD25564C8FB5B01">
                <enum>(2)</enum>
                <header>Outcomes</header>
                <text>The measures of outcomes described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965/s:4131/ss:d/p:1" proposed="true">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref> shall include, at a minimum, provisions to evaluate—</text>
                <subparagraph id="H10AC566842FE43E48A4733BF7F4E2BBB">
                  <enum>(A)</enum>
                  <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the effectiveness of comprehensive school mental health training and suicide prevention programs established under this section;</text>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="H2D77E4C8F22C4963B226791B57D9E2F3">
                  <enum>(B)</enum>
                  <text>the effectiveness of formal partnership linkages among child and family serving institutions, community support systems, and the educational system, if applicable;</text>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="H5AEAE2EE43F14F07B64C43FEDDFE7234">
                  <enum>(C)</enum>
                  <text>the effectiveness of the training program in culturally and linguistically diverse school communities;</text>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="H83C312F9C147416096380A35B581C127">
                  <enum>(D)</enum>
                  <text>the improvement in understanding mental health conditions with the purpose of providing a safe and supportive learning environment among school staff, students, and parents;</text>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="H52F254542717494D8B03AC5FFE811BD3">
                  <enum>(E)</enum>
                  <text>the improvement in—</text>
                  <clause id="HA53F5298059B4C2F83735FB07C84747C">
                    <enum>(i)</enum>
                    <text>case-finding of students in need of more intensive services;</text>
                  </clause>
                  <clause id="H23E4DE395C334987AAB4AAD27DC93E74">
                    <enum>(ii)</enum>
                    <text>effective communication with families; and</text>
                  </clause>
                  <clause id="HCEDEAE1399CD445B8C90C85570C24AFF">
                    <enum>(iii)</enum>
                    <text>referral of identified students with mental health related concerns for an evaluation for services and supports;</text>
                  </clause>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="H3DDD608D33D247FFA2D92920F8FD121D">
                  <enum>(F)</enum>
                  <text>the reduction in the number of students with mental health conditions and those identified as children with disabilities under the emotional disturbance and other health impairment categories of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Individuals with Disabilities Education Act">Individuals with Disabilities Education Act</cato:entity-ref> who are suspended and an increase in the number of such students who graduate from high school; and</text>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="HD3BAC3044C3A4C68B3F88B3462F832E2">
                  <enum>(G)</enum>
                  <text>the increased successful matriculation to postsecondary school.</text>
                </subparagraph>
              </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="H5A0BE11ABD3B4A96AC6A3252383A2D49">
              <enum>(e)</enum>
              <header>Data collection component</header>
              <paragraph id="H101C5175A8CD45C7961E76F917FA92C8">
                <enum>(1)</enum>
                <header>Annual data submissions and reports</header>
                <subparagraph id="H9D4A455A260F4FE985FC854444FBAA60">
                  <enum>(A)</enum>
                  <header>Data submission</header>
                  <clause id="H613D2FA6F29C487A842C9D9AD0CB85A6">
                    <enum>(i)</enum>
                    <header>Local educational agencies</header>
                    <text>An eligible local educational agency that receives a subgrant under this section shall annually submit to the eligible State educational agency a report that includes data to evaluate the success of the program carried out by the eligible local educational agency. Such reports shall utilize the measures of outcomes described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965/s:4131/ss:d" proposed="true">subsection (d)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
                  </clause>
                  <clause id="H9483604F379D4DFE95C47F7450870A5B">
                    <enum>(ii)</enum>
                    <header>State educational agencies</header>
                    <text>An eligible State educational agency that receives a grant under this section shall annually submit to the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="9100">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> a report that includes data from the reports submitted to the agency from eligible local educational agencies pursuant to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965/s:4131/ss:e/p:1/sp:A/cl:i" proposed="true">clause (i)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
                  </clause>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="H203CEFFD93E246EFB7C84B1FA33BA944">
                  <enum>(B)</enum>
                  <header>Report to congress</header>
                  <text>Not later than 6 months after the date the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="9100">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> receives reports under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965/s:4131/ss:e/p:1/sp:A/cl:ii" proposed="true">subparagraph (A)(ii)</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="9100">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall compile the data in the reports and conduct a general analysis of the success of the programs carried out by the local educational agencies involved with subgrant funds received under this section. The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="9100">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall prepare a report containing the compilation and general analysis, and submit the report to the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="committee" entity-id="SSHR00">Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate</cato:entity-ref> and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="committee" entity-id="HED00">Committee on Education and the Workforce of the House of Representatives</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
                </subparagraph>
              </paragraph>
              <paragraph id="H873B1E0F25E1404487086D9F4516DE6C">
                <enum>(2)</enum>
                <header>Evaluation and report</header>
                <subparagraph id="H28DE981396734E9192AE72CA9CB3718F">
                  <enum>(A)</enum>
                  <header>Evaluation</header>
                  <text>Not later than 12 months after the end of the initial subgrant period for eligible local educational agencies under this section, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="9100">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall conduct an in-depth evaluation of the success of the programs carried out by the local educational agencies with subgrant funds received under this section.</text>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="H3906CC881BBB49E6B6AF9943AB99ABCF">
                  <enum>(B)</enum>
                  <header>Report to congress</header>
                  <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="9100">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall prepare a report containing the in-depth evaluation, and submit the report to the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="committee" entity-id="SSHR00">Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate</cato:entity-ref> and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="committee" entity-id="HED00">Committee on Education and the Workforce of the House of Representatives</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
                </subparagraph>
              </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="H08971AC391D04795BE2C6F05647F2EBB">
              <enum>(f)</enum>
              <header>Terms and cost of the grant</header>
              <text>
                <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="auth-auth-approp">There are authorized to be appropriated <cato:property name="purpose">to carry out <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965/s:4131" proposed="true">this section</cato:entity-ref>
                  </cato:property> <cato:funds-and-year amount="indefinite" year="2014, 2015, 2016, 2017, 2018">such sums as may be necessary for fiscal year 2014 and each of the 4 succeeding fiscal years</cato:funds-and-year>.</cato:entity>
              </text>
            </subsection>
          </section>
          <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
        </quoted-block>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="HEEEE79C60A8C4F80834641350F0AFB7C">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Table of contents</header>
        <text>The table of contents in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965/s:2">section 2 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965</cato:entity-ref> is amended by inserting after the item relating to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965/s:4130">section 4130</cato:entity-ref> the following:</text>
        <quoted-block id="H9ADF51C9AA974836886CED90C30902EB" style="OLC">
          <toc>
            <toc-entry idref="H7A9CCA991E8348CA9D6323F8C6512E38" level="section">Sec. 4131. Training teachers and school professionals in understanding the mental health needs of children.</toc-entry>
          </toc>
          <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
        </quoted-block>
      </subsection>
    </section>
  </legis-body>
</bill>
</doc>