<doc>
  <docmeta id="113hres389ih">
    <bill congress="113" type="hres" number="389" version="ih"/>
    <revision size="2405" annotations="0" status="complete" id="3" commit-time="2013-11-12T03:36:26Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113hres389ih/3.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <resolution xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" dms-id="H676D0C54853E45FB9DAE2722E3AFE216" key="H" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print">
  <metadata>
<dublinCore>
<dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">113 HRES 389 IH: Congratulating the Minnesota Lynx women’s basketball team on winning the 2013 Women’s National Basketball Association Championship.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">2013-10-23</dc:date>
<dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code>
    <congress display="yes">113th CONGRESS</congress>
    <session display="yes">1st Session</session>
    <legis-num>H. RES. 389</legis-num>
    <current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
    <action display="yes">
      <action-date date="20131023">October 23, 2013</action-date>
      <action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="E000288">Mr. Ellison</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="M001143">Ms. McCollum</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000127">Mr. Nolan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000799">Mr. Walz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000594">Mr. Paulsen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001256">Mrs. Bachmann</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000258">Mr. Peterson</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="K000363">Mr. Kline</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>
      </action-desc>
    </action>
    <legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
    <official-title display="yes">Congratulating the Minnesota Lynx women’s basketball team on winning the 2013 Women’s National Basketball Association Championship.</official-title>
  </form>
  <preamble>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas, on October 10, 2013, the Minnesota Lynx won the 2013 Women’s National Basketball Association (WNBA);</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas this is the second national championship for the Minnesota Lynx in three years;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the Minnesota Lynx won every game in the post-season playoffs, beating the Seattle Storm in the semifinals, the Phoenix Mercury in the Western Conference finals and decisively beating the Atlanta Dream in the Championship round;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas more than 13,000 fans attended the home games at the Target Center in Minneapolis to cheer on the Minnesota Lynx;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the Minnesota Lynx features three gold medal winning Olympians, Maya Moore, Seimone Augustus, and Lindsay Whalen, as well as a highly talented team of professionals including Rebekkah Brunson, Janel McCarville, and Monica Wright; and</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the Minnesota Lynx are only one of four WNBA teams to win multiple championships, both times under the coaching guidance of Cheryl Reeve: Now, therefore, be it</text>
    </whereas>
  </preamble>
  <resolution-body id="HB0C0D50C00D44067A053981746C013E4" style="traditional">
    <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H981D6F963F0642E794F527B396FDF8ED" section-type="undesignated-section">
      <enum/>
      <text>That the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0050">House of Representatives</cato:entity-ref>—</text>
      <paragraph id="H53816826B731493BABD73538949E0833">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recognizes the achievements of the players, coaches, fans, and staff whose hard work and dedication helped the Minnesota Lynx win the 2013 Women’s National Basketball Association National Championship; and</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H5EEF699E86AD494F8D69795E85854F1C">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text>recognizes the Twin Cities region and Minnesota which enthusiastically supports the team and women’s professional basketball.</text>
      </paragraph>
    </section>
  </resolution-body>
</resolution>
</doc>