<doc>
  <docmeta id="113hconres59ih">
    <bill congress="113" type="hconres" number="59" version="ih"/>
    <revision size="4921" annotations="0" status="complete" id="3" commit-time="2013-10-17T22:32:03Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113hconres59ih/3.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <resolution xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" dms-id="H7C23A6DD6919467B9E4CA3D31DFF458D" key="H" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" resolution-type="house-concurrent" star-print="no-star-print">
  <metadata>
<dublinCore>
<title>113 HCON 59 IH: Expressing the sense of Congress that the Environmental Protection Agency should hold public listening sessions on regulations targeting carbon dioxide emissions from existing power plants in those States most directly impacted by the potential regulations.</title>
<publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</publisher>
<date>2013-10-08</date>
<format>text/xml</format>
<language>EN</language>
<rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code>
    <congress display="yes">113th CONGRESS</congress>
    <session display="yes">1st Session</session>
    <legis-num>H. CON. RES. 59</legis-num>
    <current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
    <action display="yes">
      <action-date date="20131008">October 8, 2013</action-date>
      <action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="C001047">Mrs. Capito</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="L000571">Mrs. Lummis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000292">Mr. Johnson of Ohio</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001180">Mr. McKinley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001096">Mr. Cramer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001195">Mr. Smith of Missouri</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000011">Mr. Rahall</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000395">Mr. Rogers of Kentucky</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000459">Mr. Terry</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001187">Mr. Stivers</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000558">Mr. Guthrie</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000813">Mrs. Walorski</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000565">Mr. Gosar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000467">Mr. Thompson of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000576">Mr. Long</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000569">Mr. Luetkemeyer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000618">Mr. Daines</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="B001282">Mr. Barr</cosponsor>) submitted the following concurrent resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>
      </action-desc>
    </action>
    <legis-type>CONCURRENT RESOLUTION</legis-type>
    <official-title display="yes">Expressing the sense of Congress that the Environmental Protection Agency should hold public listening sessions on regulations targeting carbon dioxide emissions from existing power plants in those States most directly impacted by the potential regulations.</official-title>
  </form>
  <preamble>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas coal provides affordable, reliable energy that provides low-cost electricity to individuals and businesses across the country;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas nearly 40 percent of all electricity generated in the United States comes from coal;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the 15 States with the highest percentage of electricity generated from coal in 2012 were West Virginia, Kentucky, Wyoming, Indiana, Missouri, North Dakota, Utah, Nebraska, New Mexico, Ohio, Colorado, Kansas, Iowa, Montana, and Wisconsin;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas <cato:entity-ref entity-type="person" entity-id="O000167">President Obama</cato:entity-ref> announced on June 25, 2013, that the Environmental Protection Agency would promulgate regulations targeting greenhouse gas emissions from existing coal-fired power plants with a proposed rule to be released in June 2014 and a final rule adopted in June 2015;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas, on September 30, 2013, the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="6800">Environmental Protection Agency</cato:entity-ref> announced the public listening sessions on rulemaking targeting greenhouse gas emissions from existing coal-fired power plants would be held in Boston, Massachusetts; New York City, New York; Philadelphia, Pennsylvania; Atlanta, Georgia; Denver, Colorado; Lenexa, Kansas; San Francisco, California; Washington, DC; Dallas, Texas; Seattle, Washington; and Chicago, Illinois;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="6800">Environmental Protection Agency</cato:entity-ref>’s announcement of the listening sessions states that <quote>[t]he feedback from these 11 public listening sessions will play an important role in helping <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="6800">EPA</cato:entity-ref> develop smart, cost-effective guidelines that reflect the latest and best information available</quote>;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas none of the 11 public listening sessions announced by the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="6800">Environmental Protection Agency</cato:entity-ref> will be held in one of the 10 States with the highest percentage of electricity generated from coal;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas none of the 11 public listening sessions announced by the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="6800">Environmental Protection Agency</cato:entity-ref> will be held in one of the top 3 coal-producing States;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the 10 States and the District of Columbia where public listening sessions will be held generate an average of 26 percent of their electricity from coal;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas regulatory efforts that could lead to the retirement of additional coal-fired power plants would have a disproportionate impact on jobs, utility rates, and the overall economy in States that rely on coal for a higher percentage of electricity generation;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="6800">Environmental Protection Agency</cato:entity-ref> should use its public listening sessions to hear the potential impact of its regulatory actions in those States where the regulatory impact would be the greatest; and</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="6800">Environmental Protection Agency’s</cato:entity-ref> stated goal of using the listening sessions to help <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="6800">EPA </cato:entity-ref>
        <quote>develop smart, cost-effective guidelines</quote> cannot be achieved by excluding the views of residents in those States that rely most heavily on coal for electricity generation: Now, therefore, be it</text>
    </whereas>
  </preamble>
  <resolution-body id="H7A3E83996140454883DF371B4BB28F78" style="traditional">
    <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HA553B438EB0745AF88E15969115A7E4F" section-type="undesignated-section">
      <enum/>
      <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That it is the sense of <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> that—</text>
      <paragraph id="H21456C498EB8425B9C937C5DC8ADE6A9">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text>public listening sessions on rulemaking targeting carbon dioxide emissions from existing power plants should be held in each of the fifteen States with the highest percentage of electricity generated by coal in 2012 (West Virginia, Kentucky, Wyoming, Indiana, Missouri, North Dakota, Utah, Nebraska, New Mexico, Ohio, Colorado, Kansas, Iowa, Montana, and Wisconsin); and</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H6B5AC05921F04634AFE38329C63DE9FA">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text>such listening sessions should be held at a time and place that would maximize the ability of individuals to participate.</text>
      </paragraph>
    </section>
  </resolution-body>
</resolution>
</doc>