<doc>
  <docmeta id="113hres548ih">
    <bill congress="113" type="hres" number="548" version="ih"/>
    <revision size="3863" annotations="0" status="complete" id="6" commit-time="2014-09-16T17:56:19Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113hres548ih/6.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <resolution xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" dms-id="HA7995E5CB3404CCDB64980E54AAE0C67" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"> 
<metadata>
<dublinCore>
<dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">113 HRES 548 IH: Amending the Rules of the House of Representatives to require the mandatory annual ethics training offered to Members, officers, and employees of the House to include a specific program of training in the prevention and deterrence of sexual harassment in employment, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">2014-04-08</dc:date>
<dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code> 
<congress display="yes">113th CONGRESS</congress> 
<session display="yes">2d Session</session> 
<legis-num>H. RES. 548</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action display="yes"> 
<action-date date="20140408">April 8, 2014</action-date> 
<action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="S001175">Ms. Speier</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HRU00">Committee on Rules</committee-name>
      </action-desc> 
</action> 
<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type> 
<official-title display="yes">Amending the Rules of the House of Representatives to require the mandatory annual ethics training offered to Members, officers, and employees of the House to include a specific program of training in the prevention and deterrence of sexual harassment in employment, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<resolution-body style="OLC" id="HAB8D7EB5293E4D0FAF2658314634FB54"> 
<section display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="section-one" id="HCE6E669907864B139BCD3918013469C5">
      <enum>1.</enum>
      <header>Inclusion of program of training in prevention and deterrence of sexual harassment in employment as part of annual mandatory ethics training for House Members and staff</header> 
<subsection id="H3A28CA2A90954854B1E805CE714DE119">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Inclusion of Program</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Clause 3(a)(6) of rule XI of the Rules of the House of Representatives is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="H0C27C13424BB42FCAFC5F6641AA81870">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>in subdivision (A)(ii), by striking the period at the end and inserting the following: <quote>, together with a specific program of training in the prevention and deterrence of sexual harassment in employment (as described in subdivision (B)).</quote>;</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8D934C2EFD154703BB299E601F523580">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>by redesignating subdivision (B) as subdivision (C); and</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCE590B64EB464ABFB6DCDE4876790F5C">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <text>by inserting after subdivision (A) the following new subdivision:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H53B1171124654811B52F04E72F6A9650" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<rules-subdivision id="HEB17E24CBEF141FA8D27C6BA4E60D2F8" indent="up1">
              <enum>(B)</enum> 
<clause id="HBE58E16B95234451B42C86EE622E4263" display-inline="yes-display-inline" indent="up1">
                <enum>(i)</enum>
                <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The program of training in the prevention and deterrence of sexual harassment in the workplace under this subdivision is a program which provides information and practical guidance regarding any applicable Federal and State laws concerning the prohibition against and the prevention and correction of sexual harassment and the remedies available to victims of sexual harassment in employment. The program shall also include practical examples aimed at instructing supervisors in the prevention of harassment, discrimination, and retaliation, and shall be presented by individuals with knowledge and expertise in the prevention of harassment, discrimination, and retaliation.</text>
              </clause> 
<clause id="H7F7B3BEAA98D461C97088741ABA3A030" indent="up1">
                <enum>(ii)</enum>
                <text>The program under this subdivision shall provide at least one hour of training, except that in the case of the training provided to a new officer or employee of the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0050">House</cato:entity-ref> under subdivision (B)(i), the program shall under this subdivision shall provide at least two hours of training.</text>
              </clause> 
<clause id="HF8B65E18893E4AEE823AFF77A7F83FB6" indent="up1">
                <enum>(iii)</enum>
                <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this subparagraph, <quote>sexual harassment</quote> means any conduct directed at an individual which consists of unwelcome sexual advances, requests for sexual favors, or any other conduct of a sexual nature, if submission by the individual to such conduct is made either explicitly or implicitly a term or condition of the individual’s employment, submission to or rejection of such conduct by the individual is used as the basis for employment decisions affecting the individual, or such conduct has the purpose or effect of interfering with the individual’s work performance or creating an intimidating, hostile, or offensive working environment. </text>
              </clause>
            </rules-subdivision>
            <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
          </quoted-block>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="H18420A2ECC4F4D5D90B9F80CA56B789D">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Effective Date</header>
        <text>The amendment made by <cato:entity-ref entity-type="bill-by-number" value="113/hres/548/s:1/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref> shall take effect upon the expiration of the 60-day period which begins on the date of the adoption of this resolution.</text>
      </subsection>
    </section> 
</resolution-body> 
</resolution>
</doc>