<doc>
  <docmeta id="113hr2535ih">
    <bill congress="113" type="hr" number="2535" version="ih"/>
    <revision size="18648" annotations="0" status="complete" id="3" commit-time="2013-08-28T16:20:58Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113hr2535ih/3.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H9E8BB87A5FBD4495A5E7A5442A6CBCE8" public-private="public">
	<metadata>
<dublinCore>
<title>113 HR 2535 IH: American Liberty Coinage and Deficit Reduction Act of 2013</title>
<publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</publisher>
<date>2013-06-27</date>
<format>text/xml</format>
<language>EN</language>
<rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>113th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 2535</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20130627">June 27, 2013</action-date>
			<action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="B001282">Mr. Barr</sponsor> (for
			 himself, <cosponsor name-id="L000565">Mr. Loebsack</cosponsor>,
			 <cosponsor name-id="S001187">Mr. Stivers</cosponsor>,
			 <cosponsor name-id="M001187">Mr. Meadows</cosponsor>, and
			 <cosponsor name-id="Y000065">Mr. Yoho</cosponsor>) introduced the following
			 bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee
			 on Financial Services</committee-name>
      </action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To cause increased seigniorage for the United States Mint
		  leading to enhanced revenue to the Treasury and increased offsets to annual
		  budget deficits in perpetuity, to require the Secretary of the Treasury to mint
		  and issue coins commemorating and celebrating American Liberty, <term>The
		  Union</term>, and the American values and attributes of freedom, independence,
		  civil governance, enlightenment, peace, strength, equality, democracy, and
		  justice, to provide for the continued and concurrent production and
		  distribution of existing presidentially-themed circulating and numismatic
		  coinage designs, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="HB24E0D35135D4C599A38406654A83FF4" style="OLC">
		<section id="HA1807341A35445FCAF2AA6518347E31F" section-type="section-one">
      <enum>1.</enum>
      <header>Short title</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the
			 <quote>
          <short-title>American Liberty Coinage and Deficit
			 Reduction Act of 2013</short-title>
        </quote>.</text>
		</section>
    <section id="H08DDE9AC30054AA2A148D8893BA868F8">
      <enum>2.</enum>
      <header>Findings</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> finds as follows:</text>
			<paragraph id="H6A8E9C004D8B4593942BA2644581A704">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text>The 50 State
			 Quarters Program showed that a circulating commemorative coinage program that
			 incorporates recurring design change dramatically increases seigniorage—the
			 profit realized by the Mint from the amount that the face value of coins
			 produced by the Mint exceeds the costs of production and distribution.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H06E529AD6787453AAB02D7E1FB4D69F5">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text>Pursuant to the
			 President’s 1967 Commission on Budget Concepts, seigniorage proceeds are used
			 to reduce the amount the government would otherwise borrow from the public to
			 finance the budget deficit. Thus, programs that increase seigniorage provide a
			 means to reduce the budget deficit without increasing taxes or cutting
			 spending.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H82556229A82D4102B3904756DE44311C">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <text>During the 10
			 years of the 50 State Quarters Program, the cumulative production of quarter
			 dollars exceeded 34,000,000,000, representing a 136 percent increase in quarter
			 dollar production as compared to the cumulative 10-year period immediately
			 preceding the program. This enhanced production level of quarter dollars
			 resulted in increased seigniorage revenues of approximately $3,000,000,000 and,
			 therefore, an equal reduction in the budget deficit.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H43CA89DA463140C7965D77BFEC87793D">
        <enum>(4)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Mint has estimated that 147,000,000
			 Americans became collectors of 50 State quarters, demonstrating that the demand
			 for circulating coins—for purposes beyond the needs of commerce—increases
			 significantly when frequent and systematic design changes are made through a
			 multiyear commemorative design series.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H75FF79AAAE644BC2B16135471EAED97E">
        <enum>(5)</enum>
        <text>Similar to the
			 collector interest and resulting seigniorage generated by the 50 State Quarters
			 Program, the Westward Journey Nickel Program, which issued a series of 5-cent
			 coins between 2004 and 2006 bearing new obverse and reverse designs
			 commemorating the 200th anniversary of the Lewis and Clark Expedition and
			 honoring President Thomas Jefferson, saw average annual nickel production
			 increase by 593,200,000 units as compared to nickel production during the 2
			 years immediately preceding the program and the 2 years immediately following
			 it.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H4892F1738DB44039AB5ABC8252BAE571">
        <enum>(6)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">From the early 1790s through the early to
			 mid 20th century, allegorical depictions of <term>Liberty</term> dominated the
			 designs of circulating United States coins. Coinage from this time period
			 served as a constant reminder to Americans and the world of a defining and
			 distinctive value of American life and culture—Liberty. These coins also
			 provided some of the most inspiring, uplifting, and beautiful coin designs ever
			 created. In numismatics, <term>Liberty</term> themed coins are among the most
			 sought after collectibles.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H05C6F85B39F64D8CB08045691AED356B">
        <enum>(7)</enum>
        <text>Given the
			 potential that a new series of <term>Liberty</term> coins would be highly
			 collectible, if produced, such a program would likely provide the means through
			 which to significantly increase seigniorage thereby reducing budget
			 deficits.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H421F0D68FAE043E897156B15D80AC1B7">
        <enum>(8)</enum>
        <text>A
			 new <term>Liberty</term> themed coinage series would allow the Nation to
			 continue to honor the past presidents currently depicted on United States coins
			 by providing for the continued and concurrent production and distribution of
			 such coins annually along with the new <term>Liberty</term> coins.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HD9B8ACE4D98C447181A5EEA0FF4ED4FC">
        <enum>(9)</enum>
        <text>A
			 new <term>Liberty</term> themed coinage series would revitalize the design of
			 United States coinage and return circulating coinage to its position as not
			 only a necessary means of exchange in commerce but also as an object of
			 aesthetic beauty and symbol of core American values.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H8E6060F37BD94EA486DF6547D56EB66D">
        <enum>(10)</enum>
        <text>In order to
			 increase the seigniorage produced by the United States Mint thereby reducing
			 deficits to be financed by the United States it is appropriate to introduce a
			 new series of circulating commemorative <term>Liberty</term> themed coins that
			 would alternate annually between the dime and quarter dollar as 1-year issues.
			 Additionally, introduction of a new <term>Liberty</term> themed half dollar
			 produced for noncirculating numismatic purposes would further enhance
			 seigniorage.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H09F77452D04C4CC2B75A7377D9A0A3AB">
        <enum>(11)</enum>
        <text>Beginning in
			 2015, the Act provides for the introduction of a 1-year circulating
			 commemorative <term>Liberty</term> themed dime that would be produced and
			 distributed concurrently with the existing dime depicting the image of
			 President Franklin D. Roosevelt. After 2015, the image of President Roosevelt
			 would continue to be utilized on the standard issue circulating dime.
			 Subsequently, in 2016, the Act provides for the introduction of a 1-year
			 circulating commemorative <term>Liberty</term> themed quarter dollar that would
			 be produced and distributed concurrently with the existing quarter dollar
			 depicting the image of President George Washington. The Washington design would
			 continue to be used in future years. In 2017, the process would begin again
			 with the introduction of a new 1-year <term>Liberty</term> themed dime, bearing
			 a new <term>Liberty</term> design that would be co-issued alongside the regular
			 issue Roosevelt Dime. In 2018, a new 1-year <term>Liberty</term> themed quarter
			 would be co-issued and the process would continue on a perpetual basis into
			 future years.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HA867DF94B29D460EB3B641A21350E79F">
        <enum>(12)</enum>
        <text>Sequencing a new
			 <term>Liberty</term> design each year is an important aspect of the program
			 designed to continually renew collector interest and, therefore, promote demand
			 for the coins in a manner to maximize seigniorage realized by the United States
			 Mint.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H1D14D43F6A3E48149F832DBF5CBE128A">
        <enum>(13)</enum>
        <text>A
			 <term>Liberty</term> themed program would also include a new
			 <term>Liberty</term> half dollar bearing a design to be utilized for a 10-year
			 term, to be issued as an ongoing annual noncirculating numismatic collector’s
			 series. The <term>Liberty</term> half dollar would be issued along with the
			 noncirculating Kennedy half dollar. At the end of each 10-year term, a new
			 <term>Liberty</term> design would be implemented with designs continuing
			 thereafter in a recurring 10-year cycle.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HCE8C8FC8ECE2422A9AEEABC64B35AE77">
        <enum>(14)</enum>
        <text>Providing
			 collectors with a new <term>Liberty</term> half dollar series will provide an
			 increase in the Mint’s numismatic profits and bolster the objectives of the
			 program to annually reduce budget deficits.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HA24B68FA7E834B4395F381F2C920A552">
        <enum>(15)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A series of circulating commemorative
			 <term>Liberty</term> themed coins will provide a new platform for the
			 advancement of American medallic art through a medium where Americans commonly
			 encounter public art—the Nation’s pocket change.</text>
			</paragraph>
    </section>
    <section id="H4535008A08594B998C0A8F81409B59DF">
      <enum>3.</enum>
      <header>American Liberty
			 Coin Program</header>
			<subsection id="H6D4570ED14A94E1887F8EC921FE1F4B5">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Program
			 contingent on deficit reduction</header>
				<paragraph id="H76306021484B400AAEE8B3A16D56B8D1">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>Determination</header>
          <text>The
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary of the Treasury</cato:entity-ref> shall carry out a study on the estimated effect of
			 the amendment made by <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="American Liberty Coinage and Deficit Reduction Act of 2013/s:3/ss:b" proposed="true">subsection (b)</cato:entity-ref> on the Federal budget deficit over the
			 10-year period beginning on January 1, 2015.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H78EF9B76EB574EEE92AB91656F55D184">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Report</header>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than the end of the 90-day period
			 beginning on the date of the enactment of this Act, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall issue a
			 report to the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> containing the estimate determined under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="American Liberty Coinage and Deficit Reduction Act of 2013/s:3/ss:a/p:1" proposed="true">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref>
			 and an explanation of how such estimate was calculated.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HC070E98A8DA54D4BBF1BEC8CBC141E34">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <header>Effective
			 date</header>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendment made by
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="American Liberty Coinage and Deficit Reduction Act of 2013/s:3/ss:b" proposed="true">subsection (b)</cato:entity-ref> shall take effect on the earlier of—</text>
					<subparagraph id="HDF0A9288B4BE4FBC85450207539ECFB2">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>the date that the
			 report is issued under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="American Liberty Coinage and Deficit Reduction Act of 2013/s:3/ss:a/p:2" proposed="true">paragraph (2)</cato:entity-ref>, if the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> determines in such
			 report that the effect on the Federal budget deficit over the 10-year period
			 beginning on January 1, 2015, will lead to a reduction in the deficit over such
			 period of $100,000,000 or more; and</text>
					</subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H5FF78996214C49D68464C1CFC52B1521">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>the end of the
			 91-day period beginning on the date of the enactment of this Act, if the
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> fails to make the report under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="American Liberty Coinage and Deficit Reduction Act of 2013/s:3/ss:a/p:2" proposed="true">paragraph (2)</cato:entity-ref> within the required
			 90-day period.</text>
					</subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="HE33F7F6203C34241B6B775AF5A0A5791">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Program</header>
        <text>
          <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc/31/5112">Section
			 5112 of title 31, United States Code</cato:entity-ref>, is amended by adding at the end the
			 following:</text>
				<quoted-block id="H35D1553197AC4FCF9703823718F4E5AD" style="OLC">
					<subsection id="H923B026C3A8741079DFCA25729616E87">
            <enum>(w)</enum>
            <header>Issuance of
				circulating dime and quarter dollar coins and numismatic half dollar coins
				commemorating and celebrating American liberty, <term>the Union</term>, and the
				American values and attributes of freedom, independence, civil governance,
				enlightenment, peace, strength, equality, democracy, and justice</header>
						<paragraph id="H7188E92F94094F698D60932B4312D1D1">
              <enum>(1)</enum>
              <header>Dime
				coins</header>
							<subparagraph id="H47064F822A804419B89401A82FBD976F">
                <enum>(A)</enum>
                <header>In
				general</header>
                <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall mint and issue dime coins in calendar
				year 2015, and every second year thereafter, that—</text>
								<clause id="H8A5388472DC248A99AEDD25B20A4D7AF">
                  <enum>(i)</enum>
                  <text>have obverse
				designs that are emblematic and allegoric of the concept of <term>American
				Liberty</term>; and</text>
								</clause>
                <clause id="HF164846CB1884871BB31EA7200085640">
                  <enum>(ii)</enum>
                  <text>have reverse
				designs that—</text>
									<subclause id="H9209BC1884EF421F955F681A35427DE1">
                    <enum>(I)</enum>
                    <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">depict an American bald eagle;</text>
									</subclause>
                  <subclause id="HF59D5DBC38C3435D93D8DAECE34EC182">
                    <enum>(II)</enum>
                    <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">depict a fasces emblematic of civil
				governance;</text>
									</subclause>
                  <subclause id="HFDD51D8C62C54069855265D96F48D939">
                    <enum>(III)</enum>
                    <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">depict the torch of knowledge;</text>
									</subclause>
                  <subclause id="H09BC0FFCC87247D5BA67276AEF17D45A">
                    <enum>(IV)</enum>
                    <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">are emblematic and allegoric of <term>The
				Union</term>; or</text>
									</subclause>
                  <subclause id="H2FBB2BE55D2F4BDFA97E19F65AC047C9">
                    <enum>(V)</enum>
                    <text>depict one or more
				of the American values and attributes of freedom, independence, peace,
				strength, equality, democracy, and justice.</text>
									</subclause>
                </clause>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph commented="no" id="H60DFB25329CF48ADB79A53AB28A50096">
                <enum>(B)</enum>
                <header>Quantity of
				issuance</header>
                <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to a
				calendar year in which dime coins are issued pursuant to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc/31/5112/w/1/A" proposed="true">subparagraph (A)</cato:entity-ref>, the
				<cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall ensure that, of the total number of dime coins issued in such
				calendar year, not less than 40 percent and not more than 50 percent of such
				coins are made up of dime coins issued pursuant to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc/31/5112/w/1/A" proposed="true">subparagraph (A)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
							</subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="HD56D3A36FCC34090B4169701B2F56429">
              <enum>(2)</enum>
              <header>Quarter dollar
				coins</header>
							<subparagraph id="H0A476C7D11224B02B236C7E5B67CD371">
                <enum>(A)</enum>
                <header>In
				general</header>
                <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall mint and issue quarter dollar coins
				in calendar year 2016, and every second year thereafter, that—</text>
								<clause id="H3869CF37D80240AD895C98C68A0AFB00">
                  <enum>(i)</enum>
                  <text>have obverse
				designs that are emblematic and allegoric of the concept of <term>American
				Liberty</term>; and</text>
								</clause>
                <clause id="H4D04A5EEDCF944D9A48842A0CD6A7BD1">
                  <enum>(ii)</enum>
                  <text>have reverse
				designs that—</text>
									<subclause id="H8816F54E1E6B4831B8D64083CFC4A616">
                    <enum>(I)</enum>
                    <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">depict an American bald eagle;</text>
									</subclause>
                  <subclause id="H35F9D0DB4C414D7991887127C80B4895">
                    <enum>(II)</enum>
                    <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">depict a fasces emblematic of civil
				governance;</text>
									</subclause>
                  <subclause id="H9B56FA734D8C487CB309BBE13861D763">
                    <enum>(III)</enum>
                    <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">depict the torch of knowledge;</text>
									</subclause>
                  <subclause id="HADE4C17E70E74ADE8A7B6C2D65C4EBF2">
                    <enum>(IV)</enum>
                    <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">are emblematic and allegoric of <term>The
				Union</term>; or</text>
									</subclause>
                  <subclause id="H596DE790AF8542B5A91945163C25159D">
                    <enum>(V)</enum>
                    <text>depict one or more
				of the American values and attributes of freedom, independence, peace,
				strength, equality, democracy, and justice.</text>
									</subclause>
                </clause>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph commented="no" id="HEC42F05AB3544502B629C1F0BA38C8BD">
                <enum>(B)</enum>
                <header>Quantity of
				issuance</header>
                <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to a
				calendar year in which quarter dollar coins are issued pursuant to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc/31/5112/w/2/A" proposed="true">subparagraph
				(A)</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall ensure that, of the total number of quarter dollar
				coins issued in such calendar year, not less than 40 percent and not more than
				50 percent of such coins are made up of quarter dollar coins issued pursuant to
				<cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc/31/5112/w/2/A" proposed="true">subparagraph (A)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
							</subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="H6E59FABB46384A3E9DCF4B13238C5195">
              <enum>(3)</enum>
              <header>Half dollar
				coins</header>
							<subparagraph id="H2CBE073483FC4FA58452C321C78F7B62">
                <enum>(A)</enum>
                <header>In
				general</header>
                <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall mint and issue half dollar coins in
				calendar year 2015, and every year thereafter, with designs that shall be
				changed every 10 years, that—</text>
								<clause id="HB83A5D24461E425BA9CBA37589937D7D">
                  <enum>(i)</enum>
                  <text>have obverse
				designs that are emblematic and allegoric of the concept of <term>American
				Liberty</term>; and</text>
								</clause>
                <clause id="H7872F126517842E29A8D11FC2DCCBA79">
                  <enum>(ii)</enum>
                  <text>have reverse
				designs that—</text>
									<subclause id="H4503D45A3C9241E9BBA37FD5AFDC7E48">
                    <enum>(I)</enum>
                    <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">depict an American bald eagle;</text>
									</subclause>
                  <subclause id="H0910C005DC584FFB92B238858830B59F">
                    <enum>(II)</enum>
                    <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">depict a fasces emblematic of civil
				governance;</text>
									</subclause>
                  <subclause id="H2FDFBE91AEE2461791993E52B00A67F9">
                    <enum>(III)</enum>
                    <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">depict the torch of knowledge;</text>
									</subclause>
                  <subclause id="H7F2E24734BBD4D1A84852CBBED067A12">
                    <enum>(IV)</enum>
                    <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">are emblematic and allegoric of <term>The
				Union</term>; or</text>
									</subclause>
                  <subclause id="H06D0D0A56B61435DB84E396A1D105207">
                    <enum>(V)</enum>
                    <text>depict one or more
				of the American values and attributes of freedom, independence, peace,
				strength, equality, democracy, and justice.</text>
									</subclause>
                </clause>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="H6C3DD2024C804AE79C74B80B81FC04E4">
                <enum>(B)</enum>
                <header>Consideration of
				Liberty mini dollar</header>
                <text>The 1977 Liberty mini dollar design prepared
				by former United States Chief Sculptor and Engraver Frank Gasparro shall be
				considered along with other potential designs for half dollar coins issued
				under this paragraph.</text>
							</subparagraph>
              <subparagraph commented="no" id="H61E41D317F7B4D25B8F7E803CBCC640B">
                <enum>(C)</enum>
                <header>Quantity of
				issuance</header>
                <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to a
				calendar year, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall ensure that, of the total number of half
				dollar coins issued in such calendar year, not less than 40 percent and not
				more than 50 percent of such coins are made up of half dollar coins issued
				pursuant to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc/31/5112/w/3/A" proposed="true">subparagraph (A)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
							</subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="HFF6E4A6EE14E4139A9B9F69810F90B37">
              <enum>(4)</enum>
              <header>Design
				requirements</header>
              <text>The coins issued in accordance with <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc/31/5112/w/1" proposed="true">paragraphs (1)</cato:entity-ref>,
				<cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc/31/5112/w/2" proposed="true">(2)</cato:entity-ref>, and <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc/31/5112/w/3" proposed="true">(3)</cato:entity-ref> shall meet the following design requirements:</text>
							<subparagraph id="H4136855A3B704493A718F02F65698357">
                <enum>(A)</enum>
                <header>Coin
				obverse</header>
                <text>The design on the obverse shall—</text>
								<clause id="HA09F76948E4C4F8D96535BE7CD443190">
                  <enum>(i)</enum>
                  <text>be
				chosen by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary</cato:entity-ref>, after consultation with the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="9537">Commission of Fine Arts</cato:entity-ref>
				and review by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Citizens Coinage Advisory Committee">Citizens Coinage Advisory Committee</cato:entity-ref>;</text>
								</clause>
                <clause id="H369705856F5B4121945BB5A33D37EE55">
                  <enum>(ii)</enum>
                  <text>contain the
				inscriptions <term>Liberty</term> and <term>In God We Trust</term>; and</text>
								</clause>
                <clause id="H9132BFEDC060491BB7A64768C86AC7F7">
                  <enum>(iii)</enum>
                  <text>contain the
				inscription of the year of minting and issuance of the coin.</text>
								</clause>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="H6852BAEA290E47DDA794164C74E0F84D">
                <enum>(B)</enum>
                <header>Coin
				reverse</header>
                <text>The design on the reverse shall—</text>
								<clause id="H9FC0857EA1894DF3A54A84BB2D6FFDD3">
                  <enum>(i)</enum>
                  <text>be
				chosen by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary</cato:entity-ref>, after consultation with the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="9537">Commission of Fine Arts</cato:entity-ref>
				and review by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Citizens Coinage Advisory Committee">Citizens Coinage Advisory Committee</cato:entity-ref>;</text>
								</clause>
                <clause id="H928DE6E836484FE0BF97501C74BA8C17">
                  <enum>(ii)</enum>
                  <text>contain the
				inscription <term>United States of America</term> and <term>E Pluribus
				Unum</term>; and</text>
								</clause>
                <clause id="HBE9CDC8600A0429AA2F502C1ACD322DF">
                  <enum>(iii)</enum>
                  <text>contain a
				designation of the value of the coin.</text>
								</clause>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="H4785FFFC0B33496CAA1B8F1296F2F32A">
                <enum>(C)</enum>
                <header>Selection and
				approval process</header>
                <text>Designs for coins issued pursuant to this
				subsection may be submitted in accordance with the design selection and
				approval process developed by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> in the sole discretion of the
				<cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
							</subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="HC4451F4766F34CF5B08D4B6B66C590F9">
                <enum>(D)</enum>
                <header>Participation</header>
                <text>The
				<cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> may include participation by artists from the States and engravers of
				the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2044">United States Mint</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
							</subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="HBFEAA2F4128A470A95A02D407DD16797">
              <enum>(5)</enum>
              <header>Issuance of
				numismatic coins</header>
              <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The
				<cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> may mint and issue such number of coins of each design selected under
				this subsection in uncirculated and proof qualities as the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> determines
				to be appropriate. To assure availability of dimes and quarter dollars minted
				and issued under this subsection in uncirculated qualities for numismatic
				purposes, a portion of any such coins shall be offered in rolls and bags at
				face value plus issuance costs.</text>
						</paragraph>
            <paragraph id="HEDC66FA80AA24C8EA6156B7FFF5D26E6">
              <enum>(6)</enum>
              <header>Silver
				coins</header>
							<subparagraph id="H011585E776564825950912CD3DB2C5B2">
                <enum>(A)</enum>
                <header>In
				general</header>
                <text>Notwithstanding <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc/31/5112/b">subsection (b)</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> may mint
				and issue such number of dimes, quarter dollar coins, and half dollar coins of
				each design selected under this subsection as the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> determines to be
				appropriate, with a content of .999 fine silver.</text>
							</subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="H8AB175FAD1C44D2FB5AD97C01C938F6B">
                <enum>(B)</enum>
                <header>Sources of
				bullion</header>
                <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall obtain silver for minting coins under
				this paragraph from available resources, including stockpiles established under
				the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Strategic and Critical Materials Stock Piling Act">Strategic and Critical Materials Stock Piling
				Act</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
							</subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
        </quoted-block>
			</subsection>
    </section>
  </legis-body>
</bill>
</doc>