<doc>
  <docmeta id="113hr3137ih">
    <bill congress="113" type="hr" number="3137" version="ih"/>
    <revision size="18661" annotations="0" status="complete" id="5" commit-time="2013-10-03T18:57:51Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113hr3137ih/5.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HF341E4CC62394B12A532AE41E95AAD69" public-private="public">
  <metadata>
<dublinCore>
<title>113 HR 3137 IH: Freedom and Mobility in Consumer Banking Act</title>
<publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</publisher>
<date>2013-09-19</date>
<format>text/xml</format>
<language>EN</language>
<rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
    <congress>113th CONGRESS</congress>
    <session>1st Session</session>
    <legis-num>H. R. 3137</legis-num>
    <current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
    <action>
      <action-date date="20130919">September 19, 2013</action-date>
      <action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="S001145">Ms. Schakowsky</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="C000714">Mr. Conyers</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000191">Mr. DeFazio</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000288">Mr. Ellison</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000551">Mr. Grijalva</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000535">Mr. Gutiérrez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000551">Ms. Lee of California</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name>
      </action-desc>
    </action>
    <legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
    <official-title>To provide a framework establishing the rights, liabilities, and responsibilities of participants in closing procedures for certain types of consumer deposit accounts, to protect individual consumer rights, and for other purposes.</official-title>
  </form>
  <legis-body id="H14559119A92B40C2A05D0883C0A2508D" style="OLC">
    <section id="HE0D60738D9D947D8A671954BFACFEF82" section-type="section-one">
      <enum>1.</enum>
      <header>Short title</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote>
          <short-title>Freedom and Mobility in Consumer Banking Act</short-title>
        </quote>.</text>
    </section>
    <section id="H197E7560C10B4A9D84C78AE0F7FC9A1C">
      <enum>2.</enum>
      <header>Consumer Rights with Respect to Closed Accounts</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">The <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
          <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Truth in Savings Act">Truth in Savings Act</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/4301">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/12/4301/etseq">12 U.S.C. 4301 et seq.</cato:entity-ref>
          </external-xref>)</cato:entity> is amended—</text>
      <paragraph id="HA0EA20881D864BE8AFD20814A512A63F">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Truth in Savings Act/s:262">section 262</cato:entity-ref> and inserting the following:</text>
        <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7DE221114ADC45B182ED27F1893F3A4F" style="OLC">
          <section id="H2E46FA52FCC24986BDC230ED74E7B957">
            <enum>262.</enum>
            <header>Findings and Purposes</header>
            <subsection id="H541CF911D7954CB28567B585C81CADE3">
              <enum>(a)</enum>
              <header>Findings</header>
              <text>
                <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> finds that—</text>
              <paragraph id="H7A6F0BA6BD724677B7E81CE3CFA9DAFE">
                <enum>(1)</enum>
                <text>economic stability would be enhanced, competition between depository institutions would be improved, and the ability of the consumer to make informed decisions regarding deposit accounts, and to verify accounts, would be strengthened if there were uniformity in the disclosure of terms and conditions on which interest is paid and fees are assessed in connection with such accounts; and</text>
              </paragraph>
              <paragraph id="HDE709A1FEDAA48D2BF5B1E7F78DDB90C">
                <enum>(2)</enum>
                <text>consumers lack meaningful choices for managing household funds because—</text>
                <subparagraph id="H118BF06EDC394911A076D3280FFE11DA">
                  <enum>(A)</enum>
                  <text>despite dissatisfaction with rising account fees at some depository institutions, consumers often find it too difficult to move their funds to new deposit accounts;</text>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="H1C087B97945347C895009B0EA384F417">
                  <enum>(B)</enum>
                  <text>the process of moving funds to new deposit accounts often involves several steps and substantial time to complete, and it is not always clear what the proper procedures are for closing an account at a given depository institution;</text>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="HCB9BDF76F33C4639948488EFA0EC09FE">
                  <enum>(C)</enum>
                  <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">depository institutions have no obligation and may lack the technical capabilities to help consumers transfer automated deposits or debits from old accounts to new accounts, causing delays and confusion;</text>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="H49E166080D6A4D8DAE328F0AED0A001F">
                  <enum>(D)</enum>
                  <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">depository institutions may charge fees to close an account and withdraw available funds, which can impede banking mobility for low-income consumers; and</text>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H224234F76245480097989BFB8CF1F6C9">
                  <enum>(E)</enum>
                  <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">some depository institutions have engaged in the practice of reopening closed accounts without the consent of the consumer.</text>
                </subparagraph>
              </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1193BB22AD184C78947E7517950EC169">
              <enum>(b)</enum>
              <header>Purposes</header>
              <text>The purposes of this Act are—</text>
              <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD11C03535D4B45C6990A840E7967A8DD">
                <enum>(1)</enum>
                <text>to allow consumers to make a meaningful comparison between competing claims of depository institutions with regard to deposit accounts by requiring the clear and uniform disclosure of—</text>
                <subparagraph id="H76AF5EA8A5B14B3DB92E880F40CB9109">
                  <enum>(A)</enum>
                  <text>the rates of interest that are payable on deposit accounts by depository institutions; and</text>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="H60AAC36672484D85A3EA587BDCC368C2">
                  <enum>(B)</enum>
                  <text>the fees that are assessable against deposit accounts; and</text>
                </subparagraph>
              </paragraph>
              <paragraph id="H6ADBF7A462EA48CDBC4B9659BBF9904A">
                <enum>(2)</enum>
                <text>to protect rights of consumers by providing a framework establishing the rights, liabilities, and responsibilities of depository institutions and consumers in closing procedures for certain types of consumer deposit accounts.</text>
              </paragraph>
            </subsection>
          </section>
          <after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block>
        </quoted-block>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H83161B86B4C84EFFA69269E0C0BEC075">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text>by inserting after <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Truth in Savings Act/s:268">section 268</cato:entity-ref> the following:</text>
        <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8BCA36547D514DBB8AAF21A54DDD7B63" style="OLC">
          <section id="H83D330BCBADA4045AF939EF7359C5FBC">
            <enum>268A.</enum>
            <header>Closure of Covered Accounts</header>
            <subsection id="H2227545AAF994AB284F84D05DA9B3A63">
              <enum>(a)</enum>
              <header>In general</header>
              <text>A depository institution may not—</text>
              <paragraph id="H3E6F59DF257447339751F65D7929144D">
                <enum>(1)</enum>
                <text>prohibit a consumer from closing a covered account at the depository institution, regardless of whether the balance in the covered account is positive, zero, or negative;</text>
              </paragraph>
              <paragraph id="H40EAAFDDD4A743B6926C9D04185DFD37">
                <enum>(2)</enum>
                <text>charge any fee to close a covered account; or</text>
              </paragraph>
              <paragraph id="H3C8308DD012E43DCBD5B06401A3155AE">
                <enum>(3)</enum>
                <text>reopen a covered account that a consumer has requested to be closed in accordance with this section to apply subsequent debits, whether preauthorized or otherwise, or for any other reason, unless the consumer expressly requests that the covered account be reopened.</text>
              </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="HE45932F1590242BD80AC7275FE441A35">
              <enum>(b)</enum>
              <header>Disclosures required</header>
              <text>A depository institution shall provide to any consumer that opens a covered account at the depository institution a description of the policies and procedures that the depository institution has in place to close a covered account—</text>
              <paragraph id="H0FD5DF676A384E64BE14DA5B83DDF2DE">
                <enum>(1)</enum>
                <text>at the time the consumer opens the covered account;</text>
              </paragraph>
              <paragraph id="HCB15FEA9E20C4B55B705A1CE403EC4D2">
                <enum>(2)</enum>
                <text>at any time, upon request of a consumer; and</text>
              </paragraph>
              <paragraph id="H5AC15500BE4F473BA88BB1984B7342A6">
                <enum>(3)</enum>
                <text>on the website of the depository institution.</text>
              </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="H15FCB207176D4CE8878794D70E1A5775">
              <enum>(c)</enum>
              <header>Regulations relating to closure of covered accounts</header>
              <paragraph id="H429EF93B2D3D417F8EA69DCEC9C6D56B">
                <enum>(1)</enum>
                <header>In general</header>
                <text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this section, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection">Bureau</cato:entity-ref>, after consultation with each agency referred to in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Truth in Savings Act/s:270/ss:a">section 270(a)</cato:entity-ref>, and public notice and opportunity for comment, shall prescribe final regulations to carry out this section.</text>
              </paragraph>
              <paragraph id="H81D17BFC21DF4FAAB830C507E537FF7D">
                <enum>(2)</enum>
                <header>Content</header>
                <text>The regulations required by this subsection shall—</text>
                <subparagraph id="H38BCA1D14432411B8D5B54FE848A2CF2">
                  <enum>(A)</enum>
                  <text>require that a depository institution close a covered account not later than 5 business days after the date on which a consumer makes a request to close the covered account, except that the closure of the covered account may be delayed—</text>
                  <clause id="H470284DEEC704646933E0B85E684B8F6">
                    <enum>(i)</enum>
                    <text>if a Federal or State law enforcement agency notifies the depository institution that the closure will interfere with a criminal investigation; or</text>
                  </clause>
                  <clause id="H74969B28738F410DB3287AFAFD41EB4B">
                    <enum>(ii)</enum>
                    <text>pursuant to any other exception that the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection">Bureau</cato:entity-ref> determines is appropriate;</text>
                  </clause>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="H9EE3E4D0FC2640B8A38337BE74579BE4">
                  <enum>(B)</enum>
                  <text>prescribe the methods by which a consumer may make a request to a depository institution to close a covered account, which, except as provided in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Truth in Savings Act/s:268A/ss:c/p:2/sp:C" proposed="true">subparagraph (C)</cato:entity-ref>, shall include requests made in person, over the phone, or by other electronic or remote means;</text>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="HCBF9648A701744AD89132DB8A558AB7A">
                  <enum>(C)</enum>
                  <text>allow a depository institution to require that a request by a consumer to close a covered account shall be made in person if the covered account contains an amount on deposit exceeding a certain monetary threshold, as determined and established by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection">Bureau</cato:entity-ref>;</text>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="H608228C7613249CFA1DFD33C47FA4E99">
                  <enum>(D)</enum>
                  <text>establish procedures that require a depository institution to positively verify the identity of a consumer requesting to close a covered account before the depository institution closes the covered account, including procedures for a depository institution to follow if the depository institution is unable to verify the identity of the consumer;</text>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="H1FEA10ADDB874883AAE2DCB61CAC577B">
                  <enum>(E)</enum>
                  <text>establish procedures for a depository institution to provide a consumer with the funds contained in a covered account that the consumer has requested to close, which shall include procedures—</text>
                  <clause id="HC30677E3C1D8489AAFA07E1017533617">
                    <enum>(i)</enum>
                    <text>that ensure that the consumer whose identity has been positively verified by the depository institution has access to any funds available for withdrawal at the time the consumer makes a request to the depository institution to close the covered account;</text>
                  </clause>
                  <clause id="HD016F15449F0487EB2171FCFEE1FDA60">
                    <enum>(ii)</enum>
                    <text>that establish a reasonable amount of time for the depository institution to remit to the consumer the remainder of any funds in the closed covered account, including funds that are subject to a dispute between the depository institution and the consumer; and</text>
                  </clause>
                  <clause id="H259275CC96ED4C868F1143E9E17DDB5D">
                    <enum>(iii)</enum>
                    <text>that allow a consumer whose identity has been positively verified by the depository institution to receive available funds from a covered account that the consumer has requested to close in the form of—</text>
                    <subclause id="H5F654B3CBE4D4CA99A624D4EFCBF2080">
                      <enum>(I)</enum>
                      <text>a cashier's check provided to the consumer;</text>
                    </subclause>
                    <subclause id="H673DF4DDA88944218C4FC917EAAF8813">
                      <enum>(II)</enum>
                      <text>an electronic funds transfer to an account designated by the consumer;</text>
                    </subclause>
                    <subclause id="HBDB5C2FC5E9E4FD297627FC6CB3A91D7">
                      <enum>(III)</enum>
                      <text>any means offered by the depository institution that the consumer has requested; or</text>
                    </subclause>
                    <subclause id="H2F9F85E76B774992864872F5DC4F6DE5">
                      <enum>(IV)</enum>
                      <text>any means that the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection">Bureau</cato:entity-ref> determines appropriate;</text>
                    </subclause>
                  </clause>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="H26E856FDD0E145F2A81FC2F1983FB809">
                  <enum>(F)</enum>
                  <text>except as provided under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Truth in Savings Act/s:268A/ss:c/p:2/sp:G" proposed="true">subparagraph (G)</cato:entity-ref>, prohibit a depository institution from imposing any fee or charge on a covered account at the depository institution after the consumer has requested to close the covered account;</text>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="H4D3BEE4685234741A36215E51730EC21">
                  <enum>(G)</enum>
                  <text>allow a depository institution to assess an overdraft fee after a consumer has requested to close a covered account, if such overdraft fee is associated with a transaction that was initiated by the consumer before the date on which the consumer made a request to the depository institution to close the covered account;</text>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="H872BB15F40744502BA0EBFE8DC385B03">
                  <enum>(H)</enum>
                  <text>not limit the ability of a consumer to earn interest that a covered account had accrued before the date on which the consumer made a request to the depository institution to close the covered account;</text>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="HEAEAC149B3BC4105AC6C2D411C0E49C6">
                  <enum>(I)</enum>
                  <text>establish procedures for a depository institution and a consumer to follow if a personal check written by the consumer is deposited by a person other than the consumer after the date on which the consumer has closed a covered account;</text>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="H90016EA4C3A840489B3827BED4F1C6DB">
                  <enum>(J)</enum>
                  <text>require the depository institution to provide the consumer with certain information before the depository institution closes a covered account of the consumer, including—</text>
                  <clause id="H077CBB5782BD4BACBE06F4B0305DB447">
                    <enum>(i)</enum>
                    <text>a list of any preauthorized transactions relating to the covered account that occurred within the 60 days preceding the date on which the consumer made a request to the depository institution to close the covered account;</text>
                  </clause>
                  <clause id="H7A88AB6E5BC7454BB51D71AB65A9CAE1">
                    <enum>(ii)</enum>
                    <text>a list of any preauthorized transactions scheduled to occur in the 60 days after the date on which the consumer made a request to the depository institution to close the covered account;</text>
                  </clause>
                  <clause id="H92952B0715EB460EAE35B21C19392252">
                    <enum>(iii)</enum>
                    <text>a list of any direct deposits into the covered account in the 60 days preceding the date on which the consumer made a request to the depository institution to close the covered account; and</text>
                  </clause>
                  <clause id="H3328ACA7E7AA4D53AFCCACC8DE1951C4">
                    <enum>(iv)</enum>
                    <text>any other information that the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection">Bureau</cato:entity-ref> determines is necessary to provide consumers with adequate information about potential preauthorized activity relating to the covered account;</text>
                  </clause>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="H2FB07E64B7144E0FAFDE20D441F6A755">
                  <enum>(K)</enum>
                  <text>prohibit a depository institution from reporting an outstanding balance or any other adverse information with respect to a covered account at the depository institution to any consumer reporting agency, as defined in <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
                      <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Fair Credit Reporting Act/s:603/ss:f">section 603(f) of the Fair Credit Reporting Act</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/1681a">
                        <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/15/1681a">15 U.S.C. 1681a</cato:entity-ref>
                      </external-xref>)</cato:entity>, if—</text>
                  <clause id="H0D644E015CEB49C587964D41727B28C4">
                    <enum>(i)</enum>
                    <text>at the time the covered account is closed, the covered account has a negative balance resulting solely from any fee assessed by the depository institution; and</text>
                  </clause>
                  <clause id="H857618C9F7074B018DF1B62F389CB69F">
                    <enum>(ii)</enum>
                    <text>that information could be used to adversely affect the ability of the consumer to open an account at another depository institution;</text>
                  </clause>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="H1D99C5C94EEA40329E8E918E5D3CE266">
                  <enum>(L)</enum>
                  <text>establish the terms under which a depository institution may report that a covered account had a negative balance at the time of the closure of the covered account to a consumer reporting agency, as defined in <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
                      <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Fair Credit Reporting Act/s:603/ss:f">section 603(f) of the Fair Credit Reporting Act</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/1681a">
                        <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/15/1681a">15 U.S.C. 1681a</cato:entity-ref>
                      </external-xref>)</cato:entity>, if the depository institution—</text>
                  <clause id="H31646429B3D44433B078A0AE7D16C9F2">
                    <enum>(i)</enum>
                    <text>notifies the consumer of the negative balance; and</text>
                  </clause>
                  <clause id="H361CC086ECAA4A54AAB67780B2389EEB">
                    <enum>(ii)</enum>
                    <text>provides the consumer with a reasonable period of time, as determined and established by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection">Bureau</cato:entity-ref>, to repay the negative balance; and</text>
                  </clause>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2B21D84DCAED4817B9F1362DE4857DB9">
                  <enum>(M)</enum>
                  <text>include any other provisions, guidance, or exceptions that the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection">Bureau</cato:entity-ref> determines are appropriate in order to facilitate the purposes of this section.</text>
                </subparagraph>
              </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6A22A9AFD70C40EC849C776A91B007C4">
              <enum>(d)</enum>
              <header>Study; rulemaking</header>
              <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC04206CE2B384409883A7B30C34E6D88">
                <enum>(1)</enum>
                <header>Study</header>
                <subparagraph id="HA24D48D15F094B61A2BF142732799028">
                  <enum>(A)</enum>
                  <header>In general</header>
                  <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0500">Comptroller General of the United States</cato:entity-ref> shall conduct a study to determine additional barriers that could limit the ability of a consumer to close a covered account.</text>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF9CAD15B82364026A4DE4E80D857CF9E">
                  <enum>(B)</enum>
                  <header>Contents of study</header>
                  <text>The study required under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Truth in Savings Act/s:268A/ss:d/p:1" proposed="true">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref> shall include, at a minimum, analysis of—</text>
                  <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1D054C00A3C646C3AA19EAD906F19D83">
                    <enum>(i)</enum>
                    <text>potential reforms to payment clearing and settlement systems that would enable depository institutions to notify consumers if a preauthorized recurring debit is directed to a covered account after the covered account has been closed;</text>
                  </clause>
                  <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC6D73043ADAC420A9BA6510691CB4DAB">
                    <enum>(ii)</enum>
                    <text>potential reforms to payment clearing and settlement systems that would automatically transfer any direct deposit, preauthorized transaction, or other similar scheduled activity relating to a closed covered account to another account designated by the consumer;</text>
                  </clause>
                  <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8B9722DA7EE4463CBB82D2EBB46AD1C7">
                    <enum>(iii)</enum>
                    <text>other factors, including technological barriers, in payment clearing and scheduling systems that limit the ability of consumers to efficiently close a covered account and transfer funds to another account; and</text>
                  </clause>
                  <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0349E50C611C43E5AA711930FC9B8F94">
                    <enum>(iv)</enum>
                    <text>recommendations to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> and the appropriate Federal banking agencies, including steps that the appropriate Federal banking agencies could take through rulemaking to facilitate the automatic transfer of funds from a closed covered account to another account designated by the consumer.</text>
                  </clause>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="HCD16A31D8AF1449080BDEBDD23285D19">
                  <enum>(C)</enum>
                  <header>Report</header>
                  <text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this subsection, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0500">Comptroller General</cato:entity-ref> shall issue a report to the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection">Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection</cato:entity-ref> on the study required under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Truth in Savings Act/s:268A/ss:d/p:1/sp:A" proposed="true">subparagraph (A)</cato:entity-ref>, including any findings and determinations made by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0500">Comptroller General</cato:entity-ref> in carrying out such study.</text>
                </subparagraph>
              </paragraph>
              <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H65027B89ED7B4936A7E4CC4B4426AB79">
                <enum>(2)</enum>
                <header>Rulemaking</header>
                <text>Not later than 1 year after the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection">Bureau</cato:entity-ref> receives the report issued under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Truth in Savings Act/s:268A/ss:d/p:1/sp:C" proposed="true">paragraph (1)(C)</cato:entity-ref> the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection">Bureau</cato:entity-ref> shall—</text>
                <subparagraph id="H860D3C5C61AA429B919546051BFA0A4D">
                  <enum>(A)</enum>
                  <text>determine whether regulations should be issued to remove barriers that limit the ability of a consumer to close a covered account; and</text>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="H41E97E384D004E7ABD55D5EF8521D6CF">
                  <enum>(B)</enum>
                  <text>if the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection">Bureau</cato:entity-ref> determines that such regulations should be issued, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection">Bureau</cato:entity-ref> shall, in consultation with each agency referred to in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Truth in Savings Act/s:270/ss:a">section 270(a)</cato:entity-ref>, and after public notice and opportunity for comment, issue such regulations.</text>
                </subparagraph>
              </paragraph>
            </subsection>
          </section>
          <after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block>
        </quoted-block>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HEE3A93C8479E4804B33771B7C29AFAC7">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <text>in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Truth in Savings Act/s:274">section 274</cato:entity-ref>, by adding at the end the following:</text>
        <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H216AE60CDF1041DBB293CE548A5FAC30" style="OLC">
          <paragraph id="H1659F14D209146289EACC7A673F2C112">
            <enum>(9)</enum>
            <header>Available for withdrawal</header>
            <text>The term <term>available for withdrawal</term>, with respect to funds deposited, means available for all uses generally permitted to the customer for actually and finally collected funds under the account agreement with the depository institution or policies of the depository institution, such as for payment of checks drawn on the account, certification of checks drawn on the account, electronic payments, withdrawals by cash, and transfers between accounts.</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H9FFCAEF2780949048F69A5AB093BF986">
            <enum>(10)</enum>
            <header>Covered account</header>
            <text>The term <term>covered account</term> means any checking, savings, or any other account that the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection">Bureau</cato:entity-ref> may include, by regulation.</text>
          </paragraph>
          <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
        </quoted-block>
      </paragraph>
    </section>
  </legis-body>
</bill>
</doc>