<doc><docmeta id="113hr772ih">
    <bill congress="113" type="hr" number="772" version="ih"/>
    <revision id="5" commit-time="2013-03-24T22:18:35+00:00" comitter="/users/favila.xml" doc="/docs/113hr772ih/5.xml" status="complete"><description>Edited via AKN</description></revision>
</docmeta><bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H8E21BE8DD3F4437AB93A5B2AED7AF374" public-private="public">
	<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>113th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 772</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20130215">February 15, 2013</action-date>
			<action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="F000010">Mr. Faleomavaega</sponsor> (for
			 himself, <cosponsor name-id="R000435">Ms. Ros-Lehtinen</cosponsor>, and
			 <cosponsor name-id="C000266">Mr. Chabot</cosponsor>) introduced the following
			 bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee
			 on Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on
			 <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Armed Services</committee-name>, for a
			 period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for
			 consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the
			 committee concerned</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To promote peaceful and collaborative resolution of the
		  South China Sea dispute.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H94E9CF3762B34A888D1451AB2A79FE0A" style="OLC">
		<section id="H37F890CA0C234546B9ABA36062E38BD7" section-type="section-one">
      <enum>1.</enum>
      <header>Findings</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline"><cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> finds the following:</text>
			<paragraph id="H417875A17D86427D839AEEF2A9E4AD82">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The South China Sea contains vital
			 commercial shipping lanes and points of access between the Indian Ocean and
			 Pacific Ocean, providing a maritime lifeline to India, Singapore, Malaysia,
			 Indonesia, the Philippines, Vietnam, Brunei, Taiwan, Japan, and the Korean
			 peninsula.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H226D9D266C6146349FA6072625F48535">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text>China, Vietnam,
			 the Philippines, Taiwan, Malaysia, and Brunei have disputed territorial claims
			 over the Spratly Islands, and China, Taiwan, and Vietnam have disputed
			 territorial claims over the Paracel Islands.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H68100FCA77BF4A4FAA675B58DD226EF1">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In 2009, the Government of the People’s
			 Republic of China submitted to the United Nations a map with the 9-dotted line
			 (also known as the Cow Tongue line) which raised questions about whether China
			 officially claims most of the 1,423,000 square miles of the South China Sea,
			 more than any other nation involved in these territorial disputes.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HE370C1FF21CB4A0EA9948AC73EDBF560">
        <enum>(4)</enum>
        <text>In November 2012,
			 China began to include a map of its territorial claims inside its passports,
			 despite the protests of its neighbors, including Vietnam and the
			 Philippines.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H43A3D9195B334A919AB068031DCD622A">
        <enum>(5)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Although not a party to these disputes, the
			 United States has a national economic and security interest in maintaining
			 peace, stability, and prosperity in East Asia and Southeast Asia, and ensuring
			 that no party threatens or uses force or coercion unilaterally to assert
			 maritime territorial claims in East Asia and Southeast Asia, including in the
			 South China Sea, the East China Sea, or the Yellow Sea.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HDE6F21367D994CC6A6BCF675EF7F3B9D">
        <enum>(6)</enum>
        <text>The Association of
			 Southeast Asian Nations (ASEAN) has promoted multilateral talks in disputed
			 areas without settling the issue of sovereignty.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H2915F10724594AA39085B7CF65D1C78D">
        <enum>(7)</enum>
        <text>In 2002, ASEAN and
			 China signed a Declaration on the Conduct of Parties in the South China
			 Sea.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H8939F6E615DB489787236599053C076B">
        <enum>(8)</enum>
        <text>That declaration
			 committed all parties to those territorial disputes to <quote>reaffirm their
			 respect for and commitment to the freedom of navigation in and over flight
			 above the South China Sea as provided for by the universally recognized
			 principles of international law</quote>, and to <quote>resolve their
			 territorial and jurisdictional disputes by peaceful means, without resorting to
			 the threat or use of force</quote>.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H636FD2ADE74C450089D9E0F7A1AA77DB">
        <enum>(9)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In July and November of 2010, the United
			 States and our Republic of Korea allies conducted joint naval exercises in the
			 Yellow Sea in international waters, as well as Republic of Korea territorial
			 waters, in the vicinity of the site of the March 2010 North Korean attack on
			 the South Korean military vessel Cheonan, these exercises drew objections from
			 Beijing over foreign operations in the Yellow Sea.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HC04677F2B0F94675934DADC57079108E">
        <enum>(10)</enum>
        <text>In September
			 2010, tensions were raised in the East China Sea near the Senkaku (Diaoyutai)
			 Islands, a territory under the legal administration of Japan, when a Chinese
			 fishing vessel deliberately rammed Japanese Coast Guard patrol boats.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H31C9B5CD5D4E45A4A65C83B77B1C87D6">
        <enum>(11)</enum>
        <text>On February 25,
			 2011, a frigate from China's navy fired shots at 3 fishing boats from the
			 Philippines.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H1A8E5E0527A9487A9EB518B013A234F7">
        <enum>(12)</enum>
        <text>On March 2, 2011,
			 the Government of the Philippines reported that two patrol boats from China
			 attempted to ram one of its surveillance ships.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H062C108907804C1BA1F051F67484ED74">
        <enum>(13)</enum>
        <text>On May 26, 2011,
			 a maritime security vessel from China cut the cables of an exploration ship
			 from Vietnam, the Binh Minh, in the South China Sea in waters near Cam Ranh Bay
			 in the exclusive economic zone of Vietnam.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H7EE52245FA3D46B9815EFC08AF9C75A9">
        <enum>(14)</enum>
        <text>On May 31, 2011,
			 three Chinese military vessels used guns to threaten the crews of four
			 Vietnamese fishing boats while they were fishing in the waters of the Truong Sa
			 (Spratly) archipelago.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H8F30950D8CD346E78050A0D5F2E4CA06">
        <enum>(15)</enum>
        <text>On June 3, 2011,
			 Vietnam's Foreign Ministry released a statement that <quote>Vietnam is
			 resolutely opposed to these acts by China that seriously violated the sovereign
			 and jurisdiction rights of Viet Nam to its continental shelf and Exclusive
			 Economic Zone (EEZ)</quote>.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H908B923955B64019BB472F09AF5C7F95">
        <enum>(16)</enum>
        <text>On June 9, 2011,
			 three vessels from China, including one fishing vessel and two maritime
			 security vessels, ran into and disabled the cables of another exploration ship
			 from Vietnam, the Viking 2, in the exclusive economic zone of Vietnam.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HE8D8CC6B7F9A4472AFD9A12121752836">
        <enum>(17)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The actions of the Government of the
			 People's Republic of China in the South China Sea have also affected United
			 States military and maritime vessels and aircraft transiting through
			 international air space and waters, including the collision of a Chinese
			 fighter plane with a United States surveillance plane in 2001, the harassment
			 of the USNS Victorious and the USNS Impeccable in March 2009, and the collision
			 of a Chinese submarine with the sonar cable of the USS John McCain in June
			 2009.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H4A763E6797204B5C8ED274421CDE51A0">
        <enum>(18)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">On July 23, 2010, former Secretary of State
			 Hillary Rodham Clinton stated at the ASEAN Regional Forum that the United
			 States, like every nation, has a national interest in freedom of navigation,
			 open access to Asia’s maritime commons, respect for international law, and
			 unimpeded commerce in the South China Sea.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H6B392800520D4A93B448E8A9CCDFC817">
        <enum>(19)</enum>
        <text>On June 23, 2011,
			 the United States stated that it was ready to provide hardware to modernize the
			 military of the Philippines.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HF8CE20C079F34A2A889CD0F4233F0600">
        <enum>(20)</enum>
        <text>The United States
			 and the Philippines conducted combined naval exercises in the Sulu Sea, near
			 the South China Sea, from June 28 to July 8, 2011.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HF18223C0A01C40059AF5D1812B771B5E">
        <enum>(21)</enum>
        <text>On July 22, 2011,
			 an Indian naval vessel, sailing about 45 nautical miles off the coast of
			 Vietnam, was warned by a Chinese naval vessel that it was allegedly violating
			 Chinese territorial waters.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H350D75B6DA72472C99C169715F34F913">
        <enum>(22)</enum>
        <text>In June 2012,
			 China's cabinet, the State Council, approved the establishment of the city of
			 Sansha to oversee the areas claimed by China in the South China Sea.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H37BFA68EDD324510BFCC92DDFE2532AA">
        <enum>(23)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In July 2012, Chinese military authorities
			 announced that they had established a corresponding Sansha garrison in the new
			 prefecture.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H3482061565E542B18B108C59731349B9">
        <enum>(24)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">On June 23, 2012, the China National
			 Offshore Oil Corporation invited bids for oil exploration in areas within 200
			 nautical miles of the continental shelf and within the exclusive economic zone
			 of Vietnam.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H0B4B9B8AFB504BBCAD8E1E656DEADC31">
        <enum>(25)</enum>
        <text>Since July 2012,
			 Chinese patrol ships have been spotted near the disputed Senkaku (Diaoyutai)
			 Islands in the East China Sea.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H1B9DB2E4CC11424C915E3F1A5B6B4B5F">
        <enum>(26)</enum>
        <text>At the July 2012
			 ASEAN Regional Forum, former Secretary of State Clinton said, <quote>We believe
			 the nations of the region should work collaboratively and diplomatically to
			 resolve disputes without coercion, without intimidation, without threats, and
			 without the use of force</quote>.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H17B5E022577249AA8AEDF445C0E6155C">
        <enum>(27)</enum>
        <text>In November 2012,
			 a regulation was approved by the Hainan People’s Congress authorizing Chinese
			 maritime police to <quote>board, search</quote> and even <quote>take
			 over</quote> ships determined to be <quote>illegally entering</quote> South
			 China Sea waters unilaterally claimed by Beijing.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H2D82D5EF638C4DA3ACE02430DA571890">
        <enum>(28)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">At a meeting with the Japanese Foreign
			 Minister on January 18, 2013, former Secretary of State Clinton stated that
			 <quote>although the United States does not take a position on the ultimate
			 sovereignty of the (Senkaku) islands, we acknowledge they are under the
			 administration of Japan</quote>, adding that <quote>We oppose any unilateral
			 actions that would seek to undermine Japanese administration, and we urge all
			 parties to take steps to prevent incidents and manage disagreements through
			 peaceful means</quote>.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HA0F86722F9DC491ABE047D816A4DEBB0">
        <enum>(29)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">On August 3, 2012, a Department of State
			 spokesperson expressed concern over <quote>China’s upgrading of the
			 administrative level of Sansha City and the establishment of a new military
			 garrison there</quote>, expressed encouragement for ASEAN and China <quote>to
			 make meaningful progress toward finalizing a comprehensive Code of
			 Conduct</quote>, and called upon claimants to <quote>explore every diplomatic
			 or other peaceful avenue for resolution, including the use of arbitration or
			 other international legal mechanisms as needed</quote>.</text>
			</paragraph>
    </section>
    <section id="HBF662FAC15A04361878F2891223E2CBF">
      <enum>2.</enum>
      <header>Sense of
			 Congress</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> that, in light of the congressional finding described above, the
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref> should—</text>
			<paragraph id="HBCA9ADC398334AF6BF5D40985DC3C41E">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">reaffirm the strong support of the United
			 States for the peaceful resolution of maritime territorial disputes in the
			 South China Sea, the Taiwan Strait, the East China Sea, and the Yellow Sea and
			 pledge continued efforts to facilitate a collaborative, peaceful process to
			 resolve these disputes;</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HA2FA39EB2B46409CBFA92A52C24A5288">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">condemn the use of threats or force by
			 naval, maritime security, and fishing vessels from China in the South China Sea
			 and the East China Sea as well as the use of force by North Korea in the Yellow
			 Sea that would escalate tensions or result in miscalculations;</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H09B4B56B50234293A682E07E81E34D3B">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <text>note that overt
			 threats and gun boat diplomacy are not constructive means for settling these
			 outstanding maritime disputes;</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H1EF6BA765AAF4931A5797ED1532FFBC4">
        <enum>(4)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">welcome the diplomatic efforts of
			 Association of Southeast Asian Nations (ASEAN) and the United States allies and
			 partners in Japan, the Republic of Korea, Taiwan, the Philippines, and India to
			 amiably and fairly resolve these outstanding disputes; and</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H46CC0696B48943EBB5A95C8C4C1ACB98">
        <enum>(5)</enum>
        <text>support the
			 continuation of operations by the United States Armed Forces in support of
			 freedom of navigation rights in international waters and air space in the South
			 China Sea, the East China Sea, the Taiwan Strait, and the Yellow Sea.</text>
			</paragraph>
    </section>
    <section id="HB4CD75BC7F08453DA579C179644C3A15">
      <enum>3.</enum>
      <header>Report on the
			 Code of Conduct for the South China Sea</header>
			<subsection id="H86AE1447ACB34876A022A1EF64AECF10">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Report</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of
			 the enactment of this Act, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref> shall submit to the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="committee" entity-id="HFA00">Committee
			 on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives</cato:entity-ref> and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="committee" entity-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign
			 Relations of the Senate</cato:entity-ref> a report on the Code of Conduct and other peaceful
			 measures for resolution of the territorial disputes in the South China
			 Sea.</text>
			</subsection>
      <subsection id="H8D9E7137F97A439A9708EC4A5FB6A9C7">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Form</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The report required under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="113hr772ih/s:3/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref>
			 shall be submitted in unclassified form, but may contain a classified annex if
			 necessary.</text>
			</subsection>
    </section>
  </legis-body>
</bill></doc>