<doc>
  <docmeta id="113hr2469ih">
    <bill congress="113" type="hr" number="2469" version="ih"/>
    <revision size="12015" annotations="0" status="complete" id="3" commit-time="2013-08-06T16:04:56Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113hr2469ih/3.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H797B1A40E95C4991858722D5409251A1" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata>
<dublinCore>
<title>113 HR 2469 IH: Major General David F. Wherley, Jr. District of Columbia National Guard Retention and College Access Act</title>
<publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</publisher>
<date>2013-06-20</date>
<format>text/xml</format>
<language>EN</language>
<rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>113th CONGRESS</congress>
<session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. R. 2469</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20130620">June 20, 2013</action-date> 
<action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>
      </action-desc>
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To direct the Mayor of the District of Columbia to establish a District of Columbia National Guard Educational Assistance Program to encourage the enlistment and retention of persons in the District of Columbia National Guard by providing financial assistance to enable members of the National Guard of the District of Columbia to attend undergraduate, vocational, or technical courses.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H0E4A0EB537014C85BE718B4ABB0BEBC5" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HF7372F6CCEAF46A38ACCF369330494A8" section-type="section-one">
      <enum>1.</enum>
      <header>District of Columbia National Guard Educational Assistance Program</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Act entitled <quote>An Act to provide for the organization of the militia of the District of Columbia</quote>, approved March 1, 1889 (sec. 49—101 et seq., D.C. Official Code) is amended by adding at the end the following new title:</text>
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H3C09AC19E32E4066BBA94275EE9462BA" display-inline="no-display-inline">
<title id="H768A8EB008764619A95800CA3088C7EF">
          <enum>II</enum>
          <header>Educational Assistance Program</header>
<section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4B4E675D1ACE4467B5F3AD0C3B1E1BEB" section-type="subsequent-section">
            <enum>201.</enum>
            <header>Short title; Findings</header>
<subsection id="H1E6E057D3ECB40EE94D6C5822AA0AD2C">
              <enum>(a)</enum>
              <header>Short Title</header>
              <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This title may be cited as the <quote>
                  <short-title>Major General David F. Wherley, Jr. District of Columbia National Guard Retention and College Access Act</short-title>
                </quote>.</text>
            </subsection>
<subsection id="HBFE02E91EE5D467BB99A03CBCC669898">
              <enum>(b)</enum>
              <header>Findings</header>
              <text>
                <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> makes the following findings:</text>
<paragraph id="HBFDEF26F7C1C43F5B052DDDFA558B228">
                <enum>(1)</enum>
                <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The District of Columbia National Guard is under the exclusive jurisdiction of the President of the United States as Commander-in-Chief and, unlike other National Guards, is permanently federalized.</text>
              </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H4FE90E689B1C4B26856FBBE53D69AE14">
                <enum>(2)</enum>
                <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The District of Columbia National Guard is unique and differs from the National Guards of the several States in that the District of Columbia National Guard is responsible, not only for residents of the District of Columbia, but also for a special and unique mission and obligation as a result of the extensive presence of the Federal Government in the District of Columbia.</text>
              </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H9264A33DDBA14735A925A9AC6303CC3D">
                <enum>(3)</enum>
                <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Consequently, the President of the United States, rather than the chief executive of the District of Columbia, is in command of the District of Columbia National Guard, and only the President can call up the District of Columbia National Guard even for local emergencies.</text>
              </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H0AAD1D5483454D7C935A11B3BBEEC99B">
                <enum>(4)</enum>
                <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The District of Columbia National Guard has been specifically trained to address the unique emergencies that may occur regarding the presence of the Federal Government in the District of Columbia.</text>
              </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H6E66CBFF72264FE99A37C04C72C64A6B">
                <enum>(5)</enum>
                <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The great majority of the members of the District of Columbia National Guard actually live in Maryland or Virginia, rather than in the District of Columbia.</text>
              </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H8B1FDD786E1C4AF781905D34EDD2C982">
                <enum>(6)</enum>
                <text>The District of Columbia National Guard has been experiencing a disproportionate decline in force in comparison to the National Guards of Maryland and Virginia.</text>
              </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H7E3942ABF62945A2AACAF7168C99AA0A">
                <enum>(7)</enum>
                <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The States of Maryland and Virginia provide additional recruiting and retention incentives, such as educational benefits, in order to maintain their force, and their National Guards have drawn recruits from the District of Columbia at a rate that puts at risk the maintenance of the necessary force levels for the District of Columbia National Guard.</text>
              </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HEBB7B837DCAA4F748AE64EB36EB8A81A">
                <enum>(8)</enum>
                <text>Funds for an educational benefit for members of the District of Columbia National Guard would provide an incentive to help reverse the loss of members to nearby National Guards and allow for maintenance and increase of necessary District of Columbia National Guard personnel.</text>
              </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H715256B50B2D445C968A05B82F0E5D6B">
                <enum>(9)</enum>
                <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The loss of members of the District of Columbia National Guard could adversely affect the readiness of the District of Columbia National Guard to respond in the event of a terrorist attack on the capital of the United States.</text>
              </paragraph>
            </subsection>
          </section>
<section id="HC1C105E5845847CBBB9D9FF538DE04F6" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section">
            <enum>202.</enum>
            <header>District of Columbia National Guard Educational Assistance Program</header>
<subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF93DB49E290745129507C382DA99DFC4">
              <enum>(a)</enum>
              <header>Educational assistance program authorized</header>
              <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Mayor of the District of Columbia, in coordination with the commanding general of the District of Columbia National Guard, shall establish a program under which the Mayor may provide financial assistance to an eligible member of the District of Columbia National Guard to assist the member in covering expenses incurred by the member while enrolled in an approved institution of higher education to pursue the member’s first undergraduate, masters, vocational, or technical degree or certification.</text>
            </subsection>
<subsection id="H6C4B578D92E2426F97075553E4158A05">
              <enum>(b)</enum>
              <header>Eligibility</header>
<paragraph id="H367CAA31758048029A504461A9646A21">
                <enum>(1)</enum>
                <header>Criteria</header>
                <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A member of the District of Columbia National Guard is eligible to receive assistance under the program established under this title if the commanding general of the District of Columbia National Guard certifies to the Mayor the following:</text>
<subparagraph id="HC355E62406504E9CBE1C1D0087CC8C7A">
                  <enum>(A)</enum>
                  <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The member has satisfactorily completed required initial active duty service.</text>
                </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H06541190F67749B0B9083851919187F3">
                  <enum>(B)</enum>
                  <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The member has executed a written agreement to serve in the District of Columbia National Guard for a period of not less than 6 years.</text>
                </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H18777D36A67C4F0F82D083C4D43ED656">
                  <enum>(C)</enum>
                  <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The member is not receiving a Reserve Officer Training Corps scholarship.</text>
                </subparagraph>
              </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HD95EA9B5762A4F33B1F63930678DFE2D">
                <enum>(2)</enum>
                <header>Maintenance of eligibility</header>
                <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To continue to be eligible for financial assistance under the program, a member of the District of Columbia National Guard must—</text>
<subparagraph id="H9205C56BFF63406BAE833E9032D82044">
                  <enum>(A)</enum>
                  <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">be satisfactorily performing duty in the District of Columbia National Guard in accordance with regulations of the National Guard (as certified to the Mayor by the commanding general of the District of Columbia National Guard);</text>
                </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HDF385C95313041208E4688C5D85B59BC">
                  <enum>(B)</enum>
                  <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">be enrolled on a full-time or part-time basis (seeking to earn at least 3, but less than 12 credit hours per semester) in an approved institution of higher education; and</text>
                </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H2777620C342145E29A6F52D5A64416AB">
                  <enum>(C)</enum>
                  <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">maintain satisfactory progress in the course of study the member is pursuing, determined in accordance with <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
                      <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Higher Education Act of 1965/s:484/ss:c">section 484(c) of the <act-name parsable-cite="HEA65">Higher Education Act of 1965</act-name>
                      </cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1091">
                        <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/20/1091/c">20 U.S.C. 1091(c)</cato:entity-ref>
                      </external-xref>)</cato:entity>.</text>
                </subparagraph>
              </paragraph>
            </subsection>
          </section>
<section id="HC582D4942445489E9A1B3BDAAAACF33C" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section">
            <enum>203.</enum>
            <header>Treatment of Assistance Provided</header>
<subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2AF685B0551642A3AD495187DB8DE154">
              <enum>(a)</enum>
              <header>Permitted Use of Funds</header>
              <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Financial assistance received by a member of the District of Columbia National Guard under the program under this title may be used to cover—</text>
<paragraph id="H2D7A2B6EA3934F569B57C787D69C874A">
                <enum>(1)</enum>
                <text>tuition and fees charged by an approved institution of higher education involved;</text>
              </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H9ED9A09D52AF45B9B31C70BF6AF8B221">
                <enum>(2)</enum>
                <text>the cost of books; and</text>
              </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HF44633EF0142439CBC04F95CC027E77F">
                <enum>(3)</enum>
                <text>laboratory expenses.</text>
              </paragraph>
            </subsection>
<subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H408A573D8D1848C88F2C26D97920AA5B">
              <enum>(b)</enum>
              <header>Amount of assistance</header>
              <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amount of financial assistance provided to a member of the District of Columbia National Guard under the program may be up to $400 per credit hour, but not to exceed $6,000 per year. If the Mayor determines that the amount available to provide assistance under this title in any year will be insufficient, the Mayor may reduce the maximum amount of the assistance authorized, or set a limit on the number of participants, to ensure that amounts expended do not exceed available amounts.</text>
            </subsection>
<subsection id="H8F2E5B91B31942D595903A3641587B8A">
              <enum>(c)</enum>
              <header>Relation to other assistance</header>
              <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Major General David F. Wherley, Jr. District of Columbia National Guard Retention and College Access Act/s:202/ss:b/p:1/sp:C" proposed="true">section 202(b)(1)(C)</cato:entity-ref>, a member of the District of Columbia National Guard may receive financial assistance under the program in addition to educational assistance provided under any other provision of law.</text>
            </subsection>
<subsection id="H5FC881BCC502495BA3723074BFDFDBB1">
              <enum>(d)</enum>
              <header>Repayment</header>
              <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A member of the District of Columbia National Guard who receives assistance under the program and who, voluntarily or because of misconduct, fails to serve for the period covered by the agreement required by <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Major General David F. Wherley, Jr. District of Columbia National Guard Retention and College Access Act/s:202/ss:b/p:1" proposed="true">section 202(b)(1)</cato:entity-ref> or fails to comply with the eligibility conditions specified in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Major General David F. Wherley, Jr. District of Columbia National Guard Retention and College Access Act/s:202/ss:b/p:2" proposed="true">section 202(b)(2)</cato:entity-ref> shall be subject to the repayment provisions of <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc/37/373">
                  <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/37/373">section 373</external-xref> of title 37, United States Code</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
            </subsection>
          </section>
<section id="H0FA17D7B7CFB4771A5FBE6F5F2C04E57" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section">
            <enum>204.</enum>
            <header>Administration and Funding of Program</header>
<subsection id="H3B6B96AA1143428286CBF64A27908D03">
              <enum>(a)</enum>
              <header>Administration</header>
              <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Mayor, in coordination with the commanding general of the District of Columbia National Guard and in consultation with approved institutions of higher education, shall develop policies and procedures for the administration of the program under this title. Nothing in this title shall be construed to require an institution of higher education to alter the institution’s admissions policies or standards in any manner to enable a member of the District of Columbia National Guard to enroll in the institution.</text>
            </subsection>
<subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H47DA133189BF4A8BAD21D1B4A723677A">
              <enum>(b)</enum>
              <header>Funding sources and gifts</header>
<paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H73896D3755BC4611A95BED78E9736FF8">
                <enum>(1)</enum>
                <header>Authorization of appropriations</header>
                <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">
                  <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="auth-auth-approp">There are authorized to be appropriated to the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2093">District of Columbia</cato:entity-ref> <cato:funds-and-year amount="indefinite">such sums as may be necessary</cato:funds-and-year> <cato:property name="purpose">to enable the Mayor to provide financial assistance under the program</cato:property>. Funds appropriated pursuant to this authorization of appropriations shall remain available until expended.</cato:entity>
                </text>
              </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H1B5674B5F0D84E24929D220937A64259">
                <enum>(2)</enum>
                <header>Transfer of funds</header>
                <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Mayor may accept the transfer of funds from Federal agencies and use any funds so transferred for purposes of providing assistance under the program. There is authorized to be appropriated to the head of any executive branch agency such sums as may be necessary to permit the transfer of funds to the Mayor to provide financial assistance under this section.</text>
              </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HFA063D0E61924D1892F6EC0006EFC265">
                <enum>(3)</enum>
                <header>Donations</header>
                <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Mayor may accept, use, and dispose of donations of services or property for purposes of providing assistance under the program.</text>
              </paragraph>
            </subsection>
          </section>
<section id="H2DC96267C3B54BBBB1519C3764C54AAC" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section">
            <enum>205.</enum>
            <header>Definition</header>
            <text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this title, the term <term>approved institution of higher education</term> means an institution of higher education (as defined in <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Higher Education Act of 1965/s:102">section 102 of the <act-name parsable-cite="HEA65">Higher Education Act of 1965</act-name>
                </cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1002">
                  <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/20/1002">20 U.S.C. 1002</cato:entity-ref>
                </external-xref>)</cato:entity>) that—</text>
<paragraph id="HB7F8AA83616D479CB00F50715BD6377A">
              <enum>(1)</enum>
              <text>is eligible to participate in the student financial assistance programs under <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
                  <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Higher Education Act of 1965/t:IV">title IV of the <act-name parsable-cite="HEA65">Higher Education Act of 1965</act-name>
                  </cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1070">
                    <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/20/1070/etseq">20 U.S.C. 1070 et seq.</cato:entity-ref>
                  </external-xref>)</cato:entity>; and</text>
            </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H28FDDF738FC64825AA386D27B245D8AD">
              <enum>(2)</enum>
              <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has entered into an agreement with the Mayor containing an assurance that funds made available under this title are used to supplement and not supplant other assistance that may be available for members of the District of Columbia National Guard.</text>
            </paragraph>
          </section>
<section id="H1FB24091AEC04247A00AD62F569C3821" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section">
            <enum>206.</enum>
            <header>Effective Date</header>
            <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Financial assistance may be provided under the program under this title to eligible members of the District of Columbia National Guard for periods of instruction that begin on or after January 1, 2013.</text>
          </section>
        </title>
        <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
      </quoted-block>
    </section> 
</legis-body> 
</bill>
</doc>