<doc>
  <docmeta id="113hres287ih">
    <bill congress="113" type="hres" number="287" version="ih"/>
    <revision size="3434" annotations="0" status="complete" id="3" commit-time="2013-08-05T18:55:22Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113hres287ih/3.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <resolution xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" dms-id="H2FE9AC37E7434C60BE029500EB89434D" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"> 
<metadata>
<dublinCore>
<title>113 HRES 287 IH: Amending the Rules of the House of Representatives to permit absent Members to participate in committee hearings using video conferencing and related technologies and to establish a remote voting system under which absent Members may cast votes in the House on motions to suspend the rules.</title>
<publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</publisher>
<date>2013-06-28</date>
<format>text/xml</format>
<language>EN</language>
<rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code> 
<congress display="yes">113th CONGRESS</congress>
<session display="yes">1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. RES. 287</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action display="yes"> 
<action-date date="20130628">June 28, 2013</action-date> 
<action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="S001193">Mr. Swalwell of California</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="P000588">Mr. Pearce</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="L000571">Mrs. Lummis</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HRU00">Committee on Rules</committee-name>
      </action-desc>
</action> 
<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type> 
<official-title display="yes">Amending the Rules of the House of Representatives to permit absent Members to participate in committee hearings using video conferencing and related technologies and to establish a remote voting system under which absent Members may cast votes in the House on motions to suspend the rules.</official-title> 
</form> 
<resolution-body style="OLC" id="HC698ADDCF895467FA85E5185AA6E0B07"> 
<section display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="section-one" id="H607C8066C08D49EF922D444FDE67AC4B">
      <enum>1.</enum>
      <header>Short title</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This resolution may be cited as the <quote>Members Operating to Be Innovative and Link Everyone Resolution</quote> or the <quote>MOBILE Resolution</quote>.</text>
    </section> 
<section id="H785222F7962240F2BBD0B20FE5A7061E">
      <enum>2.</enum>
      <header>Participation of absent members in committee hearings through video conferencing and related technologies</header> 
<subsection id="HA6B3C488FFD54EA0A79B7262346404CB">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Enabling Participation of Absent Members</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Rule XI of the Rules of the House of Representatives is amended by adding at the end the following new clause:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H4C1C663B49BC4A07A0104E30F143020D" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<rules-clause id="HAEAD8CB53A224DC28E499DD609B2691D"> 
<rules-clause-header>Participation of absent members</rules-clause-header>
            <enum>7.</enum>
            <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each committee shall permit any member of the committee who is absent from the site of a hearing convened by the committee, as well as any other individual who is invited to participate in the hearing and who is absent from the site of the hearing, to use video conferencing and related technologies in order to participate in the hearing to the same extent as members of the committee and other individuals (as the case may be) who are present at the site of the meeting.</text>
          </rules-clause>
          <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
        </quoted-block>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="HF6F3834B9C2845D5A9F34C633D64C3ED">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Inclusion of Members Participating Remotely in Determination of Quorum</header>
        <text>Subparagraphs (2) and (3) of clause 2(h) of rule XI of the Rules of the House of Representatives are each amended by adding at the end the following sentence: <quote>A committee shall adopt a rule under which a member who participates in a hearing remotely pursuant to clause 7 shall be included in determining the number of members constituting a quorum at the hearing for purposes of this subparagraph.</quote>. </text>
      </subsection>
    </section> 
<section id="HAC5266D4744C4C8EB5CB522179914641">
      <enum>3.</enum>
      <header>Permitting absent members to vote remotely on suspension motions</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Clause 1 of rule XV of the Rules of the House of Representatives is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="HC09B6F55D44B4D39A6A56450DA5C9CE8" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<rules-paragraph id="HC8F593E036D947CDA9F1DED79E068F89" indent="up1">
          <enum>(d)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" value="Clerk of the House of Representatives" entity-parent-id="0050">Clerk</cato:entity-ref>, <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" value="Chief Administrative Officer" entity-parent-id="0050">Chief Administrative Officer</cato:entity-ref>, and <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" value="Sergeant at Arms of the House of Representatives" entity-parent-id="0050">Sergeant at Arms</cato:entity-ref> shall work together to develop and implement a secure remote voting system under which any member who is absent from the floor shall be permitted to cast a vote remotely on a motion to suspend the rules under this clause if the vote is taken by electronic device. A member who casts such a vote using the remote voting system under this subparagraph shall be treated as present for purposes of determining the existence of a quorum for considering the motion.</text>
        </rules-paragraph>
        <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
      </quoted-block>
    </section> 
</resolution-body> 
</resolution>
</doc>