<doc>
  <docmeta id="113hr2939eh">
    <bill congress="113" type="hr" number="2939" version="eh"/>
    <revision size="4929" annotations="0" status="complete" id="5" commit-time="2014-07-23T16:44:46Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113hr2939eh/5.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <bill bill-stage="Engrossed-in-House" dms-id="H49D5A79C10E1425BB5D9774E932F0BA6" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc" stage-count="1"> 
<metadata>
<dublinCore>
<dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">113 HR 2939 EH: To award the Congressional Gold Medal to Shimon Peres.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"/>
<dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="no">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>113th CONGRESS</congress> <session>2d Session</session> 
<legis-num>H. R. 2939</legis-num> 
<current-chamber display="no">IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type> 
<official-title display="yes">To award the Congressional Gold Medal to Shimon Peres.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H211E0503861543B59249CCD8E5CDC3AF" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H0EA0090D1BF14C1CAAAA60FC405BD195" section-type="section-one">
      <enum>1.</enum>
      <header>Findings</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress makes the following findings:</text> 
<paragraph id="HCE1307EEF8FA4D7BA5EC18BA35D1DAD9">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text>Shimon Peres was born in Poland in 1923.</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HB052F04196A64110828A2D0FF1717206">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text>The Peres family emigrated to Tel Aviv in 1934, and all of the family members of Shimon Peres who remained in Poland were murdered during the Holocaust.</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H56FA4A8E015948738787705C5E16CE07">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <text>Before Israel gained independence, Shimon Peres earned the respect of senior leaders in the independence movement in Israel, most notably David Ben-Gurion.</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H66455D5921D9459B81F4E41056613310">
        <enum>(4)</enum>
        <text>The founding generation of Israel was central to the development of Israel, and Shimon Peres is the only surviving member of that founding generation.</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H248FC314B3624DF79174C0DB0EFAF85D">
        <enum>(5)</enum>
        <text>Shimon Peres has served in numerous high-level cabinet positions and ministerial posts in Israel, including head of the Israeli Navy, Minister of Defense, Foreign Minister, Prime Minister, and President, among many others.</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HFE79FC8F305A4EA484639DEE420F0A92">
        <enum>(6)</enum>
        <text>Shimon Peres has honorably served Israel for over 70 years, during which he has significantly contributed to United States interests and has played a pivotal role in forging the strong and unbreakable bond between the United States and Israel.</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H86EAB5A1F76A450B89B3407951DEAD32">
        <enum>(7)</enum>
        <text>By presenting the Congressional Gold Medal to Shimon Peres, the first to be awarded to a sitting President of Israel, Congress proclaims its unbreakable bond with Israel and reaffirms its continual support for Israel as we commemorate the 65th anniversary of the independence of Israel and the 90th birthday of Shimon Peres, which are both significant milestones in Israeli history.</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HDA8C247604224D86920AC615C4A45579">
        <enum>(8)</enum>
        <text>Maintaining strong bilateral relations between the United States and Israel has been a priority of Shimon Peres since he began working with the United States in the days of John F. Kennedy. The strong bond is exemplified by the following:</text> 
<subparagraph id="HB2D5D677B4984B10BA6BBEFDE9F53A18">
          <enum>(A)</enum>
          <text>President Reagan said to Shimon Peres upon his visit to the United States, <quote>Mr. Prime Minister, I thank you very much for your visit. It's been an occasion to renew a friendship and to review and enhance the strength of our unique bilateral relationship.</quote>.</text> </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H02294CA07A8B4231BC637D5BE5E524AB">
          <enum>(B)</enum>
          <text>At another point President Reagan said of Shimon Peres, <quote>His vision, his statesmanship and his tenacity are greatly appreciated here.</quote>.</text> </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H0A6D0576495948CBB9DEC9B3BFA9AC98">
          <enum>(C)</enum>
          <text>While visiting with Shimon Peres at the Residence of the President in Jerusalem, President Obama described Shimon Peres as <quote>* * * a son of Israel who’s devoted his life to keeping Israel strong and sustaining the bonds between our two nations</quote>.</text> </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H4A25DEB1E16F479987D5674267E83316">
          <enum>(D)</enum>
          <text>On March 20, 2013, Shimon Peres reaffirmed his belief in the relationship between the United States and Israel, stating, <quote>America stood by our side from the very beginning. You support us as we rebuild our ancient homeland and as we defend our land. From Holocaust to redemption.</quote>.</text> </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H55EF7269DD164FA5A23436AD4997F3E9">
          <enum>(E)</enum>
          <text>On March 21, 2013, Shimon Peres stated, <quote>* * * America is so great and we are so small. But I learned that you don't measure us by size, but by values. When it comes to values, we are you and you are us * * * As I look back, I feel that the Israel of today has exceeded the vision we had 65 years ago. Reality has surpassed our dreams. The United States of America helped us to make this possible.</quote>.</text> </subparagraph>
      </paragraph>
    </section>
<section id="HA3EA5787958B4623A0D2B0651EFD3BA2">
      <enum>2.</enum>
      <header>Congressional gold medal</header> 
<subsection id="HA506E1A6FCF940F99CACA48DE9EA4898">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Award authorized</header>
        <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="President pro tempore of the Senate" entity-parent-id="0010">President pro tempore of the Senate</cato:entity-ref> and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Speaker of the House of Representatives" entity-parent-id="0050">Speaker of the House of Representatives</cato:entity-ref> shall make appropriate arrangements for the award, on behalf of <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref>, of a single gold medal of appropriate design in honor of President Shimon Peres.</text> </subsection>
<subsection id="H41887D1612E14AEB8486EE9E75836370">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Design and striking</header>
        <text>For the purpose of the award referred to in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="bill-by-number" value="113/hr/2939/s:2/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="2000" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of the Treasury</cato:entity-ref> shall strike a gold medal with suitable emblems, devices, and inscriptions to be determined by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary</cato:entity-ref>.</text> </subsection>
    </section>
<section id="H2084A0FB21A9411EB3895F11E8F18B15">
      <enum>3.</enum>
      <header>Duplicate medals</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Under such regulations as the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="2000" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of the Treasury</cato:entity-ref> may prescribe, the Secretary may strike duplicate medals in bronze of the gold medal struck pursuant to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="bill-by-number" value="113/hr/2939/s:2" proposed="true">section 2</cato:entity-ref> and sell such duplicate medals at a price sufficient to cover the costs of the medals, including labor, materials, dies, use of machinery, and overhead expenses.<pagebreak/>
      </text> </section>
<section id="H6B5E997470DD4387A73CEB6B2B530675">
      <enum>4.</enum>
      <header>National medals</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Medals struck pursuant to this Act are national medals for purposes of <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc-chapter/31/51">
          <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/31/51">chapter 51</external-xref> of title 31, United States Code</cato:entity-ref>.</text> </section> 
</legis-body> <attestation>
    <attestation-group>
      <attestation-date date="20140519" chamber="House">Passed the House of Representatives May 19, 2014.</attestation-date>
      <attestor display="no">Karen L. Haas,</attestor>
      <role>Clerk.</role>
    </attestation-group>
  </attestation>
<endorsement display="yes"/>
</bill>
</doc>