<doc>
  <docmeta id="113hr3692ih">
    <bill congress="113" type="hr" number="3692" version="ih"/>
    <revision size="19622" annotations="0" status="complete" id="3" commit-time="2013-12-18T20:25:06Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113hr3692ih/3.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H9A151D78D9734DF48CDB88716A80C6EB" public-private="public">
  <metadata>
<dublinCore>
<dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">113 HR 3692 IH: Schools of the Future Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">2013-12-10</dc:date>
<dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
    <congress>113th CONGRESS</congress>
    <session>1st Session</session>
    <legis-num>H. R. 3692</legis-num>
    <current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
    <action>
      <action-date date="20131210">December 10, 2013</action-date>
      <action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="L000565">Mr. Loebsack</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and the Workforce</committee-name>
      </action-desc>
    </action>
    <legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
    <official-title>To authorize a competitive grant program to implement and evaluate digital learning in rural locales.</official-title>
  </form>
  <legis-body id="H6CAF305B88E9464EB84D0737089A3DE2" style="OLC">
    <section id="H04C3784577944315A71C190C17349E8E" section-type="section-one">
      <enum>1.</enum>
      <header>Short title</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote>
          <short-title>Schools of the Future Act</short-title>
        </quote>.</text>
    </section>
    <section id="HEC57A93C765442978AE62D8FE899E164">
      <enum>2.</enum>
      <header>Findings</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> finds the following:</text>
      <paragraph id="H1BF8B59DFEBB4393A88319D1DC453C65">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text>Digital learning technology holds the promise of transforming rural education by removing barriers of distance and increasing school capacity.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HF51A21E6A1CB404D99BF28EF0C327F64">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text>While many large urban local educational agencies are at the forefront of implementing new digital learning innovations, it is often harder for smaller and more rural local educational agencies to access these tools. Smaller local educational agencies with less capacity may also find it more difficult to provide the training needed to effectively implement new digital learning technologies.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H1F99F669574440ED8D677425F50275FE">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Despite the potential of digital learning in rural areas, these advancements risk bypassing rural areas without support for their implementation. Rather than having schools and local educational agencies apply digital learning innovations designed for urban environments to rural areas, it is important that digital learning technologies be developed and implemented in ways that reflect the unique needs of rural areas.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H1FB90E6F8B2D47BF84CE508125391187">
        <enum>(4)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Digital learning is rapidly expanding, and new tools for improving teaching and learning are being developed every day. A growing demand for digital learning tools and products has made rigorous evaluation of their effectiveness increasingly important, as this information would allow school and local educational agency leaders to make informed choices about how best to use these tools to improve student achievement and educational outcomes.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H6E0E083FDD8646938D4E4BDA4A6E313A">
        <enum>(5)</enum>
        <text>High-quality digital learning increases student access to courses that may not have been available to students in rural communities, increasing their college and career readiness.</text>
      </paragraph>
    </section>
    <section id="HDE9E5DCE05CA454BABD64608DDC05274">
      <enum>3.</enum>
      <header>Program authorized</header>
      <subsection id="H430D2E68BF5B4905A3F2572FC8E7C288">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Grants to eligible partnerships</header>
        <text>From the amounts appropriated to carry out this Act, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="9100">Secretary of Education</cato:entity-ref> is authorized to award grants, on a competitive basis, to eligible partnerships to carry out the activities described in <internal-xref idref="H6CAF305B88E9464EB84D0737089A3DE2" legis-path="6.">
            <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Schools of the Future Act/s:6" proposed="true">section 6</cato:entity-ref>
          </internal-xref>.</text>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="H31A5607B1D9747FF8D435831457DBFDA">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Duration of grant</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A grant under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Schools of the Future Act/s:3/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref> shall be awarded for not less than a 3-year and not longer than a 5-year period.</text>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="H8A7E7024C8AE460B83847861E5A10737">
        <enum>(c)</enum>
        <header>Fiscal Agent</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If an eligible partnership receives a grant under this Act, a school partner in the partnership shall serve as the fiscal agent for the partnership.</text>
      </subsection>
    </section>
    <section id="HA2018111E6B9469486BF6167CA099815">
      <enum>4.</enum>
      <header>Application</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">An eligible partnership desiring a grant under this Act shall submit an application to the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="9100">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="9100">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> may require, which shall include the following:</text>
      <paragraph id="HC7C9E35FCFAA40F3992732918A448F9B">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text>A description of the eligible partnership, including the name of each of the partners and their respective roles and responsibilities.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H972D3267C446421B9A39EBA89A69B397">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text>A description of the technology-based learning practice, tool, strategy, or course that the eligible partnership proposes to develop or implement using the grant funds.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H251B3B86F0C5477084DE970F7FCD18C1">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <text>An assurance that all teachers of record hold the relevant license and are otherwise qualified to implement any technology-based practice, tool, strategy, or course using the grant funds.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HF907A14C48144073AB73368441FB1609">
        <enum>(4)</enum>
        <text>An assurance that all students in a class or school implementing a practice, tool, strategy or course using the grant funds will have access to any equipment necessary to participate on a full and equitable basis.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H98D6690AF7AD47F3B0B87903D68DB3DD">
        <enum>(5)</enum>
        <text>An assurance that the proposed uses of smartphones, laptops, tablets, or other devices susceptible to inappropriate use have the informed consent of parents or guardians and are not inconsistent with any policies of the local educational agency on the use of such devices.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H1F002E016232412B8B3A33F9866DA050">
        <enum>(6)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Information relevant to the selection criteria under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Schools of the Future Act/s:5/ss:c" proposed="true">
            <internal-xref idref="HE893FF6D66E94235AEFEA3C2E6AD2BF6" legis-path="5.(c)">section 5(c)</internal-xref>
          </cato:entity-ref>.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H4E99A64618754F7DB2B05A8DB1717900">
        <enum>(7)</enum>
        <text>A description of the evaluation to be undertaken by the eligible partnership, including—</text>
        <subparagraph id="H4B0AAA7609084EA3BC607F9A32BE56E3">
          <enum>(A)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">how the school partner and the evaluation partner will work together to implement the practice, tool, strategy, or course in such a way that permits the use of a rigorous, independent evaluation design that meets the standards of the What Works Clearinghouse of the Institute of Education Sciences; and</text>
        </subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="H1978BFBAB28048399E626979030CD602">
          <enum>(B)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a description of the evaluation design that meets such standards, which will be used to measure any significant effects on the outcomes described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Schools of the Future Act/s:7/ss:a/p:1..3" proposed="true">paragraphs (1) through (3) of section 7(a)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
        </subparagraph>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HF7DD906012D64C62811A90DCEBD55A1F">
        <enum>(8)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An estimate of the number of students to be reached through the grant and evidence of its capacity to reach the proposed number of students during the course of the grant.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H4F78299D8B29456B9484BFC99570076E">
        <enum>(9)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An assurance that the school partner in the eligible partnership will ensure that each school to be served by the grant under this Act is designated with a school locale code of Fringe Rural, Distant Rural, or Remote Rural, as determined by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="9100">Secretary</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H6360DDBF86B44277A83C1273F60D66C8">
        <enum>(10)</enum>
        <text>Any other information the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="9100">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> may require.</text>
      </paragraph>
    </section>
    <section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3476D3C26F804E84A9F1081C3F8AF818" section-type="subsequent-section">
      <enum>5.</enum>
      <header>Application review and award basis</header>
      <subsection id="HB4C3682B2527459DA408523392CC4833">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Peer Review</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="9100">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall use a peer review process to review applications for grants under this Act. The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="9100">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall appoint individuals to the peer review process who have relevant expertise in digital learning, research and evaluation, standards quality and alignment, and rural education.</text>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="H6B949DCC8F6B4F929C1509C5E3481690">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Award Basis</header>
        <text>In awarding grants under this Act, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="9100">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall ensure, to the extent practicable, diversity in the type of activities funded under the grants.</text>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="HE893FF6D66E94235AEFEA3C2E6AD2BF6">
        <enum>(c)</enum>
        <header>Selection Criteria</header>
        <text>In evaluating an eligible partnership’s application for a grant under this Act, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="9100">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall consider—</text>
        <paragraph id="H93FC7D3AA09F4D7BA4389E66745317AD">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>the need for the proposed technology-based learning practice, tool, strategy, or course;</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HDCAABC3863934966A324CDAD226E2060">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>the quality of the design of the proposed practice, tool, strategy, or course;</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H6734350423564943A310646FF1CC18B8">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the strength of the existing research evidence with respect to such practice, tool, strategy, or course;</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H4F5084FAAA984DCCB5D41E249BA441C4">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
          <text>the experience of the eligible partnership; and</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H650263999CBF4E01B0289F85413D0330">
          <enum>(5)</enum>
          <text>the quality of the evaluation proposed by the eligible partnership.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
    </section>
    <section id="HB2E5419B112E4BC092C5DF9D5A0ECFF3">
      <enum>6.</enum>
      <header>Use of funds</header>
      <subsection id="H500BAF8D5A544B7CA713750B7854D8D3">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Required use of funds</header>
        <paragraph id="H920C1A63A1E9491F9B4411541319F9A4">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>In general</header>
          <text>An eligible partnership receiving a grant under this Act shall use such funds to implement and evaluate the results of technology-based learning practices, strategies, tools, or courses, including the practices, strategies, tools, or courses identified under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Schools of the Future Act/s:6/ss:a/p:2..6" proposed="true">paragraphs (2) through (6)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H692E2BA8157C46C793B2D7A63E792BB7">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Tools and courses designed to personalize the learning experience</header>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Technology-based tools and courses identified under this paragraph include the following types of tools and courses designed to personalize the learning experience:</text>
          <subparagraph id="HFEE71331F35749609DFF30120B5974F8">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>Technology-based personalized instructional systems.</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H5A8C75998A3A4333A05EC44D93716FCF">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>Adaptive software, games, or tools, that can be used to personalize learning.</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="HFA48AF417B1C4A7687BFFD9B2DC47E78">
            <enum>(C)</enum>
            <text>Computer-based tutoring courses to help struggling students.</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H8D56C01E6266493AAE279E84C49D77DC">
            <enum>(D)</enum>
            <text>Games, digital tools, and smartphone or tablet applications to improve students’ engagement, focus, and time on task.</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="HF4EE7035CF144C3CB1C853A586591C19">
            <enum>(E)</enum>
            <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Other tools and courses designed to personalize the learning experience.</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HE47C0ED702CB4613BFB89A6126ED32D8">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <header>Practices and strategies designed to aid and inform instruction</header>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Technology-based practices and strategies identified under this paragraph include the following types of practices and strategies designed to aid and inform instruction:</text>
          <subparagraph id="H4731B7C790504BBF92FC910AC9A63C65">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>Adaptive software, games, or tools that can be used for the purpose of formative assessment.</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="HD246B656562E499985DECD98098E923D">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Web resources that provide teachers and their students access to instructional and curricular materials that are—</text>
            <clause id="H1A26A8541EC54513A1374216B02CF045">
              <enum>(i)</enum>
              <text>aligned with high-quality standards; and</text>
            </clause>
            <clause id="H9B82AE1E8A7948DFA29B7A50143DF3FF">
              <enum>(ii)</enum>
              <text>designed to prepare students for college and a career, such as a repository of primary historical sources for use in history and civics courses or examples of developmentally appropriate science experiments.</text>
            </clause>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="HE1536F25635E4DB48EC62F56C4DE11A0">
            <enum>(C)</enum>
            <text>Online professional development opportunities, teacher mentoring opportunities, and professional learning communities.</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H12C33A550BBC42AE8756A91D3C18A3B9">
            <enum>(D)</enum>
            <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Tools or web resources designed to address specific instructional problems.</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H41530FB84E1D4F4793535E934FEEAFC7">
            <enum>(E)</enum>
            <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Other practices and strategies designed to personalize the learning experience.</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HCA087147C67C47C086AFADB7EAB64806">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
          <header>Tools, courses, and strategies designed to improve the achievement of students with specific educational needs</header>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Technology-based tools, courses, and strategies identified under this paragraph include the following types of tools, courses, and strategies designed to meet the needs of students with specific educational needs:</text>
          <subparagraph id="H7C2A086DA5B94C3C80A0B64976999147">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>Digital tools specifically designed to meet the needs of students with a particular disability.</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H17892D8B6F8F483EB781788D155701CE">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>Online courses that give students who are not on track to graduate or have already dropped out of school the opportunity for accelerated credit recovery.</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="HEDBE2D61E19F4B72940ADAFC6C74B98D">
            <enum>(C)</enum>
            <text>Language instruction courses, games, or software designed to meet the needs of English language learners.</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H6BF6DC22CD134ECC8933E8B391214884">
            <enum>(D)</enum>
            <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Other tools, courses, and strategies designed to personalize the learning experience.</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H7683992877EE49A094EB03DB4354339A">
          <enum>(5)</enum>
          <header>Tools, courses, and strategies designed to help students develop 21st Century skills</header>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Technology-based tools, courses, and strategies identified under this paragraph include peer-to-peer virtual learning opportunities to be used for the purposes of project-based learning, deeper learning, and collaborative learning, and other tools, courses, and strategies designed to help students develop 21st century skills, such as the ability to think critically and solve problems, be effective communicators, collaborate with others, and learn to create and innovate.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H43BA1B6309394A46A4D40087DA252810">
          <enum>(6)</enum>
          <header>Technology-based or online courses that allow students to take courses that they would not otherwise have access to</header>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Technology-based or online courses identified under this paragraph include courses or collections of courses that provide students access to courses that they would not otherwise have access to, such as the following:</text>
          <subparagraph id="H0098F9AB36524C48936C53FA623A8366">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>An online repository of elective courses.</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="HA154C19946284B0FB2D5741239E85A2B">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>Online or software-based courses in foreign languages, especially in languages identified as critical or in schools where a teacher is not available to teach the language or course level a student requires.</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="HD296AACA1CCC49ACA44195D1DFD11700">
            <enum>(C)</enum>
            <text>Online advanced or college-level courses that can be taken for credit.</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="HB0E16CD62AEF4CD1B9615E4AB50E82BC">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Authorized use of funds</header>
        <text>An eligible partnership receiving a grant under this Act may use grant funds to—</text>
        <paragraph id="HFB36DBC939234D3D84F185FE340A4E37">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">develop the technology for technology-based learning strategies, practices, courses, or tools to be carried out under the grant;</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H83079C5B8B1A4083AC5494E0FFA84DA0">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">purchase hardware or software needed to carry out such strategies, practices, courses, or tools under the grant, except that such purchases may not exceed 50 percent of total grant funds;</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HFD55688E822B4679A7312A611261DD63">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <text>address the particular needs of student subgroups, including students with disabilities and English-language learners;</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H9EADF2B7A8704F22A171A721904BD0B8">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
          <text>provide technology-based professional development or professional development on how to maximize the utility of technology; and</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H5DBF59D70FB64B799A61613DB0AC6019">
          <enum>(5)</enum>
          <text>address issues of cost and capacity in rural areas and shortage subjects.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
    </section>
    <section id="H922B2EDEFE084587BAC00E425A92C53D">
      <enum>7.</enum>
      <header>Data collection and evaluation</header>
      <subsection id="HDD62B1829D01436BBC3455A975AA6672">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>In general</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each eligible partnership receiving a grant under this Act shall require its evaluation partner to complete an independent, comprehensive, well-designed, and well-implemented evaluation that meets the standards of the What Works Clearinghouse after the third year of implementation of the grant to measure the effect of the practice, tool, strategy, or course on—</text>
        <paragraph id="H3E46039FBA2A40658509FFCBB7843905">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">student achievement, as measured by high quality assessments that provide objective, valid, reliable measures of student academic growth and information on whether a student is on-track to graduate ready for college and career;</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HFF0C05ED886445968CF2A4E3A709309C">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>costs and savings to the school partner; and</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HFA04F82166A64BAB80720947EE863344">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <text>at least one of the following:</text>
          <subparagraph id="H341402209E104ECBB33F9253521E7534">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>Student achievement gaps.</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="HBD14C1603A0F43DC93DB17A3F1674F34">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>Graduation and dropout rates.</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="HB024987E2D544904BA691B60FBB8D8FE">
            <enum>(C)</enum>
            <text>College enrollment.</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="HC5369EC2B5D24B2ABAACDA61F4A958A5">
            <enum>(D)</enum>
            <text>College persistence.</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="HC79E14ACBED74F878064C9DC536B82DE">
            <enum>(E)</enum>
            <text>College completion.</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H595A4AAC2CF04A1388F8B83F00B7C256">
            <enum>(F)</enum>
            <text>Placement in a living-wage job.</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="HC1F56CD58F674EBE959902EE7B8129D9">
            <enum>(G)</enum>
            <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Enhanced teacher or principal effectiveness as measured by valid, reliable, and multiple measures of student achievement and other appropriate measures.</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="H976089FA001F4885A8FAB490F5ED51FD">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Evaluation</header>
        <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="9100">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall—</text>
        <paragraph id="H5055E91E97994FC88BED74C69F2ED9D6">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>acting through the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="9139">Director of the Institute of Education Sciences</cato:entity-ref>—</text>
          <subparagraph id="HC23E5BE6D84A462DB461AE39DB749934">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>evaluate the implementation and impact of the activities supported under the grant program authorized under this section; and</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H02E13FB91DE6407390AE0BF89ACEC04C">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>identify best practices; and</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HCDB45D9005964DC3881D38C42FA0C22B">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>disseminate, in consultation with the regional educational laboratories established under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Education Sciences Reform Act of 2002/pt:D">part D of the Education Sciences Reform Act of 2002</cato:entity-ref> and comprehensive centers established under the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Educational Technical Assistance Act of 2002">Educational Technical Assistance Act of 2002</cato:entity-ref>, research on best practices in school leadership.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="HA955842C9C164C5AAC9D1B31B3656136">
        <enum>(c)</enum>
        <header>Implementation evaluation</header>
        <text>An evaluation partner may use funds under this Act to carry out an implementation evaluation designed to provide information that may be useful for schools, local educational agencies, States, consortia of schools, and charter school networks seeking to implement similar practices, tools, strategies, or courses in the future.</text>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="H11487D9546B14B5D8513E1B92CD30A9F">
        <enum>(d)</enum>
        <header>Publication of results</header>
        <text>Upon completion of an evaluation described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Schools of the Future Act/s:7/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref>, <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Schools of the Future Act/s:7/ss:b" proposed="true">(b)</cato:entity-ref>, or <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Schools of the Future Act/s:7/ss:c" proposed="true">(c)</cato:entity-ref> the evaluation partner shall—</text>
        <paragraph id="H0763EFA636574FB9B45E615A06BE0FB9">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>submit a report of the results of the evaluation to the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="9100">Secretary</cato:entity-ref>; and</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HAAD5E4E4D09C42668DF33D99FB370178">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>make publicly available such results.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
    </section>
    <section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB533EEE5D3CF477BB78A55A6A2EDDC4F" section-type="subsequent-section">
      <enum>8.</enum>
      <header>Definitions</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text>
      <paragraph id="H9F6407FDF69B4B5DA89381C99C3BC9B5">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <header>Eligible partnership</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>eligible partnership</term> means a partnership that includes a school partner and not less than 1—</text>
        <subparagraph id="HEB2ECA25D7D34515B5F4BD55A320B54D">
          <enum>(A)</enum>
          <text>digital learning partner, except that in a case in which a school partner or evaluation partner demonstrates expertise in digital learning to the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="9100">Secretary</cato:entity-ref>; and</text>
        </subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="H1C1FD8DD4A7A4A1A893684E6D3B68968">
          <enum>(B)</enum>
          <text>evaluation partner.</text>
        </subparagraph>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph commented="no" id="H4FC563B8E80B4455B073304E50DAB165">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <header>School partner</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>school partner</term> means a—</text>
        <subparagraph id="HAB784BB0AA824452AEF0B59309339CE5">
          <enum>(A)</enum>
          <text>local educational agency;</text>
        </subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="HB0EF1E668E3F4912A6C233177C77AA29">
          <enum>(B)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a charter school network that does not include virtual schools;</text>
        </subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="H69D2DE858E924A2382E8EFE835B43E78">
          <enum>(C)</enum>
          <text>a consortium of public elementary schools or secondary schools;</text>
        </subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="H9726FC9ED31B415AACEEBC0A2F646F39">
          <enum>(D)</enum>
          <text>a regional educational service agency or similar regional educational service provider; or</text>
        </subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="H3587CE3E8A3347868F49D11BE5023F75">
          <enum>(E)</enum>
          <text>a consortium of the entities described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Schools of the Future Act/s:8/p:2/sp:A..D" proposed="true">subparagraphs (A) through (D)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
        </subparagraph>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H0D76163B91FE4FC384DD684FD7F3D6CC">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <header>Digital Learning partner</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>digital learning partner</term> means an organization with expertise in the technology required to develop or implement the digital learning practices, tools, strategies, or courses proposed by the school partner with which the digital learning partner will partner or has partnered under this Act, such as—</text>
        <subparagraph commented="no" id="HCB62C500FBD7495D8C00A39BB90DDBB2">
          <enum>(A)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an institution of higher education;</text>
        </subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="H8062714CD9864BE2BB49158B5DBACD7A">
          <enum>(B)</enum>
          <text>a nonprofit organization; or</text>
        </subparagraph>
        <subparagraph commented="no" id="HDC8C02D6F6124D76A9D0CC3C1F075DF7">
          <enum>(C)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an organization with school development or turnaround experience.</text>
        </subparagraph>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H7AAF0F00D9D84C3D862DC451C6F26EE5">
        <enum>(4)</enum>
        <header>Evaluation partner</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>evaluation partner</term> means a partner that has the expertise and ability to carry out the evaluation of a grant received under this Act, such as—</text>
        <subparagraph commented="no" id="H9AB6CF75574540CEAD4367784CCEB317">
          <enum>(A)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an institution of higher education;</text>
        </subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="H1033B72719A7464BA424642C005E1CDA">
          <enum>(B)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a nonprofit organization with expertise in evaluation; or</text>
        </subparagraph>
        <subparagraph commented="no" id="H696B59F3BABB48789F4618048E74DBFE">
          <enum>(C)</enum>
          <text>an evaluation firm.</text>
        </subparagraph>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph commented="no" id="HC955B5DCC57B40F5894138961994CB73">
        <enum>(5)</enum>
        <header>Institution of higher education</header>
        <text>The term <term>institution of higher education</term> has the meaning given the term in <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Higher Education Act of 1965/s:102">section 102 of the Higher Education Act of 1965</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1002">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/20/1002">20 U.S.C. 1002</cato:entity-ref>
            </external-xref>)</cato:entity>.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph commented="no" id="H9B11E2BC73514243A7D4BF000FB37950">
        <enum>(6)</enum>
        <header>Local educational agency</header>
        <text>The term <term>local educational agency</term> has the meaning given the term in <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965/s:9101">section 9101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7801">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/20/7801">20 U.S.C. 7801</cato:entity-ref>
            </external-xref>)</cato:entity>.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph commented="no" id="H0EEDC9C27D8F4882B6D6A8CCE890B773">
        <enum>(7)</enum>
        <header>Secretary</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Education.</text>
      </paragraph>
    </section>
  </legis-body>
</bill>
</doc>