<doc>
  <docmeta id="113hr4842ih">
    <bill congress="113" type="hr" number="4842" version="ih"/>
    <revision size="17992" annotations="0" status="complete" id="4" commit-time="2014-06-26T18:20:30Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113hr4842ih/4.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H302BC4F302A14E8A95002A8F1BE81AA3" public-private="public">
	<metadata>
<dublinCore>
<dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">113 HR 4842 IH: Business Supply Chain Transparency on Trafficking and Slavery Act of 2014</dc:title>
<dc:publisher xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">2014-06-11</dc:date>
<dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>113th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>2d Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 4842</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20140611">June 11, 2014</action-date>
			<action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="M000087">Mrs. Carolyn B. Maloney of New York</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="S000522">Mr. Smith of New Jersey</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Education and the Workforce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To amend the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 to require certain companies to disclose information
			 describing any measures the company has taken to identify and address
			 conditions of forced labor, slavery, human trafficking, and the worst
			 forms of child labor within the company’s supply chains.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H2DB0BF190C6D4765A7A67F752D11D067" style="OLC">
		<section id="H37888BEEACA74A0FA24214886C30A06C" section-type="section-one">
      <enum>1.</enum>
      <header>Short title</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote>
          <short-title>
            <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Business Supply Chain Transparency on Trafficking and Slavery Act of 2014" proposed="true">Business Supply Chain Transparency on Trafficking and Slavery Act of 2014</cato:entity-ref>
          </short-title>
        </quote>.</text>
		</section>
    <section id="H4D2F248B7E874C7488C9ABC364284867">
      <enum>2.</enum>
      <header>Findings and sense of congress</header>
			<subsection id="H02B798E11CB34F868107C1C78EA0B443">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Findings</header>
        <text>Congress finds the following:</text>
				<paragraph id="HCA316B844EC84F92A9CCAC46EF11F2E6">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>In 2012, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1600" entity-type="federal-body">Department of Labor</cato:entity-ref> identified 134 goods from 74 countries around the world made by
			 forced labor and child labor.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H4C426F0B57AA4EFFA3D2B5916707880A">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>The United States is the world’s largest importer, and in the 21st century, investors, consumers,
			 and broader civil society increasingly demand information about the human
			 rights impact of products in the United States market.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HE86ED2C608DE4982A01DC6827DEAE71D">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <text>Courts have also ruled that consumers do not have standing to bring a civil action in United States
			 courts for enforcement of this provision of the Tariff Act, because the
			 legislative intent was to protect American manufacturers from unfairly
			 priced goods, not to protect consumers from tainted goods, consequently,
			 there are fewer than 40 enforcement actions on record in the past 80
			 years.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H6D133372750441A2973D5B4C5DF5649B">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Mechanisms under Federal law related to forced labor, slavery, human trafficking, and the worst
			 forms of child labor in the stream of commerce suffer from similar
			 problems of limited scope, broad expectations, and inability to provide
			 information about specific supplies whose goods are tainted.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H9EF37B78BF8946B7A9F30EFC076BDFE4">
          <enum>(5)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="19UN" entity-type="federal-body">United Nations</cato:entity-ref> Guiding Principles on Business and Human Rights affirm that business enterprises
			 have a responsibility to respect human rights, and that States have a duty
			 to ensure these rights are protected. Such Guiding Principles also clarify
			 that the duty to protect against business-related human rights abuses
			 requires States to take the necessary steps to prevent and address human
			 rights abuses to workers through effective policies and regulation.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H7E45130884BA49148A5EE2D4306BC38C">
          <enum>(6)</enum>
          <text>The <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Trafficking Victims Protection Reauthorization Act of 2003">Trafficking Victims Protection Reauthorization Act of 2003</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/108/193">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="public-law" value="public-law/108/193">Public Law 108–193</cato:entity-ref>
            </external-xref>)</cato:entity> together with
			 the <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Trafficking Victims Protection Act of 2005">Trafficking Victims Protection Act of 2005</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/109/164">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="public-law" value="public-law/109/164">Public Law 109–164</cato:entity-ref>
            </external-xref>)</cato:entity>
			 provide for the termination of Federal contracts where a Federal
			 contractor or subcontractor engages in severe forms of trafficking in
			 persons or has procured a commercial sex act during the period of time
			 that the grant, contract, or cooperative agreement is in effect, or uses
			 forced labor in the performance of the grant, contract, or cooperative
			 agreement. The Trafficking Victims Protection Act of 2005 also provide
			 United States courts with criminal jurisdiction abroad over Federal
			 employees, contractors, or subcontractors who participate in severe forms
			 of trafficking in persons or forced labor.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H4B5E84CC1BAA40BAB4272D25BBCF4FF6">
          <enum>(7)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Executive Order 13126, Prohibition of Acquisition of Products Produced by Forced or Indentured
			 Child Labor, Executive Order 13627, Strengthening Protections Against
			 Trafficking In Persons In Federal Contracts, and <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2013/t:XVII">title XVII of the
			 National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2013</cato:entity-ref> (<cato:entity-ref entity-type="public-law" value="public-law/112/239">Public Law
			 112–239</cato:entity-ref>)</cato:entity> have prohibited Federal contractors, subcontractors, and their
			 employees from engaging in the following trafficking-related activities:
			 charging labor recruitment fees; confiscating passports and other identity
			 documents of workers; and using fraudulent recruitment practices,
			 including failing to disclose basic information or making material
			 misrepresentations about the terms and conditions of employment. Such
			 Executive order and Acts also require Federal contractors, subcontractors,
			 and their employees to maintain an anti-trafficking compliance plan that
			 includes, among other elements, a complaint mechanism and procedures to
			 prevent subcontractors at any tier from engaging in trafficking in
			 persons.</text>
				</paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="H99A41BF073D14562BCCF42AC39F7B17C">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Sense of congress</header>
        <text>It is the sense of <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> that—</text>
				<paragraph id="H4F0335DFBF5C48F38FCC7C43B5223078">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">forced labor, slavery, human trafficking, and the worst forms of child labor are among the most
			 egregious forms of abuse that humans commit against each other, for the
			 sake of commercial profit;</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H02FAD8CC7B754C8DBD3EAE176549B4ED">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the legislative and regulatory framework to prevent goods produced by forced labor, slavery, human
			 trafficking, and the worst forms of child labor from passing into the
			 stream of commerce in the United States is gravely inadequate;</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HED0E77DBCE1149D593CA13832E1542C7">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">legislation is necessary to provide consumers information on products that are free of child labor,
			 forced labor, slavery, and human trafficking; and</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H7E769DA8FD50468D9E2331868EF81990">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">through publicly available disclosures, businesses and consumers can avoid inadvertently promoting
			 or sanctioning these crimes through production and purchase of goods and
			 products that have been tainted in the supply chains.</text>
				</paragraph>
      </subsection>
    </section>
    <section id="HF20EE32AD2B948758368E6EAF4461FBA">
      <enum>3.</enum>
      <header>Disclosure of information relating to efforts to combat the Use of Forced Labor, Slavery,
			 Trafficking in Persons, or the Worst Forms of Child Labor</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">
        <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
          <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Securities Exchange Act of 1934/s:13">Section 13 of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/78m">
          <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/15/78m">15 U.S.C. 78m</cato:entity-ref>
        </external-xref>)</cato:entity> is amended by adding at the end
			 the following new subsection:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H85EB04E428F1464895470F0B8D551F2E" style="OLC">
				<subsection id="HD36AF9A9BA8B4F57B73D812FFC654A0E">
          <enum>(s)</enum>
          <header>Disclosures relating to efforts To combat the Use of Forced Labor, Slavery, Trafficking in Persons,
			 or the Worst Forms of Child Labor</header>
					<paragraph id="H30B6B0FDF2AB413DA006C3F5C2217D12">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <header>Regulations</header>
            <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of the <short-title>
                <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Global Supply Chain Transparency for Trafficking, Forced Labor, and Child Labor Eradication Act">Global Supply Chain Transparency for Trafficking, Forced Labor, and Child Labor Eradication Act</cato:entity-ref>
              </short-title>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="5000">Commission</cato:entity-ref>, in consultation with the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1900" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref>, shall promulgate regulations to
			 require that any covered issuer required to file reports with the
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="5000">Commission</cato:entity-ref> under this section to include annually in such reports, a
			 disclosure whether the covered issuer has taken any measures during the
			 year for which such reporting is required to identify and address
			 conditions of forced labor, slavery, human trafficking, and the worst
			 forms of child labor within the covered issuer’s supply chain, and a
			 description of such measures taken. Such disclosure shall include, under
			 the heading ‘Policies to Address Forced Labor, Slavery, Human Trafficking,
			 and the Worst Forms of Child Labor’, information describing to what
			 extent, if any, the covered issuer conducts any of the following
			 activities:</text>
						<subparagraph id="H9D702F96E8E3498B86121AE9EADAC50C">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whether the covered issuer maintains a policy to identify and eliminate the risks of forced labor,
			 slavery, human trafficking, and the worst forms of child labor within the
			 covered issuer’s supply chain (such disclosure to include the text of the
			 policy or substantive description of the elements of the policy), and
			 actions the covered issuer has taken pursuant to or in the absence of such
			 policy.</text>
						</subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H0C7A9C479BA249ADA713FBBE9B53AA79">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whether the covered issuer maintains a policy prohibiting its employees and employees of entities
			 associated with its supply chain for engaging in commercial sex acts with
			 a minor.</text>
						</subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="HD9D6EB393EB0447ABB1F3821CC66DD2E">
              <enum>(C)</enum>
              <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The efforts of the covered issuer to evaluate and address the risks of forced labor, slavery, human
			 trafficking, and the worst forms of child labor in the product supply
			 chain. If such efforts have been made, such disclosure shall—</text>
							<clause id="H3BE802922871439CADE9247511A6DB17">
                <enum>(i)</enum>
                <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">describe any risks identified within the supply chain, and the measures taken toward eliminating
			 those risks;</text>
							</clause>
              <clause id="H4A672514BE104EE29178203E20EABBE5">
                <enum>(ii)</enum>
                <text>specify whether the evaluation was or was not conducted by a third party;</text>
							</clause>
              <clause id="HE7539DA7644D4F0996CE41247616124D">
                <enum>(iii)</enum>
                <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">specify whether the process includes consultation with the independent labor organizations (as such
			 term is defined in <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
                    <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="National Labor Relations Act/s:2">section 2 of the National Labor Relations Act</cato:entity-ref> (<cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/29/152">29
			 U.S.C. 152</cato:entity-ref>)</cato:entity>), workers’ associations, or workers within workplaces and
			 incorporates the resulting input or written comments from such independent
			 labor organizations, workers’ associations, or workers and if so, the
			 disclosure shall describe the entities consulted and specify the method of
			 such consultation; and</text>
							</clause>
              <clause id="H29A708BADD6549568346386FC1C129C2">
                <enum>(iv)</enum>
                <text>specify the extent to which the process covers entities within the supply chain, including entities
			 upstream in the product supply chain and entities across lines of products
			 or services.</text>
							</clause>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H4615627027BB42EB9C1035B1C0EC74C5">
              <enum>(D)</enum>
              <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The efforts of the covered issuer to ensure that audits of suppliers within the supply chain of the
			 covered issuer are conducted to—</text>
							<clause id="H1171BA9E93E742938354962B611B42A8">
                <enum>(i)</enum>
                <text>investigate the working conditions and labor practices of such suppliers;</text>
							</clause>
              <clause id="H91CE50BDB38F4429A957437FB8085BA6">
                <enum>(ii)</enum>
                <text>verify whether such suppliers have in place appropriate systems to identify risks of forced labor,
			 slavery, human trafficking, and the worst forms of child labor within
			 their own supply chain; and</text>
							</clause>
              <clause id="H369EFF7F7DD44443BBBAF0DFF62CFF15">
                <enum>(iii)</enum>
                <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">evaluate whether such systems are in compliance with the policies of the covered issuer or efforts
			 in absence of such policies.</text>
							</clause>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="HF40D4EC9E6D2430DB2EE499C5364C36A">
              <enum>(E)</enum>
              <text>The efforts of the covered issuer to—</text>
							<clause id="H90D2C500D301473A80B5BB46B48DDE72">
                <enum>(i)</enum>
                <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">require suppliers in the supply chain to attest that the manufacture of materials incorporated into
			 any product and the recruitment of labor are carried out in compliance
			 with the laws regarding forced labor, slavery, human trafficking, and the
			 worst forms of child labor of the country or countries in which the
			 covered issuer is doing business;</text>
							</clause>
              <clause id="HF3FCE4D7B0164FA692344727868DF25B">
                <enum>(ii)</enum>
                <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">maintain internal accountability standards, supply chain management, and procurement systems, and
			 procedures for employees, suppliers, contractors, or other entities within
			 its supply chain failing to meet the covered issuer’s standards regarding
			 forced labor, slavery, human trafficking, and the worst forms of child
			 labor, including a description of such standards, systems, and procedures;</text>
							</clause>
              <clause id="H81D91206D87C4B869186A0BB1304F041">
                <enum>(iii)</enum>
                <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">train the employees and management who have direct responsibility for supply chain management on
			 issues related to forced labor, slavery, human trafficking, and the worst
			 forms of child labor, particularly with respect to mitigating risks within
			 the supply chains of products; and</text>
							</clause>
              <clause id="H9649A89F2EDC41B0B3047748A23608B6">
                <enum>(iv)</enum>
                <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">ensure that labor recruitment practices at all suppliers associated with the supply chain comply
			 with the covered issuer’s policies or efforts in absence of such policies
			 for eliminating exploitive labor practices that contribute to forced
			 labor, slavery, human trafficking, and the worst forms of child labor,
			 including by complying with audits of labor recruiters and disclosing the
			 results of such audits.</text>
							</clause>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="HFC97510DD50E4BD686CD88614EF1DB46">
              <enum>(F)</enum>
              <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The efforts of the covered issuer in cases where forced labor, slavery, human trafficking, and the
			 worst forms of child labor have been identified within the supply chain,
			 to ensure that remedial action is provided to those who have identified as
			 victims, including support for programs designed to prevent the recurrence
			 of those events within the industry or sector in which they have been
			 identified.</text>
						</subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="HB6507B853D6548A99EBCAA3148008ECA">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <header>Requirements for availability of information</header>
						<subparagraph id="H06E2AD346ADB41FDAFAA9697B3E8859C">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <header>In general</header>
              <text>The regulations promulgated under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Securities Exchange Act of 1934/s:13/ss:s/p:1" proposed="true">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref> shall require—</text>
							<clause id="H7C8A5DD32E4941E2A22CD5BB95E307CC">
                <enum>(i)</enum>
                <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that the required information be disclosed by the covered issuer on the Internet website of the
			 covered issuer through a conspicuous and easily understandable link to the
			 relevant information that shall be labeled <quote>Global Supply Chain Transparency</quote>; and</text>
							</clause>
              <clause id="H9181704EDA4244EFB1C6A4C34E260D5F">
                <enum>(ii)</enum>
                <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">if an individual submits a written request to the covered issuer for such information, that the
			 covered issuer provides the individual with a written disclosure of the
			 required information under this section within 30 days of the receipt of
			 such request.</text>
							</clause>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H878267A7639A4B73AEECC844D9B00ADB">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <header>Disclosure</header>
              <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="5000">Commission</cato:entity-ref> shall make available to the public in a searchable format on the Commission’s
			 website—</text>
							<clause id="HD6A09918810F4E279A454F907778E4EB">
                <enum>(i)</enum>
                <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a list of covered issuers required to disclose any measures taken by the company to identify and
			 address conditions of forced labor, slavery, human trafficking, and the
			 worst forms of child labor within the covered issuer’s supply chain, as
			 required by this subsection; and</text>
							</clause>
              <clause id="HA5959043F67B41DE91A41609907D72FE">
                <enum>(ii)</enum>
                <text>a compilation of the information submitted under the rules issued under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Securities Exchange Act of 1934/s:13/ss:s/p:1" proposed="true">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
							</clause>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="HDEF53C4F6C864A06850975DA28CB791E">
            <enum>(3)</enum>
            <header>Definitions</header>
            <text>As used in this subsection—</text>
						<subparagraph id="H501FCF9765284920B4BC7D7CA4DDC439">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <term>covered issuer</term> means an issuer that has annual worldwide global receipts in excess of $100,000,000;</text>
						</subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="HB58C32425742490DB0AA1CC4CE6C9A6B">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>the terms <term>forced labor</term>, <term>slavery</term>, and <term>human trafficking</term> mean any labor practice or human trafficking activity in violation of national and international
			 standards, including International Labor Organization Convention No. 182,
			 the <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
                  <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Trafficking Victims Protection Act of 2000">Trafficking Victims Protection Act of 2000</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/106/386">
                  <cato:entity-ref entity-type="public-law" value="public-law/106/386">Public Law 106–386</cato:entity-ref>
                </external-xref>)</cato:entity>, and
			 acts that would violate the criminal provisions related to slavery and
			 human trafficking under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc-chapter/18/77">
                  <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/77">
                  chapter 77
                </external-xref> of title 18, United States Code</cato:entity-ref>, if
			 they had been committed within the jurisdiction of the United States;</text>
						</subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H41C4FEB412814ABC988CA4E29D22E6D8">
              <enum>(C)</enum>
              <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the terms <term>remediation</term> and <term>remedial action</term> mean the activities or systems that an issuer puts in place to address non-compliance with the
			 standards identified through monitoring or verification, which may apply
			 to individuals adversely affected by the non-compliant conduct or address
			 broader systematic processes;</text>
						</subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H5F0F57B7495A4B4791A5C4DA723168E3">
              <enum>(D)</enum>
              <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <term>supply chain</term>, with respect to a covered issuer disclosing the information required under the regulations
			 promulgated under this section, means all labor recruiters, suppliers of
			 products, component parts of products, and raw materials used by such
			 entity in the manufacturing of such entity’s products whether or not such
			 entity has a direct relationship with the supplier; and</text>
						</subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="HD1C8564C4FD745C686CB7F7D9815A8AC">
              <enum>(E)</enum>
              <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <term>the worst forms of child labor</term> means child labor in violation of national and international standards, including International
			 Labor Organization Convention No. 182.</text>
						</subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
      </quoted-block>
		</section>
    <section commented="no" id="HFE08D57507C54843B7E49F4F2405D236">
      <enum>4.</enum>
      <header>Disclosures on website of Department of Labor</header>
			<subsection id="H6EBEC636757840DE968ABBDF7C1C045A">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>In general</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1600" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of Labor</cato:entity-ref> shall make available to the public in a searchable format on the Department
			 of Labor’s website—</text>
				<paragraph id="H75FC3AFCEAA04CAE9A0F7804E32C1C0F">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a list of companies required to disclose any measures taken by the company to identify and address
			 conditions of forced labor, slavery, human trafficking, and the worst
			 forms of child labor within the covered issuer’s supply chain, as required
			 by <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Securities Exchange Act of 1934/s:13/ss:s" proposed="true">section 13(s) of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934</cato:entity-ref>, as added by
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Business Supply Chain Transparency on Trafficking and Slavery Act of 2014/s:3" proposed="true">section 3</cato:entity-ref>; and</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H26E32090693544729E6A7DB910AF084D">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>a compilation of the information disclosed pursuant to such requirements.</text>
				</paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="H894EBA7414DF4A959EF6AAE9BF08CCA6">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Top 100 list</header>
        <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1600" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of Labor</cato:entity-ref>, in consultation with the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1900" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref> and other appropriate Federal
			 and international agencies, independent labor evaluators, and human rights
			 groups, shall annually develop and publish on the Internet website of the
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1600" entity-type="federal-body">Department of Labor</cato:entity-ref> a list of top 100 companies adhering to supply chain
			 labor standards, as established under relevant Federal and international
			 guidelines.</text>
			</subsection>
    </section>
  </legis-body>
</bill>
</doc>