<doc>
  <docmeta id="113hres58ih">
    <bill congress="113" type="hres" number="58" version="ih"/>
    <revision size="3706" annotations="0" id="3" commit-time="2013-03-07T23:44:15+00:00" committer="favila" doc="113hres58ih/3.xml" status="complete">
      <description/>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <resolution xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" dms-id="H94B55D2149E44AC78FE625BF633A646A" key="H" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print">
	<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">113th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session display="yes">1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. RES. 58</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20130206">February 6, 2013</action-date>
			<action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="L000566">Mr. Latta</sponsor> submitted
			 the following resolution; which was referred to the
			 <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and
			 Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on
			 <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Science, Space, and
			 Technology</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the
			 Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the
			 jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">Expressing the sense of the House of
		  Representatives that any comprehensive plan to reform our national energy
		  policy must promote the expanded use of renewable and alternative energy
		  sources; increase our domestic refining capacity; promote conservation and
		  increased energy efficiency; expand research and development, including
		  domestic exploration; and enhance consumer education.</official-title>
	</form>
	<preamble>
		<whereas>
      <text>Whereas the United States consumes roughly an average of
			 18,949,000 barrels of oil per day;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the global average of daily oil consumption stands
			 at 87,421,000 barrels of oil per day;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the United States total annual energy consumption
			 is approximately 94.547 quadrillion BTU, with the global total annual energy
			 consumption at 482.872 quadrillion BTU;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the United States share of world energy
			 consumption is projected to fall from 19.5 percent in 2009 to 14.8 percent in
			 2035;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas according to the International Energy Agency,
			 China surpassed the United States in energy consumption in 2009 and the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="8932">Energy
			 Information Administration</cato:entity-ref> projects China’s energy consumption to exceed that
			 of the United States between the years 2015 and 2020;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the United States has an estimated 235-year coal
			 reserve, coal is the most abundant and efficient domestic fuel source, and
			 processes such as gasification and liquefaction offer cleaner alternatives for
			 utilizing this resource;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas renewable sources of energy account for 8.090
			 quadrillion BTU per year in the United States; and</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas such sources such as biomass, geothermal,
			 hydropower, nuclear, solar, and wind need and deserve our attention and the
			 necessary resources to encourage their commercial viability: Now, therefore, be
			 it</text>
		</whereas>
  </preamble>
	<resolution-body id="H7566661469A944CDB5E3B2A16726050A" style="traditional">
		<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HE41491A01EBE45D786AB353A08550BEA" section-type="undesignated-section">
      <enum/>
      <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That it is the sense of the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0050">House of
			 Representatives</cato:entity-ref> that in order to meet our Nation’s growing long-term energy
			 demands and maintain our economic viability in the world marketplace, the
			 following must be addressed in any comprehensive and economically viable energy
			 bill considered by the 113th Congress:</text>
			<paragraph id="HA9AFA201CC2B4A9A948CDB18360E63C2">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text>Taking advantage
			 of our abundant domestic coal supply.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H5E4545A5F3D9446182F2AB77EAD615BC">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text>Using recent
			 technological innovations to exploit our vast supply of natural gas.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HC4FCA6B5CCF746FF92C56C0F6EE19D15">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <text>Increasing our
			 domestic oil production and refining capacity.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HB17625DAE2B34D1AAC5F19CBEC1EE92A">
        <enum>(4)</enum>
        <text>Expanding use of
			 renewable and alternative energy sources, with a focus on nuclear
			 energy.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HB303003669224E9FAA9D1FE7E5443DDA">
        <enum>(5)</enum>
        <text>Promoting and
			 providing incentives for an increase in conservation and energy
			 efficiency.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HDB35E15C2230440D9E42AF8625C42A43">
        <enum>(6)</enum>
        <text>Expanding and
			 promoting additional research and development through new and innovative
			 methods such as public-private partnerships.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H79E2438F803B4091962A62C3AE90FAEF">
        <enum>(7)</enum>
        <text>Enhancing consumer
			 awareness and education regarding methods to increase energy efficiency and
			 available alternative fuel sources to reduce our dependence on Middle Eastern
			 oil.</text>
			</paragraph>
    </section>
  </resolution-body>
</resolution>
</doc>