<doc>
  <docmeta id="113hr2681ih">
    <bill congress="113" type="hr" number="2681" version="ih"/>
    <revision size="20859" annotations="0" status="complete" id="4" commit-time="2013-08-06T15:25:19Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113hr2681ih/4.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HC2D63FC03F894CFD95C04E85A69FAD3B" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>113 HR 2681 IH: District of Columbia-Maryland Reunion Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2013-07-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>113th CONGRESS</congress> <session>1st Session</session> 
<legis-num>H. R. 2681</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20130711">July 11, 2013</action-date> 
<action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="G000552">Mr. Gohmert</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc> 
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To provide for the retrocession of the District of Columbia to Maryland, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H9C54158D8B4A4CAFA2050CB3D6CDCB09" style="OLC"> 
<section section-type="section-one" id="H96E9F1117B7E41A6A53CD7B95A424631" display-inline="no-display-inline">
      <enum>1.</enum>
      <header>Short title</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote>
          <short-title>District of Columbia-Maryland Reunion Act</short-title>
        </quote>.</text>
    </section> 
<section id="H8364035E7B0A4713BA7C8E87E81FC0DD">
      <enum>2.</enum>
      <header>Findings</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">
        <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> finds the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H591F3E6F785D48A2B570EB4B0070B845">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text>Residents of Washington, DC, pay Federal income tax, but do not have voting members in the United States Congress.</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7A095342D73641D9AE0C224F734F3372">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text>Article I, section 2, clause 1 of the United States Constitution states that the <quote>House of Representatives shall be composed of members chosen every second year by the people of the several states.</quote>. </text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCCABFC544F464D30A84411C92729801F">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <text>The Founding Fathers did not consider the proposed district that would become Washington, DC, a State under the Constitution, as evidenced when Alexander Hamilton offered an amendment to the Constitution during the New York ratification to provide full congressional representation to Washington, DC, but the convention rejected the amendment on July 22, 1788. Thomas Tredwell stated at the same convention that the plan for Washington, DC, <quote>departs from every principle of freedom</quote> because it did not give residents full representation in Congress.</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2A324AFE5BC949DAA1AB0CB33D905D02">
        <enum>(4)</enum>
        <text>Chief Justice Marshall held in Hepburn v. Ellzey in 1805 that the term <term>states</term> in Article I, section 2, clause 1 of the Constitution does not include Washington, DC, for representation purposes.</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H790AA0D7406C4886BB1806722BBBC97C">
        <enum>(5)</enum>
        <text>Seven Supreme Court Justices affirmed Chief Justice Marshall’s Hepburn reasoning in National Mut. Ins. Co. of Dist. of Col. v. Tidewater Transfer Co. in 1949. </text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H755FDD8B5D1047AA9F3B266ADF13D7C6">
        <enum>(6)</enum>
        <text>A Democrat-controlled Congress in 1978 attempted to amend the Constitution to provide Washington, DC, with full congressional representation. The Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives reported the resolution and stated that granting congressional representation to the District of Columbia as it is presently constituted would require a constitutional amendment, because <quote>statutory action alone will not suffice</quote>.</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HAE27E9B75B6E46C0A339B56DB81F2A40">
        <enum>(7)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Proposals to grant Washington, DC, congressional representation will inevitably be challenged in court, calling into question the validity of any narrowly-passed legislation that a Washington, DC, member votes on and leaving Washington, DC, residents in a continued state of flux over their status.</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2A679FB56DB140F29C7F9B7DBD65E59A">
        <enum>(8)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Amending the Constitution requires two-thirds approval by each house of Congress and ratification by three-fourths of the States. In 1978, there was success in obtaining a favorable vote from two-thirds of both the House and the Senate on a constitutional amendment to provide Washington, DC, with full congressional representation, but the requirement for ratification by three-fourths of the States could not be obtained.</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6E79E207D199455FBBA48D3A16FA8FE5">
        <enum>(9)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An alternative to a potentially lengthy and difficult constitutional amendment process is ceding Washington, DC, back to Maryland, just as an area of 31 square miles that was originally ceded by Virginia was returned to that State by Federal legislation in 1847, thereby ensuring that the portion of Washington, DC, in Virginia would have Senate and House representation.</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCCB195BB25704A0DB55B320E71B87668">
        <enum>(10)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline"> In 1847, there was a desire to allow the District of Columbia land on the west side of the Potomac River that was not being used by the federal government to have its own proper representation in Congress.</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H55AA089E138C4D48B7AC2E3FDBA762B8">
        <enum>(11)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Obtaining the desired representation for this portion of Washington, DC, would have required a constitutional amendment unless the land were given back to Virginia.</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H307804AED75A43B3889D0927B7C80507">
        <enum>(12)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Instead of trying to pass a constitutional amendment, Congress in 1847 legislatively ceded back to Virginia from the District of Columbia the non-Federal land composed of 31 square miles on the west side of the Potomac River.</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H52D6E7AC7DB5456FB26864564CDEFCA4">
        <enum>(13)</enum>
        <text>Accordingly, the District of Columbia would clearly and constitutionally have 2 Senators and a Representative with full voting rights by ceding the District of Columbia to Maryland after Maryland’s acceptance of such retrocession, while maintaining the exclusive legislative authority and control of Congress over the National Capital Service Area in the District of Columbia.</text>
      </paragraph>
    </section> 
<section id="H852171B754BF4E8E9628FFC8DAD97F68">
      <enum>3.</enum>
      <header>Retrocession of District of Columbia to Maryland</header> 
<subsection id="H0FEBCC6FD2A5495FAD609144B8EFFA2D">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>In general</header>
        <text>Upon the issuance of a proclamation by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="District of Columbia-Maryland Reunion Act/s:8" proposed="true">section 8</cato:entity-ref> and except as provided in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="District of Columbia-Maryland Reunion Act/s:3/ss:b" proposed="true">subsection (b)</cato:entity-ref>, the territory ceded to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> by the State of Maryland to serve as the District constituting the permanent seat of the Government of the United States is ceded and relinquished to the State of Maryland.</text>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="H6546C5EC2A32422EA95B058EF23F6EC1">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Continuation of Federal control over National Capital Service Area</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="District of Columbia-Maryland Reunion Act/s:3/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref>, the National Capital Service Area described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="District of Columbia-Maryland Reunion Act/s:5" proposed="true">section 5</cato:entity-ref> shall not be ceded and relinquished to the State of Maryland and shall continue to serve as the permanent seat of the Government of the United States, and <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> shall continue to exercise exclusive legislative authority and control over such Area.</text>
      </subsection>
    </section> 
<section id="H61D1E5AB6AFB4057B30A65AEB3178F81">
      <enum>4.</enum>
      <header>Effect on judicial proceedings in District of Columbia</header> 
<subsection id="HEAD6A6BFABB94F03A06678071DAD7B28">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Continuation of suits</header>
        <text>No writ, action, indictment, cause, or proceeding pending in any court of the District of Columbia on the effective date of this Act shall abate as a result of the enactment of this Act, but shall be transferred and shall proceed within such appropriate court of the State of Maryland as established under the laws or constitution of the State of Maryland.</text>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="H8967E85E03D34D19935348ADD69582EF">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Appeals</header>
        <text>An order or decision of any court of the District of Columbia for which no appeal has been filed as of the effective date of this Act shall be considered an order or decision of a court of the State of Maryland for purposes of appeal from and appellate review of such order or decision in an appropriate court of the State of Maryland.</text>
      </subsection>
    </section> 
<section id="H78458258838C4E0492513251EE4D73E3">
      <enum>5.</enum>
      <header>National Capital Service Area</header> 
<subsection id="HC58CBABDB2594D97B4A3E14B40FC5E79">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Description</header>
        <text>The National Capital Service Area referred to in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="District of Columbia-Maryland Reunion Act/s:3/ss:b" proposed="true">section 3(b)</cato:entity-ref> is comprised of the principal Federal monuments, the White House, the United States Capitol, the United States Supreme Court Building, and the Federal executive, legislative, and judicial office buildings located adjacent to the Mall and the United States Capitol (but shall not include the District Building), and is more particularly described as the territory located within the following boundaries:</text>
        <continuation-text continuation-text-level="subsection">Beginning at the point on the present Virginia-District of Columbia boundary due west of the northernmost point of Theodore Roosevelt Island and running due east of the eastern shore of the Potomac River;</continuation-text>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="H3B4189453B8445D7A372219F8670C8FD">
        <enum/>
        <text/>
<paragraph id="H7538AF5A82034844AAB19AA075843C5D">
          <enum/>
          <text>thence generally south along the shore at the mean high water mark to the northwest corner of the Kennedy Center;</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD240490E1EC9491DA47C1263BA77537E">
          <enum/>
          <text>thence east along the north side of the Kennedy Center to a point where it reaches the E Street Expressway;</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H45B29C117D294BB1965CBDE78F3F11B7">
          <enum/>
          <text>thence east on the expressway to E Street Northwest and thence east on E Street Northwest to Nineteenth Street Northwest;</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1FBF514B21B4433F864F48E32964581D">
          <enum/>
          <text>thence north on Nineteenth Street Northwest to F Street Northwest;</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA9A2EAC57C6A4CF2AD9D86D79C51C5C8">
          <enum/>
          <text>thence east on F Street Northwest to Eighteenth Street Northwest;</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HAEA94487F85145929F6768251ECAD8C8">
          <enum/>
          <text>thence south on Eighteenth Street Northwest to Constitution Avenue Northwest;</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H29878D1D4D2049F6BD991875C2CDE571">
          <enum/>
          <text>thence east on Constitution Avenue to Seventeenth Street Northwest;</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H035BCC491BCA45B98478641FA11EFA96">
          <enum/>
          <text>thence north on Seventeenth Street Northwest to H Street Northwest;</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2C045506667540158E2D36C90083E11D">
          <enum/>
          <text>thence east on H Street Northwest to Madison Place Northwest;</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9CD08B7C062C47F6A86A2F91C3D8A041">
          <enum/>
          <text>thence south on Madison Place Northwest to Pennsylvania Avenue Northwest;</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF50E1D416C9F43AE8A03B79578E47B31">
          <enum/>
          <text>thence east on Pennsylvania Avenue Northwest to Fifteenth Street Northwest;</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6E00484516C647FCA5AEB3ABF9BB8258">
          <enum/>
          <text>thence south on Fifteenth Street Northwest to Pennsylvania Avenue Northwest;</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFFE29914B3064621BB8AD0323622D935">
          <enum/>
          <text>thence southeast on Pennsylvania Avenue Northwest to Tenth Street Northwest;</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBB863295E7F8439C9599CB620D4A0FD9">
          <enum/>
          <text>thence north on Tenth Street Northwest to E Street Northwest;</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF922102727A845CDA231ED45F39A39D4">
          <enum/>
          <text>thence east on E Street Northwest to Ninth Street Northwest;</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA230F511450945119CEC2D4CAC1AF7B1">
          <enum/>
          <text>thence south on Ninth Street Northwest to Pennsylvania Avenue Northwest;</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6EE13E1B7D3B4B018BF68A382A09792B">
          <enum/>
          <text>thence southeast on Pennsylvania Avenue Northwest to John Marshall Place Northwest;</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCEFAF161835E4373ABFBE16076403888">
          <enum/>
          <text>thence north on John Marshall Place Northwest to C Street Northwest;</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0BA6F62AB43947378E6FE742DFD35962">
          <enum/>
          <text>thence east on C Street Northwest to Third Street Northwest;</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCC34B4D95D9D4F53920D51C379FB5228">
          <enum/>
          <text>thence north on Third Street Northwest to D Street Northwest;</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6ABA74A67BFF41ED924E921EA2397DB0">
          <enum/>
          <text>thence east on D Street Northwest to Second Street Northwest;</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC8F3B128E4B843C08BA37C09665A1D9D">
          <enum/>
          <text>thence south on Second Street Northwest to the intersection of Constitution Avenue Northwest and Louisiana Avenue Northwest;</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA6AB414D55DE4D4A99209C74B51079F4">
          <enum/>
          <text>thence northeast on Louisiana Avenue Northwest to North Capitol Street;</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF802BD5C7C9B48A89DC7EBD916926BA9">
          <enum/>
          <text>thence north on North Capitol Street to Massachusetts Avenue Northwest;</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H32EF1B7D13A54F0C851914EFFF9CC60E">
          <enum/>
          <text>thence southeast on Massachusetts Avenue Northwest so as to encompass Union Square;</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6E76FD1002404969A3543AAD5877A4E9">
          <enum/>
          <text>thence following Union Square to F Street Northeast;</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8FD82B21B07B4E21A75688BB2383A39D">
          <enum/>
          <text>thence east on F Street Northeast to Second Street Northeast;</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H998A0068CD8648E4BDDD3FA4A8CEAEAB">
          <enum/>
          <text>thence south on Second Street Northeast to D Street Northeast;</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD2E917CE18904D7DAA18B40E2C840B21">
          <enum/>
          <text>thence west on D Street Northeast to First Street Northeast;</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2B6AF485EE4A4DAB865A0BB244B4D578">
          <enum/>
          <text>thence south on First Street Northeast to C Street Northeast;</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDF28DBE70894428EB222124E13AF1B8D">
          <enum/>
          <text>thence east on C Street Northeast to Third Street Northeast;</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE09064A58E6249CB9DB954035C15EDDD">
          <enum/>
          <text>thence south on Third Street Northeast to Maryland Avenue Northeast;</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2C520179E771498F9F69663B7A7B983F">
          <enum/>
          <text>thence south and west on Maryland Avenue Northeast to Constitution Avenue Northeast;</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7C41ECDF3F23436FAD6E965BEB8DF5D9">
          <enum/>
          <text>thence west on Constitution Avenue Northeast to First Street Northeast;</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HEB3BA976B98642EBA3DDA6680C42B7E8">
          <enum/>
          <text>thence south on First Street Northeast to Maryland Avenue Northeast;</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1D6C63C1911A411182204061C67A8F11">
          <enum/>
          <text>thence generally north and east on Maryland Avenue to Second Street Northeast;</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H530F4A2EF38E481EBA21AEA0405B0A6D">
          <enum/>
          <text>thence south on Second Street Northeast to East Capitol Street;</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H16F1B0D3F32A408AA066255AEFD268BC">
          <enum/>
          <text>thence east on East Capitol Street to Third Street Northeast;</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6E72CED6220F4B51833F6702227936B5">
          <enum/>
          <text>thence south on Third Street Northeast to Independence Avenue Southeast;</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD6C899D70C3043F9941435D9D8880099">
          <enum/>
          <text>thence west on Independence Avenue Southeast to Second Street Southeast;</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD8D009C6FFFC49DAA6AA9C47722E5359">
          <enum/>
          <text>thence south on Second Street Southeast to C Street Southeast;</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HEDF4073625DC43F38015403C4722A22D">
          <enum/>
          <text>thence west on C Street Southeast to New Jersey Avenue Southeast;</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H477BB950B7724FEDB39A6FAEE1644E3E">
          <enum/>
          <text>thence south on New Jersey Avenue Southeast to D Street Southeast;</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD2A448EA6B70492387DF8434E7DA10DD">
          <enum/>
          <text>thence west on D Street Southeast to Washington Avenue Southwest;</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6DBA192330A54F39B8DA6DC5298D7B7B">
          <enum/>
          <text>thence north and west on Washington Avenue Southwest to the intersection of Independence Avenue Southwest and Second Street Southwest;</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H384C48A4FFE34F6598FE7FF210299417">
          <enum/>
          <text>thence south on Second Street Southwest to Virginia Avenue Southwest;</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD4B16C37016D471AA2F4B69C95CC40E2">
          <enum/>
          <text>thence generally west on Virginia Avenue to Third Street Southwest;</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HEF0FBFCDE68B4B1BA0404CDFBA4FE3C0">
          <enum/>
          <text>thence north on Third Street Southwest to C Street Southwest;</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H39E7305BE2F34ED1B2F85654E3D65F79">
          <enum/>
          <text>thence west on C Street Southwest to Sixth Street Southwest;</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE9A3AE0CF9B847DA9879F5EAA4C8C464">
          <enum/>
          <text>thence south on Sixth Street Southwest to E Street Southwest;</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFA552F215D0E4BECB03010F93E67637B">
          <enum/>
          <text>thence west on E Street Southwest to Seventh Street Southwest;</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBDA5ED6DF97C4EF6AF30712CCC7C5B9B">
          <enum/>
          <text>thence north on Seventh Street Southwest to Maryland Avenue Southwest;</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0340E8107B2247CDA0B86F5040C389BD">
          <enum/>
          <text>thence west on Maryland Avenue Southwest to Ninth Street Southwest;</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBE255327BCE349438EDD722BEA605253">
          <enum/>
          <text>thence north on Ninth Street Southwest to Independence Avenue Southwest;</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7EEB7CC57A03431A83F47C0C2A07ECD9">
          <enum/>
          <text>thence west on Independence Avenue Southwest to Twelfth Street Southwest;</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC45A4BBA18E344F380A23C2B31C03516">
          <enum/>
          <text>thence south on Twelfth Street Southwest to D Street Southwest;</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA00A9BBCCDFA4531BEC1620AA69DC208">
          <enum/>
          <text>thence west on D Street Southwest to Fourteenth Street Southwest;</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H34DD0226FC5848D7AEB21C47BAB39580">
          <enum/>
          <text>thence south on Fourteenth Street Southwest to the middle of the Washington Channel;</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD364E30EE78D4AE1971F99061310FA0A">
          <enum/>
          <text>thence generally south and east along the midchannel of the Washington Channel to a point due west of the northern boundary line of Fort Lesley McNair;</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H34B6E7F1B1B543DE9B67B282D4B2D85F">
          <enum/>
          <text>thence due east to the side of the Washington Channel;</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA2F03C839F0D448DB4D0E646998DA7CB">
          <enum/>
          <text>thence following generally south and east along the side of the Washington Channel at the mean high water mark, to the point of confluence with the Anacostia River, and along the northern shore at the mean high water mark to the northernmost point of the Eleventh Street Bridge;</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H710EE2FA9A8B49CDA6408CA01530910B">
          <enum/>
          <text>thence generally south and west along such shore at the mean high water mark to the point of confluence of the Anacostia and Potomac Rivers;</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HECF172FF1AF9435294B2B7172912FFB7">
          <enum/>
          <text>thence generally south and east along the northern side of the Eleventh Street Bridge to the eastern shore of the Anacostia River;</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDBCB3426A692425E8DE7C8D6E897300C">
          <enum/>
          <text>thence generally south along the eastern shore at the mean high water mark of the Potomac River to the point where it meets the present southeastern boundary line of the District of Columbia;</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE604E708F7104F19B9A94F9FAC4057AF">
          <enum/>
          <text>thence south and west along such southeastern boundary line to the point where it meets the present Virginia-District of Columbia boundary;</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H91B62478A2274524B3C096BA929C0A86">
          <enum/>
          <text>thence generally north and west up the Potomac River along the Virginia-District of Columbia boundary to the point of beginning.</text>
        </paragraph> </subsection>
<subsection id="HBFBE2D4696A845ACB1CDD9D4820C6D05">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Streets and sidewalks</header>
        <text>The National Capital Service Area shall include any street (and sidewalk thereof) that bounds such Area.</text>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="H550CCEE0DFF644AB87C542D74DA4DCDD">
        <enum>(c)</enum>
        <header>Affronting or abutting Federal real property</header> 
<paragraph id="HBC4604EEBBA64951AD6E78186D363301">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>In general</header>
          <text>The National Capital Service Area shall include any Federal real property affronting or abutting such Area as of the effective date of this Act.</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H835273D79C1B4D3FB120B03CEB232907">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Property included</header>
          <text>For purposes of <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="District of Columbia-Maryland Reunion Act/s:5/ss:c/p:1" proposed="true">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref>, Federal real property affronting or abutting the National Capital Service Area—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HEC367DA1A5A94B79A10A7881B25673C5">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>shall include the Department of Housing and Urban Development Building, the Department of Energy Building, Fort Lesley McNair, the Washington Navy Yard, the Anacostia Naval Annex, the United States Naval Station, Bolling Air Force Base, and the Naval Research Laboratory; and</text>
          </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H75F04995BAAC4183B657B544CF3A1A93">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>shall not include any portion of Rock Creek Park, any portion of Anacostia Park east of the northern side of the Eleventh Street Bridge, or any territory not located in the District of Columbia on the day before the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
    </section> 
<section id="HE5454B7341524E2BBF64C53E68AD840A">
      <enum>6.</enum>
      <header>Transition provisions relating to House of Representatives</header> 
<subsection id="HCCB98A6152724198ABB6E6791147FC57">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Temporary increase in apportionment</header> 
<paragraph id="H333D8D1C890945B7AA35A3316FADC5AB">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>In general</header>
          <text>Until the taking effect of the first reapportionment occurring after the effective date of this Act—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H4CAC48948FF94DCFA5490FC49380E40D">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>the individual serving as the Delegate to the House of Representatives from the District of Columbia shall serve as a member of the House of Representatives from the State of Maryland;</text>
          </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2B7DF4C2A24B4970BE5B94186F493661">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>the State of Maryland shall be entitled to 1 additional Representative until the taking effect of such reapportionment; and</text>
          </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H485207D17E714F34AB944931CB282D18">
            <enum>(C)</enum>
            <text>such Representative shall be in addition to the membership of the House of Representatives as now prescribed by law.</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4B34FD7221774614809C9E066079F2B8">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Increase not counted against total number of members</header>
          <text>The temporary increase in the membership of the House of Representatives provided under paragraph (1) shall not operate to either increase or decrease the permanent membership of the House of Representatives as prescribed in the <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Reapportionment Act of 1911" official-title="true">Act of August 8, 1911</cato:entity-ref> (<cato:entity-ref entity-type="statute-at-large" value="statute-at-large/37/13">37 Stat. 13</cato:entity-ref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/2">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/2/2">2 U.S.C. 2</cato:entity-ref>
              </external-xref>)</cato:entity>, nor shall such temporary increase affect the basis of reapportionment established by the <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Act of November 15, 1941" official-title="true">Act of November 15, 1941</cato:entity-ref> (<cato:entity-ref entity-type="statute-at-large" value="statute-at-large/55/761">55 Stat. 761</cato:entity-ref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/2a">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/2/2a">2 U.S.C. 2a</cato:entity-ref>
              </external-xref>)</cato:entity>, for the 82nd Congress and each Congress thereafter.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="H2514FFC96CAE4BFDBA2D5073ED1F1DC8">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Repeal of laws providing for delegate from the District of Columbia</header> 
<paragraph id="H13FBF5EC1260411995AFDEFAFBE398F7">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>In general</header>
          <text>Sections 202 and 204 of the District of Columbia Delegate
			 Act (<cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="public-law" value="public-law/91/405">Public Law 91–405</cato:entity-ref>; sections 1–401 and 1–402, D.C. Official Code) are
			 repealed, and the provisions of law amended or repealed by such sections are
			 restored or revived as if such sections had not been enacted.</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDF1957474103466C9331B352C0D638F5">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Effective date</header>
          <text>The amendments made by this subsection shall take effect on the date on which the individual serving as the Delegate to the House of Representatives from the District of Columbia first serves as a member of the House of Representatives from the State of Maryland.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
    </section> 
<section id="H3A81681769354F7793F2C3AE4A77A835">
      <enum>7.</enum>
      <header>Effect on other laws</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">No law or regulation which is in force on the effective date of this Act shall be deemed amended or repealed by this Act except to the extent specifically provided in this Act, or to the extent that such law or regulation is inconsistent with this Act.</text>
    </section> 
<section id="H432E8DEEC1CD45108DF78AD75A19460E">
      <enum>8.</enum>
      <header>Proclamation regarding acceptance of retrocession by Maryland</header> 
<subsection id="H8565BA61E5A844D6B27E38BF5431C999">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Proclamation by State of Maryland</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 30 days after the State of Maryland enacts legislation accepting the retrocession described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="District of Columbia-Maryland Reunion Act/s:3/ss:a" proposed="true">section 3(a)</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> shall issue a proclamation announcing such acceptance and declaring that the territory ceded to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> by the State of Maryland to serve as the District constituting the permanent seat of the Government of the United States has been ceded back to the State of Maryland.</text>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="H3BDC1054326D46C1890647E0F3C5B04D">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Report by Congressional Budget Office on Economic Impact</header> 
<paragraph id="H9F6E76E862314254ABCD33AFFEDDB70F">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>In general</header>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0800">Director of the Congressional Budget Office</cato:entity-ref> shall prepare a report analyzing the anticipated economic impact on the State of Maryland of the State's acceptance of the retrocession described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="District of Columbia-Maryland Reunion Act/s:3/ss:a" proposed="true">section 3(a)</cato:entity-ref>, including the anticipated effect on the budgets of the State government and local governments, and shall submit the report to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> and the governor of Maryland.</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD0A5742584D04E62A6B52366EE06A29E">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Delay in enactment of legislation</header>
          <text>The State of Maryland may not enact legislation accepting the retrocession described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="District of Columbia-Maryland Reunion Act/s:3/ss:a" proposed="true">section 3(a)</cato:entity-ref> until the expiration of the 1-year period which begins on the date the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0800">Director of the Congressional Budget Office</cato:entity-ref> submits the report prepared under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="District of Columbia-Maryland Reunion Act/s:8/ss:b/p:1" proposed="true">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref> to the governor of Maryland.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
    </section> 
<section id="H0C9F1B8C2C7043D99FBCE536BA71E373">
      <enum>9.</enum>
      <header>Effective date</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">The provisions of this Act and the amendments made by this Act shall take effect on the date the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> issues a proclamation under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="District of Columbia-Maryland Reunion Act/s:8" proposed="true">section 8</cato:entity-ref> or the date of the ratification of an amendment to the Constitution of the United States repealing the twenty-third article of amendment to the Constitution, whichever comes later.</text>
    </section> 
</legis-body> 
</bill>
</doc>