<doc>
  <docmeta id="113hres355ih">
    <bill congress="113" type="hres" number="355" version="ih"/>
    <revision size="7312" annotations="0" status="complete" id="3" commit-time="2013-10-09T20:25:42Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113hres355ih/3.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <resolution xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" dms-id="H99F2209C59344790931F5C178CF1CB14" key="H" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print">
  <metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>113 HRES 355 IH: Commemorating the 20th anniversary of the establishment of the Corporation for National and Community Service.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2013-09-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code>
    <congress display="yes">113th CONGRESS</congress>
    <session display="yes">1st Session</session>
    <legis-num>H. RES. 355</legis-num>
    <current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
    <action display="yes">
      <action-date date="20130925">September 25, 2013</action-date>
      <action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="C001090">Mr. Cartwright</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="F000030">Mr. Farr</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000216">Ms. DeLauro</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000053">Mr. Rangel</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000797">Ms. Wasserman Schultz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001097">Mr. Cárdenas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001245">Ms. Bordallo</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001034">Mr. Honda</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000551">Ms. Lee of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001143">Ms. McCollum</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000187">Ms. Waters</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000808">Ms. Wilson of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000032">Ms. Jackson Lee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000486">Ms. Roybal-Allard</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001084">Mr. Cicilline</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001091">Mr. Castro of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001068">Mr. Cohen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001067">Ms. Clarke</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000617">Ms. DelBene</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000565">Mr. Loebsack</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001168">Mr. Sarbanes</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000510">Mr. Smith of Washington</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000128">Mr. Van Hollen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000312">Mr. McGovern</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000523">Mr. Price of North Carolina</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S001187">Mr. Stivers</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and the Workforce</committee-name>
      </action-desc>
    </action>
    <legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
    <official-title display="yes">Commemorating the 20th anniversary of the establishment of the Corporation for National and Community Service.</official-title>
  </form>
  <preamble>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="9577">Corporation for National and Community Service</cato:entity-ref> (in this preamble referred to as the <quote>CNCS</quote>) was established under <cato:entity entity-type="law-citation">
          <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="National and Community Service Act of 1990/s:191">section 191 of the National and Community Service Act of 1990</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12651">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/42/12651">42 U.S.C. 12651</cato:entity-ref>
          </external-xref>)</cato:entity>, as added by <cato:entity entity-type="law-citation">
          <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="National and Community Service Trust Act of 1993/s:202">section 202 of the National and Community Service Trust Act of 1993</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/103/82">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="public-law" value="public-law/103/82">Public Law 103–82</cato:entity-ref>
          </external-xref>; <cato:entity-ref entity-type="statute-at-large" value="statute-at-large/107/873">107 Stat. 873</cato:entity-ref>)</cato:entity>;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas, since 1993, the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="9577">CNCS</cato:entity-ref> has operated as an independent Federal agency, overseeing all national and community service programs authorized by the <cato:entity entity-type="law-citation">
          <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="National and Community Service Act of 1990">National and Community Service Act of 1990</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12501">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/42/12501/etseq">42 U.S.C. 12501 et seq.</cato:entity-ref>
          </external-xref>)</cato:entity> and the <cato:entity entity-type="law-citation">
          <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Domestic Volunteer Service Act of 1973">Domestic Volunteer Service Act of 1973</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4950">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/42/4950/etseq">42 U.S.C. 4950 et seq.</cato:entity-ref>
          </external-xref>)</cato:entity>;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="9577">CNCS</cato:entity-ref> connects people of all ages and backgrounds with opportunities to give back to their communities and the United States;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas programs conducted by the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="9577">CNCS</cato:entity-ref> address unmet national and local needs, and renew an ethic of civic responsibility and community spirit in the United States by encouraging citizens to participate in service;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas, since 1993, millions of people in the United States have served in AmeriCorps, Senior Corps, Learn and Serve America, and other <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="9577">CNCS</cato:entity-ref> programs, addressing the most pressing challenges facing the United States, from helping students graduate and supporting veterans and military families to preserving the environment and helping communities recover from natural disasters;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas participants serve in tens of thousands of locations across the country, bolstering the civic, neighborhood, and faith-based organizations that are so vital to the economic and social well-being of the people of the United States;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas national service expands economic opportunity by creating more sustainable, resilient communities and providing education, career skills, and leadership abilities for those who serve;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas national service represents a unique and cost-effective partnership between public and private organizations, invests in community solutions, and leverages State and local resources to strengthen community impact and increase the return on taxpayer dollars;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas, in 2009, <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> passed the <cato:entity entity-type="law-citation">
          <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Serve America Act">Serve America Act</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/13">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="public-law" value="public-law/111/13">Public Law 111–13</cato:entity-ref>
          </external-xref>; <cato:entity-ref entity-type="statute-at-large" value="statute-at-large/123/1460">123 Stat. 1460</cato:entity-ref>)</cato:entity> with strong bipartisan support, authorizing the most sweeping expansion of national service in a generation, expanding opportunities to serve, focusing service on key national priorities, increasing efficiency and accountability, and strengthening the capacity of organizations and communities to solve problems through the Social Innovation Fund, the Volunteer Generation Fund, and other initiatives;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas AmeriCorps and Senior Corps support the military community by engaging veterans in service, helping veterans readjust to civilian life, and providing support to military families;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas more than 17,000 veterans have served as AmeriCorps members and have helped veterans and military families access benefits and services, conduct job searches, and provide safe and affordable housing;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="9577">CNCS</cato:entity-ref> is working to increase the number of veterans and military families served by and engaged in programs supported by the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="9577">CNCS</cato:entity-ref>;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas, since 1994, <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="9577">CNCS</cato:entity-ref> programs and members have provided critical services to millions of people in the United States who have been affected by floods, fires, hurricanes, tornadoes, and other disasters and emergencies, helping families and communities rebuild their lives;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="9577">CNCS</cato:entity-ref> has partnered with the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7022">Federal Emergency Management Agency</cato:entity-ref> to launch FEMA Corps, an innovative partnership that strengthens the disaster response capacity of the United States, increases the reliability and diversity of the disaster response workforce, promotes an ethic of service, prepares young people for careers in emergency management, and saves a significant amount of taxpayer dollars; and</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the Task Force on Expanding National Service established by <cato:entity-ref entity-type="person" entity-id="O000167">President Barack Obama</cato:entity-ref> is working to expand the ability of people in the United States to serve their communities by developing strategies to meet national priorities through partnerships between Federal agencies and the private sector: Now, therefore, be it</text>
    </whereas>
  </preamble>
  <resolution-body id="H45C34E5631984C0A9DF75F07C8BF05FB" style="traditional">
    <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H920C3E416CFA4D01851952568F7FB0B8" section-type="undesignated-section">
      <enum/>
      <text>That the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0050">House of Representatives</cato:entity-ref>—</text>
      <paragraph id="HD43553085D7A4A37BF17487EDA8566DD">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text>commemorates the 20th anniversary of the establishment of the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="9577">Corporation for National and Community Service</cato:entity-ref>;</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HEBF870045E4C4C51806EA1717225BCD1">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text>recognizes that, for 20 years, the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="9577">Corporation for National and Community Service</cato:entity-ref> has worked to improve lives, strengthen communities, expand economic opportunity, foster innovation and civic engagement, and engage millions of people in the United States in solving critical problems through national service;</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HC1DF4DCF9A3243DDA45C755351CA9573">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <text>recognizes that, since the inception of AmeriCorps in 1994, more than 820,000 people have served as AmeriCorps members, serving approximately 1,000,000,000 hours, mobilizing millions of volunteers, and improving the lives of countless people in the United States;</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H94D92EAFAEB34E33B09A5DDB640FA00D">
        <enum>(4)</enum>
        <text>welcomes the efforts of the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="9577">Corporation for National and Community Service</cato:entity-ref> to increase the involvement of veterans and military families in national service and to expand services to the military community;</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H996E558C22624B3BA68DDDB351CB696B">
        <enum>(5)</enum>
        <text>supports the goal of the <cato:entity entity-type="law-citation">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Serve America Act">Serve America Act</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/13">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="public-law" value="public-law/111/13">Public Law 111–13</cato:entity-ref>
            </external-xref>; <cato:entity-ref entity-type="statute-at-large" value="statute-at-large/123/1460">123 Stat. 1460</cato:entity-ref>)</cato:entity> to increase the number of approved national service positions to 250,000 by 2017; and</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H043EDD03172E4C99B29745FDCFFF3871">
        <enum>(6)</enum>
        <text>recognizes and thanks all those who have served in AmeriCorps, Senior Corps, and other programs conducted by the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="9577">Corporation for National and Community Service</cato:entity-ref> for demonstrating commitment, dedication, and patriotism through their service to the people of the United States.</text>
      </paragraph>
    </section>
  </resolution-body>
</resolution>
</doc>