<doc>
  <docmeta id="113hr5623ih">
    <bill congress="113" type="hr" number="5623" version="ih"/>
    <revision size="15176" annotations="0" status="complete" id="4" commit-time="2014-10-20T21:47:13Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113hr5623ih/4.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H6E8E025686924ED890A8BBDFD59FD3DA" public-private="public">
	<metadata>
<dublinCore>
<dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">113 HR 5623 IH: National Parents Corps Act of 2014</dc:title>
<dc:publisher xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">2014-09-18</dc:date>
<dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>113th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>2d Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 5623</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20140918">September 18, 2014</action-date>
			<action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="L000287">Mr. Lewis</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and the Workforce</committee-name>
      </action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To establish a National Parents Corps Program, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H2DDC221EE6AF4ED28C70ED5C51B55BE2" style="OLC">
		<section id="HB250DB919B564EEDBEE4205881DF2C96" section-type="section-one">
      <enum>1.</enum>
      <header>Short title</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote>
          <short-title>
            <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="National Parents Corps Act of 2014" proposed="true">National Parents Corps Act of 2014</cato:entity-ref>
          </short-title>
        </quote>.</text>
		</section>
    <section id="H7992C2DEDA764FE18590EAFE0CCA366E">
      <enum>2.</enum>
      <header>Findings</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Congress finds as follows:</text>
			<paragraph id="H7E69D6E3E0E04617AE9DE3A5125A8875">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nearly 25 percent of children in the United States ages 12 to 17 have used an illicit drug in their
			 lifetime, according to the Substance Abuse and Mental Health
			 Administration's 2012 National Survey on Drug Use and Health (NSDUH).</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H79852F65B554494D9F5B3AEB387D83E9">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The American Lung Association states, approximately 4,000 children under age 18 try their first
			 cigarette and more than 950 of them will become new, regular daily
			 smokers. Moreover, according to NSDUH, among children ages 12 to 17 who
			 smoked cigarettes in the last month, 54.6 percent also used an illicit
			 drug.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H73C50A28D9484190BF7874A75F5838CA">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Partnership for Drug-Free Kids says parents have more influence over their children than
			 friends, music, TV, the Internet, and celebrities. It adds, children whose
			 parents teach them about drug risks are significantly less likely to use
			 drugs.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H9589BB75CC874872B6A12ADFABFED873">
        <enum>(4)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In response to concerns about youth violence and drug, tobacco, and alcohol use by youth, the White
			 House unveiled the Parents Corps in 2003. It was initially a 3-year
			 initiative operating in 9 States to bring together citizenship, service,
			 and responsibility to empower parents to keep their children, schools, and
			 communities drug-free.</text>
			</paragraph>
    </section>
    <section commented="no" id="HDF0E69F4CF2349609C5C9CDF3509433F">
      <enum>3.</enum>
      <header>National Parents Corps Program</header>
			<subsection id="H20AE0EEE121C44F28790C6C8BDACCF61">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Grant To establish the Program</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to the availability of appropriations to carry out this Act, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Office of Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Prevention" entity-parent-id="1550">Administrator</cato:entity-ref> shall, not
			 later than 3 months after the date of the enactment of this Act, award a
			 grant to an eligible nonprofit entity to establish a National Parents
			 Corps Program (referred to in this Act as the <quote>Program</quote>) to promote safety, combat youth violence, and combat drug and alcohol abuse in schools in the
			 United States. The eligible nonprofit entity awarded such grant shall be
			 known as the <quote>NPCP Nonprofit Partner</quote>.</text>
			</subsection>
      <subsection id="H492A417D608B41EDA1F886B10DA6E4C1">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Program activities</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The NPCP Nonprofit Partner shall use the grant awarded under this section to establish and
			 administer the Program, which shall include—</text>
				<paragraph id="H18E8AD2469FD4506ADB46BE087E6C724">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>employing Parent Leaders to carry out the Program at eligible schools that are selected to host
			 Parent Leaders, in accordance with <internal-xref idref="H49DBF9F03B4242329B11E7BCFA34257C" legis-path="5.">
              <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="National Parents Corps Act of 2014/s:4" proposed="true">sections 4</cato:entity-ref> and <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="National Parents Corps Act of 2014/s:5" proposed="true">5</cato:entity-ref>
            </internal-xref>; and</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H6AA7148A502B470997756177E3121A1B">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">working with schools, parents of children enrolled in schools, local nonprofit organizations, and
			 law enforcement agencies and officers to promote safety, combat youth
			 violence, and combat drug, alcohol, and tobacco abuse in schools.</text>
				</paragraph>
      </subsection>
    </section>
    <section commented="no" id="H0E4CF6F380B747B9B05F58192BAF0FF6">
      <enum>4.</enum>
      <header>Participation of schools</header>
			<subsection commented="no" id="H6B8F3063F03146D8800541F94DD046F3">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>In general</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of enactment of this Act and annually thereafter, the NPCP
			 Nonprofit Partner shall solicit applications from eligible schools
			 desiring to participate in the Program by hosting a Parent Leader. Each
			 eligible school selected to host a Parent Leader shall enter into a
			 memorandum of understanding with the NPCP Nonprofit Partner—</text>
				<paragraph commented="no" id="HDEB11C68A6E94E218CEF62DE9F76B183">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>in which the eligible school agrees to participate in the Program and host a Parent Leader for the
			 number of years that is equal to the number of grade levels taught at the
			 school; and</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph commented="no" id="H0E35174CD0AE49FDBA088D6501C4101A">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>that outlines the parameters and goals of hosting a Parent Leader and carrying out the Program at
			 the eligible school, including how the Parent Leader and the operation of
			 the Program will address the cultural, social, and crime prevention needs
			 and goals of the students at such school.</text>
				</paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection commented="no" id="H51CC2A9EAB6C4E71A8C3E17BBBA5341D">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Selection considerations</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In selecting eligible schools to host Parent Leaders under this Act, the NPCP Nonprofit Partner
			 shall ensure that, to the extent practicable, the eligible schools
			 selected represent schools—</text>
				<paragraph commented="no" id="HEEFA6B5B00734F44BD1BAC8A531FB115">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>that are located in a variety of geographical regions in the United States;</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph commented="no" id="H23F8A3A9EA6B4DEB93DF495ED6C28432">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>in urban, rural, and suburban areas; and</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph commented="no" id="HF819472C02894BB4B8481BBE59F08E5F">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <text>in ethnically and economically diverse communities.</text>
				</paragraph>
      </subsection>
    </section>
    <section commented="no" id="H49DBF9F03B4242329B11E7BCFA34257C">
      <enum>5.</enum>
      <header>Parent Leaders</header>
			<subsection commented="no" id="H4D7E4484876E432CBBD4387151326C80">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Parent Leader for each school</header>
        <text>For each eligible school selected to participate in the Program as a host school under <internal-xref idref="H0E4CF6F380B747B9B05F58192BAF0FF6" legis-path="4.">
            <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="National Parents Corps Act of 2014/s:4" proposed="true">section 4</cato:entity-ref>
          </internal-xref>, the NPCP Nonprofit Partner shall, after consultation with the principal of the selected school,
			 solicit applications for, hire, and employ one Parent Leader. The
			 Nonprofit Partner shall use the grant funds provided under this Act to
			 train, supervise, support, and provide a salary and benefits to each
			 Parent Leader.</text>
			</subsection>
      <subsection commented="no" id="HCE9EA2659CF344FCBAAE1EB2398B90BF">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Duties of Parent Leaders</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each Parent Leader employed by the Nonprofit Partner shall, with respect to the eligible school
			 hosting the Parent Leader—</text>
				<paragraph commented="no" id="H76F6EEE884D54CB0A1FFBB1EA00E0B0B">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>educate and mobilize parents of students at the school to combat criminal and gang activity and
			 prevent students from social, cultural, and commercial forces that
			 encourage children and adolescents to initiate the use of drugs, alcohol,
			 and tobacco;</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph commented="no" id="HA8C52957D0F440DE9F8C43D0BF725566">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">create a delivery system to provide parents of students at the school with information regarding
			 science-based prevention and analysis related to early recognition of
			 behaviors and traits that may lead to or indicate drug, alcohol, and
			 tobacco use and abuse, gang activity, and violence;</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph commented="no" id="H8B1DAA81E060431A8C6FEDF0FDFB536D">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <text>work with school officials, other parents of students at the school, and students at the school to
			 develop programs and practices to treat, prevent, and reduce violence and
			 drug, alcohol, and tobacco addiction for students at the school;</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph commented="no" id="H606420A59E4649278E3CAA8EF0F72147">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
          <text>assist parents of students at the school and school administrators with finding professional
			 assistance for any child who—</text>
					<subparagraph commented="no" id="HFD0E746107794D7984BF66597232698D">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>is using drugs, including referrals to professionals who can assess the needs of the child for
			 counseling, treatment, and other appropriate assistance; or</text>
					</subparagraph>
          <subparagraph commented="no" id="H63778A68CCB34C59AFB6F050F3F4CEF2">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>is engaged in violent activities or gang activities;</text>
					</subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph commented="no" id="H4751D64CD01E4F589E2AC684213F432A">
          <enum>(5)</enum>
          <text>recruit and train parent and student volunteers from the school to participate in drug and violence
			 prevention and education outreach and programming; and</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H5ACAB6B1C05B417F8AEF6CB6D4C6C772">
          <enum>(6)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">consult with the NPCP Nonprofit Partner, school administrators, local government authorities, local
			 nonprofit organizations, and other parents to develop best practices and
			 training models related to the prevention of school violence and drug,
			 alcohol, and tobacco use and abuse by students.</text>
				</paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection commented="no" id="H837835EE91DE41A0ABE65A5E936A7CDB">
        <enum>(c)</enum>
        <header>Parent Leader eligibility</header>
        <text>To be eligible to be employed as a Parent Leader under this Act, an individual shall—</text>
				<paragraph commented="no" id="H7B2090BA44094B448F272CA032007C3E">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">be the parent (as such term is defined in <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965/s:9101">section 9101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education
			 Act of 1965</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7801">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/20/7801">20 U.S.C. 7801</cato:entity-ref>
            </external-xref>)</cato:entity>) of at least one student who will be
			 enrolled, during the first year the individual will be employed as a
			 Parent Leader, in the lowest grade level offered at the school that will
			 host the Parent Leader;</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph commented="no" id="H8113361EAAC54F2A8E51F2780E9468BD">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>not be employed full-time at any position other than as a Parent Leader;</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph commented="no" id="H35DBB7396F264C27A2E9AD9882F5D338">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">complete a background check, including criminal records checks, fingerprint-based checks of State
			 and national crime information databases (as defined in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc/28/534/f/3/A">section
			 534(f)(3)(A) of title 28, United States Code</cato:entity-ref>), checks in any available
			 child abuse and neglect registries, and checks in any available sex
			 offender registries; and</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph commented="no" id="HDF0F2BB92D13490B9F160102623ECAB8">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
          <text>enter into an agreement with the NPCP Nonprofit Partner to serve as a Parent Leader for a number of
			 years that is equal to the number of years normally required for a student
			 to complete all of the grade levels offered at the school that will host
			 the Parent Leader (as determined by the school), except that the
			 individual shall not be required to continue to serve as Parent Leader in
			 the case of an extreme, unforeseen circumstance (such as death,
			 disability, relocation, or criminal activity) that prevents the individual
			 from completing the term of service required under this paragraph.</text>
				</paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="H200E7C7CCD1547FB8BD10526796DEAFE">
        <enum>(d)</enum>
        <header>Vacancies</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If an individual who is employed as a Parent Leader is unable to complete the term of service
			 required under <internal-xref idref="HDF0F2BB92D13490B9F160102623ECAB8" legis-path="5.(c)(4)">subsection (c)(4)</internal-xref>, the NPCP Nonprofit Partner shall, after consultation with the host school at which the Parent
			 Leader was serving, promptly solicit applications for, hire, and employ
			 another individual to serve as Parent Leader at such school, in accordance
			 with the requirements of this section.</text>
			</subsection>
    </section>
    <section commented="no" id="HE6611F76E78441A6893379D1255288EF">
      <enum>6.</enum>
      <header>Reporting requirements</header>
			<subsection commented="no" id="HA7A3FE00A591474D9B2834F868D9AAFA">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Reports by Parent Leaders</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not less than once each calendar quarter during each year a Parent Leader is employed by the NPCP
			 Nonprofit Partner, the Parent Leader shall submit to the NPCP Nonprofit
			 Partner and the school hosting the Parent Leader a report including
			 activities carried out by the Parent Leader to carry out the Program, the
			 results of such activities, best practices observed and used by the Parent
			 Leader to carry out the Program, and any other information the Parent
			 Leader, the NPCP Nonprofit Partner, or the school hosting the Parent
			 Leader determine to be appropriate.</text>
			</subsection>
      <subsection commented="no" id="H031FF529E2B648AD8158B201BCF6E3CB">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Reports by NPCP Nonprofit Partner</header>
        <text>Not later than 6 months after the date of the enactment of this Act, and every 6 months thereafter,
			 the NPCP Nonprofit Partner shall prepare and submit to the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Office of Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Prevention" entity-parent-id="1550">Administrator</cato:entity-ref> a
			 report on the progress and effectiveness of the Program, including—</text>
				<paragraph id="H6AC054D90F2143BF87ED5C1F3CFFF6AF">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>statistics, trends, and other data analyzing whether the Program is effective at preventing school
			 violence and drug, alcohol, and tobacco use and abuse by students;</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HA8B3C10FA58F4D8BB27192FB00B59DC0">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>a summary of the reports submitted by Parent Leaders; and</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H65ABBEB19525475DAD8FE557C3315E5B">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <text>the results and best practices reported by the Parent Leader at each school hosting a Parent
			 Leader.</text>
				</paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection commented="no" id="H8CB6D13BBDC34DA389DA33CEF04A9F3D">
        <enum>(c)</enum>
        <header>Reports by Administrator</header>
        <text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this section, and annually thereafter,
			 the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Office of Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Prevention" entity-parent-id="1550">Administrator</cato:entity-ref> shall prepare and submit to the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1500" entity-type="federal-body">Attorney General</cato:entity-ref> and the
			 appropriate Congressional committees a report relating to the progress and
			 effectiveness of the Program.</text>
			</subsection>
    </section>
    <section id="HBDCDA44091E146D784256CDE2BCCCCF1">
      <enum>7.</enum>
      <header>Sense of the Congress</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> that eligible schools selected to host a Parent Leader in
			 accordance with <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="National Parents Corps Act of 2014/s:4" proposed="true">section 4</cato:entity-ref> should take such actions as may be necessary to
			 secure funding to employ a Parent Leader to carry out the Program after
			 Federal funding is no longer available to carry out this Act.</text>
		</section>
    <section id="H8D48040488524474B3575E6DA50D9235">
      <enum>8.</enum>
      <header>Definitions</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text>
			<paragraph id="HBB471D74A3834E6F8EC5734D5A6FB5F2">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <header>Administrator</header>
        <text>The term <term>Administrator</term> means the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-parent-id="1550" entity-type="federal-body" value="Office of Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Prevention">Administrator of the Office of Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Prevention</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph commented="no" id="H399E8E64CDA44E55B5F0AF0A80792817">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <header>Eligible nonprofit entity</header>
        <text>The term <term>eligible nonprofit entity</term> means an organization described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:501/ss:c/p:3">
            <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/501">section 501(c)(3)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986</cato:entity-ref> that—</text>
				<subparagraph commented="no" id="H5F594D7C127544E7A54D4CFEA204B8D1">
          <enum>(A)</enum>
          <text>was operating on the day before the date of the enactment of this Act;</text>
				</subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="HFDFEE50E39484E028A248B33DE77C22C">
          <enum>(B)</enum>
          <text>has demonstrated experience administering Federal grants in a fiscally responsible manner, as
			 determined by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Office of Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Prevention" entity-parent-id="1550">Administrator</cato:entity-ref>;</text>
				</subparagraph>
        <subparagraph commented="no" id="H429568B5A29B4EFDB737D725565FEDA7">
          <enum>(C)</enum>
          <text>has administered national programs relating to addiction and parenting;</text>
				</subparagraph>
        <subparagraph commented="no" id="HA96968B56D8C4F61B5B6825831D8A458">
          <enum>(D)</enum>
          <text>has developed and administered programs similar to the Program authorized under this Act;</text>
				</subparagraph>
        <subparagraph commented="no" id="H826A71968B3B4E2DB9B5B6A567EEA394">
          <enum>(E)</enum>
          <text>has worked with the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="9577" entity-type="federal-body">Corporation for National and Community Service</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="7500" entity-type="federal-body">Department of Health and
			 Human Services</cato:entity-ref>, and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1500" entity-type="federal-body">Department of Justice</cato:entity-ref> in assessing and developing
			 initiatives relating to youth drug prevention and parental involvement;
			 and</text>
				</subparagraph>
        <subparagraph commented="no" id="HFE246BA0BF17480E827576DA073FE52B">
          <enum>(F)</enum>
          <text>has as its mission to focus on child and youth drug prevention.</text>
				</subparagraph>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph commented="no" id="H13C5AC1363504E25BD121B4CF049870D">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <header>Eligible school</header>
        <text>The term <term>eligible school</term> means a public middle school or secondary school (as such term is defined in <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965/s:9101">section 9101 of the
			 Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7801">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/20/7801">20 U.S.C. 7801</cato:entity-ref>
          </external-xref>)</cato:entity>) that has
			 demonstrated a commitment, as determined by the Secretary, to—</text>
				<subparagraph id="H060266B5E8FC4F6DAEAAF8BC9CD639DD">
          <enum>(A)</enum>
          <text>increasing parental involvement in the school; and</text>
				</subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="HA01BC0B54ADB438FA727B61E8D4277CF">
          <enum>(B)</enum>
          <text>reducing drug, alcohol, and tobacco abuse by students enrolled in the school.</text>
				</subparagraph>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H288F4BF1612F4B409E52298709A28CC5">
        <enum>(4)</enum>
        <header>Appropriate Congressional committees</header>
        <text>The term <term>appropriate Congressional committees</term> means the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="committee" entity-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="committee" entity-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Labor</cato:entity-ref>, and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="committee" entity-id="HAP00">Appropriations
			 Committee in the House of Representatives</cato:entity-ref>, and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="committee" entity-id="SSJU00">Committee on the
			 Judiciary</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="committee" entity-id="SSHR00">Committee on Health, Education, Labor and Pensions</cato:entity-ref>, and the
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="committee" entity-id="SSAP00">Appropriations Committee in the Senate</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
			</paragraph>
    </section>
    <section id="HA6CE8A8779A2455F9FD042D742F83301">
      <enum>9.</enum>
      <header>Authorization of appropriations</header>
			<subsection id="HADB9D095D4A34F388A9CA25831384A46">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>In general</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">
          <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="auth-auth-approp">In addition to other amounts otherwise appropriated to carry out the purposes of this Act, there
			 are authorized to be appropriated <cato:property name="purpose">to carry out <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="National Parents Corps Act of 2014" proposed="true">this Act</cato:entity-ref>
            </cato:property> <cato:funds-and-year amount="5500000" year="2015, 2016, 2017, 2018, 2019, 2020, 2021, 2022, 2023, 2024, 2025">$5,500,000 for
			 each of the fiscal years 2015 through 2025</cato:funds-and-year>.</cato:entity>
        </text>
			</subsection>
      <subsection id="HE25BBF3516F347848094278FFC7E7E6C">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Funding from other sources</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Office of Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Prevention" entity-parent-id="1550">Administrator</cato:entity-ref>, the NPCP Nonprofit Partner, and eligible schools selected to host a Parent
			 Leader in accordance with <internal-xref idref="H0E4CF6F380B747B9B05F58192BAF0FF6" legis-path="4.">
            <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="National Parents Corps Act of 2014/s:4" proposed="true">section 4</cato:entity-ref>
          </internal-xref> are authorized to solicit, receive, and use funding from State, local, and private sources to
			 carry out the Program, including for expenses related to employing Parent
			 Leaders.</text>
			</subsection>
    </section>
  </legis-body>
</bill>
</doc>