<doc>
  <docmeta id="113hres315eh">
    <bill congress="113" type="hres" number="315" version="eh"/>
    <revision size="6854" annotations="0" status="complete" id="3" commit-time="2013-08-29T15:11:10Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113hres315eh/3.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <resolution xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" dms-id="Hda96fd9b-2c0a-459a-a11d-b62455e63efc" key="H" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Engrossed-in-House" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" stage-count="1"> 
<metadata>
<dublinCore>
<title>113 HRES 315 EH: Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 2218) to amend subtitle D of the Solid Waste Disposal Act to encourage recovery and beneficial use of coal combustion residuals and establish requirements for the proper management and disposal of coal combustion residuals that are protective of human health and the environment, and providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 1582) to protect consumers by prohibiting the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency from promulgating as final certain energy-related rules that are estimated to cost more than $1 billion and will cause significant adverse effects to the economy.</title>
<publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</publisher>
<date>2013-07-24</date>
<format>text/xml</format>
<language>EN</language>
<rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="no">IV</distribution-code> 
<congress display="no">113th CONGRESS</congress> 
<session display="no">1st Session</session> 
<legis-num>H. RES. 315</legis-num> 
<current-chamber display="yes">In the House of Representatives, U. S.,</current-chamber>
<action>
<action-date date="20130724">July 24, 2013</action-date>
</action> 
<legis-type display="yes">RESOLUTION</legis-type> 
<official-title display="no">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 2218) to amend subtitle D of the Solid Waste Disposal Act to encourage recovery and beneficial use of coal combustion residuals and establish requirements for the proper management and disposal of coal combustion residuals that are protective of human health and the environment, and providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 1582) to protect consumers by prohibiting the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency from promulgating as final certain energy-related rules that are estimated to cost more than $1 billion and will cause significant adverse effects to the economy.</official-title> 
</form> 
<resolution-body id="Hc187c432-0985-4dc8-944e-958791c26382" style="traditional"> 
<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H186e3256-36c0-4f6d-a603-ba151658c583" section-type="undesignated-section">
      <enum/>
      <text>That at any time after the adoption of this resolution the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" value="Speaker of the House of Representatives" entity-parent-id="0050">Speaker</cato:entity-ref> may, pursuant to clause 2(b) of rule XVIII, declare the House resolved into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for consideration of the bill (<cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="113 HR 2218" proposed="true">H.R. 2218</cato:entity-ref>) to amend <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Solid Waste Disposal Act/st:D">subtitle D of the Solid Waste Disposal Act</cato:entity-ref> to encourage recovery and beneficial use of coal combustion residuals and establish requirements for the proper management and disposal of coal combustion residuals that are protective of human health and the environment. The first reading of the bill shall be dispensed with. All points of order against consideration of the bill are waived. General debate shall be confined to the bill and shall not exceed one hour equally divided and controlled by the chair and ranking minority member of the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="committee" entity-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</cato:entity-ref>. After general debate the bill shall be considered for amendment under the five-minute rule. It shall be in order to consider as an original bill for the purpose of amendment under the five-minute rule the amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="committee" entity-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</cato:entity-ref> now printed in the bill. The committee amendment in the nature of a substitute shall be considered as read. All points of order against the committee amendment in the nature of a substitute are waived. No amendment to the committee amendment in the nature of a substitute shall be in order except those printed in part A of the report of the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="committee" entity-id="SSRA00">Committee on Rules</cato:entity-ref> accompanying this resolution. Each such amendment may be offered only in the order printed in the report, may be offered only by a Member designated in the report, shall be considered as read, shall be debatable for the time specified in the report equally divided and controlled by the proponent and an opponent, shall not be subject to amendment, and shall not be subject to a demand for division of the question in the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0050">House</cato:entity-ref> or in the Committee of the Whole. All points of order against such amendments are waived. At the conclusion of consideration of the bill for amendment the Committee shall rise and report the bill to the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0050">House</cato:entity-ref> with such amendments as may have been adopted. Any Member may demand a separate vote in the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0050">House</cato:entity-ref> on any amendment adopted in the Committee of the Whole to the bill or to the committee amendment in the nature of a substitute. The previous question shall be considered as ordered on the bill and amendments thereto to final passage without intervening motion except one motion to recommit with or without instructions.</text> </section>
<section id="H5CBF446D0F3841C5BB9810871B0CD714">
      <enum>2.</enum>
      <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">At any time after the adoption of this resolution the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" value="Speaker of the House of Representatives" entity-parent-id="0050">Speaker</cato:entity-ref> may, pursuant to clause 2(b) of rule XVIII, declare the House resolved into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for consideration of the bill (<cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="113 HR 1582" proposed="true">H.R. 1582</cato:entity-ref>) to protect consumers by prohibiting the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="6800">Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency</cato:entity-ref> from promulgating as final certain energy-related rules that are estimated to cost more than $1 billion and will cause significant adverse effects to the economy. The first reading of the bill shall be dispensed with. All points of order against consideration of the bill are waived. General debate shall be confined to the bill and shall not exceed one hour equally divided and controlled by the chair and ranking minority member of the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="committee" entity-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</cato:entity-ref>. After general debate the bill shall be considered for amendment under the five-minute rule. In lieu of the amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="committee" entity-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</cato:entity-ref> now printed in the bill, it shall be in order to consider as an original bill for the purpose of amendment under the five-minute rule an amendment in the nature of a substitute consisting of the text of Rules Committee Print 113–19. That amendment in the nature of a substitute shall be considered as read. All points of order against that amendment in the nature of a substitute are waived. No amendment to that amendment in the nature of a substitute shall be in order except those printed in part B of the report of the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="committee" entity-id="HRU00">Committee on Rules</cato:entity-ref> accompanying this resolution. Each such amendment may be offered only in the order printed in the report, may be offered only by a Member designated in the report, shall be considered as read, shall be debatable for the time specified in the report equally divided and controlled by the proponent and an opponent, shall not be subject to amendment, and shall not be subject to a demand for division of the question in the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0050">House</cato:entity-ref> or in the Committee of the Whole. All points of order against such amendments are waived. At the conclusion of consideration of the bill for amendment the Committee shall rise and report the bill to the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0050">House</cato:entity-ref> with such amendments as may have been adopted. Any Member may demand a separate vote in the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0050">House</cato:entity-ref> on any amendment adopted in the Committee of the Whole to the bill or to the amendment in the nature of a substitute made in order as original text. The previous question shall be considered as ordered on the bill and amendments thereto to final passage without intervening motion except one motion to recommit with or without instructions.</text> </section>
</resolution-body> 
<attestation>
    <attestation-group>
      <attestor display="no">Karen L. Haas,</attestor>
      <role>Clerk.</role>
    </attestation-group>
  </attestation>
</resolution>
</doc>