<doc>
  <docmeta id="113hr4185rh">
    <bill congress="113" type="hr" number="4185" version="rh"/>
    <revision size="15448" annotations="0" status="complete" id="7" commit-time="2014-07-11T21:19:09Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113hr4185rh/7.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <bill bill-stage="Reported-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HA5F4E4E8EA30467E92A20999E9487812" public-private="public"> 
<metadata>
<dublinCore>
<dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">113 HR 4185 RH: District of Columbia Courts, Public Defender Service, and Court Services and Offender Supervision Agency Act of 2014</dc:title>
<dc:publisher xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">2014-07-03</dc:date>
<dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IB</distribution-code> 
<calendar display="yes">Union Calendar No. 386</calendar> 
<congress display="yes">113th CONGRESS</congress> <session display="yes">2d Session</session> 
<legis-num>H. R. 4185</legis-num> 
<associated-doc role="report" display="yes">[Report No. 113–514]</associated-doc> 
<current-chamber display="yes">IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20140310">March 10, 2014</action-date> 
<action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>
      </action-desc> 
</action> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20140703">July 3, 2014</action-date> 
<action-desc>Committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union and ordered to be printed<pagebreak/>
      </action-desc> 
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title display="yes">To revise certain authorities of the District of Columbia courts, the Court Services and Offender Supervision Agency for the District of Columbia, and the Public Defender Service for the District of Columbia, and for other purposes.<pagebreak/>
    </official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="HCCB068CC6BBF42EA91B1FED8E15AA351" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HE3087534DB554FC2A630877CF7867694" section-type="section-one">
      <enum>1.</enum>
      <header>Short title</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote>
          <short-title>
            <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="District of Columbia Courts, Public Defender Service, and Court Services and Offender Supervision Agency Act of 2014" proposed="true">District of Columbia Courts, Public Defender Service, and Court Services and Offender Supervision Agency Act of 2014</cato:entity-ref>
          </short-title>
        </quote>.</text> </section> 
<section id="H685969D7F4D04328A8D19A36E96359C5">
      <enum>2.</enum>
      <header>Authorities of District of Columbia Courts</header> 
<subsection id="H962B2190BDCB4ECC8BB2711E9165B38A">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Authorization To Collect Debts and Erroneous Payments From Employees</header> 
<paragraph id="H6E20682545394A2C80C1AA2F31499784">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>In general</header>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">
            <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/11/17">Chapter 17</external-xref> of title 11, District of Columbia Official Code, is amended by adding at the end of subchapter II the following new section:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5474244250BF46029883B3EA68874DAD" style="USC"> 
<section id="H8BD4C5BB04F34FDABDBF19232F1AD08C">
              <enum>11–1733.</enum>
              <header>Collection, compromise, and waiver of employee debts and erroneous payments</header> 
<subsection id="HBB03292C7AC64CF4954CF1A5BCFD3135">
                <enum>(a)</enum>
                <header>Collection of Debts and Erroneous Payments Made to Employees</header> 
<paragraph id="HBC17E3E0ADFB4B299F8C28164CC108E3">
                  <enum>(1)</enum>
                  <header>Authority to collect</header>
                  <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Executive Officer determines that an employee or former employee of the District of Columbia Courts is indebted to the District of Columbia Courts because of an erroneous payment made to or on behalf of the employee, or any other debt, the Executive Officer may collect the amount of the indebtedness in accordance with this subsection.</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFFB56923F053488AB5D7B7513B62FD9C">
                  <enum>(2)</enum>
                  <header>Timing of collection</header>
                  <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any debt authorized to be collected under this subsection may be collected in monthly installments or at officially established regular pay period intervals, by deduction in reasonable amounts from the current pay of the employee.</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF18323D80F3C4D3A8E3AAF0B33E692AE">
                  <enum>(3)</enum>
                  <header>Source of deductions</header>
                  <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Deductions described in paragraph (2) may be made from any wages, salary, compensation, remuneration for services, or other authorized pay, including but not limited to incentive pay, back pay, and lump sum leave payments, but not including retirement pay.</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H21103F7DFAB44C39A427619729626065">
                  <enum>(4)</enum>
                  <header>Limit on amount</header>
                  <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amount deducted with respect to an employee for any period may not exceed 20 percent of the employee’s disposable pay, except that a greater percentage may be deducted upon consent of the employee involved.</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA83CDD3016DB45918ABB81650EBE4607">
                  <enum>(5)</enum>
                  <header>Collections after employment</header>
                  <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If an employee's employment ends before collection of the amount of the employee’s indebtedness is completed, deductions may be made from later non-periodic government payments of any nature due the former employee, except retirement pay, and such deductions may be made without regard to the limit under paragraph (4).</text> </paragraph>
              </subsection> 
<subsection id="H430CA17E379144EF9D87D66AA7648A27">
                <enum>(b)</enum>
                <header>Notice and Hearing Required</header> 
<paragraph id="H45B319171E194D118595597FA04B5CEB">
                  <enum>(1)</enum>
                  <header>In general</header>
                  <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in paragraph (3), prior to initiating any proceedings under subsection (a) to collect any indebtedness of an individual, the Executive Officer shall provide the individual with—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HAF42109EE429488A8D8DDE616AA601F2">
                    <enum>(A)</enum>
                    <text>a minimum of 30 days written notice, informing such individual of the nature and amount of the indebtedness determined by the District of Columbia Courts to be due, the intention of the Courts to initiate proceedings to collect the debt through deductions from pay, and an explanation of the rights of the individual under this section;</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H8B41237AA68B4032A485CBF693CEAB6D">
                    <enum>(B)</enum>
                    <text>an opportunity to inspect and copy Court records relating to the debt;</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H1F54D151394246A0B6CA1F63BE47DC5E">
                    <enum>(C)</enum>
                    <text>an opportunity to enter into a written agreement with the Courts, under terms agreeable to the Executive Officer, to establish a schedule for the repayment of the debt; and</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB52BEA5E4C5E482E86AD127F3C56EF16">
                    <enum>(D)</enum>
                    <text>an opportunity for a hearing in accordance with paragraph (2) on the determination of the Courts concerning the existence or the amount of the debt, and in the case of an individual whose repayment schedule is established other than by a written agreement pursuant to subparagraph (C), concerning the terms of the repayment schedule.</text> </subparagraph>
                </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8675859BC33046E5A2062C6A4E4F37FC">
                  <enum>(2)</enum>
                  <header>Procedures for hearings</header> 
<subparagraph id="HB4041C5A01994069BC50AE6BDBC5FFF4">
                    <enum>(A)</enum>
                    <header>Availability of hearing upon request</header>
                    <text>A hearing under this paragraph shall be provided if the individual, on or before the fifteenth day following receipt of the notice described in paragraph (1)(A), and in accordance with such procedures as the Executive Officer may prescribe, files a petition requesting such a hearing.</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2907AE3AAA154B6AA32FD1F8297C4CE1">
                    <enum>(B)</enum>
                    <header>Basis for hearing</header>
                    <text>Unless the hearing officer determines that the existence or the amount of the debt turns on an issue of credibility or veracity or cannot be resolved by a review of the documentary evidence, the hearing shall be on the written submissions.</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H3B96DB2F253A48F49CABB4832C727033">
                    <enum>(C)</enum>
                    <header>Stay of collection proceedings</header>
                    <text>The timely filing of a petition for hearing shall stay the commencement of collection proceedings.</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF5216B045FD94B279FD9676BE4D3E83A">
                    <enum>(D)</enum>
                    <header>Independent officer</header>
                    <text>A hearing under this paragraph shall be conducted by an independent hearing officer appointed in accordance with regulations promulgated under subsection (e).</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9CB4B017C65448CCA7F35E655FD876AE">
                    <enum>(E)</enum>
                    <header>Deadline for decision</header>
                    <text>The hearing officer shall issue a final decision regarding the questions covered by the hearing at the earliest practicable date, but not later than 60 days after the hearing.</text> </subparagraph>
                </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H576218A2A6E7431F975AB78B802FFF24">
                  <enum>(3)</enum>
                  <header>Exception</header>
                  <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Paragraphs (1) and (2) shall not apply to routine intra-Courts adjustments of pay that are attributable to clerical or administrative errors or delays in processing pay documents that have occurred within the 4 pay periods preceding the adjustment and to any adjustment that amounts to $50 or less, if at the time of such adjustment, or as soon thereafter as practical, the individual is provided written notice of the nature and the amount of the adjustment and a point of contact for contesting such adjustment.</text> </paragraph>
              </subsection> 
<subsection id="H56ADAC695130401888F0A3196626B542">
                <enum>(c)</enum>
                <header>Compromise</header> 
<paragraph id="H8B9559B783FC4C0DA7D211038F4C3991">
                  <enum>(1)</enum>
                  <header>Authority to compromise claims</header>
                  <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Executive Officer may—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HB63F60C28B884E918AA06086DF98E795">
                    <enum>(A)</enum>
                    <text>compromise a claim to collect an indebtedness under this section if the amount involved is not more than $100,000; and</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA0016E0E948C40CF81E7C4E18554D4C3">
                    <enum>(B)</enum>
                    <text>suspend or end collection action on such a claim if it appears that no person liable on the claim has the present or prospective ability to pay a significant amount of the claim or if the cost of collecting the claim is likely to be more than the amount recovered.</text> </subparagraph>
                </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H80984F86617B45AAA54ABF026B29F745">
                  <enum>(2)</enum>
                  <header>Effect of compromise</header>
                  <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A compromise under this subsection is final and conclusive unless gotten by fraud, misrepresentation, presenting a false claim, or mutual mistake of fact.</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE814A19C842244E198F1AB67845CC5BA">
                  <enum>(3)</enum>
                  <header>No liability of official responsible for compromise</header>
                  <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An accountable official is not liable for an amount paid or for the value of property lost or damaged if the amount or value is not recovered because of a compromise under this subsection.</text> </paragraph>
              </subsection> 
<subsection id="H60080194C2A44D03A458103FF284CCE3">
                <enum>(d)</enum>
                <header>Waiver of Claim</header> 
<paragraph id="H5A1A55FA5634422589D51036B070AE57">
                  <enum>(1)</enum>
                  <header>Authority to waive claims</header>
                  <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon application from a person liable on a claim to collect an indebtedness under this section, the Executive Officer may, with written justification, waive the claim if collection would be—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H3413FB642DD947FD8F24EC8CE0904DE9">
                    <enum>(A)</enum>
                    <text>against equity;</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H493F4F800BA3447CA9388D033721A58E">
                    <enum>(B)</enum>
                    <text>against good conscience; and</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H8D21A0EB9DE14CC88A95AD436E583CF1">
                    <enum>(C)</enum>
                    <text>not in the best interests of the Courts.</text> </subparagraph>
                </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H68CCA65CBBC74927BA9674F85C2D22ED">
                  <enum>(2)</enum>
                  <header>Limitations on authority</header>
                  <text>The Executive Officer may not exercise the authority under this subsection to waive a claim if—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HA771CF30FD8F4B34AF71A1863E1135D4">
                    <enum>(A)</enum>
                    <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the Executive Officer’s opinion, there exists, in connection with the claim, an indication of fraud, misrepresentation, fault, or lack of good faith on the part of the employee, former employee, or any other person having an interest in obtaining a waiver of the claim; or</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA4DF24A13A8B49529E7181850922324E">
                    <enum>(B)</enum>
                    <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the application for waiver is received in the Executive Officer’s office after the expiration of 3 years immediately following the date on which the erroneous payment was discovered or 3 years after the date of the enactment of this section, whichever is later, except if the claim involves money owed for Federal health benefits, Federal life insurance, or Federal retirement benefits.</text> </subparagraph>
                </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB83327017B894DC8B9A669493395E618">
                  <enum>(3)</enum>
                  <header>Denial of application for waiver</header>
                  <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A decision by the Executive Officer to deny an application for a waiver under this subsection shall be the final administrative decision of the District government.</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3B6FC65083AC45FBA33AA7852C54EC1F">
                  <enum>(4)</enum>
                  <header>Refund of amounts already collected against claim subsequently waived</header>
                  <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Courts have been reimbursed for a claim under this section in whole or in part, and a waiver of the claim is then granted, the employee or former employee shall be entitled to a refund of the amount of the reimbursement upon application for that refund, so long as the application is received not later than 2 years after the effective date of the waiver.</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H332E2C33A989409681794C85C33370F8">
                  <enum>(5)</enum>
                  <header>Effect on accounts of Courts</header>
                  <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the audit and settlement of accounts of any accountable official, full credit shall be given for any amounts with respect to which collection by the Courts is waived under this subsection.</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H69D5F9C989494A6A9DCCCBBCD9A32188">
                  <enum>(6)</enum>
                  <header>Validity of payments</header>
                  <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An erroneous payment or debt, the collection of which is waived under this subsection, is a valid payment for all purposes.</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE9BC1B4424A5480BB56750C9F6D00523">
                  <enum>(7)</enum>
                  <header>No effect on other authorities</header>
                  <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing contained in this subsection shall be construed to affect in any way the authority under any other statute to litigate, settle, compromise, or waive any claim of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2093">District of Columbia</cato:entity-ref>.</text> </paragraph>
              </subsection> 
<subsection id="HB7ACA1FE1F704F3983A9B35959D4F7B5">
                <enum>(e)</enum>
                <header>Regulations</header>
                <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Executive Officer’s authority under this section shall be subject to regulations promulgated by the Joint Committee on Judicial Administration.</text>
              </subsection>
            </section>
            <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
          </quoted-block> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3AD9F84D1CCE4707BC97817D2CD9CD42">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Clerical amendment</header>
          <text>The table of contents of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/11/17">chapter 17</external-xref> of title 11, District of Columbia Official Code, is amended by adding at the end of the items relating to subchapter II the following new item:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2652B437D7F74BC09A9487638859DFC3" style="USC"> 
<toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> 
<toc-entry level="section">11–1733. Collection, compromise, and waiver of employee debts and erroneous payments.</toc-entry>
            </toc>
            <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
          </quoted-block> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H635C6897EAB6465EA0DB0CD2962C689F">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <header>Effective date</header>
          <text>The amendments made by this subsection shall apply with respect to erroneous payments made and debts incurred before, on, or after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text> </paragraph>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="HD137999B8F2C4B9494AB31D7703AE153">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Authorization To Purchase Uniforms for Personnel</header>
        <text>Section 11–1742(b), District of Columbia Official Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new sentence: <quote>Under the authority of the previous sentence, the Executive Officer may purchase uniforms to be worn by nonjudicial employees of the District of Columbia Courts whose responsibilities warrant the wearing of uniforms, so long as the cost of furnishing a uniform to an employee during a year does not exceed the amount applicable for the year under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc/5/5901/a/1">
              <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/5/5901">
              section 5901(a)(1)
            </external-xref> of title 5, United States Code</cato:entity-ref> (relating to the uniform allowance for employees of the Government of the United States).</quote>.</text> </subsection>
    </section> 
<section id="H061A0EEA2B9A4336BC550275E53EDBD2">
      <enum>3.</enum>
      <header>Authorities of Court Services and Offender Supervision Agency</header> 
<subsection id="HFDFCC2E37BEB4BCDAABF746368E494A1">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Authority To Develop and Operate Incentive Programs for Sentenced Offenders</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">
          <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="National Capital Revitalization and Self-Government Improvement Act of 1997/s:11233/ss:b/p:2/sp:F">Section 11233(b)(2)(F) of the National Capital Revitalization and Self-Government Improvement Act of 1997</cato:entity-ref> (sec. 24–133(b)(2)(F), D.C. Official Code) is amended by striking <quote>sanctions</quote> and inserting <quote>sanction and incentive</quote>.</text> </subsection> 
<subsection id="HF7BD66562ED14CA8BE60F59CF5D5F0A4">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Permanent Authority To Accept Gifts</header>
        <text>
          <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="National Capital Revitalization and Self-Government Improvement Act of 1997/s:11233/ss:b/p:3/sp:A">Section 11233(b)(3)(A) of such Act</cato:entity-ref> (sec. 24–133(b)(3)(A), D.C. Official Code) is amended to read as follows:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H62D310F577234DEFBEC4829701D3F096" style="OLC"> 
<subparagraph id="HEBC77736C6B54BD0B6D9880DFAF3A8BF">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <header>Authority to accept gifts</header>
            <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="9594">Director</cato:entity-ref> may accept, solicit, and use on behalf of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="9594">Agency</cato:entity-ref> any monetary or nonmonetary gift, donation, bequest, or use of facilities, property, or services for the purpose of aiding or facilitating the work of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="9594">Agency</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
        </quoted-block> </subsection> 
<subsection id="H7F092A83C6B94159848634CE753891F3">
        <enum>(c)</enum>
        <header>Permanent Authority To Accept and Use Reimbursements From District Government</header>
        <text>
          <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="National Capital Revitalization and Self-Government Improvement Act of 1997/s:11233/ss:b/p:4">Section 11233(b)(4) of such Act</cato:entity-ref> (sec. 24–133(b)(4)) is amended by striking <quote>During fiscal years 2006 through 2008, the Director</quote> and inserting <quote>The Director</quote>.</text> </subsection>
    </section> 
<section id="H0973B63A3EAC4D4C9C41B030E370CCBB">
      <enum>4.</enum>
      <header>Authorities of Public Defender Service</header> 
<subsection id="H8C4F944670D546EEAE9A77A05E68F4AE">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Acceptance and Use of Services of Volunteers</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">
          <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="National Capital Revitalization and Self-Government Improvement Act of 1997/s:307/ss:b">Section 307(b) of such Act</cato:entity-ref> (sec. 2–1607(b), D.C. Official Code) is amended by striking <quote>the Service may accept public grants and private contributions made to assist it</quote> and inserting <quote>the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1023">Service</cato:entity-ref> may accept and use public grants, private contributions, and voluntary and uncompensated (gratuitous) services to assist it</quote>.</text> </subsection> 
<subsection id="H1FD4FB4380994856B2261506C3C9E309">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Treatment of Members of Board of Trustees as Employees of Service for Purposes of Liability</header> 
<paragraph id="H262B6B9375EB4F21962CA58A0FE0DD8B">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>In general</header>
          <text>
            <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="National Capital Revitalization and Self-Government Improvement Act of 1997/s:303/ss:d">Section 303(d) of such Act</cato:entity-ref> (sec. 2–1603(d), D.C. Official Code) is amended by striking <quote>employees of the District of Columbia</quote> and inserting <quote>employees of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1023">Service</cato:entity-ref>
            </quote>.</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HEB6DB3E3733F45E8A69782C639B5AEED">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Effective date</header>
          <text>The amendment made by <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="District of Columbia Courts, Public Defender Service, and Court Services and Offender Supervision Agency Act of 2014/s:4/ss:b/p:1" proposed="true">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref> shall take effect as if included in the enactment of the <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="District of Columbia Courts and Justice Technical Corrections Act of 1998">District of Columbia Courts and Justice Technical Corrections Act of 1998</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/105/274">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="public-law" value="public-law/105/274">Public Law 105–274</cato:entity-ref>
            </external-xref>)</cato:entity>.</text> </paragraph>
      </subsection>
    </section> 
</legis-body> 
<endorsement display="yes"> 
<action-date date="20140703">July 3, 2014</action-date> 
<action-desc>Committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union and ordered to be printed</action-desc>
  </endorsement> 
</bill>
</doc>