<doc>
  <docmeta id="113hres372ih">
    <bill congress="113" type="hres" number="372" version="ih"/>
    <revision size="2278" annotations="0" status="complete" id="3" commit-time="2013-10-09T20:08:58Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113hres372ih/3.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <resolution xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" dms-id="H148587BE68F247B8BB6D0117656A6B0A" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>113 HRES 372 IH: Providing for the consideration of legislation to reopen the Government.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2013-10-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code> 
<congress display="yes">113th CONGRESS</congress>
<session display="yes">1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. RES. 372</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action display="yes"> 
<action-date date="20131004">October 4, 2013</action-date> 
<action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="V000128">Mr. Van Hollen</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="M000725">Mr. George Miller of California</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="L000480">Mrs. Lowey</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HRU00">Committee on Rules</committee-name>
      </action-desc>
</action> 
<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type> 
<official-title display="yes">Providing for the consideration of legislation to reopen the Government.</official-title> 
</form> 
<resolution-body style="traditional" id="H0016317432054F8DBADEA394BEAB336D"> 
<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="HEE55E64582FA4E5D9701196F5A029C80">
      <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That immediately upon adoption of this resolution, the House shall proceed to the consideration in the House of the bill (H.R. 1164) the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Government Shutdown Prevention Act">Government Shutdown Prevention Act</cato:entity-ref>. All points of order against consideration of the bill are waived. The bill shall be considered as read. All points of order against provisions in the bill are waived. The previous question shall be considered as ordered on the bill and on any amendment thereto to final passage without intervening motion except:</text> 
<paragraph id="HB929F716D8514AD5A03E2CF132ECA3DF" display-inline="yes-display-inline">
        <enum> (1)</enum>
        <text>one hour of debate equally divided and controlled by the chair and ranking minority member of the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="committee" entity-id="HAP00">Committee on Appropriations</cato:entity-ref>;</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7F2179C2897640B0BEDEBDB03E836C34" display-inline="yes-display-inline">
        <enum> (2)</enum>
        <text>a proper amendment in the nature of a substitute providing a continuing resolution through November 15, 2013, consistent with the level of appropriations provided for by the engrossed Senate amendment to H.J. Res. 59, if offered by Representative Van Hollen of Maryland or his designee, which shall be in order without intervention of any point of order except for those arising under clause 7 of rule XVI, shall be considered as read, and shall be separately debatable for one hour equally divided and controlled by the proponent and an opponent; and</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF4F9DD408F0E421F904870F5D58D94D8" display-inline="yes-display-inline">
        <enum> (3)</enum>
        <text>one motion to recommit with or without instructions.</text>
      </paragraph>
    </section> 
<section id="HB82127F30F064495A4CE2085C4DE68FF">
      <enum>2.</enum>
      <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the amendment in the nature of a substitute referenced in the first section is offered and fails of adoption, then H.R. 1164 shall be referred to the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="committee" entity-id="HAP00">Committee on Appropriations</cato:entity-ref>. </text>
    </section> 
<section id="H7FEFB89E956947FC8468DCC46A053C8F">
      <enum>3.</enum>
      <text display-inline="yes-display-inline"> Clause 1(c) of rule XIX shall not apply to the consideration of H.R. 1164. </text>
    </section> 
</resolution-body> 
</resolution>
</doc>