<doc>
  <docmeta id="113hr765ih">
    <bill congress="113" type="hr" number="765" version="ih"/>
    <revision size="13478" annotations="0" id="5" commit-time="2013-03-24T18:06:55+00:00" committer="favila" doc="113hr765ih/5.xml" status="complete">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H0DCABBE98E6940FDA50EE0542E699931" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<form> 
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>113th CONGRESS</congress>
<session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. R. 765</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20130215">February 15, 2013</action-date> 
<action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="C001036">Mrs. Capps</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name> and <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Natural Resources</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To authorize the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to establish a program of awarding grants to owners or operators of water systems to increase resiliency or adaptability of the systems to any ongoing or forecasted changes to the hydrologic conditions of a region of the United States.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="HE274A4175BB24C85B0C1DB0FDE56CBAB" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HC286D384FEBC444194FAEDB20736F863" section-type="section-one">
      <enum>1.</enum>
      <header>Short title</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote>
          <short-title>Water Infrastructure Resiliency and Sustainability Act of 2013</short-title>
        </quote>.</text>
    </section>
<section id="H36944708B9594276A64DC68A58EFA663">
      <enum>2.</enum>
      <header>Water infrastructure resiliency and sustainability</header>
<subsection id="H6DEA88A003224E16924895933E4EBB8E">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Definitions</header>
        <text>In this section:</text>
<paragraph id="HB37D1D95203F43FF981517B18822F66A">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>Administrator</header>
          <text>The term <term>Administrator</term> means the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency.</text>
        </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H0A35BBBC7AF64A3BBBF474EE60AC9580">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Hydrologic conditions</header>
          <text>The term <term>hydrologic conditions</term> means the quality, quantity, or reliability of the water resources of a region of the United States.</text>
        </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HA76177FD6B904C4D9F0D7674124AED96">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <header>Owner or operator of a water system</header>
<subparagraph id="HBF64320E91C746D0AA52195A148111B8">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <header>In general</header>
            <text>The term <term>owner or operator of a water system</term> means an entity (including a regional, State, Tribal, local, municipal, or private entity) that owns or operates a water system.</text>
          </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HF9086D8502E44A6F9F4959CCBFD25792">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <header>Inclusion</header>
            <text>The term <term>owner or operator of a water system</term> includes—</text>
<clause id="H0324F7DE587942B2B1AEC2565DDF984F">
              <enum>(i)</enum>
              <text>a non-Federal entity that has operational responsibilities for a federally, tribally, or State-owned water system; and</text>
            </clause>
<clause id="H06998974779441CEBB6F3E44A3E6AC49">
              <enum>(ii)</enum>
              <text>an entity established by an agreement between—</text>
<subclause id="H54C313EC7C284BD9B4EA0399D0FEC167">
                <enum>(I)</enum>
                <text>an entity that owns or operates a water system; and</text>
              </subclause>
<subclause id="H986083C6128546E29B5CE53A2113A4E9">
                <enum>(II)</enum>
                <text>at least one other entity.</text>
              </subclause>
            </clause>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HD6B8DBA3974146C9884653B8A906B43F">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
          <header>Water system</header>
          <text>The term <term>water system</term> means—</text>
<subparagraph id="H60C4A6868BB6441B8887BD805CA0E76B">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>a community water system (as defined in <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Safe Drinking Water Act/s:1401">section 1401 of the Safe Drinking Water Act</cato:entity-ref> (<cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/42/300f">42 U.S.C. 300f</cato:entity-ref>)</cato:entity>);</text>
          </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HAA23FA41D9224050B71E529E5280FE26">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>a treatment works (as defined in <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Federal Water Pollution Control Act/s:212">section 212 of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act</cato:entity-ref> (<cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/33/1292">33 U.S.C. 1292</cato:entity-ref>)</cato:entity>), including a municipal separate storm sewer system (as such term is used in the <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Federal Water Pollution Control Act">Federal Water Pollution Control Act</cato:entity-ref> (<cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/33/1251/etseq">33 U.S.C. 1251 et seq.</cato:entity-ref>)</cato:entity>);</text>
          </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H07469BB6E7184B2AAA22240C5CDEC101">
            <enum>(C)</enum>
            <text>a decentralized wastewater treatment system for domestic sewage;</text>
          </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HC02E3B8F30184DD68115AEB7EA91F34F">
            <enum>(D)</enum>
            <text>a groundwater storage and replenishment system;</text>
          </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H730DA9FC0CCA40249EB3C738D1C3C646">
            <enum>(E)</enum>
            <text>a system for transport and delivery of water for irrigation or conservation; or</text>
          </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HD882DE7816EE4B5BBBEA482B26D03806">
            <enum>(F)</enum>
            <text>a natural or engineered system that manages floodwaters.</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
<subsection id="HDD150B22CC794939BAE6A8BA01C25690">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Program</header>
        <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="6800">Administrator</cato:entity-ref> shall establish and implement a program, to be known as the Water Infrastructure Resiliency and Sustainability Program, under which the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="6800">Administrator</cato:entity-ref> awards grants in each of fiscal years 2014 through 2018 to owners or operators of water systems for the purpose of increasing the resiliency or adaptability of the systems to any ongoing or forecasted changes (based on the best available research and data) to the hydrologic conditions of a region of the United States.</text>
      </subsection>
<subsection id="HCF5B6E6FE83246AA897F37D6175DEF31">
        <enum>(c)</enum>
        <header>Use of funds</header>
        <text>As a condition on receipt of a grant under this section, an owner or operator of a water system shall agree to use the grant funds exclusively to assist in the planning, design, construction, implementation, operation, or maintenance of a program or project that meets the purpose described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Water Infrastructure Resiliency and Sustainability Act of 2013/s:2/ss:b" proposed="true">subsection (b)</cato:entity-ref> by—</text>
<paragraph id="H6ECD116C84EA4467891A6A93BCD25113">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>conserving water or enhancing water use efficiency, including through the use of water metering and electronic sensing and control systems to measure the effectiveness of a water efficiency program;</text>
        </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H0F9BFEC1217B4023AF482ED13017E64F">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>modifying or relocating existing water system infrastructure made or projected to be significantly impaired by changing hydrologic conditions;</text>
        </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HBC223088BCEB455E9B75577CC0645DB6">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <text>preserving or improving water quality, including through measures to manage, reduce, treat, or reuse municipal stormwater, wastewater, or drinking water;</text>
        </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H1CFDD69A26E5404F9F11FEC96FF13ABD">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
          <text>investigating, designing, or constructing groundwater remediation, recycled water, or desalination facilities or systems to serve existing communities;</text>
        </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HD710DCA5463445FEB2906AADBA1CE917">
          <enum>(5)</enum>
          <text>enhancing water management by increasing watershed preservation and protection, such as through the use of natural or engineered green infrastructure in the management, conveyance, or treatment of water, wastewater, or stormwater;</text>
        </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H5073BDB368AF4C319AE80F6AA23F4BF8">
          <enum>(6)</enum>
          <text>enhancing energy efficiency or the use and generation of renewable energy in the management, conveyance, or treatment of water, wastewater, or stormwater;</text>
        </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H5256F4C59E33451780058DFD681E8257">
          <enum>(7)</enum>
          <text>supporting the adoption and use of advanced water treatment, water supply management (such as reservoir reoperation and water banking), or water demand management technologies, projects, or processes (such as water reuse and recycling, adaptive conservation pricing, and groundwater banking) that maintain or increase water supply or improve water quality;</text>
        </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HD3BCFE54A4A3412AA0B79956E1B48759">
          <enum>(8)</enum>
          <text>modifying or replacing existing systems or constructing new systems for existing communities or land currently in agricultural production to improve water supply, reliability, storage, or conveyance in a manner that—</text>
<subparagraph id="H190BFDEAEFB147B7AAC5C2B392F8794F">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>promotes conservation or improves the efficiency of utilization of available water supplies; and</text>
          </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H1F6170F0656142D8A07644CB4EDFCB3B">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>does not further exacerbate stresses on ecosystems or cause redirected impacts by degrading water quality or increasing net greenhouse gas emissions;</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H95B63607CAF84A3086E25A3D0E8EBF0F">
          <enum>(9)</enum>
          <text>supporting practices and projects, such as improved irrigation systems, water banking and other forms of water transactions, groundwater recharge, stormwater capture, groundwater conjunctive use, and reuse or recycling of drainage water, to improve water quality or promote more efficient water use on land currently in agricultural production;</text>
        </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HD7E14A5065B44E65B384D1FDBAF9699F">
          <enum>(10)</enum>
          <text>reducing flood damage, risk, and vulnerability by—</text>
<subparagraph id="H01D97A3F95E64CD09E5F4F7F67D107FF">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>restoring floodplains, wetlands, and uplands integral to flood management, protection, prevention, and response;</text>
          </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HA8B18EF5FF0C471F8374CC2FD5E47EC1">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>modifying levees, floodwalls, and other structures through setbacks, notches, gates, removal, or similar means to facilitate reconnection of rivers to floodplains, reduce flood stage height, and reduce damage to properties and populations;</text>
          </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H40AE285AD1F146BD847262610F05205E">
            <enum>(C)</enum>
            <text>providing for acquisition and easement of flood-prone lands and properties in order to reduce damage to property and risk to populations; or</text>
          </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H207AAFF5736643B692805000413537EC">
            <enum>(D)</enum>
            <text>promoting land use planning that prevents future floodplain development;</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H6C3A0624224D4FF696526E0391F26366">
          <enum>(11)</enum>
          <text>conducting and completing studies or assessments to project how changing hydrologic conditions may impact the future operations and sustainability of water systems; or</text>
        </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HC41D5FF1784249AA975C04AB34D4D1FC">
          <enum>(12)</enum>
          <text>developing and implementing measures to increase the resilience of water systems and regional and hydrological basins, including the Colorado River Basin, to rapid hydrologic change or a natural disaster (such as tsunami, earthquake, flood, or volcanic eruption).</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
<subsection id="H4B848135B17B405ABCC18007431BF459">
        <enum>(d)</enum>
        <header>Application</header>
        <text>To seek a grant under this section, the owner or operator of a water system shall submit to the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="6800">Administrator</cato:entity-ref> an application that—</text>
<paragraph id="H6505F078FF434F4FA5871CB85A4A4751">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>includes a proposal of the program, strategy, or infrastructure improvement to be planned, designed, constructed, implemented, or maintained by the water system;</text>
        </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H8D9D33603A704369935247754973C334">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>cites the best available research or data that demonstrate—</text>
<subparagraph id="H97BF036CD8DF4EF79E60DF64E308A7C5">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>the risk to the water resources or infrastructure of the water system as a result of ongoing or forecasted changes to the hydrological system of a region, including rising sea levels and changes in precipitation patterns; and</text>
          </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HD3DA116949FA4AB49484823246FA7C0B">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>how the proposed program, strategy, or infrastructure improvement would perform under the anticipated hydrologic conditions;</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H2391155CE8D34E069045E3698F258BAC">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <text>explains how the proposed program, strategy, or infrastructure improvement is expected—</text>
<subparagraph id="H8B090927105D43148C2A8D1E6ECE4078">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>to enhance the resiliency of the water system, including source water protection for community water systems, to the anticipated hydrologic conditions; or</text>
          </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H7F1B2C1FC44C4206A56157205B1DF029">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>to increase efficiency in the use of energy or water of the water system; and</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HC88FF047198945ED944D6E41EF0D8417">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
          <text>describes how the proposed program, strategy, or infrastructure improvement is consistent with an applicable State, tribe, or local climate adaptation plan, if any.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
<subsection id="HA578BB6BB0E143A99672A23009152DA7">
        <enum>(e)</enum>
        <header>Priority</header>
<paragraph id="H47B5F90D8F494079B249D0DB9DF84071">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>Water systems at greatest and most immediate risk</header>
          <text>In selecting grantees under this section, subject to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Water Infrastructure Resiliency and Sustainability Act of 2013/s:2/ss:h/p:2" proposed="true">subsection (h)(2)</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="6800">Administrator</cato:entity-ref> shall give priority to owners or operators of water systems that are, based on the best available research and data, at the greatest and most immediate risk of facing significant negative impacts due to changing hydrologic conditions.</text>
        </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HFB4ACA7A5D8145FAAA58C286EFE68C90">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Goals</header>
          <text>In selecting among applicants described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Water Infrastructure Resiliency and Sustainability Act of 2013/s:2/ss:e/p:1" proposed="true">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="6800">Administrator</cato:entity-ref> shall ensure that, to the maximum extent practicable, the final list of applications funded for each year includes a substantial number that propose to utilize innovative approaches to meet one or more of the following goals:</text>
<subparagraph id="H8C3962C0CCCC402E80F8938DC937DD2B">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>Promoting more efficient water use, water conservation, water reuse, or recycling.</text>
          </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HA7A067DE4F614B63BB907CB668047162">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>Using decentralized, low-impact development technologies and nonstructural approaches, including practices that use, enhance, or mimic the natural hydrological cycle or protect natural flows.</text>
          </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HA2EF61ACF9304EE8828205F65788BA34">
            <enum>(C)</enum>
            <text>Reducing stormwater runoff or flooding by protecting or enhancing natural ecosystem functions.</text>
          </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HF461ADD760C14B3BBBE4078C3BEC7F8F">
            <enum>(D)</enum>
            <text>Modifying, upgrading, enhancing, or replacing existing water system infrastructure in response to changing hydrologic conditions.</text>
          </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H36C56BD72E314CAF9FD243036E08BDDA">
            <enum>(E)</enum>
            <text>Improving water quality or quantity for agricultural and municipal uses, including through salinity reduction.</text>
          </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HF3580D3EB4594A11B7D49DD285848DF8">
            <enum>(F)</enum>
            <text>Providing multiple benefits, including to water supply enhancement or demand reduction, water quality protection or improvement, increased flood protection, and ecosystem protection or improvement.</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
<subsection id="H4060420901F84CEABFF4917ED23C30CF">
        <enum>(f)</enum>
        <header>Cost-Sharing</header>
<paragraph id="H41BAF09B7B98448DBB5535C132C404A3">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>Federal share</header>
          <text>The share of the cost of any program, strategy, or infrastructure improvement that is the subject of a grant awarded by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="6800">Administrator</cato:entity-ref> to the owner or operator of a water system under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Water Infrastructure Resiliency and Sustainability Act of 2013/s:2/ss:b" proposed="true">subsection (b)</cato:entity-ref> paid through funds distributed under this section shall not exceed 50 percent of the cost of the program, strategy, or infrastructure improvement.</text>
        </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HCE424C8B86C0426FAD52B5145364CD6F">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Calculation of non-Federal share</header>
          <text>In calculating the non-Federal share of the cost of a program, strategy, or infrastructure improvement proposed by a water system in an application submitted under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Water Infrastructure Resiliency and Sustainability Act of 2013/s:2/ss:d" proposed="true">subsection (d)</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="6800">Administrator</cato:entity-ref> shall—</text>
<subparagraph id="H71FE2C19B8964864B2D1BD497E9DB78E">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>include the value of any in-kind services that are integral to the completion of the program, strategy, or infrastructure improvement, including reasonable administrative and overhead costs; and</text>
          </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HEEF757AD56DC4B58BDB7545963BE9019">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>not include any other amount that the water system involved receives from the Federal Government.</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
<subsection id="H1687E760FD554BD5AFAFC954F9B319F8">
        <enum>(g)</enum>
        <header>Report to Congress</header>
        <text>Not later than 3 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, and every 3 years thereafter, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="6800">Administrator</cato:entity-ref> shall submit to the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> a report on progress in implementing this section, including information on project applications received and funded annually.</text>
      </subsection>
<subsection id="HFC56A2BBC6D1425B8F6B09C97E492C9D">
        <enum>(h)</enum>
        <header>Authorization of Appropriations</header>
<paragraph id="HACF5C8E9EFAD4644BDD9066CECC51571">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>In general</header>
          <text>
            <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="auth-auth-approp">
              <cato:property name="purpose">To carry out <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Water Infrastructure Resiliency and Sustainability Act of 2013/s:2" proposed="true">this section</cato:entity-ref>
              </cato:property>, there is authorized to be appropriated <cato:funds-and-year amount="50000000" year="2014, 2015, 2016, 2017, 2018">$50,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2014 through 2018</cato:funds-and-year>.</cato:entity>
          </text>
        </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H70355577A50E4C628C38A2FA40DB0B8D">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Limitation</header>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Of the amount made available to carry out this section for a fiscal year, not more than 20 percent may be made available to grantees for activities described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Water Infrastructure Resiliency and Sustainability Act of 2013/s:2/ss:c/p:10">subsection (c)(10)</cato:entity-ref> (relating to reducing flood damage, risk, and vulnerability).</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
    </section> 
</legis-body> 
</bill>
</doc>