<doc>
  <docmeta id="113hres431ih">
    <bill congress="113" type="hres" number="431" version="ih"/>
    <revision size="4762" annotations="0" status="complete" id="3" commit-time="2014-01-02T22:39:03Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113hres431ih/3.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <resolution xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" dms-id="H65FA23AA2D0A4DF189AFFEA4F372923D" key="H" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print">
  <metadata>
<dublinCore>
<dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">113 HRES 431 IH: Calling on the United States Senate to increase sanctions against Iran.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">2013-12-05</dc:date>
<dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code>
    <congress display="yes">113th CONGRESS</congress>
    <session display="yes">1st Session</session>
    <legis-num>H. RES. 431</legis-num>
    <current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
    <action display="yes">
      <action-date date="20131205">December 5, 2013</action-date>
      <action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="S001176">Mr. Scalise</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="G000410">Mr. Gene Green of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000289">Mr. Jordan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000055">Mr. Aderholt</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000575">Mr. Lankford</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001256">Mrs. Bachmann</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000448">Mr. Franks of Arizona</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000798">Mr. Walberg</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000373">Mr. Pitts</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001053">Mrs. Hartzler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001188">Mr. Stutzman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001095">Mr. Cotton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001182">Mr. Mulvaney</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000552">Mr. Gohmert</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000582">Mr. Roe of Tennessee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000362">Mr. King of Iowa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000591">Mr. Price of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000599">Mr. Posey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000795">Mr. Wilson of South Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000578">Mr. LaMalfa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000606">Mr. Pittenger</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000814">Mr. Weber of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000601">Mr. Palazzo</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001179">Mr. Marino</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000810">Mr. Woodall</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000460">Mr. Farenthold</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000295">Mr. Joyce</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001192">Mr. Stewart</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001282">Mr. Barr</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001059">Mr. Hultgren</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001243">Mrs. Blackburn</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001192">Mr. McAllister</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001052">Mr. Harris</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="D000615">Mr. Duncan of South Carolina</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Judiciary</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Financial Services</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
    </action>
    <legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
    <official-title display="yes">Calling on the United States Senate to increase sanctions against Iran.</official-title>
  </form>
  <preamble>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas Iran continues to pose a threat to the United States through its pursuit of a nuclear weapons capability, work on its ballistic missile program, and state sponsorship of terrorism;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas on July 31, 2013, the United States House of Representatives passed the Nuclear Iran Prevention Act of 2013, H.R. 850, by an overwhelmingly bipartisan vote of 400–20–1;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas this legislation highlights the devastating threat that a nuclear-armed Iran would pose to the United States, United States allies, and United States interests globally;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas Israel is a vital ally of the United States;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas Iran, which rejects Israel’s right to exist, is a continued threat to the safety and security of the United States and Israel, both through its support of terrorist groups like Hamas and Hezbollah and through its ongoing efforts to acquire nuclear weapons;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas Iran has threatened to <quote>wipe [Israel] off the map</quote>, in violation of article 2, paragraph 4 of the United Nations Charter;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas Iran possesses ballistic missiles that can reach Israel and is working to develop intercontinental ballistic missiles that could reach the United States;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas Iran has constructed a large explosives containment vessel at the Parchin military complex and the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="19UE">International Atomic Energy Agency</cato:entity-ref> (IAEA) has requested to inspect this complex for traces of weaponization research;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="19UE">IAEA</cato:entity-ref> issued a report exposing Iran’s nuclear intentions and in November 2011 concluded that <quote>contrary to the relevant resolutions of the Board of Governors and the Security Council, Iran has not suspended its [nuclear] enrichment related activities</quote> and continues to proceed with a nuclear weapons proliferation program, and the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="19UE">IAEA</cato:entity-ref> Board of Governors has issued 10 resolutions condemning Iran’s nuclear program;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" value="Security Council" entity-parent-id="19UN">United Nations Security Council</cato:entity-ref> has required Iran to cooperate fully with the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="19UE">IAEA’s</cato:entity-ref> investigation into its nuclear activities, suspend its uranium enrichment program, suspend its construction of a heavy-water reactor and related projects, and ratify the Additional Protocol to its <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="19UE">IAEA</cato:entity-ref> safeguards agreement;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas Iran, in violation of multiple <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" value="Security Council" entity-parent-id="19UN">United Nations Security Council</cato:entity-ref> resolutions, has continued to enrich uranium, continued work on its heavy-water reactor and related projects, and has not ratified the Additional Protocol to its <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="19UE">IAEA</cato:entity-ref> safeguards agreement;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas multiple rounds of tough sanctions have been effective in bringing Iran to the negotiating table and the threat of increased sanctions has the ability to compel Iran to abandon its nuclear ambitions; and</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the P5+1 interim agreement will not prevent Iran from acquiring a nuclear weapons capability: Now, therefore, be it</text>
    </whereas>
  </preamble>
  <resolution-body id="H67D2ED2BD2E144C39459C2F09FA7EE06" style="traditional">
    <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H5EF3F3DB9E8B471F982606A3D1D20755" section-type="undesignated-section">
      <enum/>
      <text>That—</text>
      <paragraph id="HD24C77E110654B6299990A9A6D764698">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">it is the policy of the United States to prevent Iran from acquiring a nuclear weapons capability; and</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H838DBF0483A24872A0757B6C709C9B66">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0050">House of Representatives</cato:entity-ref> calls on the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0010">United States Senate</cato:entity-ref> to take immediate action on the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Nuclear Iran Prevention Act of 2013">Nuclear Iran Prevention Act of 2013</cato:entity-ref> to increase sanctions against Iran.</text>
      </paragraph>
    </section>
  </resolution-body>
</resolution>
</doc>