<doc>
  <docmeta id="113hres475rh">
    <bill congress="113" type="hres" number="475" version="rh"/>
    <revision size="5328" annotations="0" status="complete" id="6" commit-time="2014-02-21T20:33:52Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113hres475rh/6.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <resolution xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" dms-id="H18b61e07-1c30-494e-9e28-4838e8e7ef61" key="H" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Reported-in-House" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print">
	<metadata>
<dublinCore>
<dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">113 HRES 475 RH: Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 3193) to amend the Consumer Financial Protection Act of 2010 to strengthen the review authority of the Financial Stability Oversight Council of regulations issued by the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection, and for other purposes; providing for proceedings during the period from February 13, 2014, through February 24, 2014; and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">2014-02-10</dc:date>
<dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code>
		<calendar display="yes">House Calendar No. 84</calendar>
		<congress display="yes">113th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session display="yes">2d Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. RES. 475</legis-num>
		<associated-doc display="yes" role="report">[Report No. 113–350]</associated-doc>
		<current-chamber display="yes">IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20140210">February 10, 2014</action-date>
			<action-desc>
        <cosponsor name-id="S000250">Mr. Sessions</cosponsor>, from the <committee-name committee-id="HRU00">Committee on Rules</committee-name>, reported the following resolution; which was referred to the House Calendar and ordered to be
			 printed</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 3193) to amend the Consumer Financial Protection Act
			 of 2010 to strengthen the review authority of the Financial Stability
			 Oversight Council of regulations issued by the Bureau of Consumer
			 Financial Protection, and for other purposes; providing for proceedings
			 during the period from February 13, 2014, through February 24, 2014; and
			 for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<resolution-body id="Hfc14831b-f20b-46d7-9a97-65291a6f014b" style="traditional">
		<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="He3766d9b-0cd3-4e59-a2fa-4fcfbe261355" section-type="undesignated-section">
      <enum/>
      <text>That at any time after adoption of this resolution the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" value="Speaker of the House of Representatives" entity-parent-id="0050">Speaker</cato:entity-ref> may, pursuant to clause 2(b) of rule
			 XVIII, declare the House resolved into the Committee of the Whole House on
			 the state of the Union for consideration of the bill (<cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="113 HR 3193" proposed="true">H.R. 3193</cato:entity-ref>) to amend
			 the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Consumer Financial Protection Act of 2010">Consumer Financial Protection Act of 2010</cato:entity-ref> to strengthen the review
			 authority of the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-parent-id="2000" value="Financial Stability Oversight Council">Financial Stability Oversight Council</cato:entity-ref> of regulations
			 issued by the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-parent-id="9559" value="Consumer Financial Protection Bureau">Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection</cato:entity-ref>, and for other
			 purposes. The first reading of the bill shall be dispensed with. All
			 points of order against consideration of the bill are waived. General
			 debate shall be confined to the bill and amendments specified in this
			 section and shall not exceed one hour equally divided and controlled by
			 the chair and ranking minority member of the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="committee" entity-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial
			 Services</cato:entity-ref>. After general debate the bill shall be considered for amendment
			 under the five-minute rule. It shall be in order to consider as an
			 original bill for the purpose of amendment under the five-minute rule an
			 amendment in the nature of a substitute consisting of the text of Rules
			 Committee Print 113-36 modified by the amendment printed in part A of the
			 report of the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="committee" entity-id="HRU00">Committee on Rules</cato:entity-ref> accompanying this resolution. That
			 amendment in the nature of a substitute shall be considered as read. All
			 points of order against that amendment in the nature of a substitute are
			 waived. No amendment to that amendment in the nature of a substitute shall
			 be in order except those printed in part B of the report of the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="committee" entity-id="HRU00">Committee
			 on Rules</cato:entity-ref> accompanying this resolution. Each such amendment may be offered
			 only in the order printed in the report, may be offered only by a Member
			 designated in the report, shall be considered as read, shall be debatable
			 for the time specified in the report equally divided and controlled by the
			 proponent and an opponent, shall not be subject to amendment, and shall
			 not be subject to a demand for division of the question in the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0050">House</cato:entity-ref> or in
			 the Committee of the Whole. All points of order against such amendments
			 are waived. At the conclusion of consideration of the bill for amendment
			 the Committee shall rise and report the bill to the House with such
			 amendments as may have been adopted. Any Member may demand a separate vote
			 in the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0050">House</cato:entity-ref> on any amendment adopted in the Committee of the Whole to the
			 bill or to the amendment in the nature of a substitute made in order as
			 original text. The previous question shall be considered as ordered on the
			 bill and amendments thereto to final passage without intervening motion
			 except one motion to recommit with or without instructions.</text>
		</section>
    <section id="H6C6D087D5DE1464098AF08705CAA8103">
      <enum>2.</enum>
      <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">On any legislative day during the period from February 13, 2014, through February 24, 2014—</text>
			<subsection id="HAABFE75689C442EB9C784F2D0DEE72B2">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <text>the Journal of the proceedings of the previous day shall be considered as approved; and</text>
			</subsection>
      <subsection id="H056A6EDD3AE74D8FB2F9ED29F3509F08">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <text>the Chair may at any time declare the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0050">House</cato:entity-ref> adjourned to meet at a date and time, within the limits
			 of clause 4, section 5, article I of the Constitution, to be announced by
			 the Chair in declaring the adjournment.</text>
			</subsection>
    </section>
    <section id="H621269106ACA445A8B35333CF021D775">
      <enum>3.</enum>
      <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" value="Speaker of the House of Representatives" entity-parent-id="0050">Speaker</cato:entity-ref> may appoint Members to perform the duties of the Chair for the duration of the period
			 addressed by section 2 of this resolution as though under clause 8(a) of
			 rule I.</text>
		</section>
    <section id="H0822820149FF4879B83391C4047FA821">
      <enum>4.</enum>
      <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The requirement of clause 6(a) of rule XIII for a two-thirds vote to consider a report from the
			 <cato:entity-ref entity-type="committee" entity-id="HRU00">Committee on Rules</cato:entity-ref> on the same day it is presented to the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0050">House</cato:entity-ref> is waived
			 with respect to any resolution reported through the legislative day of
			 February 12, 2014, providing for consideration or disposition of a measure
			 relating to the public debt limit.</text>
		</section>
  </resolution-body>
	<endorsement>
    <action-date>February 10, 2014</action-date>
    <action-desc>Referred to the House Calendar and ordered to be
			 printed</action-desc>
  </endorsement>
</resolution>
</doc>