<doc>
  <docmeta id="113hconres41ih">
    <bill congress="113" type="hconres" number="41" version="ih"/>
    <revision size="5847" annotations="0" status="complete" id="5" commit-time="2013-07-29T23:25:10Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113hconres41ih/5.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <resolution xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" dms-id="HEA3D05963806468FAA1B5637B75FFD29" key="H" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" resolution-type="house-concurrent" star-print="no-star-print">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>113 HCON 41 IH: Encouraging peace and reunification on the Korean Peninsula.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2013-06-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">113th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session display="yes">1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. CON. RES. 41</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20130625">June 25, 2013</action-date>
			<action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="R000053">Mr. Rangel</sponsor> submitted
			 the following concurrent resolution; which was referred to the
			 <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign
			 Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the
			 <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed
			 Services</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the
			 Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the
			 jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>CONCURRENT RESOLUTION</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">Encouraging peace and reunification on the
		  Korean Peninsula.</official-title>
	</form>
	<preamble>
		<whereas>
      <text>Whereas the Republic of Korea (hereinafter in this
			 resolution referred to as <term>South Korea</term>) and Democratic People's
			 Republic of Korea (hereinafter in this resolution referred to as <term>North
			 Korea</term>) have never formally ended hostilities and have been technically
			 in a state of war since the Armistice Agreement was signed on July 27,
			 1953;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the United States, as representing the United
			 Nations Forces Command which was a signatory to the Armistice Agreement, and
			 with 28,500 of its troops currently stationed in South Korea, has a stake in
			 the progress towards peace and reunification on the Korean Peninsula;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas progress towards peace and reunification on the
			 Korean Peninsula would mean greater security and prosperity for the region and
			 the world;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas at the end of World War II, Korea officially
			 gained independence from Japanese rule, as agreed to at the Cairo Conference on
			 November 22, 1943, through November 26, 1943;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas on August 10, 1945, the Korean Peninsula was
			 temporarily divided along the 38th parallel into two military occupation zones
			 commanded by the United States and the Soviet Union;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas on June 25, 1950, communist North Korea invaded
			 the South, thereby initiating the Korean War and diminishing prospects for a
			 peaceful unification of Korea;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas during the Korean War, approximately 1,789,000
			 members of the United States Armed Forces served in-theater along with the
			 South Korean forces and 20 other members of the United Nations to secure peace
			 on the Korean Peninsula and the Asia-Pacific region;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas since the end of the Korean War era, the United
			 States Armed Forces have remained in South Korea to promote regional
			 peace;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas North Korea’s provocations in the recent years
			 have escalated tension and instability in the Asia-Pacific region;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas one of the largest obstacles to peace and
			 reunification on the Korean Peninsula is the presence of nuclear weapons in
			 North Korea;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas North Korea’s refusal to denuclearize disrupts
			 peace and security on the Korean Peninsula;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas beginning in 2003, the United States along with
			 the two Koreas, Japan, People's Republic of China, and the Russian Federation,
			 have engaged in six rounds of Six-Party Talks, aimed at finding a peaceful
			 resolution to the security concerns resulting from North Korea’s nuclear
			 development;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas North Korea has recently signaled openness to
			 resume the Six-Party Talks, which halted in 2009 due to North Korea’s
			 increasing inflammatory rhetoric and belligerent acts, including a satellite
			 launch, sinking of South Korean naval ship, and shelling of Yeonpyeong
			 Island;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the three-mile wide buffer zone between the two
			 Koreas, known as the Demilitarized Zone or DMZ, is the most heavily armed
			 border in the world;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas South Korea and North Korea remain the only
			 divided nation in the world;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the Korean War separated more than 10,000,000
			 Korean family members, including 100,000 Korean Americans who after 60 years of
			 separation are still waiting to see their families in North Korea;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas reunification remains a long-term goal for the
			 Governments of both North and South Korea;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas South Korea and North Korea are both full members
			 of the United Nations, whose stated purpose includes maintaining international
			 peace and security, and to that end <quote>take effective collective measures
			 for the prevention and removal of threats to the peace</quote>;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the United States and South Korea have
			 continuously stood shoulder-to-shoulder to promote and defend international
			 peace and security, economic prosperity, human rights, and the rule of law both
			 on the Korean Peninsula and beyond; and</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas July 27, 2013, marks the 60th anniversary of the
			 Armistice Agreement of the Korean War: Now, therefore, be it</text>
		</whereas>
  </preamble>
	<resolution-body id="H918D47A5F372499795D106336FDF416E" style="traditional">
		<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H6D37EDBB1E8743DD9BD6FDCE404EBFEC" section-type="undesignated-section">
      <enum/>
      <text>That <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref>—</text>
			<paragraph id="HE3ADCAE306204C58BADD13F3B3A39794">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recognizes the historical importance of the
			 Korean War, which began on June 25, 1950;</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H4162275B13A843DD8836E0E527478C6B">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text>honors the noble
			 service and sacrifice of the United States Armed Forces and the armed forces of
			 allied countries that served in Korea since 1950 to the present;</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H6B687B3E2CC542C7818646DF18CCAF83">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <text>reaffirms the
			 commitment of the United States to its alliance with South Korea for the
			 betterment of peace and prosperity on the Korean Peninsula; and</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H34D8E14631634FBAB2F8598D4DF22630">
        <enum>(4)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">calls on North Korea to abide by
			 international law and cease its nuclear proliferation in order to resume talks
			 that could eventually lead to peace and reunification.</text>
			</paragraph>
    </section>
  </resolution-body>
</resolution>
</doc>