<doc>
  <docmeta id="113hr673ih">
    <bill congress="113" type="hr" number="673" version="ih"/>
    <revision size="17804" annotations="0" id="9" commit-time="2013-04-01T20:35:00+00:00" committer="favila" doc="113hr673ih/9.xml" status="complete">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H92E6F3DEED2C41B1B36DBAEBD8030976" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<form> 
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>113th CONGRESS</congress>
<session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. R. 673</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20130213">February 13, 2013</action-date> 
<action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="R000435">Ms. Ros-Lehtinen</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="C000266">Mr. Chabot</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001078">Mr. Connolly</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000567">Mr. Lance</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000448">Mr. Franks of Arizona</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000795">Mr. Wilson of South Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001257">Mr. Bilirakis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000814">Mr. Weber of Texas</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="D000615">Mr. Duncan of South Carolina</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To continue restrictions against and prohibit diplomatic recognition of the Government of North Korea, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="HAB18F9F253FC44B5B06DF84FCD146ABD" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H37C9799F5D7343F9BAE4C1F7B902E9A6" section-type="section-one">
      <enum>1.</enum>
      <header>Short title</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote>
          <short-title>North Korea Sanctions and Diplomatic Nonrecognition Act of 2013</short-title>
        </quote>.</text>
    </section> 
<section id="H695EE00B65564D94A4167E0E4AED2C35">
      <enum>2.</enum>
      <header>Findings</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">
        <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> finds the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H4834318B0A83454A802E8F58F2A36F59">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">North Korean negotiators in the Six-Party diplomatic process did not act in good faith by their refusal to agree to a transparent verification process for denuclearization consistent with <quote>international standards</quote>, including provisions for nuclear sampling, following North Korea’s removal on October 11, 2008, from the list of state sponsors of terrorism maintained by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Department of State</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1EC19A659F1C43FCA79B8DB59AAE06A9">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text>International press reports indicate that North Korea has continued to provide support to Iran in the areas of missile technology and nuclear development and has provided Iran’s surrogates, Hezbollah and Hamas, with both missile technology and training in tunneling techniques with which to attack Israel, an ally of the United States.</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC9D10220B17B4D5C8194B2B11DFBCB31">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <text>International press reports indicate that North Korea was engaged for a number of years in assistance to Syria in the construction of a nuclear reactor in the Syrian desert which was destroyed in a strike by Israeli forces on September 6, 2007.</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC14920BE371A4CB4B0FE2FD32BC4E84F">
        <enum>(4)</enum>
        <text>North Korean negotiators continue to refuse to address in a humane and sincere manner the issue of the abduction of civilians of Japan and the Republic of Korea, both allies of the United States, as well as the abductions of citizens from a number of other countries, including France, Lebanon, Romania, and Thailand.</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H47063BCF24974D20825AEA1608D16F47">
        <enum>(5)</enum>
        <text>Defectors coming out of North Korea have provided testimony that United States permanent resident, Reverend Kim Dong-shik, the spouse and father of United States citizens, was tortured and murdered inside North Korea after his abduction by Pyongyang’s agents on the Chinese border in January 2000 and that his remains are currently being held at a military facility inside North Korea.</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8CEF5F07F63A49FBBEF180BD4A33BAA6">
        <enum>(6)</enum>
        <text>
          <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> authoritatively expressed its view, in <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="North Korean Human Rights Act of 2004/s:202/ss:b/p:2">section 202(b)(2) of the North Korean Human Rights Act of 2004</cato:entity-ref> (<cato:entity-ref entity-type="public-law" value="public-law/108/333">Public Law 108–333</cato:entity-ref>; <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/22/7832/b/2">22 U.S.C. 7832(b)(2)</cato:entity-ref>)</cato:entity> that <quote>United States nonhumanitarian assistance to North Korea shall be contingent on North Korea’s substantial progress</quote> on human rights improvements, release of and accounting for abductees, family reunification, reform of North Korea’s labor camp system, and the decriminalization of political expression, none of which has occurred.</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7D997B17CBDA487D943A172E5BAE3A7D">
        <enum>(7)</enum>
        <text>
          <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> further authoritatively expressed its view, in <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="North Korean Human Rights Reauthorization Act of 2008/s:2">section 2 of the North Korean Human Rights Reauthorization Act of 2008</cato:entity-ref> (<cato:entity-ref entity-type="public-law" value="public-law/110/346">Public Law 110–346</cato:entity-ref>)</cato:entity> that <quote>human rights and humanitarian conditions inside North Korea are deplorable</quote> and that <quote>North Korean refugees remain acutely vulnerable</quote>.</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H41A04B1C478145B18FA649AFC923A998">
        <enum>(8)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">
          <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> has determined that any missile test or launch conducted by North Korea would be in direct violation of United Nations Security Council resolution 1695, adopted on July 16, 2006, which <quote>condemns the multiple launches by the DPRK (North Korea) of ballistic missiles on July 5 2006 local time</quote>, and United Nations Security Council Resolution 1718, adopted on October 9, 2006, which <quote>demands that the DPRK (North Korea) not conduct any further nuclear test or launch of a ballistic missile</quote> and <quote>decides that the DPRK shall suspend all activities related to its ballistic missile programme and in this context re-establish its pre-existing commitments to a moratorium on missile launching</quote>, and further determines that the resulting sanctions imposed under such resolution 1718 would again come into full effect following a missile test or launch.</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3A88621F897A4F55ACF15A5B5673371A">
        <enum>(9)</enum>
        <text>
          <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> has further determined that a return by North Korea to the Six-Party diplomatic process following any missile test or launch by Pyongyang must include a firm and transparent commitment to the complete, verifiable and irreversible dismantlement of all of North Korea’s nuclear programs, including those derived both from plutonium as well as highly enriched uranium.</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H70F1D161068144268A91160A4DBB13F9">
        <enum>(10)</enum>
        <text>Japanese press reports have indicated that a delegation of approximately fifteen Iranian missile experts arrived in North Korea in March 2009 <quote>to help Pyongyang prepare for a rocket launch</quote>, including senior officials with the Iranian rocket and satellite producer Shahid Hemmat Industrial Group, and that they brought with them a letter from their President Mahmoud Ahmadinejad to North Korean leader Kim Jong-Il stressing the importance of cooperating on space technology.</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2C6ED755F31A4BA4A89A9B8D6ECAB83E">
        <enum>(11)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">North Korea, in defiance of the international community’s efforts to end nuclear proliferation and in violation of its international obligations, conducted a second underground nuclear test on May 25, 2009 (local time), in violation of United Nations Security Council Resolution 1718, which resulted in the passage of United Nations Security Council Resolution 1874 on June 12, 2009, which imposed additional sanctions and inspection requirements with regard to North Korea.</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD918C3AE0A24482799A57EAD69A991A7">
        <enum>(12)</enum>
        <text>North Korea, according to Western press reports, transshipped missile parts, used to run Iran’s solid fuel ballistic missile program, to Tehran via Air Iran flights which landed in Beijing, China in 2007.</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA3DFDD1EA6BF411F81981D2D4316C510">
        <enum>(13)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Press reports in March 2011 indicated that opposition forces in Libya, when they took positions from Qaddafi forces, discovered North Korean weapons caches, including rockets and anti-aircraft guns, unpacked from crates labeled “bulldozer parts,” which would represent a clear violation of United Nations sanctions.</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0C250F7792D64174BD259F0A296AD9D5">
        <enum>(14)</enum>
        <text>On August 16, 2012, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1101">President</cato:entity-ref> signed into law the <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Ambassador James R. Lilley and Congressman Stephen J. Solarz North Korea Human Rights Reauthorization Act of 2012">Ambassador James R. Lilley and Congressman Stephen J. Solarz North Korea Human Rights Reauthorization Act of 2012</cato:entity-ref> (<cato:entity-ref entity-type="public-law" value="public-law/112/172">Public Law 112–172</cato:entity-ref>)</cato:entity>.</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA6725C2426F54F50A4F667064C4D4606">
        <enum>(15)</enum>
        <text>
          <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> further authoritatively expressed its view in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="public-law" value="public-law/112/172/s:2">section 2 of Public Law 112–172</cato:entity-ref> that <quote>although the transition to the leadership of Kim Jong-Un after the death of Kim Jong-Il has introduced new uncertainties and possibilities, the fundamental human rights and humanitarian conditions inside North Korea remain deplorable, North Korean refugees remain acutely vulnerable, and the findings in the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="North Korean Human Rights Act of 2004">2004 Act</cato:entity-ref> and <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="North Korean Human Rights Reauthorization Act of 2008">2008 Reauthorization</cato:entity-ref> remain substantially accurate today.</quote>.</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBBB2AAAC5113420EA326CA5AD3AD0715">
        <enum>(16)</enum>
        <text>Notwithstanding the succession of Kim Jong-Un as supreme leader of North Korea following the death of his father in December 2011, Pyongyang has continued a policy of horrendous human rights violations, including the issuance of new <quote>shoot to kill</quote> orders for refugees attempting to cross the border into China and an increased reliance on public executions to intimidate the North Korean populace.</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBCA6A162FD794D7A812758976664B69C">
        <enum>(17)</enum>
        <text>The new Kim Jong-Un regime also displayed duplicity in its negotiations with the United States and other Six-Party partners by launching a missile in April 2012 in direct violation of its <quote>Leap Day Agreement</quote> to carry out a moratorium on nuclear and long-range missile tests.</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA2A06B027ACA4C3B8883B4A22D3E1F0C">
        <enum>(18)</enum>
        <text>Pyongyang defied the international community and relevant United Nations Security Council resolutions by launching a long-range missile on December 12, 2012, resulting in the unanimous passage of United Nations Security Council Resolution 2087 on January 22, 2013.</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H015C181669284BF0AC797A649AEA4905">
        <enum>(19)</enum>
        <text>The regime in Pyongyang further defied the international community and relevant United Nations Security Council resolutions by conducting a nuclear test on February 12, 2013.</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H506A79F6625F4E9C996DDB1361AC44F5">
        <enum>(20)</enum>
        <text>According to the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1434">United States Geological Survey</cato:entity-ref>, seismic activity was detected in North Korea with an earthquake measuring 4.9 magnitude, larger than the 2006 and 2009 explosions, and the epicenter of the quake was close to a North Korean nuclear test site.</text>
      </paragraph>
    </section> 
<section id="HF8DDF04D3DFC47CBAC83070366B21564">
      <enum>3.</enum>
      <header>Continuation of restrictions against the Government of North Korea</header> 
<subsection id="HB100E832C0F1447FAAA7215D75487860">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Finding</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">
          <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> finds that subsequent to the decision of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref> on October 11, 2008, to rescind the designation of North Korea as a state sponsor of terrorism, North Korea has committed acts that can be defined as international terrorism or as highly provocative, including—</text> 
<paragraph id="HD28E7333F53947BFB6F4676C2BB06692">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>the dispatch of a covert team of two North Korean military-trained agents to South Korea with orders to assassinate the late North Korean defector Hwang Jang-yop who were apprehended by South Korean officials in April 2010;</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H87E6D2B6E8384095B164DDD2D0DFFB63">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>complicity in the sinking of the South Korean naval vessel Cheonan on March 26, 2010, which resulted in the deaths of 46 South Korean naval personnel;</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDCF3CA3183824A22B9680EEA70729B85">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the shipment of weapons by North Korea, seized in Bangkok in December 2009, which were bound for delivery to foreign terrorist organizations Hezbollah and Hamas, according to a statement made by Israeli Foreign Minister Avigdor Lieberman in Tokyo on May 12, 2010;</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD4582F56C67044E2BDA07F25C0090F6B">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
          <text>the sudden and unprovoked bombardment by North Korean artillery of the civilian-populated South Korean island of Yeonpyeong-do on November 23, 2010, which resulted in the deaths of two South Korean civilians and two Republic of Korea (ROK) marines; and</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H52B13A2876E045BB87B84CC755AC5A5A">
          <enum>(5)</enum>
          <text>the sentencing by Seoul Central District Court in January 2011 of North Korean agent Ri Dong Sam to 10 years in prison for impersonating a refugee in August 2010 to enter South Korea under orders to assassinate leading North Korean defector Hwang Jang-yop.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection> 
<subsection commented="no" id="HE1F984FC2D784A449604E8A7F78D371C">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Continuation of restrictions</header>
        <text>Notwithstanding the decision by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref> on October 11, 2008, to rescind the designation of North Korea as a state sponsor of terrorism, and in light of the congressional finding described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="North Korea Sanctions and Diplomatic Nonrecognition Act of 2013/s:3/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref>, restrictions against the Government of North Korea that were imposed by reason of a determination of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref> that the Government of North Korea is a state sponsor of terrorism, as well as sanctions against the Government of North Korea (including sanctions that ban the importation into the United States of North Korean products and goods), that are in effect as of the date of the enactment of this Act shall remain in effect, and shall not be lifted, unless the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1101">President</cato:entity-ref> makes the certification described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="North Korea Sanctions and Diplomatic Nonrecognition Act of 2013/s:3/ss:c" proposed="true">subsection (c)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="HA4343E1E7B514ABF9602782083BAADA9">
        <enum>(c)</enum>
        <header>Certification</header>
        <text>The certification referred to in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="North Korea Sanctions and Diplomatic Nonrecognition Act of 2013/s:3/ss:b" proposed="true">subsection (b)</cato:entity-ref> is a certification to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> containing a determination of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> that the Government of North Korea—</text> 
<paragraph id="HCC9C88DC25FA4B5FB34F711C594313DD">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is no longer engaged in the illegal transfer of missile or nuclear technology, particularly to the governments of Iran, Syria, or any other state sponsor of terrorism, or to Burma;</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H14FA8441B8254B7AA90C9AC1F1AA3DE6">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is no longer engaged in training in combat operations or tunneling, or harboring, supplying, financing, or supporting in any way—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HC556E619441C4612A8BD78FDE0D4DFBC">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Hamas, Hezbollah, the Japanese Red Army, or any member of such organizations;</text>
          </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H1F5D3CD1AB1742008F11100FCCB7E6CA">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any organization designated by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref> as a foreign terrorist organization in accordance with <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Immigration and Nationality Act/s:219/ss:a">section 219(a) of the Immigration and Nationality Act</cato:entity-ref> (<cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/8/1189/a">8 U.S.C. 1189(a)</cato:entity-ref>)</cato:entity>; and</text>
          </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5EE73BD689E446A194F3517991B60338">
            <enum>(C)</enum>
            <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any person included on the annex to Executive Order 13224 (September 21, 2001) and any other person identified under section 1 of that Executive Order whose property and interests are blocked by that section (commonly known as a <quote>specially designated global terrorist</quote>);</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCEC4F3F8C4A2448FB1EB9DA4B2A26021">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is no longer engaged in the counterfeiting of United States currency <quote>supernotes</quote>;</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD240A96B1FC445018C29A2E16F9B87BC">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
          <text>is no longer engaged in the international trafficking of illicit narcotics into the United States, Japan, Australia, or other allied countries of the United States;</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD6A3361C406F42A79D7891A48C708931">
          <enum>(5)</enum>
          <text>has returned the last remains of United States permanent resident, Reverend Kim Dong-shik, to his United States citizen widow, family, and church members, so that he may be provided with a proper Christian burial in Chicago;</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H03D92EB573E748C2BA8AC2266E0642BE">
          <enum>(6)</enum>
          <text>has released the Japanese nationals recognized as abduction victims by the Government of Japan as well as abduction victims recognized by the Government of the Republic of Korea;</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5DC427FD71604681862A94A4FC167CEE">
          <enum>(7)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has released an estimated 600 surviving South Korean POWs, and any other surviving POWs from the Korean War, who have been held in North Korea against their will and in violation of the Armistice Agreement since hostilities ended in July 1953;</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HADCE907782F94581A1663971D999E4F5">
          <enum>(8)</enum>
          <text>has made concrete provisions for unrestricted family reunification meetings for those individuals among the two-million strong Korean-American community who maintain family ties with relatives inside North Korea;</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H164CAAE6BD564F42B1B85DBFE3E72663">
          <enum>(9)</enum>
          <text>has opened the North Korean penal system, including the gulag of concentration camps holding an estimated 200,000 political and religious prisoners, to unrestricted and regular visits by representatives of the International Committee of the Red Cross (ICRC);</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H64B9C37BD8B3482CA52B6385D3E65B34">
          <enum>(10)</enum>
          <text>has made provision for unrestricted and regular access by representatives of the United National High Commissioner for Refugees to refugees forcibly repatriated to North Korea to determine their general health and welfare;</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H402BFC1AA8E94828841A94BFC02951C0">
          <enum>(11)</enum>
          <text>has made concrete provisions for unrestricted contact, including direct communications and meetings, between representatives of international and South Korean religious organizations, including Christians and Buddhists, and their co-believers inside North Korea; and</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H18397DDDF4794D8F824AABEB40B07E3D">
          <enum>(12)</enum>
          <text>has offered apologies to the government and people of the Republic of Korea for the deaths that North Korea inflicted due to the unprovoked attacks on the South Korean naval vessel Cheonan on March 26, 2010, and on the island of Yeonpyeong-do on November 23, 2010.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="H55A70849397842F3BBAA048F544095F4">
        <enum>(d)</enum>
        <header>Sense of Congress</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It is the sense of <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> that, in light of the congressional finding described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="North Korea Sanctions and Diplomatic Nonrecognition Act of 2013/s:3/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref> should redesignate North Korea as a state sponsor of terrorism immediately upon the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
      </subsection> 
<subsection commented="no" id="HBA3DD959FCF64FBBA66D06A893D417BA">
        <enum>(e)</enum>
        <header>State sponsor of terrorism defined</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <term>state sponsor of terrorism</term> means any country the government of which the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref> determines has repeatedly provided support for acts of international terrorism pursuant to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Export Administration Act of 1979/s:6/ss:j">section 6(j) of the Export Administration Act of 1979</cato:entity-ref> (as continued in effect pursuant to the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="International Emergency Economic Powers Act">International Emergency Economic Powers Act</cato:entity-ref>), <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Arms Export Control Act/s:40">section 40 of the Arms Export Control Act</cato:entity-ref>, <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Foreign Assistance Act of 1961/s:620A">section 620A of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961</cato:entity-ref>, or any other provision of law.</text>
      </subsection>
    </section> 
<section id="H4E042430D2B0485991FE1F9D69D97CB2">
      <enum>4.</enum>
      <header>Continuation of diplomatic nonrecognition of North Korea</header> 
<subsection id="HC2E64B61BD82496CBD05BB08E1BE8E42">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Finding</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">
          <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> finds that the United States did not grant diplomatic recognition to North Korea upon its establishment as a client regime of the former Soviet Union in 1948. The United States has consistently continued to withhold such formal diplomatic recognition during the 61 years since the sudden and unprovoked attack by North Korean forces on the Republic of Korea on June 25, 1950, an attack which led directly to the Korean War and the deaths of over 36,000 United States military personnel as well as at least 2,000,000 Koreans and over 3,000 soldiers from Allied countries.</text>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="H3F3B2A142A734B9B9449FAF0F8766EBB">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Continuation of diplomatic nonrecognition</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No funds may be expended for the establishment of a United States diplomatic presence in North Korea, including an Embassy, Consulate, or liaison office, until such time as the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> certifies to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> that the Government of North Korea has met all of the benchmarks specified in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="North Korea Sanctions and Diplomatic Nonrecognition Act of 2013/s:3" proposed="true">section 3</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
      </subsection>
    </section> 
<section id="H21DCB3B13A114C5DB0F5181AB2EC441C">
      <enum>5.</enum>
      <header>International response to a North Korean missile launch or nuclear test</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Given North Korea’s third nuclear weapons test on February 12, 2013, in violation of United Nations Security Council Resolutions 1695, 1718, 1874, and 2087, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> shall instruct the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1958">United States Permanent Representative to the United Nations</cato:entity-ref> to use the voice, vote, and influence of the United States to secure adoption of a United Nations Security Council resolution condemning North Korea’s action as a violation of United Nations Security Council Resolutions 1695, 1718, 1874, and 2087 and requiring the implementation of comprehensive sanctions and an inspection regime against North Korea.</text>
    </section> 
</legis-body> 
</bill>
</doc>