<doc>
  <docmeta id="113hres584ih">
    <bill congress="113" type="hres" number="584" version="ih"/>
    <revision size="4360" annotations="0" status="complete" id="4" commit-time="2014-07-31T18:40:41Z" committer="zwilliams" doc="113hres584ih/4.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <resolution xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" dms-id="H43125FEC97B04CD28430BB28317FF2B8" key="H" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print">
	<metadata>
<dublinCore>
<dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">113 HRES 584 IH: Expressing support for the designation of May 11, 2014, through May 17, 2014, as Food Allergy Awareness Week.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">2014-05-13</dc:date>
<dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">113th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session display="yes">2d Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. RES. 584</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20140513">May 13, 2014</action-date>
			<action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="I000057">Mr. Israel</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="M001157">Mr. McCaul</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="R000577">Mr. Ryan of Ohio</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>
      </action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">Expressing support for the designation of May 11, 2014, through May 17, 2014, as Food Allergy
			 Awareness Week.</official-title>
	</form>
	<preamble>
		<whereas>
      <text>Whereas as many as 15,000,000 people in the United States, including nearly 6,000,000 children
			 under the age of 18, have food allergies, which are potentially
			 life-threatening;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas data from the <cato:entity-ref entity-id="7523" entity-type="federal-body">Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC)</cato:entity-ref> shows a 50-percent increase
			 in the prevalence of food allergies in children under age 18 from 1997 to
			 2011;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas there is no cure for food allergy and limited understanding of the underlying reasons for
			 the increase in prevalence of food allergies among children;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas 8 foods, shellfish, fish, milk, eggs, tree nuts, peanuts, soy, and wheat, cause 90 percent
			 of all food allergy reactions in the United States;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas strict avoidance of offending foods is the only way to prevent an allergic reaction;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas reactions typically occur when an individual unknowingly eats a food containing an
			 ingredient to which they are allergic;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the symptoms of a food-allergic reaction can include hives, vomiting, respiratory distress,
			 swelling of the throat, anaphylaxis, and death;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas anaphylaxis is a serious allergic reaction that is rapid in onset and may cause death;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas according to the <cato:entity-ref entity-id="7523" entity-type="federal-body">CDC</cato:entity-ref>, food allergy results in more than 300,000 ambulatory care visits a
			 year involving children under age 18;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas those with food allergies and parents of children with food allergies develop plans for
			 food allergy management that include prompt access to epinephrine;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas Food Allergy Research &amp; Education (FARE), a national, nonprofit organization dedicated to finding a cure for food
			 allergies, and to keep individuals with food allergies safe and included,
			 recognizes and supports Food Allergy Awareness Week during May of every
			 calendar year;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas outreach and education to the public may improve the response to an allergic reaction;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas public awareness of food allergies may also enhance the commitment to research to
			 understand the causes for food allergies and interventions for allergic
			 reaction; and</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas this year Food Allergy Awareness Week is recognized during the week of May 11, 2014,
			 through May 17, 2014: Now, therefore, be it</text>
    </whereas>
  </preamble>
	<resolution-body id="H0C5DD52884C24E17A9845F9E0EAAB95E" style="traditional">
		<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HBF1B091A809045C28F1B4A006C135B3B" section-type="undesignated-section">
      <enum/>
      <text>That the <cato:entity-ref entity-id="0050" entity-type="federal-body">House of Representatives</cato:entity-ref>—</text>
			<paragraph id="H5EB5BABDF7D2444498F9ADC9CA716F66">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">supports the designation of Food Allergy Awareness Week;</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H91B0E83FA1CF4412886F1CE6A0B6680A">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text>encourages the President to issue a proclamation in support of the goals and ideals of Food Allergy
			 Awareness Week;</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H8E064D4DBE92442E97BEA66A69520C32">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <text>encourages States, territories, possessions of the United States, and localities to support the
			 goals and ideals of Food Allergy Awareness Week;</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H6D0477CA1C524D37A02AAEC600099903">
        <enum>(4)</enum>
        <text>encourages media organizations to participate in Food Allergy Awareness Week and help educate the
			 public about food allergies;</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H4F01D5B45348439D8A6467ED0EB61635">
        <enum>(5)</enum>
        <text>recognizes and reaffirms the Nation’s commitment to research the causes of food allergies,
			 interventions for allergic reactions, and the best way to prevent
			 individuals from having reactions; and</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H0A67BB4222094837B46E474DEE4B0C3A">
        <enum>(6)</enum>
        <text>recognizes all people in the United States living with food allergies, expresses gratitude to their
			 family members and friends who are a source of love and protection to
			 them, and salutes the health care professionals, teachers, and other
			 caregivers and medical researchers who provide assistance to those so
			 affected.</text>
			</paragraph>
    </section>
  </resolution-body>
</resolution>
</doc>