<doc>
  <docmeta id="113hr3179ih">
    <bill congress="113" type="hr" number="3179" version="ih"/>
    <revision size="5267" annotations="0" status="complete" id="6" commit-time="2013-10-03T20:10:58Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113hr3179ih/6.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H3C498A601C7347F9846959EA15849EE0" public-private="public">
  <metadata>
<dublinCore>
<title>113 HR 3179 IH: To amend the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 to provide a specific limited exemption from the overtime pay requirements of such Act for work related to disaster or catastrophe claims adjustment after a major disaster.</title>
<publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</publisher>
<date>2013-09-25</date>
<format>text/xml</format>
<language>EN</language>
<rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
    <congress>113th CONGRESS</congress>
    <session>1st Session</session>
    <legis-num>H. R. 3179</legis-num>
    <current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
    <action>
      <action-date date="20130925">September 25, 2013</action-date>
      <action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="H001067">Mr. Hudson</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="H000324">Mr. Hastings of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000604">Mr. Payne</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000508">Mr. McKeon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000485">Mr. McIntyre</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000013">Mr. Bachus</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000573">Mr. Garcia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000808">Ms. Wilson of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000292">Mr. Enyart</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000795">Mr. Wilson of South Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001048">Mr. Hunter</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000583">Mr. Rooney</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000797">Ms. Wasserman Schultz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000018">Mr. Salmon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000210">Mr. Andrews</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001242">Mr. Bishop of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001053">Mr. Cole</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="R000588">Mr. Richmond</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and the Workforce</committee-name>
      </action-desc>
    </action>
    <legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
    <official-title>To amend the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 to provide a specific limited exemption from the overtime pay requirements of such Act for work related to disaster or catastrophe claims adjustment after a major disaster.</official-title>
  </form>
  <legis-body id="H157897A675034232A6D72DD3B5046D8D" style="OLC">
    <section id="HB6974197246647EFB9B7FBCD6C85FAF6" section-type="section-one">
      <enum>1.</enum>
      <header>Limited exemption for disaster or catastrophe claims adjusters</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">
        <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
          <cato:entity-ref value="Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938/s:7" entity-type="act">Section 7 of the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/207">
            <cato:entity-ref value="usc/29/207" entity-type="uscode">29 U.S.C. 207</cato:entity-ref>
          </external-xref>)</cato:entity> is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
      <quoted-block id="H74FA8CAB06764C7C83ACE1A920CD98F7" style="OLC">
        <subsection id="H507889B30E814311AB83169EDE824F34">
          <enum>(s)</enum>
          <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H5985052AFF084DC9BBE5E2D2D28AFE3D">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <text>The provisions of this section shall not apply for a period of 2 years after the occurrence of a major disaster to any employee—</text>
            <subparagraph id="H0519FF77FFCB4070BB38DCDABEE331A6" indent="up1">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>employed to adjust or evaluate claims resulting from or relating to such major disaster, by an employer not engaged, directly or through an affiliate, in underwriting, selling, or marketing property, casualty, or liability insurance policies or contracts;</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="HE694572F646F4C33B39A3D8BCDDD5026" indent="up1">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>who receives from such employer on average weekly compensation of not less than $591.00 per week or any minimum weekly amount established by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1600" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary</cato:entity-ref>, whichever is greater, for the number of weeks such employee is engaged in any of the activities described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" proposed="true" value="Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938/s:7/ss:s/p:1/sp:C" entity-type="act">subparagraph (C)</cato:entity-ref>; and</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="HFACA63F8B9A746B99B724291ADE7DBE9" indent="up1">
              <enum>(C)</enum>
              <text>whose duties include any of the following:</text>
              <clause id="H55117DA4A59A4CA69A9FFA06AB4AE2D8">
                <enum>(i)</enum>
                <text>interviewing insured individuals, individuals who suffered injuries or other damages or losses arising from or relating to a disaster, witnesses, or physicians;</text>
              </clause>
              <clause id="HD7F757F3B2C7446B940005C741F03A44">
                <enum>(ii)</enum>
                <text>inspecting property damage or reviewing factual information to prepare damage estimates;</text>
              </clause>
              <clause id="H60101187883A4727BEB0FE09458A4540">
                <enum>(iii)</enum>
                <text>evaluating and making recommendations regarding coverage or compensability of claims or determining liability or value aspects of claims;</text>
              </clause>
              <clause id="HD47011CE9E084C8D95DACFF9D2E3B4AA">
                <enum>(iv)</enum>
                <text>negotiating settlements; or</text>
              </clause>
              <clause id="HEC24F585C92D44248FA97FB8946198A6">
                <enum>(v)</enum>
                <text>making recommendations regarding litigation.</text>
              </clause>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H21FFA01A87D742A4B92CEAC0F963A2C2" indent="up1">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <text>Notwithstanding any other provision of <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" value="Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938/s:18" entity-type="act">section 18</cato:entity-ref>, in the event of a major disaster, this Act exclusively shall govern all such employers in lieu of any State or other Federal law or regulation or local law or regulation, with respect to the employees described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" proposed="true" value="Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938/s:7/ss:s/p:1" entity-type="act">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H7F6A5458387149E2A2AE04E57D01F011" indent="up1">
            <enum>(3)</enum>
            <text>The exemption in this subsection shall not affect the exemption provided by <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" value="Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938/s:13/ss:a/p:1" entity-type="act">section 13(a)(1)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H5E531C57A2E74BD380ECE8145F02685A" indent="up1">
            <enum>(4)</enum>
            <text>For purposes of this subsection—</text>
            <subparagraph id="H95CD07A918BE4BDFAEE5FBA0A84D70F4">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>the term <term>major disaster</term> means any natural catastrophe, including any hurricane, tornado, storm, high water, wind driven water, tidal wave, tsunami, earthquake, volcanic eruption, landslide, mudslide, snowstorm, or drought, or, regardless of cause, any other catastrophe, including fire, flood, explosion, land collapse, avalanche, or pollutant or chemical release;</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H921E6F4B49D840D78144C0E7CE930DC1">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>the term <term>employee employed to adjust or evaluate claims resulting from or relating to such major disaster</term> means an individual who timely secured or secures a license required by applicable law to engage in and perform the activities described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" proposed="true" value="Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938/s:7/ss:s/p:1/sp:C/cl:i..v" entity-type="act">clauses (i) through (v) of paragraph (1)(C)</cato:entity-ref> relating to a major disaster, and is employed by an employer that maintains worker compensation insurance coverage or protection for its employees, if required by applicable law, and withholds applicable Federal, State, and local income and payroll taxes from the wages, salaries and any benefits of such employees; and</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="HD440CB86A656454691E464DDA58AEBE8">
              <enum>(C)</enum>
              <text>the term <term>affiliate</term> means a company that, by reason of ownership or control of twenty-five percent (25%) or more of the outstanding shares of any class of voting securities of one or more companies, directly or indirectly, controls, is controlled by, or is under common control with, another company.</text>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
      </quoted-block>
    </section>
  </legis-body>
</bill>
</doc>