<doc>
  <docmeta id="113hconres60ih">
    <bill congress="113" type="hconres" number="60" version="ih"/>
    <revision size="3941" annotations="0" status="complete" id="3" commit-time="2013-10-17T22:33:03Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113hconres60ih/3.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <resolution xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" dms-id="HA58D34FD1CCC40B0AFA42933F4DC3A89" key="H" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" resolution-type="house-concurrent" star-print="no-star-print">
  <metadata>
<dublinCore>
<title>113 HCON 60 IH: Expressing the sense of Congress that financial institutions should work proactively with their customers affected by the shutdown of the Federal Government who may be facing short-term financial hardship and long-term damage to their creditworthiness through no fault of their own.</title>
<publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</publisher>
<date>2013-10-11</date>
<format>text/xml</format>
<language>EN</language>
<rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code>
    <congress display="yes">113th CONGRESS</congress>
    <session display="yes">1st Session</session>
    <legis-num>H. CON. RES. 60</legis-num>
    <current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
    <action display="yes">
      <action-date date="20131011">October 11, 2013</action-date>
      <action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="W000187">Ms. Waters</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="H000874">Mr. Hoyer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000128">Mr. Van Hollen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000933">Mr. Moran</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000290">Ms. Edwards</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001078">Mr. Connolly</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000087">Mrs. Carolyn B. Maloney of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000207">Mr. Watt</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000344">Mr. Sherman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001137">Mr. Meeks</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001037">Mr. Capuano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H000636">Mr. Hinojosa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001049">Mr. Clay</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000562">Mr. Lynch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001157">Mr. David Scott of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000553">Mr. Al Green of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001061">Mr. Cleaver</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001160">Ms. Moore</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000288">Mr. Ellison</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000593">Mr. Perlmutter</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001047">Mr. Himes</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001083">Mr. Carney</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001185">Ms. Sewell of Alabama</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000454">Mr. Foster</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000380">Mr. Kildee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001191">Mr. Murphy of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000620">Mr. Delaney</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001281">Mrs. Beatty</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="H001064">Mr. Heck of Washington</cosponsor>) submitted the following concurrent resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
    </action>
    <legis-type>CONCURRENT RESOLUTION</legis-type>
    <official-title display="yes">Expressing the sense of Congress that financial institutions should work proactively with their customers affected by the shutdown of the Federal Government who may be facing short-term financial hardship and long-term damage to their creditworthiness through no fault of their own.</official-title>
  </form>
  <resolution-body id="H4D8A3837221A4822A04C3B6AFDA88BF3" style="traditional">
    <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H53DFD3B002D043308BDB1EBA31C3F77B" section-type="undesignated-section">
      <enum/>
      <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That it is the sense of <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> that—</text>
      <paragraph id="HD587D40A41E84AAB951A2DE668D88490">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">financial institutions should work with their customers affected by the shutdown of the Federal Government that began on October 1, 2013;</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HCB2A5341B56848D0ADDD9AA8D91291E2">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text>individuals affected by the shutdown who are or will be facing financial distress should contact their lenders to alert them of their situation immediately;</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HC25A77E76FC34092B342006CABD451E1">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <text>affected customers may face financial hardship in making timely payments on their debts, such as mortgages, student loans, car loans, credit cards, and other debt due to the temporary delay or permanent loss of their salaries;</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H9A817BB92DC3497193FEC1D3D49A25C5">
        <enum>(4)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">financial institutions should consider temporarily waiving or reducing penalty, late payment, and similar fees in order to provide quick relief to their affected customers;</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H13DE8853F13746F09ADB498FCB70BD5A">
        <enum>(5)</enum>
        <text>affected employees of the Federal Government may be experiencing financial stress through no fault of their own and their creditworthiness should not be impaired because of the shutdown;</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HF8C4BD1A531040988A7CD175DA40EDF6">
        <enum>(6)</enum>
        <text>prudent workout arrangements that are consistent with safe and sound lending practices are generally in the long-term best interest of the financial institution, the borrower, and the economy;</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H3C7BEA16BD8D4D3F8A25B109DF699E96">
        <enum>(7)</enum>
        <text>financial institutions should work pro­ac­tive­ly to identify their customers who have been affected and adopt flexible, prudent arrangements to help such customers meet their debt obligations;</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H9BD3E6A2D6CE4373B5577F1E33163036">
        <enum>(8)</enum>
        <text>prudent efforts to adopt flexible workout arrangements for affected employees and their families should not be subject to examiner criticism or negative examinations; and</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H85F5B9C854AC4FF69F2AD7C9D1B9C510">
        <enum>(9)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">employees furloughed due to the shutdown of the Federal Government should be compensated at their standard rate of compensation for the period beginning October 1, 2013, through the date on which the lapse in appropriations ends, consistent with the principle adopted by the House when it passed the bill, <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="113 HR 3223" proposed="true">H.R. 3223</cato:entity-ref> on October 5, 2013, by a vote of 407–0.</text>
      </paragraph>
    </section>
  </resolution-body>
</resolution>
</doc>