<doc>
  <docmeta id="113hr5233ih">
    <bill congress="113" type="hr" number="5233" version="ih"/>
    <revision size="15711" annotations="0" status="complete" id="4" commit-time="2014-08-12T20:18:47Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113hr5233ih/4.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HC5494EC8520F40AB83380460FF21CCB5" public-private="public">
	<metadata>
<dublinCore>
<dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">113 HR 5233 IH: Trade Secrets Protection Act of 2014</dc:title>
<dc:publisher xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">2014-07-29</dc:date>
<dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>113th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>2d Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 5233</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20140729">July 29, 2014</action-date>
			<action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="H001065">Mr. Holding</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="N000002">Mr. Nadler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C000556">Mr. Coble</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C000714">Mr. Conyers</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C000266">Mr. Chabot</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000294">Mr. Jeffries</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000588">Mr. Richmond</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="D000617">Ms. DelBene</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>
      </action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To amend <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/90">chapter 90</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code, to provide Federal jurisdiction for the theft
			 of trade secrets, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="HD45DAE0B99594A1F8C1F6DEC3398A1C0" style="OLC">
		<section id="H4F5BD4A399C24F889B7D16328203E730" section-type="section-one">
      <enum>1.</enum>
      <header>Short title</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote>
          <short-title>
            <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Trade Secrets Protection Act of 2014" proposed="true">Trade Secrets Protection Act of 2014</cato:entity-ref>
          </short-title>
        </quote>.</text>
		</section>
    <section id="H54FC7EAE964E4CE2BF07AB87E538BA7A">
      <enum>2.</enum>
      <header>Federal jurisdiction for theft of trade secrets</header>
			<subsection id="H01C10D80C0F54FDA918BF6804AE26829">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>In general</header>
        <text>
          <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc/18/1836">
            <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/18/1836">Section 1836</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code</cato:entity-ref>, is amended by striking subsection (b) and inserting
			 the following:</text>
				<quoted-block id="HF8E238E273BC43409A361CD11A51EA4C" style="OLC">
					<subsection id="H763CCDCDC4514926B6E333180D731B1F">
            <enum>(b)</enum>
            <header>Private civil actions</header>
						<paragraph id="HF1BAF84825E1419C8BD8AE9BA79B1B58">
              <enum>(1)</enum>
              <header>In general</header>
              <text>An owner of a trade secret may bring a civil action under this subsection if the person is
			 aggrieved by a misappropriation of a trade secret that is related to a
			 product or service used in, or intended for use in, interstate or foreign
			 commerce.</text>
						</paragraph>
            <paragraph id="HBA9B4D04DB5B42CC8D0A388517A813E8">
              <enum>(2)</enum>
              <header>Civil seizure</header>
							<subparagraph id="HD256CE28CD09453BBE9EB2284F41489C">
                <enum>(A)</enum>
                <header>In general</header>
								<clause id="HE392E6C127BA4725BE3381B4893DCAE6">
                  <enum>(i)</enum>
                  <header>Application</header>
                  <text>Based on an affidavit or verified complaint satisfying the requirements of this paragraph, the
			 court may, upon ex parte application, issue an order providing for the
			 seizure of property necessary to preserve evidence in a civil action
			 brought under paragraph (1) or to prevent the propagation or dissemination
			 of the trade secret that is the subject of the action.</text>
								</clause>
                <clause id="H2C1202E544D946DCA6C85CFC0371BE46">
                  <enum>(ii)</enum>
                  <header>Requirements for issuing order</header>
                  <text>The court may not grant an application under clause (i) unless the court finds that it clearly
			 appears from specific facts that—</text>
									<subclause id="H65D29C45E51E45BFAF0A93410FDC6854">
                    <enum>(I)</enum>
                    <text>an order issued pursuant to Rule 65(b) of the Federal Rules of Civil Procedure would be inadequate
			 to achieve the purpose of this paragraph because the party to which the
			 order would be issued would evade, avoid, or otherwise not comply with
			 such an order;</text>
									</subclause>
                  <subclause id="HD8CD68C251894CB6889BC007B8DE0D3C">
                    <enum>(II)</enum>
                    <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an immediate and irreparable injury will occur if such seizure is not ordered;</text>
									</subclause>
                  <subclause id="H3E73349EF470415C883D836EB344D736">
                    <enum>(III)</enum>
                    <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the harm to the applicant of denying the application outweighs the harm to the legitimate interests
			 of the person against whom seizure would be ordered of granting the
			 application and substantially outweighs the harm to any third parties who
			 may be harmed by such seizure;</text>
									</subclause>
                  <subclause id="H3DA4E504A5954F49AA278CD37BF4D0E5">
                    <enum>(IV)</enum>
                    <text>the applicant is likely to succeed in showing that the person against whom seizure would be ordered
			 misappropriated the trade secret and is in possession of the trade secret;</text>
									</subclause>
                  <subclause id="H5298A756D991427D924ACB2D5DD6831D">
                    <enum>(V)</enum>
                    <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the application describes with reasonable particularity the matter to be seized and, to the extent
			 reasonable under the circumstances, identifies the location where the
			 matter is to be seized;</text>
									</subclause>
                  <subclause id="H9B6873BEFAA141479681E659BD52B1EA">
                    <enum>(VI)</enum>
                    <text>the person against whom seizure would be ordered, or persons acting in concert with such person,
			 would destroy, move, hide, or otherwise make such matter inaccessible to
			 the court, if the applicant were to proceed on notice to such person; and</text>
									</subclause>
                  <subclause id="H1712298E33E64B2293BA54E475B47EB4">
                    <enum>(VII)</enum>
                    <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the applicant has not publicized the requested seizure.</text>
									</subclause>
                </clause>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="H8E26BCBC47C248E3A844832D678EB4F5">
                <enum>(B)</enum>
                <header>Elements of order</header>
                <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If an order is issued under subparagraph (A), it shall—</text>
								<clause id="H5DB389A0972649BAB37781CE0C15153E">
                  <enum>(i)</enum>
                  <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">set forth findings of fact and conclusions of law required for the order;</text>
								</clause>
                <clause id="H455F2C18ED37435196B25F63B3B8C8FF">
                  <enum>(ii)</enum>
                  <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide for the seizure of any property in a manner that minimizes any interruption of the business
			 operations of third parties and, to the extent possible, does not
			 interrupt those legitimate business operations of the person accused of
			 misappropriating the trade secret that are unrelated to the trade secret
			 that has allegedly been misappropriated;</text>
								</clause>
                <clause id="HE18BEC470D0B4A5B9151A54DB4F65492">
                  <enum>(iii)</enum>
                  <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">be accompanied by an order protecting the property from disclosure by restricting the access of the
			 applicant, including during the seizure, and prohibiting any copies, in
			 whole or in part, of the seized property, to prevent undue damage to the
			 party against whom the order has issued or others, until such parties have
			 an opportunity to be heard in court;</text>
								</clause>
                <clause id="H00C59BBAF6514B13A6F0C7923FAD645C">
                  <enum>(iv)</enum>
                  <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">set a date for a hearing at the earliest possible time, and not later than 7 days after the order
			 has issued, unless the party against whom the order is directed and others
			 harmed by the order consent to another date for such hearing, except that
			 a party against whom the order has issued or any person harmed by the
			 order may move the court at any time to dissolve or modify the order after
			 giving notice to the applicant who obtained the order; and</text>
								</clause>
                <clause id="H5CBCB906D6164715B45BA816B30B65F5">
                  <enum>(v)</enum>
                  <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">require the person obtaining the order to provide the security determined adequate by the court for
			 the payment of such damages as any person may be entitled to recover as a
			 result of a wrongful or excessive seizure or wrongful or excessive
			 attempted seizure under this paragraph.</text>
								</clause>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="HB4639D4882BE462DA7F9D6F0AAA5CB3E">
                <enum>(C)</enum>
                <header>Protection from publicity</header>
                <text>The court shall take appropriate action to protect the person against whom an order under this
			 paragraph is directed from publicity, by or at the behest of the person
			 obtaining the order, about such order and any seizure under such order.</text>
							</subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="HEFEB52AD720243639312D56A62365F91">
                <enum>(D)</enum>
                <header>Materials in custody of court</header>
                <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any materials seized under this paragraph shall be taken into the custody of the court. The court
			 shall secure the seized material from physical and electronic access
			 during the seizure and while in the custody of the court.</text>
							</subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="H19E998A3DB434CE18705557DB90BF91D">
                <enum>(E)</enum>
                <header>Service of order</header>
                <text>The court shall order that service of a copy of the order under this paragraph shall be made by a
			 Federal law enforcement officer, or may be made by a State or local law
			 enforcement officer, who, upon making service, shall carry out the seizure
			 under the order.</text>
							</subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="H285A98073AEA452AA33E97437B17CBDE">
                <enum>(F)</enum>
                <header>Action for damage caused by wrongful seizure</header>
                <text>A person who suffers damage by reason of a wrongful or excessive seizure under this paragraph has a
			 cause of action against the applicant for the order under which such
			 seizure was made, and shall be entitled to the same relief as is provided
			 under <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
                    <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Trademark Act of 1946/s:34/ss:d/p:11">section 34(d)(11) of the Trademark Act of 1946</cato:entity-ref> (<cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/15/1116/d/11">15 U.S.C.
			 1116(d)(11)</cato:entity-ref>)</cato:entity>. The security posted with the court under subparagraph (B)(v)
			 shall not limit the recovery of third parties for damages.</text>
							</subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="HC6D376E0A6AD4312A604E03FFD09E446">
              <enum>(3)</enum>
              <header>Remedies</header>
              <text>In a civil action brought under this subsection with respect to the misappropriation of a trade
			 secret, a court may—</text>
							<subparagraph id="H961842D3DA154916BC5F748083E38488">
                <enum>(A)</enum>
                <text>grant an injunction—</text>
								<clause id="H1A4AFB29D3EB4ACCA45CADF1356A10D0">
                  <enum>(i)</enum>
                  <text>to prevent any actual or threatened misappropriation described in paragraph (1) on such terms as
			 the court deems reasonable;</text>
								</clause>
                <clause id="H04091FB942B84AABB66CD303B26D9939">
                  <enum>(ii)</enum>
                  <text>if determined appropriate by the court, requiring affirmative actions to be taken to protect the
			 trade secret; and</text>
								</clause>
                <clause id="H411F0E4BBFAB446FA5548578BDE2E334">
                  <enum>(iii)</enum>
                  <text>in exceptional circumstances that render an injunction inequitable, that conditions future use of
			 the trade secret upon payment of a reasonable royalty for no longer than
			 the period of time for which such use could have been prohibited;</text>
								</clause>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="HE072FFE721F84119AA66BB318259A329">
                <enum>(B)</enum>
                <text>award—</text>
								<clause id="HF6749475E4A948F5AC4E9CBFE2C1641F">
                  <enum>(i)</enum>
									<subclause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HC609E6D1D5174C44B266ABAD4159D1AC">
                    <enum>(I)</enum>
                    <text>damages for actual loss caused by the misappropriation of the trade secret; and</text>
									</subclause>
                  <subclause id="H38B398B1797A43EA996E724F5FAF4099" indent="up1">
                    <enum>(II)</enum>
                    <text>damages for any unjust enrichment caused by the misappropriation of the trade secret that is not
			 addressed in computing damages for actual loss; or</text>
									</subclause>
                </clause>
                <clause id="H801DB3199B8D445D9FBFAD5E0BF89F47">
                  <enum>(ii)</enum>
                  <text>in lieu of damages measured by any other methods, the damages caused by the misappropriation
			 measured by imposition of liability for a reasonable royalty for the
			 misappropriator’s unauthorized disclosure or use of the trade secret;</text>
								</clause>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="H1B7184C44A704D36B35076967716905F">
                <enum>(C)</enum>
                <text>if the trade secret is willfully and maliciously misappropriated, award exemplary damages in an
			 amount not more than 3 times the amount of the damages awarded under
			 subparagraph (B); and</text>
							</subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="H949810FD654D46CF92344DB9A87949EF">
                <enum>(D)</enum>
                <text>if a claim of the misappropriation is made in bad faith, a motion to terminate an injunction is
			 made or opposed in bad faith, or the trade secret was willfully and
			 maliciously misappropriated, award reasonable attorney’s fees to the
			 prevailing party.</text>
							</subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection id="H876D12D2AFCB4A0287C2F911EF66FE70">
            <enum>(c)</enum>
            <header>Jurisdiction</header>
            <text>The district courts of the United States shall have original jurisdiction of civil actions brought
			 under this section.</text>
					</subsection>
          <subsection id="H85A23A6746A040A897A253F490AE13EC">
            <enum>(d)</enum>
            <header>Period of limitations</header>
            <text>A civil action under subsection (b) may not be commenced later than 5 years after the date on which
			 the misappropriation with respect to which the action would relate is
			 discovered or by the exercise of reasonable diligence should have been
			 discovered. For purposes of this subsection, a continuing misappropriation
			 constitutes a single claim of misappropriation.</text>
          </subsection>
          <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
        </quoted-block>
			</subsection>
      <subsection id="H540258D549BC49038314F1246ACD949D">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Definitions</header>
        <text>
          <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc/18/1839">
            <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/18/1839">Section 1839</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code</cato:entity-ref>, is amended—</text>
				<paragraph id="HEA44A209C0DA4509B286CDFF8B3D61DF">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>in paragraph (3), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HFDBA6FCC41F246E181C26BDE982B6F1E">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>in paragraph (4), by striking the period at the end and inserting a semicolon; and</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H99E4244E665C4A7A87945BD03910BB71">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <text>by adding at the end the following:</text>
					<quoted-block id="HF717042FC32342C6B107B8F2B1581129" style="OLC">
						<paragraph id="HFE29447185044B198FE1325A9734C600">
              <enum>(5)</enum>
              <text>the term <term>misappropriation</term> means—</text>
							<subparagraph id="H8BEFC3DA63A0499FB826AD16D49EE8A4">
                <enum>(A)</enum>
                <text>acquisition of a trade secret of another by a person who knows or has reason to know that the trade
			 secret was acquired by improper means; or</text>
							</subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="H23F8B5FA062544CCADE9A8FB394BE10B">
                <enum>(B)</enum>
                <text>disclosure or use of a trade secret of another without express or implied consent by a person who—</text>
								<clause id="HD972A10D45394B89825E351E08903B84">
                  <enum>(i)</enum>
                  <text>used improper means to acquire knowledge of the trade secret;</text>
								</clause>
                <clause id="HEA17EE482E734EC2BAA545D56881C0D8">
                  <enum>(ii)</enum>
                  <text>at the time of disclosure or use, knew or had reason to know that the knowledge of the trade secret
			 was—</text>
									<subclause id="H27DA20188CA74DDB80266B09053ECA36">
                    <enum>(I)</enum>
                    <text>derived from or through a person who had used improper means to acquire the trade secret;</text>
									</subclause>
                  <subclause id="H2760ECDBEEF940FAB5C4719B38E0719A">
                    <enum>(II)</enum>
                    <text>acquired under circumstances giving rise to a duty to maintain the secrecy of the trade secret or
			 limit the use of the trade secret; or</text>
									</subclause>
                  <subclause id="H3F6D10CDD97D47CBB1D1A1D9DE46FAFF">
                    <enum>(III)</enum>
                    <text>derived from or through a person who owed a duty to the person seeking relief to maintain the
			 secrecy of the trade secret or limit the use of the trade secret; or</text>
									</subclause>
                </clause>
                <clause id="HBCF0DE81584E406A8FDBAC78B16B8495">
                  <enum>(iii)</enum>
                  <text>before a material change of the position of the person, knew or had reason to know that—</text>
									<subclause id="H145EF9465FA848E88FE69F829F89B397">
                    <enum>(I)</enum>
                    <text>the trade secret was a trade secret; and</text>
									</subclause>
                  <subclause id="H7C8A746598C74107B45783F393070099">
                    <enum>(II)</enum>
                    <text>knowledge of the trade secret had been acquired by accident or mistake;</text>
									</subclause>
                </clause>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="HFE84C999F8B24884A0BC0089B876CBE3">
              <enum>(6)</enum>
              <text>the term <term>improper means</term>—</text>
							<subparagraph id="HAC5871B9E1CD4096AB25DA3824513F84">
                <enum>(A)</enum>
                <text>includes theft, bribery, misrepresentation, breach or inducement of a breach of a duty to maintain
			 secrecy, or espionage through electronic or other means; and</text>
							</subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="H0D4A33836D4A49779F838F7104BB3D6F">
                <enum>(B)</enum>
                <text>does not include reverse engineering or independent derivation; and</text>
							</subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="H11CCE44F6B834668A275BC0496374F57">
              <enum>(7)</enum>
              <text>the term <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
                  <term>
                  <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Trademark Act of 1946">Trademark Act of 1946</cato:entity-ref>
                </term> means the Act entitled <quote>
                  <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Lanham Act">An Act to provide for the registration and protection of trademarks used in commerce, to carry out
			 the provisions of certain international conventions, and for other
			 purposes,</cato:entity-ref> approved July 5, 1946 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/1051">
                    <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/15/1051/etseq">15 U.S.C. 1051 et seq.</cato:entity-ref>
                  </external-xref>) (commonly
			 referred to as the <quote>
                    <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Trademark Act of 1946">Trademark Act of 1946</cato:entity-ref>
                  </quote> or the <quote>Lanham Act</quote>)</quote>
                </cato:entity>.</text>
            </paragraph>
            <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
          </quoted-block>
				</paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="HDB91B1727A44416EAFC4D876079FA183">
        <enum>(c)</enum>
        <header>Exceptions to prohibition</header>
        <text>
          <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc/18/1833">
            <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/18/1833">Section 1833</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code</cato:entity-ref>, is amended, in the matter preceding paragraph (1), by
			 inserting <quote>or create a private right of action for</quote> after <quote>prohibit</quote>.</text>
			</subsection>
      <subsection id="HED98C709CB0B40EDB2643EE3EB5433ED">
        <enum>(d)</enum>
        <header>Conforming amendments</header>
				<paragraph id="H503DCDA2B7E84CF7B07D1D81D7EF3080">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>The section heading for <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc/18/1836">
              <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/18/1836">section 1836</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code</cato:entity-ref>, is amended to read as
			 follows:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H57330066FFD440AD997E1D23E4337354" style="USC">
						<section id="H9254A9C8B3584C848C01FF60D0CE2900">
              <enum>1836.</enum>
              <header>Civil proceedings</header>
            </section>
            <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
          </quoted-block>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HA0E3100574A64761AF44CFBCDE36AB9A">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>The table of sections for <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc-chapter/18/90">
              <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/90">chapter 90</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code</cato:entity-ref>, is amended by striking the
			 item relating to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc/18/1836" proposed="true">section 1836</cato:entity-ref> and inserting the following:</text>
					<quoted-block id="H49004622FDD54E9E98FE375D54D6566F" style="USC">
						<toc regeneration="no-regeneration">
							<toc-entry level="section">1836. Civil proceedings.</toc-entry>
            </toc>
            <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
          </quoted-block>
				</paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection commented="no" id="HDB30BA6622F84AF1A9E3880FB83F2CF2">
        <enum>(e)</enum>
        <header>Effective date</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendments made by this section shall apply with respect to any misappropriation of a trade
			 secret (as defined in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc/18/1839">
            <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/18/1839">section 1839</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code</cato:entity-ref>, as
			 amended by this section) for which any act occurs on or after the date of
			 the enactment of this Act.</text>
			</subsection>
      <subsection id="H672FE2C47CBC421EB57327B0201A5E38">
        <enum>(f)</enum>
        <header>Rule of construction</header>
        <text>Nothing in the amendments made by this section shall be construed to modify the rule of
			 construction under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc/18/1838">
            <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/18/1838">section 1838</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code</cato:entity-ref>, or to
			 preempt any other provision of law.</text>
			</subsection>
    </section>
  </legis-body>
</bill>
</doc>