<doc>
  <docmeta id="113hr4341ih">
    <bill congress="113" type="hr" number="4341" version="ih"/>
    <revision size="4608" annotations="0" status="complete" id="4" commit-time="2014-04-03T21:55:47Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113hr4341ih/4.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H7F30E4AF41824403AD1E2FB7A30AA4B1" public-private="public">
	<metadata>
<dublinCore>
<dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">113 HR 4341 IH: Truth in Advertising Act of 2014</dc:title>
<dc:publisher xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">2014-03-27</dc:date>
<dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>113th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>2d Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 4341</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20140327">March 27, 2014</action-date>
			<action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="R000435">Ms. Ros-Lehtinen</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="C001036">Mrs. Capps</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="D000610">Mr. Deutch</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>
      </action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To direct the Federal Trade Commission to submit to Congress a report on the use, in advertising
			 and other media for the promotion of commercial products, of images that
			 have been altered to materially change the physical characteristics of the
			 faces and bodies of the individuals depicted.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="HCF19EC6E90CC4BA3836E4ED5CB3F28B3" style="OLC">
		<section id="H5AA29F0343AE48FF8882DA00BA1240FB" section-type="section-one">
      <enum>1.</enum>
      <header>Short title</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote>
          <short-title>
            <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Truth in Advertising Act of 2014" proposed="true">Truth in Advertising Act of 2014</cato:entity-ref>
          </short-title>
        </quote>.</text>
		</section>
    <section id="HCC5FA03708BB4E3584C863E6FC914BC5">
      <enum>2.</enum>
      <header>Findings</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">
        <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> finds the following:</text>
			<paragraph id="HCF1D2D14367F4DCB8CE61F9DC72AA614">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text>Advertisers regularly alter images used in print and electronic media to materially change the
			 physical characteristics of models’ faces and bodies, often altering the
			 models’ size, proportions, shape, and skin color, removing signs of
			 ageing, and making other similar changes to models’ appearance.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H4FD47DE7876B488BB58B3FA4ED61AACE">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text>An increasing amount of academic evidence links exposure to such altered images with emotional,
			 mental, and physical health issues, including eating disorders, especially
			 among children and teenagers. There is particular concern about the
			 marketing of such images to children and teenagers through distribution in
			 teen-oriented publications, advertising displayed in public places outside
			 the home, and online media.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H273A796BF67A4DFDBD4F19FEAA9B2C54">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <text>Such altered images can create distorted and unrealistic expectations and understandings of
			 appropriate and healthy weight and body image.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H29DFD50BFCF04F8A8183026849C4B34F">
        <enum>(4)</enum>
        <text>The dissemination of unrealistic body standards has been linked to eating disorders among men and
			 women of varying age groups, but it has a particularly destructive health
			 effect on children and teenagers.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HD32C545838D34789978973AB62EB2E8A">
        <enum>(5)</enum>
        <text>Academic evidence has demonstrated a connection between the use of very thin models in advertising
			 and consumer attitudes toward a brand based on such advertising, as well
			 as a material influence of the use of such models on consumer purchase
			 intent, conduct, and reliance.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H4C7C7C1A9A994493BF63B5A5A7A7F3CF">
        <enum>(6)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In 2011, the American Medical Association adopted a policy encouraging advertising associations to
			 work with public and private sector organizations concerned with child and
			 adolescent health to develop guidelines for advertisements, especially
			 those appearing in teen-oriented publications, that would discourage the
			 altering of photographs in a manner that could promote unrealistic
			 expectations of appropriate body image.</text>
			</paragraph>
    </section>
    <section id="HF98B6A89DF7E4544AF754377CC6FE345">
      <enum>3.</enum>
      <header>Report by Federal Trade Commission</header>
			<subsection id="H7CC99B27EF994E2189F0F08F5FC62214">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>In general</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 18 months after the date of the enactment of this Act, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="2900" entity-type="federal-body">Federal Trade Commission</cato:entity-ref>
			 shall submit to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> a report that contains—</text>
				<paragraph id="HCB7523C058A84437A38BE853F2AA3694">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>a strategy to reduce the use, in advertising and other media for the promotion of commercial
			 products, of images that have been altered to materially change the
			 physical characteristics of the faces and bodies of the individuals
			 depicted; and</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HC21485232A9A494B96FCF5DA4A2A1886">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recommendations for an appropriate, risk-based regulatory framework with respect to such use.</text>
				</paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="HEF8E9ADAACFC4C1B935BC11821B3602C">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Input of external stakeholders and experts</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In preparing the report required by <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Truth in Advertising Act of 2014/s:3/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="2900" entity-type="federal-body">Federal Trade Commission</cato:entity-ref> shall solicit
			 input from external stakeholders and experts on the strategy and
			 recommendations required to be included in such report. The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2900">Commission</cato:entity-ref>, in
			 consultation with the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="National Institute of Mental Health" entity-id="7529">Director of the National Institute of Mental Health</cato:entity-ref>
			 and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="7522" entity-type="federal-body">Administrator of the Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services
			 Administration</cato:entity-ref>, shall ensure that input is obtained from an appropriate
			 number of stakeholders and experts and, to the extent practicable, from
			 stakeholders and experts that are geographically and culturally diverse
			 and that include stakeholders and experts from the physical and mental
			 health, business, and consumer advocacy communities.</text>
			</subsection>
    </section>
  </legis-body>
</bill>
</doc>