<doc>
  <docmeta id="113hr3549ih">
    <bill congress="113" type="hr" number="3549" version="ih"/>
    <revision size="32347" annotations="0" status="complete" id="4" commit-time="2013-11-29T19:07:00Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113hr3549ih/4.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H3F4D994AAF6B4E048408CF6866555DBB" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata>
<dublinCore>
<dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">113 HR 3549 IH: Protecting Adoption Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">2013-11-20</dc:date>
<dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>113th CONGRESS</congress> <session>1st Session</session> 
<legis-num>H. R. 3549</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20131120">November 20, 2013</action-date> 
<action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="H001053">Mrs. Hartzler</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="K000382">Ms. Kuster</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name>
      </action-desc> 
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To promote permanent families for children, privacy and safety for unwed mothers, responsible fatherhood, and security for adoptive parents by establishing a National Responsible Father Registry and encouraging States to enter into agreements to contribute the information contained in the State’s Responsible Father Registry to the National Responsible Father Registry, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H7E70C0C0AA6F4EF4BCE752C30F7CAF61" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HCAB40D3E15544A41AF1E0D6ECC58409F" section-type="section-one">
      <enum>1.</enum>
      <header>Short title</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote>
          <short-title>Protecting Adoption Act</short-title>
        </quote>.</text>
    </section> 
<section id="HE78FB9E055AB4AAABF70478AF63B033C">
      <enum>2.</enum>
      <header>Findings and purposes</header> 
<subsection id="H2A64CE771611449A880691ACEFAD569A">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Findings</header>
        <text>
          <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> makes the following findings:</text> 
<paragraph id="H15078D98157144AFAF19C6A82AD79D75">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>Responsible father registries, also known as possible father registries or putative father registries, exist in as many as 34 States.</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDBAAAA90F80148A6AA9B76634E625B96">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>The Supreme Court of the United States in Lehr v. Robertson (463 U.S. 248) (1983), found responsible father registries to be constitutional.</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE8C366F31B5E4679895ECC17E1958D76">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <text>Responsible father registries help to speed up the stable placement of children by providing a mechanism to determine whether there are any possible fathers who may have an interest in participating in the placement decisions of the child so that the possible father can timely assert his rights or so that the father’s rights can be waived, surrendered, or terminated and the child made available for adoption or placement.</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB97F17A8E05C4D1DA9248D8774279C7A">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
          <text>Responsible father registries protect the privacy and safety of unwed mothers by removing the burden from the mother to provide information about any possible fathers, disclosure of which would be an invasion of her privacy and may cause harm to the mother, particularly in the case of rape or domestic violence.</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE5EBD372AE0D49A5A96F014DD5626480">
          <enum>(5)</enum>
          <text>Responsible father registries serve to protect the rights of men who wish to be involved in the placement decisions of a child they believe they may have fathered by creating a mechanism for such men to undertake responsibility and to protect their rights without having to rely upon others to protect their rights, and to indicate their desire to be notified in a timely manner of certain legal proceedings related to the child, including proceedings related to termination of rights, adoption, and the placement of the child into State custody.</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBE6C309E30E54A02A51597FA03F853BB">
          <enum>(6)</enum>
          <text>Responsible father registries protect the privacy of possible fathers by providing a mechanism for men to submit identifying information to a database with restricted access.</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H50EF780BD0324930BF3B221BFCD38CA2">
          <enum>(7)</enum>
          <text>Responsible father registries protect the interests of adoptive parents and increase the security of adoptions by reducing the risk that possible fathers cannot be located in a timely manner. One of the biggest risks to the finalization of an adoption is the inability of the parties to an adoption proceeding to timely locate the possible fathers. When possible fathers are not provided with timely notice of an adoption proceeding related to a child they may have fathered and discover such proceeding later, the adoption proceeding often is delayed or disrupted. In addition to causing emotional stress and significant costs associated with this problem, such cases, particularly when they attract media attention, create a chilling effect on adoption in that prospective adoptive parents may decide not to pursue the option of adoption for fear that they will be involved in such a case.</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HEAA0FF16D1384DC4A65E9F8E324EF8A0">
          <enum>(8)</enum>
          <text>Interstate travel of mothers and the filing of legal actions relating to a child in a State other than the State in which a possible father may have registered may circumvent and eliminate the protections such unwed mothers and possible fathers are provided by the individual State Responsible Father Registries, because there are no agreements or mechanisms between the States to identify or to provide notice to possible fathers who have registered in another State.</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB98BB95851714EFAADA338F8899FC6D5">
          <enum>(9)</enum>
          <text>The inability of States to coordinate and cross-check their responsible father registries may jeopardize or delay the placement of the child in a permanent home and undermines the benefits to unwed mothers, protections intended for registered possible fathers, and security for adoptive parents that State registries are intended to afford.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="H596B5F5342774E87A76372D8D5950322">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Purposes</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The purposes of this Act are—</text> 
<paragraph id="H5FD35C043C7E4679962B4DABC6C53A2A">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>to provide for a national database that would accept possible father registrations from participating State Responsible Father Registries and directly from possible fathers, and would transmit the results of specific searches of such registrations to authorized parties involved in any State’s proceedings, whether the State participates in the national registry or not, for adoption, the placement of a child in State custody, or the termination of a father’s rights;</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H14868F4F12D042379A5D18A313A8F91F">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>to enable children to find a permanent home more quickly by providing identifying information on possible fathers thereby enabling the fathers’ rights to be addressed in a more timely manner;</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCA8E2FC8BB264629952F5E55DE16C4C5">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <text>to remove the burden from the mother of having to identify potential fathers, to protect her privacy and safety, especially in cases of rape or domestic violence;</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H57BF305824FD487AA72676AA83097DE4">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
          <text>to empower men to take responsibility for the protection of their rights by enabling them to register in a participating State or directly with the national registry, increasing the likelihood of men receiving notice of a proceeding in another State and reducing the opportunity for the mother to deprive a possible father of the ability to assert his rights by withholding accurate information concerning the possible father, by moving, or by traveling to another State; and</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H753D528DEDFB47FB868074B8034E6DDF">
          <enum>(5)</enum>
          <text>to reduce the risk to prospective adoptive parents of delayed or disrupted placements resulting from challenges to adoptions due to a possible father’s untimely receipt of notice of such proceedings.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
    </section> 
<section id="HCD835107569140ACA0D5FA0660406AC0">
      <enum>3.</enum>
      <header>Registries to facilitate adoptions</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">
        <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
          <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Social Security Act/t:IV/pt:B">Part B of title IV of the <act-name parsable-cite="SSA">Social Security Act</act-name>
          </cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/620">
          <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/42/620/etseq">42 U.S.C. 620 et seq</cato:entity-ref>.</external-xref>)</cato:entity> is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF24C5EBA0849426AA7EADA6D5DAB31D1" style="OLC"> 
<subpart id="H00CD86977BF245878691BB5E67F97BD3">
          <enum>4</enum>
          <header>National and State Responsible Father Registries to facilitate adoptions</header> 
<section id="H2CB44443CD81461C8D8A463A4FCA6AA1">
            <enum>445.</enum>
            <header>Definitions</header>
            <text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this subpart:</text> 
<paragraph id="HB194E351B1794AE6B5990002FB307410">
              <enum>(1)</enum>
              <header>Business day</header>
              <text>The term <term>business day</term> means a day on which Federal or State offices, as applicable, are open for regular business.</text>
            </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H32FA8111EFA34709948D0DDE9002EB08">
              <enum>(2)</enum>
              <header>Eligible party</header>
              <text>The term <term>eligible party</term> means—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H15C7F17A82A241E39D18597FDB8C2BB1">
                <enum>(A)</enum>
                <text>public and licensed private adoption or child placement agencies gathering information for a planned or pending adoption or the termination of rights of one or more possible fathers;</text>
              </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC62174102353493F9D302C411530D775">
                <enum>(B)</enum>
                <text>licensed attorneys representing a party in a planned or pending adoption or in the termination of rights of one or more possible fathers;</text>
              </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HCBA7B0BA8F714B7EAD726444D3D3362F">
                <enum>(C)</enum>
                <text>State agencies or entities responsible for the placement of children; and</text>
              </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H072CB30D7B76473E81F5318FA0040FA8">
                <enum>(D)</enum>
                <text>State courts.</text>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDA868C20890E4350A4DF05034D2D6DC0">
              <enum>(3)</enum>
              <header>National Responsible Father Registry</header>
              <text>The term <term>National Responsible Father Registry</term> means the registry established and maintained under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Social Security Act/s:445A" proposed="true">section 445A</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
            </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6D06052EE62E413F9C36A797EC9BDCD2">
              <enum>(4)</enum>
              <header>Notice</header>
              <text>The term <term>notice</term> means notice to all possible fathers of a proceeding sufficient to satisfy the notice requirements of the law of the State in which the proceeding is pending.</text>
            </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H580B1B585F494752B8CBE0555DDE363E">
              <enum>(5)</enum>
              <header>Pending adoption</header>
              <text>The term <term>pending adoption</term> means any adoption in which an adoption petition has been filed and is still pending with a court pursuant to State law.</text>
            </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB27A5E4A99774A8B89EB5CF650A8603B">
              <enum>(6)</enum>
              <header>Planned adoption</header>
              <text>The term <term>planned adoption</term> means any plan for the adoption of a child or children in which the birth mother has contacted an attorney or a public or licensed private adoption agency about placing her child for adoption, or in which a public or licensed private adoption agency is working to place a child for adoption.</text>
            </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6AEC04F3CDBA40F7ADD2296781588197">
              <enum>(7)</enum>
              <header>Proceeding</header>
              <text>The term <term>proceeding</term> means a proceeding relating to a child that a possible father has or may have fathered regarding a planned or pending adoption of the child, the entry of the child into State custody, or the termination of a possible father’s rights to the child.</text>
            </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9AB53F3486FF4701BE004390F18C8EE5">
              <enum>(8)</enum>
              <header>Possible father</header>
              <text>The term <term>possible father</term> or <term>putative father</term> means a man who has had sexual relations with a woman to whom he is not married and is therefore presumed to know that such woman may be pregnant as a result of such relations.</text>
            </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDF447E1B054046259F0000D7C988FCE1">
              <enum>(9)</enum>
              <header>Search</header>
              <text>The term <term>search</term> means a request for information regarding the existence of all possible fathers related to a child that is the subject of a proceeding.</text>
            </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD59814A87F5644B0A19B3369E2211A55">
              <enum>(10)</enum>
              <header>State Responsible Father Registry</header>
              <text>The term <term>State Responsible Father Registry</term> means, with respect to a State, the registry established or modified and maintained under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Social Security Act/s:445C" proposed="true">section 445C</cato:entity-ref> for that State.</text>
            </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0279FA5D0B31422888660316AAEEA306">
              <enum>(11)</enum>
              <header>Participating State</header>
              <text>The term <term>participating State</term> means a State that has entered into an agreement with the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Social Security Act/s:445B" proposed="true">section 445B</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
            </paragraph>
          </section> 
<section id="H0647FDB62AD84B539C0CE4C56DBEC924">
            <enum>445A.</enum>
            <header>National Responsible Father Registry</header> 
<subsection id="H972631A54EFD4914A222E2A0085F2563">
              <enum>(a)</enum>
              <header>Establishment and maintenance</header> 
<paragraph id="H8B487A82D6B240D6A006A71FE54DD99E">
                <enum>(1)</enum>
                <header>In general</header>
                <text>Not later than the date that is 180 days after the date of enactment of this subpart, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall establish and maintain an automated National Responsible Father Registry that contains the information described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Social Security Act/s:445C/ss:c" proposed="true">section 445C(c)</cato:entity-ref> and that provides a mechanism for men to register such information directly with the National Responsible Father Registry.</text>
              </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H01DAE6D906CE4610B43AF4B670540CF4">
                <enum>(2)</enum>
                <header>Data entry and deletion requirements</header> 
<subparagraph id="H93B0C0222BB3460496374011B841110F">
                  <enum>(A)</enum>
                  <header>Data entry</header>
                  <text>Information transmitted by a State or a possible father under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Social Security Act/s:445C/ss:d/p:2" proposed="true">section 445C(d)(2)</cato:entity-ref> shall be entered into the National Responsible Father Registry not later than the date that is 2 business days after the date on which such information is received.</text>
                </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H626132D5A72B46FAA260DA39277A18EC">
                  <enum>(B)</enum>
                  <header>Responsible father registration</header>
                  <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall establish procedures under which a possible father may submit the information described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Social Security Act/s:445C/ss:c" proposed="true">section 445C(c)</cato:entity-ref> directly to the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> for the purpose of including such information in the National Responsible Father Registry. Such procedures shall—</text> 
<clause id="HC2455C712C16414EBB7AA5F3C1199B59">
                    <enum>(i)</enum>
                    <text>require the possible father to verify by submission of a sworn statement or such other means as the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> determines appropriate that the information submitted is his own personal information and that it is true and correct to the best of his knowledge;</text>
                  </clause> 
<clause id="HD79BD4F9970E4983A00AC6D8C9CD81A6">
                    <enum>(ii)</enum>
                    <text>provide that no fee shall be charged to the possible father for registering in the National Responsible Father Registry; and</text>
                  </clause> 
<clause id="H9161924F807E4FD094A526979853D9C4">
                    <enum>(iii)</enum>
                    <text>allow possible fathers to submit registrations by mail or electronic means.</text>
                  </clause>
                </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA5E940427D9A446FA7C1CB816EE39E12">
                  <enum>(C)</enum>
                  <header>Application of Federal penalties for submission of false information</header>
                  <text>Any person who knowingly submits false information to the National Responsible Father Registry directly or indirectly through transmission of information submitted to a State Responsible Father Registry shall be subject to penalties in accordance with the provisions of <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc/18/1001">
                      <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/18/1001">section 1001</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
                </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H75A3CD768FFE4648AD2723AA42120434">
                  <enum>(D)</enum>
                  <header>Deletion of data</header>
                  <text>Information entered into the National Responsible Father Registry shall remain in the registry for not less than 20 years from the date of entry.</text>
                </subparagraph>
              </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4A2B529FE204446BA948DDBE686E307B">
                <enum>(3)</enum>
                <header>Access to information in the National Responsible Father Registry</header> 
<subparagraph id="H713201F20F5B46EA94A6F13BA5BFCF5F">
                  <enum>(A)</enum>
                  <header>In general</header>
                  <text>Subject to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Social Security Act/s:445A/ss:a/p:3/sp:B" proposed="true">subparagraph (B)</cato:entity-ref>, access to the information contained in the National Responsible Father Registry is limited to an eligible party.</text>
                </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H204DA59154534A7185C35289F78F8E3A">
                  <enum>(B)</enum>
                  <header>Limited access for registrants</header>
                  <text>Each possible father who registers in the National Responsible Father Registry may file a search request with the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> for the limited purpose of confirming that the information he provided is contained in the National Registry.</text>
                </subparagraph>
              </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H18AB28409F3C46DFB752273D69FE3497">
                <enum>(4)</enum>
                <header>Search requests</header> 
<subparagraph id="H8BBA1608697A4607804864D727C8D82F">
                  <enum>(A)</enum>
                  <header>By an eligible party</header>
                  <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall accept a request from an eligible party to search the National Responsible Father Registry only if the request has been verified for authenticity.</text>
                </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HAC2B74546CC64812A3177A1FCB989994">
                  <enum>(B)</enum>
                  <header>By a registrant</header>
                  <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall accept a request from a possible father who has registered in the National Responsible Father Registry to search the National Responsible Father Registry only if the request has been verified for authenticity.</text>
                </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H42D3E0EF119C41EDA07F7F1DACCD2F42">
                  <enum>(C)</enum>
                  <header>Fee</header>
                  <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> is authorized to charge a reasonable fee for a search conducted under this section.</text>
                </subparagraph>
              </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2EF24CFA74784B8F956E37899678F7A5">
                <enum>(5)</enum>
                <header>Limitation on disclosure of information</header>
                <text>No information contained in the National Responsible Father Registry shall be disclosed to any person if the disclosure of the information would contravene a national security interest of the United States or if the disclosure would compromise the confidentiality of census data.</text>
              </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H42D95E87EF1D45AE979ACAB0EA5EFA70">
                <enum>(6)</enum>
                <header>Methods for requesting a search of the national database</header>
                <text>An eligible party may request a search under this section either electronically or through the mail.</text>
              </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H867E65E40F62447ABC550B676DB61759">
                <enum>(7)</enum>
                <header>Certificate of search</header> 
<subparagraph id="HE289BD5371914DE4B638664CF8E1FC98">
                  <enum>(A)</enum>
                  <header>Issuance</header>
                  <text>Within 2 business days of receipt of a search request, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall issue by mail or electronic means a certificate of search to the person who requested the search.</text>
                </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF7A0D8D8ED3E4114A560B31DE1CB181C">
                  <enum>(B)</enum>
                  <header>Contents of eligible party search</header>
                  <text>The certificate of search on behalf of an eligible party shall contain—</text> 
<clause id="H44FB1F695C8E44EB8BAC3BB2BA05F15F">
                    <enum>(i)</enum>
                    <text>the names and most recent contact information for all possible fathers who are registered in the National Responsible Father Registry or registered in any participating State Responsible Father Registry;</text>
                  </clause> 
<clause id="H25C79AF4D702485B8AEE524882CDE4AE">
                    <enum>(ii)</enum>
                    <text>the latest date through which data in the National Responsible Father Registry has been updated; and</text>
                  </clause> 
<clause id="HFBAAC356CCD84CAB83FCDA1026CCA6B1">
                    <enum>(iii)</enum>
                    <text>the list of the State Responsible Father Registries whose data is included in the search database and the date through which the data from each participating State was last updated.</text>
                  </clause>
                </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB814A8DA8F1B403186F4442A208FF465">
                  <enum>(C)</enum>
                  <header>Contents of registrant search</header>
                  <text>The certificate of search on behalf of a possible father who has registered in the National Responsible Father Registry shall only contain the information provided to the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> by the registrant himself or provided by the registrant to a participating State registry and transmitted by that State registry to the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
                </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD5CA4D7C654C41B8BF5F84EB044AF4FC">
                  <enum>(D)</enum>
                  <header>Effect of certificate</header>
                  <text>A certificate of search issued under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Social Security Act/s:445A/ss:a/p:7/sp:B" proposed="true">subparagraph (B)</cato:entity-ref> shall serve as evidence of efforts by the eligible party who requested the search to locate a possible father in order to provide those possible fathers identified in the certificate with notice of a proceeding.</text>
                </subparagraph>
              </paragraph>
            </subsection> 
<subsection id="H38F83E157A764DD58DAF4FA551499FE0">
              <enum>(b)</enum>
              <header>National educational campaign</header>
              <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall establish a nationwide responsible fatherhood and responsible father registry educational campaign that is designed to inform possible fathers, unwed mothers, possible adoptive parents, and eligible parties of the existence of the National Responsible Father Registry, the advantages of possible fathers registering either in the National Responsible Father Registry or a State Responsible Father Registry, or both, the rights and responsibilities of possible fathers, unwed mothers, possible adoptive parents, and eligible parties with regard to a proceeding, and the role of the National Responsible Father Registry and a State Responsible Father Registry in a proceeding.</text>
            </subsection>
          </section> 
<section id="H005FB2DDAEE84793AACBBA3FA805E0F5">
            <enum>445B.</enum>
            <header>Agreements with States to promote responsible fatherhood</header> 
<subsection id="HEB5BBCD4F8E444DB8A023BD17238D4F5">
              <enum>(a)</enum>
              <header>In general</header>
              <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall use all reasonable efforts to encourage States to enter into an agreement with the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> to become a participating State under this subpart. Such agreements shall—</text> 
<paragraph id="H4B12C75DEAA6401194E288D3CD6B13E2">
                <enum>(1)</enum>
                <text>require that the State comply with the requirements for State Responsible Father Registries under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Social Security Act/s:445C" proposed="true">section 445C</cato:entity-ref>;</text>
              </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2A235396646E46319BE9F44E746F88EB">
                <enum>(2)</enum>
                <text>require that the State provide for a process under which a registered possible father will receive notice of a proceeding at the most recent address he provided to the registry, within State determined guidelines and time limits;</text>
              </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3BCD718978C04BD6AC2DC84038E8913E">
                <enum>(3)</enum>
                <text>require the State to provide annual reviews and reports to the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> on the State Responsible Father Registry, including such information as may be necessary to measure compliance with the requirements under this subpart;</text>
              </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5AA4D4339E9E48679880E40A60F19050">
                <enum>(4)</enum>
                <text>require the State to, in accordance with standards prescribed by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref>, cooperate with other States and the Federal Government to assist individuals and governments in their efforts to locate and provide notice to possible fathers;</text>
              </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H75F6FA50E823484C98A29C79CE1B2DAB">
                <enum>(5)</enum>
                <text>encourage the State to establish or designate a single organizational unit within the State that meets such staffing and organizational requirements as the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> may prescribe to administer the State Responsible Father Registry;</text>
              </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8412627429F34EBC9E6FF725DC615880">
                <enum>(6)</enum>
                <text>encourage the State to enter into cooperative agreements between the State and appropriate entities, such as those specified in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Social Security Act/s:445C/ss:e/p:2" proposed="true">section 445C(e)(2)</cato:entity-ref>, to assist the organizational unit established or designated to administer the State Responsible Father Registry;</text>
              </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H50323874AFA144AC94FB8855CB740F6D">
                <enum>(7)</enum>
                <text>encourage the State to amend its long-arm jurisdictional statute to ensure that personal jurisdiction is established in a proceeding for a father registered in the National Responsible Father Registry;</text>
              </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H630F8576BF674107A237968E5323597A">
                <enum>(8)</enum>
                <text>encourage States to develop, establish, and operate programs that are designed—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H905E007172DD4BA59C753B889C1B4856">
                  <enum>(A)</enum>
                  <text>to improve the protection of the rights of possible fathers in a proceeding;</text>
                </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF296F0B5116C4DC6AF729A57BBD2FDCB">
                  <enum>(B)</enum>
                  <text>to assist mothers in making responsible plans for their children's future; and</text>
                </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H3FC44368F8154C04B603BE508DFC218D">
                  <enum>(C)</enum>
                  <text>to protect the privacy and safety of possible fathers and of birth mothers, including those who have been the victims of violence, by, among other things, enabling birth mothers to proceed with an adoption or placement plan without being required to disclose her sexual partners; and</text>
                </subparagraph>
              </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1FE5567B08244FC8BDC17E53797B631D">
                <enum>(9)</enum>
                <text>encourage States to enact laws and regulations to address the pre-birth abandonment of a child by the biological father and abandonment of a child by the biological father subsequent to birth.</text>
              </paragraph>
            </subsection> 
<subsection id="HA865B356178B4791AA0EAD0ACA7CAB4C">
              <enum>(b)</enum>
              <header>Grants To promote responsible fatherhood</header>
              <text>An agreement with a State that meets the requirements of <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Social Security Act/s:445B/ss:c" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref> may include a grant to the State as provided for under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Social Security Act/s:445D" proposed="true">section 445D</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
            </subsection>
          </section> 
<section id="H6D97B3A34394415EB73EDE1EC313F19B">
            <enum>445C.</enum>
            <header>State Responsible Father Registries</header> 
<subsection id="HB685C81498E047159413CCF14F78E604">
              <enum>(a)</enum>
              <header>Establishment and maintenance</header> 
<paragraph id="H6F63FB875D8545DE85D810FB88F4267B">
                <enum>(1)</enum>
                <header>In general</header>
                <text>Subject to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Social Security Act/s:445C/ss:a/p:2" proposed="true">paragraph (2)</cato:entity-ref>, each State that is a participating State under this subpart shall provide assurances to the Secretary that the State has, or will establish, and will maintain an automated responsible father registry that meets the requirements of this section.</text>
              </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC9CF8D7E40344D2DBBB1B67599E86252">
                <enum>(2)</enum>
                <header>Existing State Responsible Father Registries</header>
                <text>A State that has a responsible father registry in existence on the date of enactment of this subpart and desires to enter into an agreement with the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Social Security Act/s:445B" proposed="true">section 445B</cato:entity-ref> shall provide assurances to the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> that the State will, not later than 180 days from the last day of the first regular session of the State legislature that begins after the date of enactment of this subpart, modify the registry to the extent necessary for the registry to meet the requirements of this section with respect to responsible fathers who register with the State on or after that day. For purposes of the previous sentence, in the case of a State that has a 2-year legislative session, each year of the session is considered to be a separate, regular session of the State legislature.</text>
              </paragraph>
            </subsection> 
<subsection id="H93D55B962DEE45209E373D30E296D40A">
              <enum>(b)</enum>
              <header>Registration with the State Responsible Father Registry</header> 
<paragraph id="H538D1772269B4F0C9E06D33AE7A5650B">
                <enum>(1)</enum>
                <header>Submission of information</header>
                <text>The State shall establish procedures under which the possible father of a child may submit the information described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Social Security Act/s:445C/ss:c" proposed="true">subsection (c)</cato:entity-ref> to the State for the purpose of including the information in the State Responsible Father Registry. Such procedures shall provide that, in order for the possible father to be entitled to notice of any proceeding, the possible father must submit information for inclusion in the State Responsible Father Registry within State-determined time limits.</text>
              </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0768F674619F4B01B19FA7503DCECB32">
                <enum>(2)</enum>
                <header>Verification</header>
                <text>The procedures established under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Social Security Act/s:445C/ss:b/p:1" proposed="true">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref> shall require the possible father to verify by submission of a sworn statement or such other means as the State, in consultation with the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref>, determines appropriate that the information submitted is his own personal information and that it is true and correct to the best of his knowledge.</text>
              </paragraph>
            </subsection> 
<subsection id="HA109C8F73B304D8B9CC44CF1262B2E32">
              <enum>(c)</enum>
              <header>Contents</header>
              <text>With respect to a child, the State Responsible Father Registry shall contain information sufficient to identify the possible father, which may include (but is not limited to)—</text> 
<paragraph id="H4F2BB5AE808A44ADBC219BA0939977CF">
                <enum>(1)</enum>
                <text>the name of the possible father (including any other names by which he may be known);</text>
              </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB717BD2B3E904B6D90936D591F8BC931">
                <enum>(2)</enum>
                <text>the date of birth of the possible father;</text>
              </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H81143E97CCB44E1CBCC65A3983382BC5">
                <enum>(3)</enum>
                <text>the Social Security number of the possible father, if any;</text>
              </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDFA47257C3544C25A8ED594FAD959CA8">
                <enum>(4)</enum>
                <text>the State of issue and driver's license number of the possible father, if any;</text>
              </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9141C0F4B754400D83951DC9DBB1EBCC">
                <enum>(5)</enum>
                <text>the address provided by the possible father at which he requests notice;</text>
              </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2CCEC31C995A49FBA0292260BB08AA22">
                <enum>(6)</enum>
                <text>all known telephone numbers for the possible father;</text>
              </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA3B25F79D8304E428FB85B1D942C1EA9">
                <enum>(7)</enum>
                <text>the name and address of the employer of the possible father, if any;</text>
              </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4107BF75A2EF4181B35E716772C7B61B">
                <enum>(8)</enum>
                <text>the name of the mother (including any other names by which she may be known);</text>
              </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFEC618BEC12F4B88807A02AD2AFE1750">
                <enum>(9)</enum>
                <text>the most recent address of the mother, if known;</text>
              </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC1F40DCB86174BC2AF6850F83873CB5F">
                <enum>(10)</enum>
                <text>the date of birth of the mother, if known;</text>
              </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBFF051CA1FD64C1CAD5154C3527B9D5A">
                <enum>(11)</enum>
                <text>the Social Security number of the mother, if known;</text>
              </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H36611BDA9EF54C46BD19331486171D73">
                <enum>(12)</enum>
                <text>the State of issue and driver's license number of the mother, if known;</text>
              </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF816A00AE16946109E735A3C05621F57">
                <enum>(13)</enum>
                <text>the city and State where possible conception took place;</text>
              </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H20FA88FDC436422F8E65FB2BB981C7C8">
                <enum>(14)</enum>
                <text>the date or estimated date (or range of dates) of possible conception;</text>
              </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H331474EA90484AA29C16D79A0DF0DE75">
                <enum>(15)</enum>
                <text>the birth date of the child or the approximate delivery date, if known; and</text>
              </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H761F100B50494BEA8DB118D7673234FF">
                <enum>(16)</enum>
                <text>the name and gender of the child, if known.</text>
              </paragraph>
            </subsection> 
<subsection id="HCFF46C9780F1404387F6BA10AC345161">
              <enum>(d)</enum>
              <header>Collection of State information and transmission to the National Responsible Father Registry</header> 
<paragraph id="H25A2EB2E77E442BABC7918229FA48A97">
                <enum>(1)</enum>
                <header>Collection</header>
                <text>The State shall collect the information described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Social Security Act/s:445C/ss:c" proposed="true">subsection (c)</cato:entity-ref> submitted by the possible father and enter such information into the State Responsible Father Registry.</text>
              </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3895E4C20530414F98D0913B828F8916">
                <enum>(2)</enum>
                <header>Transmission</header>
                <text>Not later than the date that is 3 business days after the date on which any information described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Social Security Act/s:445C/ss:c" proposed="true">subsection (c)</cato:entity-ref> is entered into the State Responsible Father Registry, the State shall furnish such information to the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref>, in an electronic format designated by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref>, for purposes of including the information in the National Responsible Father Registry.</text>
              </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6CD28F24BFBA4D9885CF047051E521C1">
                <enum>(3)</enum>
                <header>Requirement</header>
                <text>The procedures established under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Social Security Act/s:445C/ss:b/p:1" proposed="true">subsection (b)(1)</cato:entity-ref> shall include a means by which a possible father is informed that the registry may be used to establish an obligation to support a child or children. Except as provided in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Social Security Act/s:445C/ss:g" proposed="true">subsection (g)</cato:entity-ref>, registration shall not constitute an admission of guilt to any crime under Federal or State law.</text>
              </paragraph>
            </subsection> 
<subsection id="H1A05204789694A41B75D21D310FDA0B2">
              <enum>(e)</enum>
              <header>Establishment of Registration Centers</header> 
<paragraph id="HA273EF3E34974F8194F726A7473B6A0E">
                <enum>(1)</enum>
                <header>In general</header>
                <text>The State shall establish centers in various locations throughout the State so that registration forms for the State Responsible Father Registry are easily accessible to possible fathers.</text>
              </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H74E1374E6FC041F29F5DBD510E6055C3">
                <enum>(2)</enum>
                <header>Sites</header>
                <text>The sites of the centers described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Social Security Act/s:445C/ss:e/p:1" proposed="true">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref> may include (but are not limited to) the following:</text> 
<subparagraph id="H3DA9FAB8CA8545B9A676C92B5DB80EF9">
                  <enum>(A)</enum>
                  <text>State and local hospitals.</text>
                </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H965D0AF8CDF549768A5F0A0463F001D4">
                  <enum>(B)</enum>
                  <text>Courthouses in which family courts are located.</text>
                </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H41E66E8C5DA64F2A9D5D9502DFF98302">
                  <enum>(C)</enum>
                  <text>State departments of motor vehicles.</text>
                </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HDB40F3B8C014404D9356AB3BC7F0172B">
                  <enum>(D)</enum>
                  <text>State welfare agencies.</text>
                </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE6BD40E6252F47D092F7ABEABB73D7C7">
                  <enum>(E)</enum>
                  <text>State health department offices.</text>
                </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB610044BBBAD4323BEF7CBBF65176E68">
                  <enum>(F)</enum>
                  <text>State vital records offices.</text>
                </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H71DC2600C1704285A57C603E224555A9">
                  <enum>(G)</enum>
                  <text>State probate courts.</text>
                </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H1E5EC33D5C1C46AFA2029BACAB84D79D">
                  <enum>(H)</enum>
                  <text>State-operated or -sponsored websites for each center established in accordance with this subsection.</text>
                </subparagraph>
              </paragraph>
            </subsection> 
<subsection id="H039335E408E44CC19741FA8DF711CB64">
              <enum>(f)</enum>
              <header>Method of submitting registration</header>
              <text>The State shall permit a possible father to submit information to the State Responsible Father Registry electronically, in person, or by mail. The State shall not charge a fee for registering in the State Responsible Father Registry.</text>
            </subsection> 
<subsection id="H37EDB6734FFE49F387489FB9C391EAAB">
              <enum>(g)</enum>
              <header>Penalties for submission of false information</header>
              <text>A State shall have in effect a law that provides that any person who knowingly submits false information to a State Responsible Father Registry shall be guilty of the highest class of misdemeanor under State law.</text>
            </subsection> 
<subsection id="HCEC57434F4864C7596414A99D473632A">
              <enum>(h)</enum>
              <header>Accuracy of data</header>
              <text>A possible father is solely responsible for the accuracy of the information contained in his registration and he shall be responsible for updating the information, if needed to keep it accurate. The information contained in the registration is presumed accurate. Notice regarding a proceeding shall be deemed received by the possible father if sent or delivered to him at the most recent address he provided in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Social Security Act/s:445C/ss:c/p:5" proposed="true">subsection (c)(5)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
            </subsection> 
<subsection id="H1A90F88097454F8E9CC75F952BFA30C9">
              <enum>(i)</enum>
              <header>Privacy safeguards</header>
              <text>The State shall establish procedures to ensure that the information maintained in the State Responsible Father Registry is subject to the same privacy safeguards as the privacy safeguards required under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Social Security Act/s:454/p:26">section 454(26)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
            </subsection>
          </section> 
<section id="H66FF5751A1314FDB8DC9987AE2850907">
            <enum>445D.</enum>
            <header>Grants to States to promote responsible fatherhood</header> 
<subsection id="HB6442E42F30D4167A7B99E64BFB80F06">
              <enum>(a)</enum>
              <header>Grants to States</header>
              <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> may make a grant to a State that enters into an agreement with the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> pursuant to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Social Security Act/s:445B" proposed="true">section 445B</cato:entity-ref> to become a participating State for purposes of—</text> 
<paragraph id="H2F8BB54AE6F44D8E98791BBAF9342A4B">
                <enum>(1)</enum>
                <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">modifying an existing State Responsible Father Registry to the extent necessary for the registry to meet the requirements of <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Social Security Act/s:445C" proposed="true">section 445C</cato:entity-ref>; or</text>
              </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5CFF0D0C88E24D83A63FCC16E5F305C7">
                <enum>(2)</enum>
                <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">establishing a State Responsible Father Registry that meets the requirements of <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Social Security Act/s:445C" proposed="true">section 445C</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
              </paragraph>
            </subsection> 
<subsection id="HF9206674B95844E3BF53C738B559F160">
              <enum>(b)</enum>
              <header>Condition</header>
              <text>As a condition for receiving a grant under this section, a State shall agree to—</text> 
<paragraph id="HD47AF88BAE0E4E33A68007226CAC1B3E">
                <enum>(1)</enum>
                <text>maintain an automated State Responsible Father Registry in accordance with the requirements of <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Social Security Act/s:445C" proposed="true">section 445C</cato:entity-ref>; and</text>
              </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC1BC8252AA2443989DF5C1493E482294">
                <enum>(2)</enum>
                <text>support the nationwide responsible fatherhood and responsible father registry educational campaign established under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Social Security Act/s:445A/ss:b" proposed="true">section 445A(b)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
              </paragraph>
            </subsection> 
<subsection id="H336D6F4D2F3B49F78BA523806ECAF077">
              <enum>(c)</enum>
              <header>Amount</header>
              <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A grant made under this section shall be in such an amount as the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> determines appropriate.</text>
            </subsection> 
<subsection id="H7021E366D49748349F03ACE91EB220AF">
              <enum>(d)</enum>
              <header>Use of funds</header>
              <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Funds received under a grant made under this section may be used to reimburse a participating State in whole or in part for costs incurred to modify an existing State Responsible Father Registry or to establish a State Responsible Father Registry, and to reimburse the State in whole or in part for costs incurred to satisfy the conditions specified in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Social Security Act/s:445D/ss:b" proposed="true">subsection (b)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
            </subsection> 
<subsection id="HDFA69113F0DC44E6BEF29B5D6932AAAA">
              <enum>(e)</enum>
              <header>Authorization of appropriations</header>
              <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">
                <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="auth-auth-approp">There are authorized to be appropriated <cato:funds-and-year amount="indefinite" year="2014,..">such sums as are necessary for fiscal year 2014 and each fiscal year thereafter</cato:funds-and-year> <cato:property name="purpose">for purposes of making grants to States under <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Social Security Act/s:445D" proposed="true">this section</cato:entity-ref>
                  </cato:property>.</cato:entity>
              </text>
            </subsection>
          </section>
        </subpart>
        <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
      </quoted-block>
    </section> 
</legis-body> 
</bill>
</doc>