<doc>
  <docmeta id="113hr126eh">
    <bill congress="113" type="hr" number="126" version="eh"/>
    <revision size="3809" annotations="0" status="complete" id="4" commit-time="2013-08-05T14:07:50Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113hr126eh/4.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <bill bill-stage="Engrossed-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H2DD39929CC8645659E40B9BA9D6490CD" public-private="public" stage-count="1"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>113 HR 126 EH: Corolla Wild Horses Protection Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date/>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="no">IB</distribution-code> 
<congress display="yes">113th CONGRESS</congress> <session display="yes">1st Session</session> 
<legis-num>H. R. 126</legis-num> 
<current-chamber display="no">IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type> 
<official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of the Interior to enter into an agreement to provide for management of the free-roaming wild horses in and around the Currituck National Wildlife Refuge.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="HE391BB56FF584565BC68FE83F5609FD2" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H3E50FDD9C99744739FF50AB941F9836D" section-type="section-one">
      <enum>1.</enum>
      <header>Short title</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote>
          <short-title>Corolla Wild Horses Protection Act</short-title>
        </quote>.</text> </section> 
<section id="H277346C8B04B4E43B32721B0C413315A" section-type="subsequent-section">
      <enum>2.</enum>
      <header>Wild horses in and around the Currituck National Wildlife Refuge</header> 
<subsection id="HDB8AD9EC7B804BB793382EDAA7DA88A2">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Agreement required</header> 
<paragraph id="H4A85D0351C8145F0BC9FE0E0EEA2D128">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>In general</header>
          <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1400">Secretary of the Interior</cato:entity-ref> shall enter into an agreement with the Corolla Wild Horse Fund (a nonprofit corporation established under the laws of the State of North Carolina), the County of Currituck, North Carolina, and the State of North Carolina within 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act to provide for management of free-roaming wild horses in and around the Currituck National Wildlife Refuge.</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF5EA5D65AA6D43E8B9F5E3C7C8A4E2D1">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Terms</header>
          <text>The agreement shall—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H85D2488A6CBD462886E8DCB2DD81A1F6">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>allow a herd of not less than 110 and not more than 130 free-roaming wild horses in and around such refuge, with a target population of between 120 and 130 free-roaming wild horses;</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB848AC9CA85842258E77EBC85DC6F935">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>provide for cost-effective management of the horses while ensuring that natural resources within the refuge are not adversely impacted;</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HFAF91B0FD1D8440F90F7A92877D83002">
            <enum>(C)</enum>
            <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide for introduction of a small number of free-roaming wild horses from the herd at Cape Lookout National Seashore as is necessary to maintain the genetic viability of the herd in and around the Currituck National Wildlife Refuge; and</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HAF1CDD44E7D24225BA2C8CDE1361D20E">
            <enum>(D)</enum>
            <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">specify that the Corolla Wild Horse Fund shall pay the costs associated with—</text> 
<clause id="H3B4B296105CD4B31A8283EC62AC4ABFE">
              <enum>(i)</enum>
              <text>coordinating a periodic census and inspecting the health of the horses;</text> </clause> 
<clause id="H6AB25B847E5247B2873F2B4630CAD9C4">
              <enum>(ii)</enum>
              <text>maintaining records of the horses living in the wild and in confinement;</text> </clause> 
<clause id="H859277C63ED74100BBD2451EE0C71ACA">
              <enum>(iii)</enum>
              <text>coordinating the removal and placement of horses and monitoring of any horses removed from the Currituck County Outer Banks; and</text> </clause> 
<clause id="H4973722E237C48FCA0131831E7D51409">
              <enum>(iv)</enum>
              <text>administering a viable population control plan for the horses including auctions, adoptions, contraceptive fertility methods, and other viable options.</text> </clause>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="H663DAC985432469687D539F67F461138">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Requirements for introduction of horses from Cape Lookout National Seashore</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">During the effective period of the memorandum of understanding between the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1443">National Park Service</cato:entity-ref> and the Foundation for Shackleford Horses, Inc. (a non-profit corporation organized under the laws of and doing business in the State of North Carolina) signed in 2007, no horse may be removed from Cape Lookout National Seashore for introduction at Currituck National Wildlife Refuge except—</text> 
<paragraph id="H716169E797024A26A7C63F471ADBBA20">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with the approval of the Foundation; and</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA3EC0F9DC4AE4644968DFC3884C6CAFA">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">consistent with the terms of such memorandum (or any successor agreement) and the Management Plan for the Shackleford Banks Horse Herd signed in January 2006 (or any successor management plan).</text> </paragraph>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="HAE211D9BF1524CC28D1925665522E4BD">
        <enum>(c)</enum>
        <header>No liability created</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this section shall be construed as creating liability for the United States for any damages caused by the free-roaming wild horses to any person or property located inside or outside the boundaries of the refuge.</text> </subsection>
    </section> 
</legis-body> <attestation>
    <attestation-group>
      <attestation-date date="20130603" chamber="House">Passed the House of Representatives June 3, 2013.</attestation-date>
      <attestor display="no">Karen L. Haas,</attestor>
      <role>Clerk.</role>
    </attestation-group>
  </attestation>
<endorsement display="yes"/>
</bill>
</doc>