<doc>
  <docmeta id="113hr3862ih">
    <bill congress="113" type="hr" number="3862" version="ih"/>
    <revision size="17084" annotations="0" status="complete" id="4" commit-time="2014-01-28T16:22:00Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113hr3862ih/4.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HFE1B37D967A74C55ABB648317672DC1D" public-private="public">
  <metadata>
<dublinCore>
<dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">113 HR 3862 IH: Clean Water Affordability Act of 2014</dc:title>
<dc:publisher xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">2014-01-14</dc:date>
<dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
    <congress>113th CONGRESS</congress>
    <session>2d Session</session>
    <legis-num>H. R. 3862</legis-num>
    <current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
    <action>
      <action-date date="20140114">January 14, 2014</action-date>
      <action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="L000566">Mr. Latta</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="W000799">Mr. Walz</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>
      </action-desc>
    </action>
    <legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
    <official-title>To amend the Federal Water Pollution Control Act to assist municipalities and regional sewer authorities that would experience a significant hardship raising the revenue necessary to finance projects and activities for the construction of wastewater treatment works, and for other purposes.</official-title>
  </form>
  <legis-body id="H0C72E0BD4D83466991E0417723A444B0" style="OLC">
    <section id="H8FC201C0B38D448CA1DFB23E21F5261A" section-type="section-one">
      <enum>1.</enum>
      <header>Short title</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote>
          <short-title>Clean Water Affordability Act of 2014</short-title>
        </quote>.</text>
    </section>
    <section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H87B18D0D19004AEEAC3575186117659C">
      <enum>2.</enum>
      <header>Integrated permitting process</header>
      <subsection id="H8E8052BAD63F41F1A22D38F7DEB2D795">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>In general</header>
        <text>
          <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Federal Water Pollution Control Act/s:402/ss:a">Section 402(a) of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/1342">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/33/1342/a">33 U.S.C. 1342(a)</cato:entity-ref>
          </external-xref>)</cato:entity> is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
        <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA094B75CC0E64520BB097D9E78FA62D9" style="OLC">
          <paragraph id="H262C956CBEAE41EEB5893059703D1D63">
            <enum>(6)</enum>
            <header>Integrated Permits</header>
            <subparagraph id="H80D2FDBB346B426CB7EF620DE51ACE40">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <header>Definition of publicly owned permittee</header>
              <text>In this paragraph, the term <term>publicly owned permittee</term> means either—</text>
              <clause id="HF4E5F16D9B0942B1866396C62D8F02B2">
                <enum>(i)</enum>
                <text>a treatment works (as defined in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Federal Water Pollution Control Act/s:212">section 212</cato:entity-ref>) that is publicly owned; or</text>
              </clause>
              <clause id="H1E271B573B144D2BAA294397B7EC2816">
                <enum>(ii)</enum>
                <text>a municipal separate storm sewer system referred to in this section.</text>
              </clause>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="HD5EF64BE87994784B06F2407B120C027">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <header>Planning approach</header>
              <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="6800">Administrator</cato:entity-ref> shall establish a comprehensive and integrated planning approach to the obligations under this section of a publicly owned permittee—</text>
              <clause id="HBBBB9C5B8E724A068C32B88F1A4AB499">
                <enum>(i)</enum>
                <text>under which permit obligations may be implemented according to a schedule that—</text>
                <subclause id="HCD4A2A298C734317A8F876104D084BE0">
                  <enum>(I)</enum>
                  <text>accounts for the financial capability of the publicly owned permittee;</text>
                </subclause>
                <subclause id="HC47903F1F96F413D8031E81953B3B1D1">
                  <enum>(II)</enum>
                  <text>prioritizes permit obligations according to the most cost-effective and environmentally beneficial outcomes;</text>
                </subclause>
                <subclause id="HC525D7FAF16E48EC9D360F1113BFD55E">
                  <enum>(III)</enum>
                  <text>accounts for the preexisting maintenance, operational, and regulatory obligations of the publicly owned permittee under this section; and</text>
                </subclause>
                <subclause id="HE4896FEE161A40D0B1337568D38FA6AD">
                  <enum>(IV)</enum>
                  <text>enables the publicly owned permittee to implement innovative approaches to meet those obligations; and</text>
                </subclause>
              </clause>
              <clause id="H95BF3D4D38BF451BAB8BD9F64ADEBC65">
                <enum>(ii)</enum>
                <text>that accounts for changed circumstances in the obligations of the publicly owned permittee, such as—</text>
                <subclause id="H08A99CDA93A0428B9C3A8C703A333FA3">
                  <enum>(I)</enum>
                  <text>new innovative treatment approaches;</text>
                </subclause>
                <subclause id="HA415158AC0A8401C9749121D55080958">
                  <enum>(II)</enum>
                  <text>new regulatory requirements; and</text>
                </subclause>
                <subclause id="HE44164F46446475194002235D5F626C4">
                  <enum>(III)</enum>
                  <text>changes in financial capability.</text>
                </subclause>
              </clause>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
        </quoted-block>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="H7CE5B1A0FCAA4C578F7AA5F793C969AF">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Duration of permits</header>
        <text>
          <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Federal Water Pollution Control Act/s:402/ss:b/p:1/sp:B">Section 402(b)(1)(B) of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/1342">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/33/1342/b/1/B">33 U.S.C. 1342(b)(1)(B)</cato:entity-ref>
          </external-xref>)</cato:entity> is amended by inserting before the semicolon at the end the following: <quote>, except that a permit with a term of more than 5 years but not more than 25 years may be approved if the permittee has an approved integrated plan established under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Federal Water Pollution Control Act/s:402/ss:a/p:6">subsection (a)(6)</cato:entity-ref>
          </quote>.</text>
      </subsection>
    </section>
    <section id="H7281B8D227B54934B0A4D19FB92EB767">
      <enum>3.</enum>
      <header>Updating of guidance</header>
      <subsection id="H2051F978C718406BB99FE11D3525E2AC">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Definitions</header>
        <text>In this section, the following definitions apply:</text>
        <paragraph id="H02892EF5B2C04B089EBBD8E26AA0ECA4">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>Administrator</header>
          <text>The term <quote>Administrator</quote> means the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H82D1FAD7AC75484ABE6BCE5063566A08">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Affordability</header>
          <text>The term <quote>affordability</quote> means, with respect to payment of a utility bill, a measure of whether an individual customer or household can pay the bill without undue hardship or unreasonable sacrifice in the essential lifestyle or spending patterns of the individual or household, as determined by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="6800">Administrator</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HF8F886F12DA74B46AF1A0B7D11337400">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <header>Financial capability</header>
          <text>The term <quote>financial capability</quote> means the financial capability of a community to make investments necessary to make water quality-related improvements, taking into consideration the criteria described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Clean Water Affordability Act of 2014/s:3/ss:b/p:2/sp:A" proposed="true">subsection (b)(2)(A)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H204476BF1D6540CFB48622A544BCD62E">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
          <header>Guidance</header>
          <text>The term <quote>guidance</quote> means the guidance published by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="6800">Administrator</cato:entity-ref> entitled <quote>Combined Sewer Overflows—Guidance for Financial Capability Assessment and Schedule Development</quote> and dated February 1997, as applicable to combined sewer overflows and sanitary sewer overflows.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="H4A4FCA2861E7489FB6F15D0E2A6A3CC3">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Updating</header>
        <paragraph id="H8D3F7FE1C33B46B2B30FCC40439BAE15">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>In general</header>
          <text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="6800">Administrator</cato:entity-ref> shall update the guidance to ensure that the evaluations by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="6800">Administrator</cato:entity-ref> of financial capability assessment and schedule development meet the criteria described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Clean Water Affordability Act of 2014/s:3/ss:b/p:2" proposed="true">paragraph (2)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H6ABADF31A03243F7A1F5B174DA651704">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Criteria</header>
          <text>The criteria described in this paragraph are that, under the updated guidance—</text>
          <subparagraph id="HB5B9721E90204AB6A9E12375A77D7C90">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>in assessing the financial capability of a community—</text>
            <clause id="H75A877661FEB4B77AB984E5BD436CDD3">
              <enum>(i)</enum>
              <text>greater emphasis should be placed on local economic conditions;</text>
            </clause>
            <clause id="HEAD80F20FDFC45EFB2B8EBA67C579209">
              <enum>(ii)</enum>
              <text>for regional systems, consideration should be given to the economic conditions of political jurisdictions and significant demographic groups within each region;</text>
            </clause>
            <clause id="H21E36E8E90524524BBBFA826754FB2E1">
              <enum>(iii)</enum>
              <text>prescriptive formulas for use in calculating financial capability and thresholds for expenditure should not be considered to be the only indicator of the financial capability of a community;</text>
            </clause>
            <clause id="HEE103A8BE1D4423AABDAEB0F426B8D5A">
              <enum>(iv)</enum>
              <text>site-specific local conditions should be taken into consideration in analyzing financial capability;</text>
            </clause>
            <clause id="H9925EB4D90754AE0B345E7DEECAC1709">
              <enum>(v)</enum>
              <text>a single measure of financial capability or affordability (such as median household income) should be viewed in the context of other economic measures, rather than as a threshold to be achieved; and</text>
            </clause>
            <clause id="HDA2DFC87A67C4457BA3E874A8536C55C">
              <enum>(vi)</enum>
              <subclause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HC79F84F472D3407DB1587D92084D53C8">
                <enum>(I)</enum>
                <text>consideration should be given to the economic outlook of a community, including the potential impact of program requirements over time, in the development of implementation schedules; and</text>
              </subclause>
              <subclause id="H25524074C28A4969946FACE569DC5D75" indent="up1">
                <enum>(II)</enum>
                <text>the assessment should take into consideration other essential community investments relating to water quality improvements;</text>
              </subclause>
            </clause>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H2FAC3A3E6D6B4500B36E4F72D102A93B">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>with respect to the timing of implementation of water quality-related improvements—</text>
            <clause id="H8018BABB9C424760B694E14379C73FEE">
              <enum>(i)</enum>
              <text>environmental improvement implementation schedules should be structured to mitigate the potential adverse impact on distressed populations resulting from the costs of the improvements;</text>
            </clause>
            <clause id="H2C6235CC8F5043DFB06E7975D2891311">
              <enum>(ii)</enum>
              <text>implementation schedules should reflect local community financial conditions and economic impacts;</text>
            </clause>
            <clause id="HE75E7C8173DC406981EB65993D126E07">
              <enum>(iii)</enum>
              <text>implementation schedules should allow permittees up to 30 years to implement water quality-related improvements in appropriate cases in which the cost of implementing the improvements places a high financial burden on the permittee; and</text>
            </clause>
            <clause id="HD29746762D3F406B8A66BFF475A2F2F3">
              <enum>(iv)</enum>
              <text>existing implementation schedules should be modified in appropriate cases taking into consideration the criteria set forth in this subparagraph;</text>
            </clause>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="HEDDAC15FE57542F0A157409054A889FF">
            <enum>(C)</enum>
            <text>with respect to implementation—</text>
            <clause id="H524F7A7B0AA24F7697E13F0201E694CD">
              <enum>(i)</enum>
              <text>a determination of local financial capability may be achieved through an evaluation of an array of factors the relative importance of which may vary across regions and localities; and</text>
            </clause>
            <clause id="H50402678BC6845F7867AF892D680A7EA">
              <enum>(ii)</enum>
              <text>an appropriate methodology should give consideration to such various factors as are appropriate to recognize the prevailing and projected economic concerns in a community; and</text>
            </clause>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H21A623710A2441BF99F3E842D9C1F6BE">
            <enum>(D)</enum>
            <text>the residential indicator should be revised to include—</text>
            <clause id="HF5EA28F22DD24159B9408D50FAFC7989">
              <enum>(i)</enum>
              <text>a consideration of costs imposed upon ratepayers for essential utilities;</text>
            </clause>
            <clause id="H2F745D853035479DA1C5A78B290E854D">
              <enum>(ii)</enum>
              <text>increased consideration and quantification of local community-imposed costs in regional systems;</text>
            </clause>
            <clause id="H749976207E9E4859A6DCBF6CE9A63030">
              <enum>(iii)</enum>
              <text>a mechanism to assess impacts on communities with disparate economic conditions throughout the entire service area of a utility;</text>
            </clause>
            <clause id="H92E109821697490597EBF5B5BDA41F3E">
              <enum>(iv)</enum>
              <text>a consideration of the industrial and population trends of a community;</text>
            </clause>
            <clause id="H9474945B76FC4584A2F14CCD3A235A00">
              <enum>(v)</enum>
              <text>recognition that—</text>
              <subclause id="HACAE7D041DCC40FAB5CD7C448A057370">
                <enum>(I)</enum>
                <text>the median household income of a service area reflects a numerical median rather than the distribution of incomes within the service area; and</text>
              </subclause>
              <subclause id="H5C6937056EA5409E8189EF5CBC8DB7EA">
                <enum>(II)</enum>
                <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">more representative methods of determining affordability, such as shelter costs, essential utility payments, State affordability criteria, and State and local tax efforts, should be considered;</text>
              </subclause>
            </clause>
            <clause id="H3669A30ACE8549ED8AFD3C374DB9AA6A">
              <enum>(vi)</enum>
              <text>a consideration of low-income ratepayer percentages; and</text>
            </clause>
            <clause id="H61ACC7393AE54906B85163D21B1305F8">
              <enum>(vii)</enum>
              <text>impacts relating to program delivery, such as water quality infrastructure market saturation and program management.</text>
            </clause>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H4D7BFC3B2BE846D28A5F3A4165CCF866">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <header>Implementation</header>
          <text>The updated guidance should indicate that, in a case in which a previously approved long-term control plan or associated enforceable agreement does not prohibit modification of the plan or terms of the agreement (including financial capability considerations), and all parties are in agreement that a change is needed or that the plan or agreement does not prohibit reopening to address changes in the economic or financial status of the community since the effective date of the plan or agreement, reconsideration and modification of financial capability determinations and implementation schedules based on the criteria described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Clean Water Affordability Act of 2014/s:3/ss:b/p:2" proposed="true">paragraph (2)</cato:entity-ref> is appropriate.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HBECE86E4A72447138C8F38DD60C3BF23">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
          <header>Applicability</header>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="6800">Administrator</cato:entity-ref> shall apply the updated guidance, including the criteria described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Clean Water Affordability Act of 2014/s:3/ss:b/p:2" proposed="true">paragraph (2)</cato:entity-ref>, to each determination and analysis of affordability, financial capability, or widespread and substantial economic impact related to implementation of a program under the <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Federal Water Pollution Control Act">Federal Water Pollution Control Act</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/1251">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/33/1251/etseq">33 U.S.C. 1251 et seq</cato:entity-ref>.</external-xref>)</cato:entity>.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="H1C82C8D1D5C945B8B3389F2B049B478D">
        <enum>(c)</enum>
        <header>Publication and submission</header>
        <text>Upon completion of the updating of guidance under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Clean Water Affordability Act of 2014/s:3/ss:b" proposed="true">subsection (b)</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="6800">Administrator</cato:entity-ref> shall publish in the Federal Register and submit to the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="committee" entity-id="SSEV00">Committee on Environment and Public Works of the Senate</cato:entity-ref> and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="committee" entity-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives</cato:entity-ref> the updated guidance.</text>
      </subsection>
    </section>
    <section id="HAE33378DEF1A4FADAB11DC8DE6BCC915">
      <enum>4.</enum>
      <header>Capitalization grant agreements</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">
        <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
          <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Federal Water Pollution Control Act/s:602/ss:b">Section 602(b) of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/1382">
          <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/33/1382/b">33 U.S.C. 1382(b)</cato:entity-ref>
        </external-xref>)</cato:entity> is amended—</text>
      <paragraph id="H46B59BBE48FB4CD28DA0634F8C63F743">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text>by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end of <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Federal Water Pollution Control Act/s:602/ss:b/p:9">paragraph (9)</cato:entity-ref>;</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H59C6EDCCBEE346899FD70AD35AC05BE5">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text>by striking the period at the end of <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Federal Water Pollution Control Act/s:602/ss:b/p:10">paragraph (10)</cato:entity-ref> and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HC9696C31087649D2A40F802A621F7D88">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <text>by adding at the end the following:</text>
        <quoted-block id="HC3AF3506A58F4EBAA1D3D2FBE49C9F9E" style="OLC">
          <paragraph id="H0EF679E1ED18461F9402BA78C2A10557">
            <enum>(11)</enum>
            <text>the State will use at least 15 percent of the amount of each capitalization grant received by the State under this title after September 30, 2015, to provide assistance to municipalities of fewer than 10,000 individuals that meet the affordability criteria established by the State under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Federal Water Pollution Control Act/s:603/ss:i/p:2" proposed="true">section 603(i)(2)</cato:entity-ref> for activities included on the State’s priority list established under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Federal Water Pollution Control Act/s:603/ss:g">section 603(g)</cato:entity-ref>, to the extent that there are sufficient applications for such assistance.</text>
          </paragraph>
          <after-quoted-block>. </after-quoted-block>
        </quoted-block>
      </paragraph>
    </section>
    <section id="H0C22E61BD99D4624A6FDF807A8D3A4C7">
      <enum>5.</enum>
      <header>Water pollution control revolving loan funds</header>
      <subsection id="HC1E367F23FDD41BAADE20806AC76C747">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Extended Repayment Period</header>
        <text>
          <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Federal Water Pollution Control Act/s:603/ss:d/p:1">Section 603(d)(1) of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/1383">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/33/1383/d/1">33 U.S.C. 1383(d)(1)</cato:entity-ref>
          </external-xref>)</cato:entity> is amended—</text>
        <paragraph id="HD1914C4AD1F543C4B5127AC820EDBEB1">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Federal Water Pollution Control Act/s:603/ss:d/p:1/sp:A">subparagraph (A)</cato:entity-ref> by striking <quote>20 years</quote> and inserting <quote>the lesser of 30 years or the design life of the project to be financed with the proceeds of the loan</quote>; and</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H140A7CDCEF4441418E23705CADFBD3BF">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Federal Water Pollution Control Act/s:603/ss:d/p:1/sp:B">subparagraph (B)</cato:entity-ref> by striking <quote>not later than 20 years after project completion</quote> and inserting <quote>upon the expiration of the term of the loan</quote>.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="H5CC5BB2BB4244A9398039A0542CAE209">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Additional Subsidization</header>
        <text>
          <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Federal Water Pollution Control Act/s:603">Section 603 of such Act</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/1383">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/33/1383">33 U.S.C. 1383</cato:entity-ref>
          </external-xref>)</cato:entity> is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
        <quoted-block id="HFD586D200A4E44F792088658FD070AAE" style="OLC">
          <subsection id="H36BDDD5643F04611965DA119AB6B385A">
            <enum>(i)</enum>
            <header>Additional Subsidization</header>
            <paragraph id="H822F9ADDD1854334BA7F896F16DA2D1A">
              <enum>(1)</enum>
              <header>In general</header>
              <text>In any case in which a State provides assistance to a municipality or intermunicipal, interstate, or State agency under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Federal Water Pollution Control Act/s:603/ss:d">subsection (d)</cato:entity-ref>, the State may provide additional subsidization, including forgiveness of principal, negative interest loans, and grants to benefit a municipality that—</text>
              <subparagraph id="HFC0DD94931B04E5F9DA3F7643967C04B">
                <enum>(A)</enum>
                <text>meets the State’s affordability criteria established under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Federal Water Pollution Control Act/s:603/ss:i/p:2" proposed="true">paragraph (2)</cato:entity-ref>; or</text>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="H3FA40D1824AB4DE99BFE93D781E9AB7D">
                <enum>(B)</enum>
                <text>does not meet the State’s affordability criteria if the recipient—</text>
                <clause id="H21F57107391E40CF9166F1D785EF855C">
                  <enum>(i)</enum>
                  <text>seeks additional subsidization to benefit individual ratepayers in the residential user rate class; and</text>
                </clause>
                <clause id="HA93BAAE3341E40FAAE38AD00D5A8CC6D">
                  <enum>(ii)</enum>
                  <text>demonstrates to the State that such ratepayers will experience a significant hardship from the increase in rates necessary to finance the project or activity for which assistance is sought.</text>
                </clause>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph commented="no" id="H9EDC5F243DD84F1BAB1058EC47705D74">
              <enum>(2)</enum>
              <header>Affordability criteria</header>
              <subparagraph commented="no" id="H492B81CB06A641C88BA95886794B4ED0">
                <enum>(A)</enum>
                <header>Establishment</header>
                <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">On or before September 30, 2015, and after providing notice and an opportunity for public comment, a State shall establish affordability criteria to assist in identifying municipalities that would experience a significant hardship raising the revenue necessary to finance a project or activity eligible for assistance under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Federal Water Pollution Control Act/s:603/ss:c/p:1">section 603(c)(1)</cato:entity-ref> if additional subsidization is not provided. Such criteria shall be based on income data, population trends, and other data determined relevant by the State, including whether the project or activity is to be carried out in an economically distressed area, as described in <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
                    <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Public Works and Economic Development Act of 1965/s:301">section 301 of the Public Works and Economic Development Act of 1965</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/3161">
                    <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/42/3161">42 U.S.C. 3161</cato:entity-ref>
                  </external-xref>)</cato:entity>.</text>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph commented="no" id="H4C2560E4E9EB430BBA91E74E291CFA68">
                <enum>(B)</enum>
                <header>Existing criteria</header>
                <text>If a State has previously established, after providing notice and an opportunity for public comment, affordability criteria that meet the requirements of <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Federal Water Pollution Control Act/s:603/ss:i/p:2/sp:A" proposed="true">subparagraph (A)</cato:entity-ref>, the State may use the criteria for the purposes of this subsection. For purposes of this Act, any such criteria shall be treated as affordability criteria established under this paragraph.</text>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph commented="no" id="H33EB745141CC4E18890AECC2E311BBA9">
                <enum>(C)</enum>
                <header>Information to assist States</header>
                <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="6800">Administrator</cato:entity-ref> may publish information to assist States in establishing affordability criteria under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Federal Water Pollution Control Act/s:603/ss:i/p:2/sp:A" proposed="true">subparagraph (A)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="HB44EC5D41AF94B22828E18899DF0D947">
              <enum>(3)</enum>
              <header>Use of capitalization grants</header>
              <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A State shall use not less than 20 percent but not more than 30 percent of the amount of the capitalization grants received by the State under this title in fiscal years beginning after September 30, 2015, to provide additional subsidization to eligible recipients under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Federal Water Pollution Control Act/s:603/ss:i/p:1" proposed="true">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
        </quoted-block>
      </subsection>
    </section>
  </legis-body>
</bill>
</doc>