<doc>
  <docmeta id="113hr1715ih">
    <bill congress="113" type="hr" number="1715" version="ih"/>
    <revision size="13234" annotations="0" status="complete" id="7" commit-time="2013-05-14T18:48:46Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113hr1715ih/7.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H67422069B6E249DE84C12938ECA9DCF6" public-private="public" bill-type="olc">
  <metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dublinCore>
      <dc:title>113 HR 1715 IH: Expedited Consideration of Cuts, Consolidations, and Savings Act of 2013</dc:title>
      <dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
      <dc:date>2013-04-24</dc:date>
      <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
      <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
      <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    </dublinCore>
  </metadata>
  <form>
    <distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
    <congress>113th CONGRESS</congress>
    <session>1st Session</session>
    <legis-num>H. R. 1715</legis-num>
    <current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
    <action>
      <action-date date="20130424">April 24, 2013</action-date>
      <action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="P000595">Mr. Peters of Michigan</sponsor>(for himself,<cosponsor name-id="G000562">Mr. Gardner</cosponsor>,<cosponsor name-id="C001083">Mr. Carney</cosponsor>, and<cosponsor name-id="P000598">Mr. Polis</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the<committee-name committee-id="HBU00">Committee on the Budget</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on<committee-name committee-id="HRU00">Rules</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
    </action>
    <legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
    <official-title>To establish procedures for the expedited consideration by Congress of the recommendations set forth in the Cuts, Consolidations, and Savings report prepared by the Office of Management and Budget.</official-title>
  </form>
  <legis-body id="H61D19DD72F5A422691C4707468C4780B" style="OLC">
    <section id="H061BB211564945E99C969927D8129BC7" section-type="section-one">
      <enum>1.</enum>
      <header>Short title</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the<quote>
          <short-title>Expedited Consideration of Cuts, Consolidations, and Savings Act of 2013</short-title>
        </quote>.</text>
    </section>
    <section id="H3A4B0160975E4CB8B993EEB0CE59B703">
      <enum>2.</enum>
      <header>Expedited consideration of Cuts, Consolidations, and Savings prepared by the Office of Management and Budget</header>
      <subsection id="H700F35ED834046AC9DD55DD98535C88F">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>In General</header>
        <text>
          <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Congressional Budget and Impoundment Control Act of 1974/t:X/pt:B">Part B of title X of the Congressional Budget and Impoundment Control Act of 1974</cato:entity-ref>(<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/681">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/2/681/etseq">2 U.S.C. 681 et seq.</cato:entity-ref>
            </external-xref>)</cato:entity>is amended by redesignating<cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Congressional Budget and Impoundment Control Act of 1974/s:1013..1017">sections 1013 through 1017</cato:entity-ref>as<cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Congressional Budget and Impoundment Control Act of 1974/s:1014..1018" proposed="true">sections 1014 through 1018</cato:entity-ref>, respectively, and inserting after<cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Congressional Budget and Impoundment Control Act of 1974/s:1012">section 1012</cato:entity-ref>the following new section:</text>
        <quoted-block id="H036C6C50690F498F812FCCFB802D1D5A" style="traditional">
          <section id="HEACED5567D48499087E6FD02337786B3">
            <enum>1013.</enum>
            <header>Cuts, Consolidations, and Savings prepared by the Office of Management and Budget</header>
            <subsection commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H3F70F26376FB46F0A5EEB00C857C26DD">
              <enum>(a)</enum>
              <header>In general</header>
              <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President may propose, at the time and in the manner provided in<cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Congressional Budget and Impoundment Control Act of 1974/s:1013/ss:b" proposed="true">subsection (b)</cato:entity-ref>, the carrying out of all or part of the recommendations contained in the most recent Cuts, Consolidations, and Savings prepared by the Office of Management and Budget.</text>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="HC76984BBB52A48C99F71CF4F67DDF5C9">
              <enum>(b)</enum>
              <header>Transmittal of Special Message</header>
              <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 120 days after the publication of any Cuts, Consolidations, and Savings prepared by the<cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1103">Office of Management and Budget</cato:entity-ref>, the<cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref>may transmit to<cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref>a special message to carry out all or part of the recommendations contained in that Cuts, Consolidations, and Savings. The<cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref>shall include with that special message a draft bill or joint resolution that would carry out his recommendations.</text>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="H7A587E538F3C4938AE3F44B1F74BFFD3">
              <enum>(c)</enum>
              <header>Procedures for Expedited Consideration</header>
              <paragraph id="HA0A70E5223EC48B991F2E934992027E4">
                <enum>(1)</enum>
                <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H6348A5F06711466E82775908FF6641B6">
                  <enum>(A)</enum>
                  <text>Before the close of the second day of continuous session of the applicable House after the date of receipt of a special message transmitted to<cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref>under<cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Congressional Budget and Impoundment Control Act of 1974/s:1013/ss:b" proposed="true">subsection (b)</cato:entity-ref>, the majority leader or minority leader of the House of Congress in which the Act involved originated shall introduce (by request) the draft bill or joint resolution accompanying that special message. If the bill or joint resolution is not introduced as provided in the preceding sentence, then, on the third day of continuous session of that House after the date of receipt of that special message, any Member of that House may introduce the bill or joint resolution.</text>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="HBBA73B678A9D41FA8741B915F3531197" indent="up1">
                  <enum>(B)</enum>
                  <text>The bill or joint resolution shall be referred to the committee or committees with subject matter jurisdiction over that measure. The committee or committees shall report the bill or joint resolution without substantive revision and with or without recommendation. The bill or joint resolution shall be reported not later than the seventh day of continuous session of that House after the date of receipt of that special message. If a committee fails to report the bill or joint resolution within that period, that committee shall be automatically discharged from consideration of the bill or joint resolution, and the bill or joint resolution shall be placed on the appropriate calendar.</text>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="HF48F6FE08D784EBDBCC8B7717C7ECA4A" indent="up1">
                  <enum>(C)</enum>
                  <text>A vote on final passage of the bill or joint resolution shall be taken in that House on or before the close of the 10th calendar day of continuous session of that House after the date of the introduction of the bill or joint resolution in that House. If the bill or joint resolution is agreed to, the Clerk of the House of Representatives (in the case of a bill or joint resolution agreed to in the<cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0050">House of Representatives</cato:entity-ref>) or the<cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Secretary of the Senate" entity-parent-id="0010">Secretary of the Senate</cato:entity-ref>(in the case of a bill or joint resolution agreed to in the<cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0010">Senate</cato:entity-ref>) shall cause the bill or joint resolution to be engrossed, certified, and transmitted to the other House of Congress on the same calendar day on which the bill or joint resolution is agreed to.</text>
                </subparagraph>
              </paragraph>
              <paragraph id="H3A668A5DBD5E4EB5A5B1445EC0AA4DB9">
                <enum>(2)</enum>
                <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H48359190861943748A84BC03C3149346">
                  <enum>(A)</enum>
                  <text>A bill or joint resolution transmitted to the House of Representatives or the Senate pursuant to<cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Congressional Budget and Impoundment Control Act of 1974/s:1013/ss:c/p:1/sp:C" proposed="true">paragraph (1)(C)</cato:entity-ref>shall be referred to the committee or committees of jurisdiction of that House. The committee or committees shall report the bill or joint resolution without substantive revision and with or without recommendation. The bill or joint resolution shall be reported not later than the seventh day of continuous session of that House after it receives the bill or joint resolution. A committee failing to report the bill or joint resolution within such period shall be automatically discharged from consideration of the bill or joint resolution, and the bill or joint resolution shall be placed upon the appropriate calendar.</text>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="H038B714F2865475C9ABEDA2FC89900D6" indent="up1">
                  <enum>(B)</enum>
                  <text>A vote on final passage of a bill or joint resolution transmitted to that House shall be taken on or before the close of the 10th calendar day of continuous session of that House after the date on which the bill or joint resolution is transmitted. If the bill or joint resolution is agreed to in that House, the<cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Clerk of the House of Representatives" entity-parent-id="0050">Clerk of the House of Representatives</cato:entity-ref>(in the case of a bill or joint resolution agreed to in the<cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0050">House of Representatives</cato:entity-ref>) or the<cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Secretary of the Senate" entity-parent-id="0010">Secretary of the Senate</cato:entity-ref>(in the case of a bill or joint resolution agreed to in the<cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0010">Senate</cato:entity-ref>) shall cause the engrossed bill or joint resolution to be returned to the House in which the bill or joint resolution originated.</text>
                </subparagraph>
              </paragraph>
              <paragraph id="H3CB00AE239F545D9BD8524CF7675030A">
                <enum>(3)</enum>
                <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HD535654982B847118D165951B9CA91B3">
                  <enum>(A)</enum>
                  <text>A motion in the<cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0050">House of Representatives</cato:entity-ref>to proceed to the consideration of a bill or joint resolution under this section shall be highly privileged and not debatable. An amendment to the motion shall not be in order, nor shall it be in order to move to reconsider the vote by which the motion is agreed to or disagreed to.</text>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="HF169F7B51E8C4132B7D4E4C715FA065A" indent="up1">
                  <enum>(B)</enum>
                  <text>Debate in the<cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0050">House of Representatives</cato:entity-ref>on a bill or joint resolution under this section shall not exceed 4 hours, which shall be divided equally between those favoring and those opposing the bill or joint resolution. A motion further to limit debate shall not be debatable. It shall not be in order to move to recommit a bill or joint resolution under this section or to move to reconsider the vote by which the bill or joint resolution is agreed to or disagreed to.</text>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="HC56A449FEA874022A6AF3E366E2D68AF" indent="up1">
                  <enum>(C)</enum>
                  <text>Appeals from decisions of the Chair relating to the application of the Rules of the House of Representatives to the procedure relating to a bill or joint resolution under this section shall be decided without debate.</text>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="HA156CDE0254744D8A950E7193420EF4A" indent="up1">
                  <enum>(D)</enum>
                  <text>Except to the extent specifically provided in the preceding provisions of this subsection, consideration of a bill or joint resolution under this section shall be governed by the Rules of the House of Representatives.</text>
                </subparagraph>
              </paragraph>
              <paragraph id="H360227391E81436995D27868A69D83B7">
                <enum>(4)</enum>
                <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H3BCC279908F648049D615EEF792A73D5">
                  <enum>(A)</enum>
                  <text>A motion in the<cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0010">Senate</cato:entity-ref>to proceed to the consideration of a bill or joint resolution under this section shall be privileged and not debatable. An amendment to the motion shall not be in order, nor shall it be in order to move to reconsider the vote by which the motion is agreed to or disagreed to.</text>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="H19E6C936C75B4E9E8E7C374FB598242C" indent="up1">
                  <enum>(B)</enum>
                  <text>Debate in the<cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0010">Senate</cato:entity-ref>on a bill or joint resolution under this section, and all debatable motions and appeals in connection therewith, shall not exceed 10 hours. The time shall be equally divided between, and controlled by, the majority leader and the minority leader or their designees.</text>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="H0BC68DBCFD254506B4548E5E9553EFDC" indent="up1">
                  <enum>(C)</enum>
                  <text>Debate in the<cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0010">Senate</cato:entity-ref>on any debatable motion or appeal in connection with a bill or joint resolution under this section shall be limited to not more than 1 hour, to be equally divided between, and controlled by, the mover and the manager of the bill or joint resolution, except that in the event the manager of the bill or joint resolution is in favor of any such motion or appeal, the time in opposition thereto, shall be controlled by the minority leader or his designee. Such leaders, or either of them, may, from time under their control on the passage of a bill or joint resolution, allot additional time to any Senator during the consideration of any debatable motion or appeal.</text>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="H2346011BB68D4E488ADF0EAD738CDAFB" indent="up1">
                  <enum>(D)</enum>
                  <text>A motion in the<cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0010">Senate</cato:entity-ref>to further limit debate on a bill or joint resolution under this section is not debatable. A motion to recommit a bill or joint resolution under this section is not in order.</text>
                </subparagraph>
              </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="H720914F3C94849AD8A422C4A41BB6D59">
              <enum>(d)</enum>
              <header>Amendments Prohibited</header>
              <text>No amendment to a bill or joint resolution considered under this section shall be in order in either the<cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0050">House of Representatives</cato:entity-ref>or the<cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0010">Senate</cato:entity-ref>. No motion to suspend the application of this subsection shall be in order in either House, nor shall it be in order in either House to suspend the application of this subsection by unanimous consent.</text>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="HD349C7FB04A0413AA408E489E5B6CF70">
              <enum>(e)</enum>
              <header>Definitions</header>
              <text>For purposes of this section continuity of a session of either House of Congress shall be considered as broken only by an adjournment of that House sine die, and the days on which that House is not in session because of an adjournment of more than 3 days to a date certain shall be excluded in the computation of any period.</text>
            </subsection>
          </section>
          <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
        </quoted-block>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="HC4EE40019EFF40DDA7F135DE9BA8D7E7">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Exercise of Rulemaking Powers</header>
        <text>
          <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Congressional Budget and Impoundment Control Act of 1974/s:904">Section 904 of such Act</cato:entity-ref>(<cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/2/621/note">
              <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/621">2 U.S.C. 621</external-xref>note</cato:entity-ref>)</cato:entity>is amended—</text>
        <paragraph id="H1822FB8262C24B59A00A3827462DC058">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>by striking<quote>and 1017</quote>in<cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Congressional Budget and Impoundment Control Act of 1974/s:904/ss:a">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref>and inserting<quote>1013, and 1018</quote>; and</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HAD81758D3A6E4DC993FCE795D3B775DC">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>by striking<quote>section 1017</quote>in<cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Congressional Budget and Impoundment Control Act of 1974/s:904/ss:d">subsection (d)</cato:entity-ref>and inserting<quote>sections 1013 and 1018</quote>.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="HEFF0DCBC2C3F472AA9E7E99468A319FD">
        <enum>(c)</enum>
        <header>Conforming Amendments</header>
        <paragraph id="H16DCB75BAEB443B98960699C21D457CC">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>
            <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Congressional Budget and Impoundment Control Act of 1974/s:1011">Section 1011 of such Act</cato:entity-ref>(<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/682">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/2/682//5">2 U.S.C. 682(5)</cato:entity-ref>
              </external-xref>)</cato:entity>is amended—</text>
          <subparagraph id="H866BBC4F78E3478ABAA9D6BFA2240179">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>in<cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Congressional Budget and Impoundment Control Act of 1974/s:1011/p:4">paragraph (4)</cato:entity-ref>, by striking<quote>1013</quote>and inserting<quote>1014</quote>; and</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="HF0E5E06EA3174796A55BE67F690049F7">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>in<cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Congressional Budget and Impoundment Control Act of 1974/s:1011/p:5">paragraph (5)</cato:entity-ref>—</text>
            <clause id="H046E5D68114D470C820DA6B56BEA6693">
              <enum>(i)</enum>
              <text>by striking<quote>1016</quote>and inserting<quote>1017</quote>; and</text>
            </clause>
            <clause id="HE9527599F90E49F6A07A84DEE93C36AD">
              <enum>(ii)</enum>
              <text>by striking<quote>1017(b)(1)</quote>and inserting<quote>1018(b)(1)</quote>.</text>
            </clause>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H486051AA47984D0E99CFE8F27C34DA20">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>
            <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Congressional Budget and Impoundment Control Act of 1974/s:1015">Section 1015 of such Act</cato:entity-ref>(<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/685">2 U.S.C. 685</external-xref>)</cato:entity>(as redesignated by<cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Expedited Consideration of Cuts, Consolidations, and Savings Act of 2013/s:2/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref>) is amended—</text>
          <subparagraph id="HCDCCFC873BC8467298001F4CD6C1AA72">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>by striking<quote>1012 or 1013</quote>each place it appears and inserting<quote>1012, 1013, or 1014</quote>;</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H3B8799755EBF40E49106945D3BE5E1D0">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>in<cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Congressional Budget and Impoundment Control Act of 1974/s:1015/ss:b/p:1">subsection (b)(1)</cato:entity-ref>, by striking<quote>1012</quote>and inserting<quote>1012 or 1013</quote>;</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="HC4287CF3E92E492FB8715D25455F4D06">
            <enum>(C)</enum>
            <text>in<cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Congressional Budget and Impoundment Control Act of 1974/s:1015/ss:b/p:2">subsection (b)(2)</cato:entity-ref>, by striking<quote>1013</quote>and inserting<quote>1014</quote>; and</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H80860D17683044C884A6C24754963069">
            <enum>(D)</enum>
            <text>in<cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Congressional Budget and Impoundment Control Act of 1974/s:1015/ss:e/p:2">subsection (e)(2)</cato:entity-ref>—</text>
            <clause id="H791DD7712D4C4F769DD45DA817EB97B4">
              <enum>(i)</enum>
              <text>by striking<quote>and</quote>at the end of<cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Congressional Budget and Impoundment Control Act of 1974/s:1015/ss:e/p:2/sp:A">subparagraph (A)</cato:entity-ref>;</text>
            </clause>
            <clause id="H97AD04E06F13405D8D4FC9A40DA8674C">
              <enum>(ii)</enum>
              <text>by redesignating<cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Congressional Budget and Impoundment Control Act of 1974/s:1015/ss:e/p:2/sp:B">subparagraph (B)</cato:entity-ref>as<cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Congressional Budget and Impoundment Control Act of 1974/s:1015/ss:e/p:2/sp:C" proposed="true">subparagraph (C)</cato:entity-ref>;</text>
            </clause>
            <clause id="H56760200073A4AC9A4F69A33DA484345">
              <enum>(iii)</enum>
              <text>by striking<quote>1013</quote>in<cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Congressional Budget and Impoundment Control Act of 1974/s:1015/ss:e/p:2/sp:C" proposed="true">subparagraph (C)</cato:entity-ref>(as so redesignated) and inserting<quote>1014</quote>; and</text>
            </clause>
            <clause id="HA5254DE5ABC9408C8F26FA1972FE52E7">
              <enum>(iv)</enum>
              <text>by inserting after<cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Congressional Budget and Impoundment Control Act of 1974/s:1015/ss:e/p:2/sp:A">subparagraph (A)</cato:entity-ref>the following new subparagraph:</text>
              <quoted-block id="HC8DDEE1CC7814FD3BF0D9E7E1BDCEE79" style="OLC">
                <subparagraph id="H333363BB98234566968B5B7FF49CFFF2">
                  <enum>(B)</enum>
                  <text>he has transmitted a special message under<cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Congressional Budget and Impoundment Control Act of 1974/s:1013">section 1013</cato:entity-ref>with respect to a proposed rescission; and</text>
                </subparagraph>
                <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
              </quoted-block>
            </clause>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="HB8AC58E175B9446A99F86A7452F3B827">
        <enum>(d)</enum>
        <header>Clerical Amendments</header>
        <text>The table of sections for<cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Congressional Budget and Impoundment Control Act of 1974/t:X/spt:B">subpart B of title X of such Act</cato:entity-ref>is amended—</text>
        <paragraph id="HFEB19BC912E24B9F87429BE651858194">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>by redesignating the items relating to<cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Congressional Budget and Impoundment Control Act of 1974/s:1013..1017">sections 1013 through 1017</cato:entity-ref>as items relating to<cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Congressional Budget and Impoundment Control Act of 1974/s:1014..1018" proposed="true">sections 1014 through 1018</cato:entity-ref>; and</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HB8C3C59ECD2343E4A8B2AF7ED04D471B">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>by inserting after the item relating to<cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Congressional Budget and Impoundment Control Act of 1974/s:1012">section 1012</cato:entity-ref>the following new item:</text>
          <quoted-block id="H1F91C34C24B64DF0822C9A4915BC864A" style="OLC">
            <toc regeneration="no-regeneration">
              <toc-entry level="section">Sec. 1013. Expedited consideration of certain proposed rescissions.</toc-entry>
            </toc>
            <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
          </quoted-block>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
    </section>
    <section id="H6A0718839DE542F9AB3294490B4B4021">
      <enum>3.</enum>
      <header>Termination</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">The authority provided by<cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Congressional Budget and Impoundment Control Act of 1974/s:1013">section 1013 of the Congressional Budget and Impoundment Control Act of 1974</cato:entity-ref>(as added by<cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Expedited Consideration of Cuts, Consolidations, and Savings Act of 2013/s:2" proposed="true">section 2</cato:entity-ref>) shall terminate effective on the date in 2018 on which the Congress adjourns sine die.</text>
    </section>
  </legis-body>
</bill>
</doc>