<doc>
  <docmeta id="113hres668ih">
    <bill congress="113" type="hres" number="668" version="ih"/>
    <revision size="3223" annotations="0" status="complete" id="4" commit-time="2014-07-22T21:07:00Z" committer="zwilliams" doc="113hres668ih/4.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <resolution xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" dms-id="HECE9D80F82274D5796157E7A36DD9FF1" key="H" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print">
	<metadata>
<dublinCore>
<dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">113 HRES 668 IH: Supporting the goals and ideals of the Community Development Block Grant program.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">2014-07-14</dc:date>
<dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">113th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session display="yes">2d Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. RES. 668</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20140714">July 14, 2014</action-date>
			<action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="F000043">Mr. Fattah</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="T000463">Mr. Turner</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000312">Mr. McGovern</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001269">Mr. Barletta</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001227">Mr. Brady of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="G000564">Mr. Gibson</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name>
      </action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">Supporting the goals and ideals of the Community Development Block Grant program.</official-title>
	</form>
	<preamble>
		<whereas>
      <text>Whereas the Community Development Block Grant (CDBG) program is a Federal program administered by
			 the <cato:entity-ref entity-id="8600" entity-type="federal-body">Department of Housing and Urban Development</cato:entity-ref> and provides direct grants
			 to States and local governments for the purposes of economic and community
			 development;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the CDBG program was established under <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Housing and Community Development Act of 1974/t:I">title I of the Housing and Community Development Act
			 of 1974</cato:entity-ref>;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas this grant program was signed into law by President Gerald R. Ford on August 22, 1974, and
			 is among the longest running grant programs in our Nation’s history;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas this grant program assists more than 1,200 State and local governments each year;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas this grant program allows grantees flexibility in tackling unique and complex challenges
			 facing their communities;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the CDBG program has invested over $145 billion in urban, suburban, and rural economies
			 since its inception;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas CDBG funding is used to leverage other funds from the private sector, non-profit
			 organizations, and State and local governments;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas every CDBG dollar invested in communities leverages, on average, $4.07 in other funds;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas between fiscal years 2005 and 2013 this program has created or retained approximately
			 330,500 jobs;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the CDBG program has funded public improvements benefitting States and local communities;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas between fiscal years 2005 and 2013, the CDBG program provided public services to over 100
			 million people and assisted more than 1 million households;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the CDBG program has been used to assist communities in the aftermath of natural disasters
			 and in the midst of economic crises; and</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the CDBG program provides the largest amount of Federal assistance to State and local
			 governments for development efforts: Now, therefore, be it</text>
    </whereas>
  </preamble>
	<resolution-body id="H884C99DCC8594CB5BD079629FBEBFA78" style="traditional">
		<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HB4DE22AE076E4B34BA47C9EF02F1F266" section-type="undesignated-section">
      <enum/>
      <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the <cato:entity-ref entity-id="0050" entity-type="federal-body">House of Representatives</cato:entity-ref>—</text>
			<paragraph id="HD9B7051694084DBB86DFE84CCF0760D9">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text>supports the goals and ideals of the Community Development Block Grant program, now in its 40th
			 year of continuous service;</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H6E9C17B8D3E147D3868D0CD9BB2C7D15">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text>recognizes the benefits the CDBG program has provided to urban, suburban, and rural communities;
			 and</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HA69E1CD83F8B442785FF7078FB5114A1">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <text>acknowledges the importance of this Federal grant program to States and local communities
			 throughout the United States.</text>
			</paragraph>
    </section>
  </resolution-body>
</resolution>
</doc>