<doc>
  <docmeta id="113hr3633ih">
    <bill congress="113" type="hr" number="3633" version="ih"/>
    <revision size="1758" annotations="0" status="complete" id="3" commit-time="2013-12-09T02:52:22Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113hr3633ih/3.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H454AABFA15014BC9927A1BDA05BF401C" public-private="public">
  <metadata>
<dublinCore>
<dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">113 HR 3633 IH: Protecting Health Care Providers from Increased Administrative Burdens Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">2013-12-03</dc:date>
<dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
    <congress>113th CONGRESS</congress>
    <session>1st Session</session>
    <legis-num>H. R. 3633</legis-num>
    <current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
    <action>
      <action-date date="20131203">December 3, 2013</action-date>
      <action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="W000798">Mr. Walberg</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and the Workforce</committee-name>
      </action-desc>
    </action>
    <legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
    <official-title>To clarify that certain recipients of payments from the Federal Government related to the delivery of health care services to individuals shall not be treated as Federal contractors by the Office of Federal Contract Compliance Programs based on the work performed or actions taken by such individuals that resulted in the receipt of such payments.</official-title>
  </form>
  <legis-body id="H99F3674CFA0C4BB6B68CF019E58AA751" style="OLC">
    <section id="H65A07449046F4ABE9300F844E6476443" section-type="section-one">
      <enum>1.</enum>
      <header>Short title</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote>
          <short-title>Protecting Health Care Providers from Increased Administrative Burdens Act</short-title>
        </quote>.</text>
    </section>
    <section id="H8F8532D2CD1747FA9536E89F7735E772">
      <enum>2.</enum>
      <header>Non-Federal contractor status for entities receiving certain health care-related Federal payments</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">A State, a local government, or other recipient that receives a payment from the Federal Government, directly or indirectly and regardless of reimbursement methodology, related to the delivery of health care services to individuals, whether or not such individuals are or have been employed by the Federal Government, shall not be treated as a Federal contractor or subcontractor by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Office of Federal Contract Compliance Programs" entity-parent-id="1600">Office of Federal Contract Compliance Programs</cato:entity-ref> based on the work performed or actions taken by such individuals that resulted in the receipt of such payments.</text>
    </section>
  </legis-body>
</bill>
</doc>