<doc>
  <docmeta id="113hr3243ih">
    <bill congress="113" type="hr" number="3243" version="ih"/>
    <revision size="28982" annotations="0" status="complete" id="6" commit-time="2013-10-09T19:24:36Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113hr3243ih/6.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HB7E2D8C1FDCE40F0A6CEF0979686CF07" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata>
<dublinCore>
<title>113 HR 3243 IH: Supporting Teachers and Enhancing Manufacturing (STEM) Jobs Act of 2013</title>
<publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</publisher>
<date>2013-10-04</date>
<format>text/xml</format>
<language>EN</language>
<rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>113th CONGRESS</congress>
<session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. R. 3243</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20131004">October 4, 2013</action-date> 
<action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="E000293">Ms. Esty</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and the Workforce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To provide support for K–12 teacher professional development programs at the National Science Foundation and the Department of Education in the areas of science, technology, engineering, and mathematics education, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H3E68BDAA49E8408093F272AD5927FE03" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HFF6EE5E60E7146DAA431FFBE5EA1CF65" section-type="section-one">
      <enum>1.</enum>
      <header>Short title</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote>
          <short-title>Supporting Teachers and Enhancing Manufacturing (STEM) Jobs Act of 2013</short-title>
        </quote>.</text>
    </section> 
<section id="HA3EE95363F974BE39E0F5BF04475DCE1">
      <enum>2.</enum>
      <header>Findings</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> finds the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="HE8F5E780F14F42CFB78ECCCCBB6FCD2C">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text>There is broad consensus that increasing the number and quality of workers in STEM fields is critical to maintaining United States economic leadership and global competitiveness.</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H46AB1483887C46E3AD4F5A667E13B6E3">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text>Scientific innovation has produced approximately half of all United States economic growth since 1950.</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5A945D2554CC4B3FAFD74F7A2222758F">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <text>Due to shortages of skilled workers, approximately 600,000 United States manufacturing jobs remained vacant in 2011.</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCBA8ACD459004FAABB615A6DC342CF25">
        <enum>(4)</enum>
        <text>Over the past 10 years, growth in STEM jobs in the United States was three times greater than that of non-STEM jobs. Additionally, STEM jobs are forecasted to grow at an even faster rate in the next decade.</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H700D41178AE34443B50C3D01092CDC3D">
        <enum>(5)</enum>
        <text>United States employees in STEM fields earn higher wages, receiving 26 percent more on average than their non-STEM counterparts.</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA595F423DF4B4338AD234323D824913E">
        <enum>(6)</enum>
        <text>Employment in engineering fields is expected to grow by 11 percent by 2018. Among individuals holding undergraduate degrees, engineers earn some of the highest starting salaries on average.</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7D241A5331704377911C5CC8801FEE28">
        <enum>(7)</enum>
        <text>Employment in computer systems design and related services, which is dependent on high-level math and problem-solving skills, is projected to grow by 45 percent by 2018.</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H794FBE4B411240669860ECBCF333E78D">
        <enum>(8)</enum>
        <text>In 2008, 31 percent of United States college graduates majored in science or engineering fields, as opposed to 61 percent of graduates in Japan and 51 percent of graduates in China.</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H89F842C0111245709162D7F9B1018C36">
        <enum>(9)</enum>
        <text>In 2011, the World Economic Forum ranked the United States 48th in quality of mathematics and science K–12 teacher instruction.</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H953517766EFD43C98D19C79B9F6DEED7">
        <enum>(10)</enum>
        <text>Recent reports on standardized testing show that students in the United States perform average or below average in mathematics and science as compared to their international peers.</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC37B797E232F4859BFCD35A7697CF4EF">
        <enum>(11)</enum>
        <text>In 2011, only 45 percent of United States high school graduates were ready for college-level math, and only 30 percent were ready for college-level science.</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6C737B032C3F4051B5D093B1398D4390">
        <enum>(12)</enum>
        <text>In 2007, 33 percent of public middle school science teachers and 36 public of public middle school math teachers either did not have a college degree in the subject or were not certified to teach the subject.</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4885F871C10043D3A28BB9FC2942DE4B">
        <enum>(13)</enum>
        <text>United States teachers generally spent more time in the classroom with students and less time on professional development than their counterparts in top-performing countries.</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC090F9261C6B420984E30384B7FC1750">
        <enum>(14)</enum>
        <text>United States teachers cite inadequate support from administrators on curriculum development as one of the top reasons for leaving their jobs.</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H30C83E5125534180800BC89DCD252D79">
        <enum>(15)</enum>
        <text>Exposure to projects and problem-based learning give high school students the skills that they need to be successful in engineering undergraduate and graduate programs of study as well as future careers.</text>
      </paragraph>
    </section> 
<section id="H80BBC97E602F4B07A5C4207588755C22">
      <enum>3.</enum>
      <header>National Science Foundation master teaching fellowships track</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">The <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
          <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="National Science Foundation Authorization Act of 2002">National Science Foundation Authorization Act of 2002</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1862n">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/42/1862n/etseq">42 U.S.C. 1862n et seq.</cato:entity-ref>
          </external-xref>)</cato:entity> is amended by inserting after <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="National Science Foundation Authorization Act of 2002/s:10A">section 10A</cato:entity-ref> the following:</text> 
<quoted-block id="HAE0AC88EE2D94C42A00A1AB6D4E06972" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H494331D4649C414F84E647B8FB75079B">
          <enum>10B.</enum>
          <header>National science foundation teaching fellowships and master teaching fellowships</header> 
<subsection id="HDC57BBB3471944B4BB2DEA97655C8242">
            <enum>(a)</enum>
            <header>In general</header> 
<paragraph id="H002AD787C3E947F3B80FA3EE281C4522">
              <enum>(1)</enum>
              <header>Grants</header> 
<subparagraph id="H637946587A9A41779794B02D6B0BF881">
                <enum>(A)</enum>
                <header>In general</header>
                <text>As part of the Robert Noyce Teacher Scholarship Program established under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="National Science Foundation Authorization Act of 2002/s:10">section 10</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="4900">Director</cato:entity-ref> shall establish a separate program to award grants to eligible entities to enable such entities to administer fellowships in accordance with this section.</text>
              </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H4ECC6F4202D6422EB70754C7F02E5A5B">
                <enum>(B)</enum>
                <header>Definitions</header>
                <text>The terms used in this section have the meanings given the terms in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="National Science Foundation Authorization Act of 2002/s:10">section 10</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H538A98276D85447C998A2D0427B3C7F2">
              <enum>(2)</enum>
              <header>Fellowships</header>
              <text>Fellowships under this section shall be available only to—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H47236049974344E4BDBB4759B86BC1B3">
                <enum>(A)</enum>
                <text>science, technology, engineering, or mathematics professionals, who shall be referred to as <quote>National Science Foundation Teaching Fellows</quote> and who, in the first year of the fellowship, are enrolled in a master’s degree program leading to teacher certification or licensing; and</text>
              </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HDCCDADE35EF447E597912745DD67E4C7">
                <enum>(B)</enum>
                <text>mathematics and science elementary and secondary school teachers, who shall be referred to as <quote>National Science Foundation Master Teaching Fellows</quote>, and who possess a master’s degree in their field or who do not possess a master’s degree in education and/or their respective field but possess potential to become highly effective mathematics and science teachers and leaders in their respective schools.</text>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection> 
<subsection id="HD0DD5D7F2D764D1385CD5248C59C7A5E">
            <enum>(b)</enum>
            <header>Eligibility</header>
            <text>In order to be eligible to receive a grant under this section, an eligible entity shall enter into a partnership that—</text> 
<paragraph id="H0DC7E293C817461E94A77981A91D964C">
              <enum>(1)</enum>
              <text>shall include—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H38EAFB5550B04F0EA7DE32F8A2CEA406">
                <enum>(A)</enum>
                <text>not less than 1 high need local educational agency and a public school or a consortium of public schools served by the agency;</text>
              </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD011A07D5990468E8BA41D289B56F753">
                <enum>(B)</enum>
                <text>a department within an institution of higher education participating in the partnership that provides an advanced program of study in mathematics and science; and</text>
              </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H8E0E152FC86046B5B727C09BFBBF13E8">
                <enum>(C)</enum> 
<clause id="H4DCF0D6C63EC494099F3D9A02243FE7D" display-inline="yes-display-inline">
                  <enum>(i)</enum>
                  <text>a school or department within an institution of higher education participating in the partnership that provides a teacher preparation program; or</text>
                </clause> 
<clause id="H9438E6F724D74F14B1C3C9EECF7C881E" indent="up1">
                  <enum>(ii)</enum>
                  <text>a 2-year institution of higher education that has a teacher preparation offering or a dual enrollment program with an institution of higher education participating in the partnership; and</text>
                </clause>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H68F40D07B8C546B09BB25E05BC83DC69">
              <enum>(2)</enum>
              <text>may include 1 or more nonprofit organizations that have a demonstrated record of capacity to provide expertise or support to meet the purposes of this section.</text>
            </paragraph> </subsection> 
<subsection id="HD9AFF838474949ECACA21CF98BB4B56C">
            <enum>(c)</enum>
            <header>Use of grants</header>
            <text>Grants awarded under this section shall be used by the eligible entity (and participating institutions of higher education of the consortium, if applicable) to develop and implement a program for National Science Foundation Teaching Fellows or National Science Foundation Master Teaching Fellows, through—</text> 
<paragraph id="H297FE0A663404EE18A2F20E63F74EEAF">
              <enum>(1)</enum>
              <text>administering fellowships in accordance with this section, including providing teaching fellowship salary supplements;</text>
            </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC1DA5A9D9B7A4729BBD0814BB442AAA7">
              <enum>(2)</enum>
              <text>in the case of National Science Foundation Teaching Fellowships—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HB754BDC62B054C7E895A9183C2AEA4D4">
                <enum>(A)</enum>
                <text>offering academic courses and clinical teaching experiences leading to a master’s degree and designed to prepare individuals to teach in elementary schools and secondary schools, including such preparation as is necessary to meet the requirements for certification or licensing; and</text>
              </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6EF602893DD247B08ADD385DECDF5047">
                <enum>(B)</enum>
                <text>offering programs both during and after matriculation in the program for which the fellowship is received to enable fellows to become highly effective mathematics and science teachers, including mentoring, training, induction, and professional development activities, to fulfill the service requirements of this section, including the requirements of <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="National Science Foundation Authorization Act of 2002/s:10B/ss:e" proposed="true">subsection (e)</cato:entity-ref>, and to exchange ideas with others in their fields; and</text>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H866455933297448AA872A642104DF7F7">
              <enum>(3)</enum>
              <text>in the case of National Science Foundation Master Teaching Fellowships—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H457C2CC35C5944458DF026147E9C7920">
                <enum>(A)</enum>
                <text>in the case of fellows who have a master’s degree in education or in their respective field—</text> 
<clause id="H80B4C0AFA0534E838853A761EFCFB857">
                  <enum>(i)</enum>
                  <text>offering academic courses and leadership training to prepare individuals to become master teachers in elementary schools and secondary schools; and</text>
                </clause> 
<clause id="HFBA2EE2B10DF44B8973EEA57E871CAD0">
                  <enum>(ii)</enum>
                  <text>offering programs both during and after matriculation in the program for which the fellowship is received to enable fellows to become highly effective mathematics and science teachers, including mentoring, training, induction, and professional development activities, to fulfill the service requirements of this section, including the requirements of <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="National Science Foundation Authorization Act of 2002/s:10B/ss:e" proposed="true">subsection (e)</cato:entity-ref>, and to exchange ideas with others in their fields; and</text>
                </clause>
              </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2D41E8F09D1C4A738704B674FC000CA8">
                <enum>(B)</enum>
                <text>in the case of fellows who do not have a master’s degree in education or in their respective field—</text> 
<clause id="HC26677E0A8804F1FB0B98CB2C7FFA5B9">
                  <enum>(i)</enum>
                  <text>offering academic courses for individuals to earn a master’s degree; </text>
                </clause> 
<clause id="H6BD9731E0F6845449D10C8989CD347CF">
                  <enum>(ii)</enum>
                  <text>offering programs both during and after matriculation in the program for which the fellowship is received to enable fellows to become highly effective mathematics and science teachers, including mentoring, training, and induction, to fulfill the service requirements of this section, including the requirements of <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="National Science Foundation Authorization Act of 2002/s:10B/ss:e" proposed="true">subsection (e)</cato:entity-ref>, and to exchange ideas with others in their fields; and</text>
                </clause> 
<clause id="H8AC4D5C0AC354C3F999D2F62BFC0CEDA">
                  <enum>(iii)</enum>
                  <text>offering professional development programs that provide for continuous followup training during the academic year that may include—</text> 
<subclause id="H79D0A3F1253241EC886C3A07470538EC">
                    <enum>(I)</enum>
                    <text>an online forum that may include—</text> 
<item id="H52B652BFDEC844998E0167A758B0ADD1">
                      <enum>(aa)</enum>
                      <text>a discussion forum for Master fellows to share best practices with other fellows; and</text>
                    </item> 
<item id="H9BAFAAC29BCA4D2AB4206A560B6A2E1F">
                      <enum>(bb)</enum>
                      <text>a question and answer forum for Master fellows to ask questions of faculty from the institution of higher education or any other member of the partnership;</text>
                    </item>
                  </subclause> 
<subclause id="HB4F198DC6F5A46A8BDD908AC80338B0C">
                    <enum>(II)</enum>
                    <text>a summer workshop training of no less than 2 weeks; and</text>
                  </subclause> 
<subclause id="H01880FFDC77A4C77865AC4E0911529C8">
                    <enum>(III)</enum>
                    <text>direct interaction with faculty throughout the year.</text>
                  </subclause> </clause> </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
        </section>
        <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
      </quoted-block>
    </section> 
<section id="H13505828D88D474EB1514219CD684AB8">
      <enum>4.</enum>
      <header>Teacher and principal training and recruiting fund</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">
        
          <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965/s:2101">Sections 2101</cato:entity-ref>, <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965/s:2012">
            2012
          </cato:entity-ref>, and <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965/s:2013">
            2013 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/6601">
            <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc/20/6601">20 U.S.C. 6601</cato:entity-ref>
          </external-xref>, <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc/20/6602">6602</cato:entity-ref>, <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc/20/6603">6603</cato:entity-ref>) are amended to read as follows:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H645568591F044C95BEAF4DD9564A8025" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<section id="HC0CC841FC1F14870A0669075F258A35F">
          <enum>2101.</enum>
          <header>Purpose</header>
          <text display-inline="no-display-inline">The purpose of this part is to provide grants to State educational agencies, local educational agencies, State agencies for higher education, and eligible partnerships that may include nonprofit organizations or private corporations in order to—</text> 
<paragraph id="H5D8E250440E74C03B57FA0A12D0A8859">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <text>increase student academic achievement through strategies such as improving teacher and principal quality and increasing the number of highly qualified teachers in the classroom and highly qualified principals and assistant principals in schools; and</text>
          </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD61D9990D4584BAFA60A257E32DCEE75">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <text>hold local educational agencies and schools accountable for improvements in student academic achievement.</text>
          </paragraph>
        </section> 
<section id="H9DDB0EEFB1A642AEBD28B2C64D926F4F">
          <enum>2102.</enum>
          <header>Definitions</header>
          <text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this part:</text> 
<paragraph id="H2E338CE1D8C14BB996A6DEB71C075B0A">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <header>Arts and sciences</header>
            <text>The term <quote>arts and sciences</quote> means—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H9403B258BFEB4FF1ADD6EC8BC1BA3DB3">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>when referring to an organizational unit of an institution of higher education, any academic unit that offers one or more academic majors in disciplines or content areas corresponding to the academic subjects in which teachers teach; and</text>
            </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H89D4E31DDE7340EC8C6F24C2E00F914F">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>when referring to a specific academic subject, the disciplines or content areas in which an academic major is offered by an organizational unit described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965/s:2102/p:1/sp:A" proposed="true">subparagraph (A)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H20B016F8C18E4175A6B383BE90C5BBFF">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <header>Charter school</header>
            <text>The term <quote>charter school</quote> has the meaning given the term in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965/s:5210">section 5210</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
          </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H155E006D9CE8446C958F85B6D79C5CD4">
            <enum>(3)</enum>
            <header>High-need local educational agency</header>
            <text>The term <quote>high-need local educational agency</quote> means a local educational agency—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H167F8D41BBA744D98587DD2BF5F52DC8">
              <enum>(A)</enum> 
<clause id="HB204266DC18A4C309584B3CB83F303F3" display-inline="yes-display-inline">
                <enum>(i)</enum>
                <text>that serves not fewer than 10,000 children from families with incomes below the poverty line; or</text>
              </clause> 
<clause id="HFCCA32A85A2D449EBDFCF890B97152CD" indent="up1">
                <enum>(ii)</enum>
                <text>for which not less than 20 percent of the children served by the agency are from families with incomes below the poverty line; and</text>
              </clause>
            </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H53FF43C5CED94995B11781D437B9872B">
              <enum>(B)</enum> 
<clause id="HF76896B9B4254DD388CF797EA70B8BA7" display-inline="yes-display-inline">
                <enum>(i)</enum>
                <text>for which there may be a high percentage of teachers not teaching in the academic subjects or grade levels that the teachers were trained to teach; or</text>
              </clause> 
<clause id="HB9E45B0A140040F19D348D6C6ADF2D84" indent="up1">
                <enum>(ii)</enum>
                <text>for which there may be a high percentage of teachers with emergency, provisional, or temporary certification or licensing.</text>
              </clause>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7B339BBC49A44902935A5CDA437A2E95">
            <enum>(4)</enum>
            <header>Highly qualified paraprofessional</header>
            <text>The term <quote>highly qualified paraprofessional</quote> means a paraprofessional who has not less than 2 years of—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H088C542E93ED424E81A035B3C5326508">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>experience in a classroom; and</text>
            </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H138440773A734CE5B8C0F069AE9D5CC0">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>postsecondary education or demonstrated competence in a field or academic subject for which there is a significant shortage of qualified teachers.</text>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6DDA8435D6C043F38D7C60135A905048">
            <enum>(5)</enum>
            <header>Out-of-field teacher</header>
            <text>The term <quote>out-of-field teacher</quote> means a teacher who is teaching an academic subject or a grade level for which the teacher is not highly qualified.</text>
          </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB851474D05F04E7BB0751BA0A1375082">
            <enum>(6)</enum>
            <header>Principal</header>
            <text>The term <quote>principal</quote> includes an assistant principal.</text>
          </paragraph>
        </section> 
<section id="HB19016B9FE534730A7826730E6AA6D52">
          <enum>2103.</enum>
          <header>Authorizations of appropriations</header> 
<subsection id="H1972581C66FB4D4E9BFEA976E76D4D88">
            <enum>(a)</enum>
            <header>Grants to States, local educational agencies, and eligible partnerships</header>
            <text>
              <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="auth-auth-approp">There are authorized to be appropriated <cato:property name="purpose">to carry out <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965/t:II/pt:A">this part</cato:entity-ref> (other than subpart 5)</cato:property> <cato:funds-and-year amount="3175000000" year="2014">$3,175,000,000 for fiscal year 2014</cato:funds-and-year> and <cato:funds-and-year amount="indefinite" year="2015, 2016, 2017, 2018, 2019">such sums as may be necessary for each of the 5 succeeding fiscal years</cato:funds-and-year>.</cato:entity>
            </text>
          </subsection> 
<subsection id="HAD6F02036F554E559E408BD53ECBC04F">
            <enum>(b)</enum>
            <header>National programs</header>
            <text>
              <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="auth-auth-approp">There are authorized to be appropriated <cato:property name="purpose">to carry out <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965/t:II/pt:A/spt:5">subpart 5</cato:entity-ref>
                </cato:property> <cato:funds-and-year amount="indefinite" year="2014, 2015, 2016, 2017, 2018, 2019">such sums as may be necessary for fiscal year 2014 and each of the 5 succeeding fiscal years</cato:funds-and-year>.</cato:entity>
            </text>
          </subsection>
        </section>
        <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
      </quoted-block>
    </section> 
<section id="H761D9E52E8A94B65BF9BC40047A577D1">
      <enum>5.</enum>
      <header>Mathematics and science partnerships</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">
        <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
          <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965/t:II/pt:B">Part B of title II of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/6661">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/20/6661/etseq">20 U.S.C. 6661 et seq.</cato:entity-ref>
          </external-xref>)</cato:entity> is amended to read as follows: </text> 
<quoted-block style="other" id="H29E8644481B847EFBB150BF25AF437DE" display-inline="no-display-inline" other-style="education"> 
<part id="H566BD39EAD1F4DD99317EC423D78637E">
          <enum>B</enum>
          <header>Mathematics and Science Partnerships</header>
        </part> 
<section id="HF774CC44C25D4016B99CCF02D95D4930">
          <enum>2201.</enum>
          <header>Purposes; definitions</header> 
<subsection id="H9D7126BD9AD24F0F915885E2B673F9D5">
            <enum>(a)</enum>
            <header>Purpose</header>
            <text>The purpose of this part is to improve the academic achievement of students in the areas of mathematics and science by encouraging State educational agencies, institutions of higher education, local educational agencies, elementary schools, and secondary schools to participate in programs that—</text> 
<paragraph id="H09F769AF785946D38E023D71FDA3AD3B">
              <enum>(1)</enum>
              <text>improve and upgrade the status and stature of mathematics and science teaching by encouraging institutions of higher education to assume greater responsibility for improving mathematics and science teacher education through the establishment of a comprehensive, integrated system of recruiting, training, and advising mathematics and science teachers;</text>
            </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H59B2703BD1134D5CA53F4FED1CAF7713">
              <enum>(2)</enum>
              <text>focus on the education of mathematics and science teachers as a career-long process that continuously stimulates teachers<quote> intellectual growth and upgrades teachers</quote> knowledge and skills in order to better retain good teachers;</text>
            </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA1A8FF7BD05645C9A24F88AB51E88EAE">
              <enum>(3)</enum>
              <text>bring mathematics and science teachers in elementary schools and secondary schools together with scientists, mathematicians, and engineers to increase the subject matter knowledge of mathematics and science teachers to foster relationships and improve such teachers’ teaching skills through the use of sophisticated laboratory equipment and work space, computing facilities, libraries, and other resources that institutions of higher education are better able to provide than the elementary schools and secondary schools;</text>
            </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1FAEE3A1AABA424F872256B8535FE0A5">
              <enum>(4)</enum>
              <text>develop more rigorous mathematics and science curricula that are aligned with challenging State and local academic content standards and with the standards expected for postsecondary study and careers in engineering, mathematics, and science; and</text>
            </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCB995ED5FEB74AD1A9A5084D9937423B">
              <enum>(5)</enum>
              <text>improve and expand training of mathematics and science teachers, including training such teachers in the effective integration of technology and project-based learning units into curricula and instruction.</text>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection> 
<subsection id="H1DC857814EE3464D89F229C8D8B722B0">
            <enum>(b)</enum>
            <header>Definitions</header>
            <text>In this part:</text> 
<paragraph id="H64A7F04320434BDC86F6B64FB60E63CF">
              <enum>(1)</enum>
              <header>Eligible partnership</header>
              <text>The term <quote>eligible partnership</quote> means a partnership that—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H652EC09C640541CBB0661AA77B8B0B36">
                <enum>(A)</enum>
                <text>shall include—</text> 
<clause id="H5667D8C73ABB46A6BC8A5E5544F02545">
                  <enum>(i)</enum>
                  <text>if grants are awarded under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965/s:2202/ss:a/p:1" proposed="true">section 2202(a)(1)</cato:entity-ref>, a State educational agency;</text>
                </clause> 
<clause id="H4BA966C480D44544B928FAD82F936239">
                  <enum>(ii)</enum>
                  <text>an engineering, mathematics, or science department of an institution of higher education; and</text>
                </clause> 
<clause id="HC5E47C670269444D9ED5775C865DE22C">
                  <enum>(iii)</enum>
                  <text>a high-need local educational agency; and</text>
                </clause>
              </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HAFC899F4D30E46E092F4FB8C085D31D4">
                <enum>(B)</enum>
                <text>may include—</text> 
<clause id="H3AFFE88DE271475FBD47BF01306D577E">
                  <enum>(i)</enum>
                  <text>another engineering, mathematics, science, or teacher training department of an institution of higher education;</text>
                </clause> 
<clause id="H824455C9241741D1956F98DAE6596300">
                  <enum>(ii)</enum>
                  <text>additional local educational agencies, public charter schools, public or private elementary schools or secondary schools, or a consortium of such schools;</text>
                </clause> 
<clause id="H7ECB4EB9B33A415EB85F61A9916FFBC6">
                  <enum>(iii)</enum>
                  <text>a business; or</text>
                </clause> 
<clause id="H3EAB4D9F3FD64257A9111FDA098CAE2C">
                  <enum>(iv)</enum>
                  <text>a nonprofit or for-profit organization of demonstrated effectiveness in improving the quality of mathematics and science teachers.</text>
                </clause>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7232724A212F441390611DABF036CA88">
              <enum>(2)</enum>
              <header>Summer workshop or institute</header>
              <text>The term <quote>summer workshop or institute</quote> means a workshop or institute, conducted during the summer, that—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H1F8028813D7041CB997C9953E04C17F3">
                <enum>(A)</enum>
                <text>is conducted for a period of not less than 2 weeks;</text>
              </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HAAC2953A29EF4E95A624B8904A2B99D2">
                <enum>(B)</enum>
                <text>includes, as a component, a program that provides direct interaction between teachers and faculty from institution of higher education;</text>
              </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H52AA7F5AA1C44D72AF6920DD27096F78">
                <enum>(C)</enum>
                <text>provides for followup training during the academic year that is conducted in the classroom with direct interaction with partnership participants for a period of not less than 3 consecutive or nonconsecutive days, except that if the followup training is for teachers in rural school districts, the followup training may be conducted entirely through distance learning; and</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H29242102BE3248939964633E559EB2B4">
                <enum>(D)</enum>
                <text>may provide for continuous followup training during the academic year that is conducted via an online forum that may include—</text> 
<clause id="HF28D591784264ECF88343361C5B887C6">
                  <enum>(i)</enum>
                  <text>a discussion forum for teachers to share best practices; and</text>
                </clause> 
<clause id="H9ADEC05926E04DBEB403C338EC0A83CA" commented="no">
                  <enum>(ii)</enum>
                  <text>a question and answer forum for teachers to ask questions of any other member of the partnership.</text>
                </clause>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
        </section> 
<section id="HAD2869E877624BEF826B7CAAD110642E">
          <enum>2202.</enum>
          <header>Grants for mathematics and science partnerships</header> 
<subsection id="H7CE6AF43A5894F05A7F8C4516BA66BC5">
            <enum>(a)</enum>
            <header>Authorized activities</header>
            <text>An eligible partnership shall use funds provided under this part for one or more of the following activities related to elementary schools or secondary schools:</text> 
<paragraph id="H3C2B840E2215459FBDA2E87E6B15ADA5">
              <enum>(1)</enum>
              <text>Creating opportunities for enhanced and ongoing professional development of mathematics and science teachers that improves the subject matter knowledge of such teachers.</text>
            </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3D1CA56AE75B40E394CD1DAEEA874E9C">
              <enum>(2)</enum>
              <text>Promoting strong teaching skills for mathematics and science teachers and teacher educators, including integrating reliable scientifically based research teaching methods and technology-based teaching methods into the curriculum.</text>
            </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4CD4D0C4A9224B00BFC17C2DAA4F55F5">
              <enum>(3)</enum>
              <text>Establishing and operating mathematics and science summer workshops or institutes, including followup training, for elementary school and secondary school mathematics and science teachers that—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HFB7DABB85E4646048DD835A48D23BD45">
                <enum>(A)</enum>
                <text>shall—</text> 
<clause id="H1AEE89DEC83D4B1A9BB28987C88089C4">
                  <enum>(i)</enum>
                  <text>directly relate to the curriculum and academic areas in which the teacher provides instruction, and focus only secondarily on pedagogy;</text>
                </clause> 
<clause id="HCA6E301717CF437EA9C40114F6D4FF06">
                  <enum>(ii)</enum>
                  <text>enhance the ability of the teacher to understand and use the challenging State academic content standards for mathematics and science and to select appropriate curricula; and</text>
                </clause> 
<clause id="H419E4E90ABCA485888AFC2D5588D629D">
                  <enum>(iii)</enum>
                  <text>train teachers to use curricula that—</text> 
<subclause id="HBF85A49460D14416802F1AAA5AFCA12F">
                    <enum>(I)</enum>
                    <text>are based on scientific research;</text>
                  </subclause> 
<subclause id="HF6DBD457AEA14968BDB601B532E4CC8D">
                    <enum>(II)</enum>
                    <text>align with challenging State academic content standards;</text>
                  </subclause> 
<subclause id="H7EFD9F066C1B433595C3E3C003A9D6D1">
                    <enum>(III)</enum>
                    <text>incorporate project-based learning techniques; and</text>
                  </subclause> 
<subclause id="H7F98B3183E9B4408B548D484030DA867">
                    <enum>(IV)</enum>
                    <text>are object-centered, experiment-oriented, and concept- and content-based; and</text>
                  </subclause>
                </clause>
              </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA359CC521798410FAF0CB5D219D98DA5">
                <enum>(B)</enum>
                <text>may include—</text> 
<clause id="H47D14C50654C4EF7915C6F80DE904705">
                  <enum>(i)</enum>
                  <text>programs that provide teachers and prospective teachers with opportunities to work under the guidance of experienced teachers and college faculty;</text>
                </clause> 
<clause id="H3255306652BE42D2A233211B39FEF6B4">
                  <enum>(ii)</enum>
                  <text>instruction in the use of data and assessments to inform and instruct classroom practice; and</text>
                </clause> 
<clause id="HF41DD9237A6B439A9E7A39903C071BA0">
                  <enum>(iii)</enum>
                  <text>professional development activities, including supplemental and followup activities, such as curriculum alignment, distance learning, and activities that train teachers to utilize technology in the classroom.</text>
                </clause>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H61150A26AE92471FB6C0645202977D74">
              <enum>(4)</enum>
              <text>Recruiting and retaining quality mathematics, engineering, and science majors to teaching through the use of—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HDEDD6A2CC6414681AEA9EF9A78A20AFC">
                <enum>(A)</enum>
                <text>signing and performance incentives that are linked to activities proven effective in retaining teachers, or for recruiting individuals with demonstrated professional experience in mathematics, engineering, or science into teaching;</text>
              </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6998CAEAFB1F48A99B09E516684AC1A0">
                <enum>(B)</enum>
                <text>stipends provided to mathematics and science teachers for certification through alternative routes;</text>
              </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HFC1D5C3E4E44454B9D6A9FCFC6CE484D">
                <enum>(C)</enum>
                <text>scholarships for teachers to pursue advanced course work in mathematics, engineering, or science; and</text>
              </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA30C0EC11C3C411CB8BB861AAB7DFB42">
                <enum>(D)</enum>
                <text>other programs that the State educational agency determines to be effective in recruiting and retaining individuals with strong mathematics, engineering, or science backgrounds.</text>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBA2D839D1CB6458BA1411329F04D3620">
              <enum>(5)</enum>
              <text>Developing or redesigning more rigorous mathematics and science curricula that are aligned with challenging State and local academic content standards and with the standards expected for postsecondary study in mathematics and science.</text>
            </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H83281282CEDB493D98A777281DA9D12A">
              <enum>(6)</enum>
              <text>Establishing distance learning programs for mathematics and science teachers using curricula that are innovative, content-based, and based on scientifically based research that is current as of the date of the program involved.</text>
            </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB92815AE0A3B4675BFE5C5A380CF20F6">
              <enum>(7)</enum>
              <text>Designing programs to prepare a mathematics or science teacher at a school to provide professional development to other mathematics or science teachers at the school and to assist beginning and other teachers at the school, including (if applicable) a mechanism to integrate the teacher’s experiences from a summer workshop or institute into the provision of professional development and assistance.</text>
            </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H289AA5AE67BB4571AB93699BCCC253F0">
              <enum>(8)</enum>
              <text>Establishing and operating programs to bring mathematics and science teachers into contact with working scientists, mathematicians, and engineers, to expand such teachers’ subject matter knowledge of and research in science and mathematics.</text>
            </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB43A146E455D4ABF9A984ED503BA9C5B">
              <enum>(9)</enum>
              <text>Designing programs to identify and develop exemplary mathematics and science teachers in the kindergarten through grade 8 classrooms.</text>
            </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD38020A1F79E4F208F3398383EFEF6A3">
              <enum>(10)</enum>
              <text>Training mathematics and science teachers and developing programs to encourage young women and other underrepresented individuals in mathematics and science careers (including engineering and technology) to pursue postsecondary degrees in majors leading to such careers.</text>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection> 
<subsection id="H737A61F49A214DFF873AF21484735388">
            <enum>(b)</enum>
            <header>Evaluation and accountability plan</header> 
<paragraph id="HBD9A002F74CB415F8EED572211C11B9E">
              <enum>(1)</enum>
              <header>In general</header>
              <text>Each eligible partnership receiving a grant or subgrant under this part shall develop an evaluation and accountability plan for activities assisted under this part that includes rigorous objectives that measure the impact of activities funded under this part.</text>
            </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE6EEA3CDF66440F6886AF4D16085E85C">
              <enum>(2)</enum>
              <header>Contents</header>
              <text>The plan developed pursuant to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965/s:2202/ss:b/p:1" proposed="true">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref>—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HD3F4A6F9ABB94F68BE4AD9F47623167A">
                <enum>(A)</enum>
                <text>shall include measurable objectives to increase the number of mathematics and science teachers who participate in content-based professional development activities;</text>
              </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD4341937412A4955A5EE564479410AE9">
                <enum>(B)</enum>
                <text>shall include measurable objectives for improved student academic achievement on State mathematics and science assessments or, where applicable, an International Mathematics and Science Study assessment; and</text>
              </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H0F0FDE08A5594F299FF9AFC04F796862">
                <enum>(C)</enum>
                <text>may include objectives and measures for—</text> 
<clause id="HDBED03B34BCA47E7A069F424D55386B9">
                  <enum>(i)</enum>
                  <text>increased participation by students in advanced courses in mathematics and science; and</text>
                </clause> 
<clause id="HC2406FB66A754E65A00055439388C808">
                  <enum>(ii)</enum>
                  <text>increased percentages of elementary and secondary school teachers with academic majors or minors, or group majors or minors, in mathematics, engineering, or the sciences.</text>
                </clause>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection> 
<subsection id="HB776C48E51EB4E748F1618840A1512B8">
            <enum>(c)</enum>
            <header>Report</header>
            <text>Each eligible partnership receiving a grant or subgrant under this part shall report annually to the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="9100">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> regarding the eligible partnership’s progress in meeting the objectives described in the accountability plan of the partnership under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965/s:2202/ss:b" proposed="true">subsection (b)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
          </subsection>
        </section> 
<section id="H99573545EE2149C2B5054650964CEB94">
          <enum>2203.</enum>
          <header>Authorization of appropriations</header>
          <text display-inline="no-display-inline">
            <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="auth-auth-approp">There are authorized to be appropriated <cato:property name="purpose">to carry out <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965/t:II/pt:B" proposed="true">this part</cato:entity-ref>
              </cato:property> <cato:funds-and-year amount="450000000" year="2014">$450,000,000 for fiscal year 2014</cato:funds-and-year> and <cato:funds-and-year amount="indefinite" year="2015, 2016, 2017, 2018, 2019">such sums as may be necessary for each of the 5 succeeding fiscal years</cato:funds-and-year>.</cato:entity>
          </text>
        </section>
        <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
      </quoted-block>
    </section> 
<section id="HEA1C8A6FD553409FAA1D874DF0C9C6B0">
      <enum>6.</enum>
      <header>Special rule relating to subgrants to eligible partnerships</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">
        <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
          <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965/s:2132/ss:c">Section 2132(c) of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/6632">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/20/6632/c">20 U.S.C. 6632(c)</cato:entity-ref>
          </external-xref>)</cato:entity> is amended by striking <quote>50</quote> and inserting <quote>75</quote>. </text>
    </section> 
</legis-body> 
</bill>
</doc>