<doc>
  <docmeta id="113hr3525ih">
    <bill congress="113" type="hr" number="3525" version="ih"/>
    <revision size="15517" annotations="0" status="complete" id="3" commit-time="2013-11-23T15:51:30Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113hr3525ih/3.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H730D6E6270E740EAB7A5976D7DC9819A" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata>
<dublinCore>
<dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">113 HR 3525 IH: International Hydrocephalus Treatment and Training Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">2013-11-18</dc:date>
<dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>113th CONGRESS</congress>
<session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. R. 3525</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20131118">November 18, 2013</action-date> 
<action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="S000522">Mr. Smith of New Jersey</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name>
      </action-desc>
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To amend the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 to provide assistance for the treatment of hydrocephalus in children in developing countries, to train surgeons and other medical practitioners in innovative methods to treat and cure hydrocephalus, to fund related research, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H2E01A377BC78493598F3F00B8E913F50" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HAEEB4E16AAA24F819BCFEFA924084F2E" section-type="section-one">
      <enum>1.</enum>
      <header>Short title</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote>
          <short-title>International Hydrocephalus Treatment and Training Act</short-title>
        </quote>.</text>
    </section> 
<section id="H3D966CD562A847BFAD1F6FED01FCB61B">
      <enum>2.</enum>
      <header>Findings</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">
        <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> finds the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H48889CDE927C496D96DD9703CD0B6CE6">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text>Hydrocephalus, also known as <quote>water on the brain</quote>, is a medical condition in which an abnormal accumulation of cerebrospinal fluid in the ventricles or cavities of the brain causes increased intracranial pressure inside the skull and progressive enlargement of the head.</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H761042A11CDF41AD97DF3964FA63DE4C">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text>If left untreated, hydrocephalus leads to physical and mental disabilities and eventually death.</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA6C69A0D4915424AA151F909417E9120">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Hydrocephalus is an extremely painful condition that most commonly occurs in infants and young children as a result of a congenital abnormality (anatomic abnormality, aqueductal stenosis, spina bifida or encephalocele), or post-infectious hydrocephalus (PIH) caused by infections acquired after birth, such as meningitis, that attack the brain.</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H17BFA1335A334957BEA02C380C52C0A8">
        <enum>(4)</enum>
        <text>PIH is the most common cause of hydrocephalus globally, accounting for approximately 60 percent of all cases.</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC006B1E626BA412680AD9A2014919601">
        <enum>(5)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Three to five out of every 1,000 newborns in developing countries are either born with hydrocephalus or acquire it due to neonatal infections in the first few months of life.</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF508CB48F5484C6598E3C3D0E0649FB8">
        <enum>(6)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It is conservatively estimated that more than 300,000 children are born with or acquire hydrocephalus in the developing world each year.</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF5BB456EA79640628F19F3347B361FE2">
        <enum>(7)</enum>
        <text>Children with hydrocephalus who are not effectively treated or who are not treated in the early stages of the condition suffer from cognitive deficiencies or physical disabilities or both.</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF10CEF9E8B96481D9403E2CE66A920C9">
        <enum>(8)</enum>
        <text>Families of children who have hydrocephalus in developing countries rarely know that it is a treatable condition, where to go for treatment, or how to care for a child suffering from the condition.</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H517B84D475EF49C4BD587B96A05E1244">
        <enum>(9)</enum>
        <text>Many children with hydrocephalus in developing countries are abandoned, ostracized, or abused due to their appearance and physical and mental disabilities.</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6CFD8B3AA2E241CEB0896F70826BF3A2">
        <enum>(10)</enum>
        <text>Hydrocephalus can be treated, and advances in innovative medical procedures such as ETV/CPC have the potential to save thousands of lives annually and prevent or mitigate physical and mental disabilities in thousands of children in developing countries.</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD68923DC906846058911E6FB499ACC53">
        <enum>(11)</enum>
        <text>The current standard treatment for hydrocephalus is the VP shunt which often requires up to 5 surgical revisions before a child reaches adulthood to remedy blockages in the shunt and to account for the child’s growth. Blockages can be expected during the life of the patient and can lead to death, particularly in developing countries where access to the requisite medical expertise often is not available.</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4B4148BEAA294E2787D51DB360B8C01A">
        <enum>(12)</enum>
        <text>Due to the need for multiple replacements of a VP shunt, this treatment is expensive and creates an increased burden on fragile health systems, patients, and families.</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1B8060FA40864E05A6717F28D0E84D98">
        <enum>(13)</enum>
        <text>ETV/CPC is a shunt-less surgery for hydrocephalus that does not require a VP shunt and has been shown to be appropriate in at least two-thirds of the cases of infants with hydrocephalus. Of those cases, ETV/CPC is 93 percent effective in eliminating hydrocephalus.</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC69B438689D7446A8CBDB012AC83E56E">
        <enum>(14)</enum>
        <text>Few hospitals with the expertise and capacity to treat hydrocephalus exist in developing countries, and the demand for treatment far exceeds the capacity of health systems in those countries.</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2DC6186632C948E0979C24384BE3E985">
        <enum>(15)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Neurosurgical care for hydrocephalus in developing countries is widely unavailable due to a lack of trained neurosurgeons. In East Africa, there is only 1 neurosurgeon per 10,000,000 people. In many developing countries there are no trained neurosurgeons. </text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7E0F73766BBF4F719BC556EEB79041EE">
        <enum>(16)</enum>
        <text>Hundreds of thousands of cases of hydrocephalus in children in developing countries could be successfully treated if adequate resources are devoted to training surgeons in new techniques, such as ETV/CPC, and many future cases could be prevented if adequate resources are devoted to research means to mitigate the preventable causes of hydrocephalus.</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD3A97989B61B472F85F46235DAD3442A">
        <enum>(17)</enum>
        <text>Adoption of innovative new techniques to treat hydrocephalus, such as ETV/CPC, are more cost effective in the long term than current treatment methods since only one surgery is required in most cases, thus limiting the impact on overburdened health systems in developing countries.</text>
      </paragraph>
    </section> 
<section id="HE2315DACB1A142EAB2E1349DE7AD37E2">
      <enum>3.</enum>
      <header>Assistance to treat hydrocephalus and train surgeons</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">
        <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
          <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Foreign Assistance Act of 1961/pt:I/ch:1">Chapter 1 of part I of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961</cato:entity-ref> (<cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/22/2151">22 U.S.C. 2151 et. seq.</cato:entity-ref>)</cato:entity> is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="HAA09781B556445EC93B929B9EB20DB46">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text>by redesignating the second <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Foreign Assistance Act of 1961/s:135">section 135</cato:entity-ref> (as added by <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Senator Paul Simon Water for the Poor Act of 2005/s:5/ss:a">section 5(a) of the Senator Paul Simon Water for the Poor Act of 2005</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/109/121">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="public-law" value="public-law/109/121">Public Law 109–121</cato:entity-ref>
            </external-xref>; <cato:entity-ref entity-type="statute-at-large" value="statute-at-large/119/2536">119 Stat. 2536</cato:entity-ref>)</cato:entity>) as <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Foreign Assistance Act of 1961/s:136" proposed="true">section 136</cato:entity-ref>; and</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD7D407A24A8C4108B7F29CEDBB1B14FF">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text>by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="HC55532D698F144098F732624BE06D87B" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<section id="H4DF42E66A8D845B9B8110962361FC7E8">
            <enum>137.</enum>
            <header>Assistance to treat hydrocephalus and train surgeons</header> 
<subsection id="HC7A7FEF1C6844739984CE25DA0A22C47">
              <enum>(a)</enum>
              <header>Purposes</header>
              <text>The purposes of assistance authorized by this section are—</text> 
<paragraph id="H2830206103E24CBF959B260621BEE0D8">
                <enum>(1)</enum>
                <text>to ensure that life-saving treatment of hydrocephalus is an important priority of United States bilateral foreign assistance, including through promotion of innovative treatments and training of medical practitioners from the developing world in the latest treatment protocols and best practices for the treatment of hydrocephalus, including—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H488E1EADDA6640F4AA472D4944C66649">
                  <enum>(A)</enum>
                  <text>surgery and post-surgery care in developing countries;</text>
                </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H14293510C07B4BC0BD3192F43B77F071">
                  <enum>(B)</enum>
                  <text>the creation of a comprehensive hydrocephalus training program based in the developing world for surgeons and key members of their medical team; and</text>
                </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H75EAED0F7EF541C688452FC50CE09B09">
                  <enum>(C)</enum>
                  <text>the training of medical practitioners based in the developing world in ETV/CPC and other appropriate treatment protocols; and</text>
                </subparagraph>
              </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA76FE1FFA75D402FBC67D6B41365E9A5">
                <enum>(2)</enum>
                <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to promote research to reduce the incidence of PIH epidemiology, pathophysiology, and disease burden, and to improve treatment of hydrocephalus.</text>
              </paragraph>
            </subsection> 
<subsection id="HFE44C82CEF8F4278AFB387A32DF70873">
              <enum>(b)</enum>
              <header>Authorization</header>
              <text>To carry out the purposes of <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Foreign Assistance Act of 1961/s:137/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> is authorized to provide assistance to support a network of trained medical practitioners to treat hydrocephalus in children at pediatric hospitals and hydrocephalus treatment centers in developing countries with a high incidence of hydrocephalus.</text>
            </subsection> 
<subsection id="HE3FEFC0E8306407894B351DCD1A41E48">
              <enum>(c)</enum>
              <header>Activities supported</header> 
<paragraph id="H9F4E646E815A4B4E914F96BBBB4B6B74">
                <enum>(1)</enum>
                <header>Comprehensive program</header> 
<subparagraph id="H5FC37ACD305641F8A28900369F7CCBAB">
                  <enum>(A)</enum>
                  <header>In general</header>
                  <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Assistance provided under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Foreign Assistance Act of 1961/s:137/ss:b" proposed="true">subsection (b)</cato:entity-ref> shall, to the maximum extent practicable, be used to establish a comprehensive program to administer global hydrocephalus treatment and training activities utilizing a network of pediatric hospitals capable of performing endoscopic surgery in developing countries.</text>
                </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HEBC6D974F4E54F35B84ABB01A84C60C1">
                  <enum>(B)</enum>
                  <header>Administration</header>
                  <text>The program described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Foreign Assistance Act of 1961/s:137/ss:c/p:1/sp:A" proposed="true">subparagraph (A)</cato:entity-ref> shall be administered by healthcare executives and neurosurgeons with expertise in the treatment of hydrocephalus.</text>
                </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HDD2F17A691314F5286F42B3BAF1699E5">
                  <enum>(C)</enum>
                  <header>Responsibilities</header>
                  <text>The responsibilities of the administrators described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Foreign Assistance Act of 1961/s:137/ss:c/p:1/sp:B" proposed="true">subparagraph (B)</cato:entity-ref> shall include—</text> 
<clause id="H4170DC6EC0A34B548E44954AB4856A76">
                    <enum>(i)</enum>
                    <text>developing an appropriate education and training curriculum;</text>
                  </clause> 
<clause id="HEA53A28322D04774808F761B136B789F">
                    <enum>(ii)</enum>
                    <text>establishing quality control standards;</text>
                  </clause> 
<clause id="H290411779E7442D982AA6F4ABB6D7EE0">
                    <enum>(iii)</enum>
                    <text>instituting safety guidelines and standards; and</text>
                  </clause> 
<clause id="H30D5AB38311D46CB8620FE8272366551">
                    <enum>(iv)</enum>
                    <text>developing monitoring and evaluation protocols.</text>
                  </clause>
                </subparagraph>
              </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H543218E3A6F04523A70A1890F3E4ED6D">
                <enum>(2)</enum>
                <header>Training hospital</header> 
<subparagraph id="H007142D41A6F472B9B0E11AEA942D167" commented="no">
                  <enum>(A)</enum>
                  <header>In general</header>
                  <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Assistance provided under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Foreign Assistance Act of 1961/s:137/ss:b" proposed="true">subsection (b)</cato:entity-ref> shall, to the maximum extent practicable, be used to establish a surgeon training program within a pediatric hospital based in a developing country with a high incidence of hydrocephalus with the goal of training four surgeons annually and a total of 20 surgeons over a 5-year period to treat hydrocephalus utilizing the ETV/CPC technique.</text>
                </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB29CDA4EC20F4AF98500678F5F300CDD" commented="no">
                  <enum>(B)</enum>
                  <header>Timeline</header>
                  <text>To the maximum extent practicable, the surgeon training program described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Foreign Assistance Act of 1961/s:137/ss:c/p:2/sp:B" proposed="true">subparagraph (A)</cato:entity-ref> should be operational no later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act. </text>
                </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H1B93BF8CE18C4B68A6906A614AC26E81" commented="no">
                  <enum>(C)</enum>
                  <header>Training admissions criteria</header>
                  <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Candidates for the surgeon training program established under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Foreign Assistance Act of 1961/s:137/ss:c/p:2/sp:A" proposed="true">subparagraph (A)</cato:entity-ref> shall—</text> 
<clause id="H2F607A12FD134ABAAFE621A106B4BDEB" commented="no">
                    <enum>(i)</enum>
                    <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">have a demonstrated commitment to providing medical assistance in the developing world; and</text>
                  </clause> 
<clause id="HCDB92CF54C8A47A5A1BBCF94955EAB8E" commented="no">
                    <enum>(ii)</enum>
                    <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">certify that the candidate intends to remain and practice medicine in the developing world following completion of the program.</text>
                  </clause>
                </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H31A9C361E568404688471E9498144914">
                  <enum>(D)</enum>
                  <header>Training program methodology</header>
                  <text>The surgeon training program established under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Foreign Assistance Act of 1961/s:137/ss:c/p:2/sp:A" proposed="true">subparagraph (A)</cato:entity-ref> shall—</text> 
<clause id="H7DAC65D9746D460AA097E22D7F80BD20">
                    <enum>(i)</enum>
                    <text>be conducted by a neurosurgeon with a minimum of 3 years of full-time operating experience in the developing world;</text>
                  </clause> 
<clause id="HD4A53BFF51CD413FBC4D2F21F50B4AB8">
                    <enum>(ii)</enum>
                    <text>be a hands-on operating room experience in the developing world;</text>
                  </clause> 
<clause id="H9EC83FA5E9F147C4A1455154FFD7B251">
                    <enum>(iii)</enum>
                    <text>utilize a hydrocephalus treatment protocol with an emphasis on ETV/CPC as the preferred treatment when medically appropriate; and</text>
                  </clause> 
<clause id="H2FBF30EEF4F64B7EB91503782F3F338C">
                    <enum>(iv)</enum>
                    <text>require that each trainee complete a minimum of 50 ETV/CPC or ETV procedures and at least 25 VP shunt procedures. </text>
                  </clause>
                </subparagraph>
              </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD85D13A4486244249023A298984F0EAF">
                <enum>(3)</enum>
                <header>Treatment centers</header> 
<subparagraph id="HF716AB3CAAE347C1AFB7491172533CB3">
                  <enum>(A)</enum>
                  <header>In general</header>
                  <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Assistance provided under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Foreign Assistance Act of 1961/s:137/ss:b" proposed="true">subsection (b)</cato:entity-ref> shall, to the maximum extent practicable, be used to establish at least 20 hydrocephalus treatment centers located at public and private hospital in developing countries with a high incidence of hydrocephalus, which shall include treatment costs, endoscopy equipment and medical supplies necessary to provide ETV/CPC procedures to treat hydrocephalus.</text>
                </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF1AF6F08E57D47C1ACD4CEFB63DD9BA3">
                  <enum>(B)</enum>
                  <header>Staffing</header>
                  <text>The treatment centers described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Foreign Assistance Act of 1961/s:137/ss:c/p:3/sp:A" proposed="true">subparagraph (A)</cato:entity-ref> shall be staffed by—</text> 
<clause id="H4BB22D398E2D4D35BD98B38537B69195">
                    <enum>(i)</enum>
                    <text>one or more surgeons who have successfully completed the surgeon training program provided pursuant to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Foreign Assistance Act of 1961/s:137/ss:c/p:2" proposed="true">paragraph (2)</cato:entity-ref>; and</text>
                  </clause> 
<clause id="HD82D0A5B59374607A59A2F9E53656A91">
                    <enum>(ii)</enum>
                    <text>a patient care administrator.</text>
                  </clause>
                </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2715366A357C4CC5ADF5B711D20BE38C">
                  <enum>(C)</enum>
                  <header>Treatment</header>
                  <text>The treatment centers described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Foreign Assistance Act of 1961/s:137/ss:c/p:3/sp:A" proposed="true">subparagraph (A)</cato:entity-ref> shall—</text> 
<clause id="H299F68D74E53417D96208954FD536541">
                    <enum>(i)</enum>
                    <text>provide surgery to treat hydrocephalus in children;</text>
                  </clause> 
<clause id="HB5ED4A0172744FE181B555EB0D3185E7">
                    <enum>(ii)</enum>
                    <text>perform at least 50 hydrocephalus surgeries annually including a minimum of 25 ETV or ETV/CPC surgeries; and</text>
                  </clause> 
<clause id="H069FEE14717C4C12A7F1F09D711183D7">
                    <enum>(iii)</enum>
                    <text>provide post-surgery care and support for the children treated in accordance with <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Foreign Assistance Act of 1961/s:137/ss:c/p:3/sp:C/cl:i" proposed="true">clause (i)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
                  </clause>
                </subparagraph> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7EF0517C1A554F44B40E23827A496936">
                <enum>(4)</enum>
                <header>Medical records and data</header>
                <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Assistance provided under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Foreign Assistance Act of 1961/s:137/ss:b" proposed="true">subsection (b)</cato:entity-ref> shall, to the maximum extent practicable, include the maintenance of medical records which track patient care activities and information about the causes and incidence rates of PIH.</text>
              </paragraph>
            </subsection> 
<subsection id="H96A1E063A54440F6AEA68D9EBEFE1E15">
              <enum>(d)</enum>
              <header>Definitions</header>
              <text>In this section:</text> 
<paragraph id="H74C16F0A8C6A4CC292433DBEFBAD5DE5">
                <enum>(1)</enum>
                <header>CPC</header>
                <text>The term <term>CPC</term> means choroid plexus cauterization, a surgical procedure to reduce the production of cerebrospinal fluid in the brain.</text>
              </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5BC6FD13666A434BB6DC0E2F0081545E">
                <enum>(2)</enum>
                <header>ETV</header>
                <text>The term <term>ETV</term> means endoscopic third ventriculostomy, a shunt-less surgical procedure in which an opening is created in the floor of the third ventricle of the brain allowing cerebrospinal fluid to bypass any obstruction and flow directly to the basal cisterns.</text>
              </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3BB5F2A036254E72B256973AF6DB957E">
                <enum>(3)</enum>
                <header>ETV/CPC</header>
                <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>ETV/CPC</term> means the shunt-less surgical method for treating hydrocephalus through the combination of ETV and CPC surgical procedures.</text>
              </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H940A08CADAD24467BBD36D794E77FD68">
                <enum>(4)</enum>
                <header>Hydrocephalus</header>
                <text>The term <term>hydrocephalus</term> means a medical condition in which an abnormal accumulation of cerebrospinal fluid in the ventricles or cavities of the brain causes increased intracranial pressure inside the skull and progressive enlargement of the head.</text>
              </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8F369DC966724FD3BB8967BA5DB23D3F">
                <enum>(5)</enum>
                <header>Medical practitioners</header>
                <text>The term <term>medical practitioners</term> means physicians, nurses and other clinicians.</text>
              </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE4C8B740D51C4022ABC365CB4F80FA5A">
                <enum>(6)</enum>
                <header>PIH</header>
                <text>The term <term>PIH</term> means post-infectious or acquired hydrocephalus which is the onset of hydrocephalus after birth due to the affects of an infection, such as meningitis, that has attacked the brain.</text>
              </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H23A6E16E47A44ACD8CF4671B9F99896C">
                <enum>(7)</enum>
                <header>VP shunt</header>
                <text>The term <term>VP shunt</term> means a ventriculoperitonea shunt which is a plastic tube that is regulated by a valve and surgically placed in a brain ventricle that allows the cerebrospinal fluid to flow out of the brain through the tube and into the patient’s abdomen.</text>
              </paragraph>
            </subsection> 
<subsection id="H9955161FBBDD4E2D81DA2569A8B6A699">
              <enum>(e)</enum>
              <header>Authorization of appropriations</header>
              <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">
                <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="auth-auth-approp">Of the amounts made available to carry out this chapter for child survival and maternal health programs, there are authorized to be appropriated to the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> <cato:funds-and-year amount="indefinite" year="2014, 2015, 2016, 2017, 2018">such sums as may be necessary for each of the fiscal years 2014 through 2018</cato:funds-and-year> <cato:property name="purpose">to carry out <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Foreign Assistance Act of 1961/s:137" proposed="true">this section</cato:entity-ref>
                  </cato:property>.</cato:entity>
              </text>
            </subsection>
          </section>
          <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
        </quoted-block>
      </paragraph>
    </section> 
</legis-body> 
</bill>
</doc>