<doc>
  <docmeta id="113hr3296ih">
    <bill congress="113" type="hr" number="3296" version="ih"/>
    <revision size="2765" annotations="0" status="complete" id="3" commit-time="2013-10-21T19:47:50Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113hr3296ih/3.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H4B20866029E640DFB95F277FC8D026BD" key="H" public-private="public">
  <metadata>
<dublinCore>
<title>113 HR 3296 IH: Pay America First Act</title>
<publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</publisher>
<date>2013-10-16</date>
<format>text/xml</format>
<language>EN</language>
<rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
    <congress>113th CONGRESS</congress>
    <session>1st Session</session>
    <legis-num>H. R. 3296</legis-num>
    <current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
    <action>
      <action-date date="20131016">October 16, 2013</action-date>
      <action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="G000572">Mr. Gallego</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name>
      </action-desc>
    </action>
    <legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
    <official-title display="yes">To authorize the United States Department of Treasury to prioritize certain payments in the event that the debt limit is reached.</official-title>
  </form>
  <legis-body id="H9227D221C22B4F4BB96DFAB5A63F1253" style="OLC">
    <section id="HC93BE852E1654AD0B42BB5DD2F4B9D09" section-type="section-one">
      <enum>1.</enum>
      <header>Short title</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote>
          <short-title>Pay America First Act</short-title>
        </quote>.</text>
    </section>
    <section id="H673163A1844D48D7ACED31FFBCF2F0F6">
      <enum>2.</enum>
      <header>Authority to protect America’s seniors, veterans, and other domestic payments prior to debt obligations to foreign bondholders</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act shall take effect if the United States Government defaults on its legal obligations for the first time in its history, as evidenced by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary of the Treasury</cato:entity-ref> taking any of the following actions:</text>
      <paragraph id="id0BE40A56F2FD47189107EE1315307E48" indent="up1">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text>Withhold from making payments of debt obligations to foreign bond holders, including those in China, Iran, and the Cayman Islands, before making payments of debt obligations to programs as listed below:</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="idC9CE7BBDF12F4D698A5A72BB6B9898E0">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <text>Make a payment of a debt obligation to the Social Security and Medicare trust funds or redeem a debt obligation held by those trust funds.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id32A499F186794FDF8F65DB39A686D750">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <text>Redeem a debt obligation held by a trust fund providing veterans benefits, including the Veterans Special Life Insurance Fund, the Veterans Reopened Insurance Fund, the Armed Forces Retirement Home Fund, and the Court of Veteran Appeals Retirement Fund.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="idF0760249C0B24555B830646676670E5B">
        <enum>(c)</enum>
        <text>Redeem a debt obligation held by an intragovernmental fund with the purpose of assisting Americans during a natural disaster, including reserves for the National Flood Insurance Program and other disaster relief funds appropriated to the President.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id9C2E56EA399542F4B0A7CAD718065161">
        <enum>(d)</enum>
        <text>Make a payment of debt obligations to the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="9700">Department of Defense</cato:entity-ref>, including civilian and uniformed personnel (Army, Navy, Marines, Air Force), military active pay and military retirement benefits, and military benefits to their families.</text>
      </paragraph>
    </section>
    <section id="H8254047EE2514428B3AA02F4C0DB1FFD">
      <enum>3.</enum>
      <header>Report on certain actions</header>
      <paragraph id="id228842F3F56A4270B67ECAA3A472D6EA" indent="up1">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general, after the date of the enactment of this Act, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary of Treasury</cato:entity-ref> exercises his or her authority under subsection (a), the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall thereafter submit a report each week to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> on the payments issued and amount of revenues incoming and remaining reserves for upcoming payments issued.</text>
      </paragraph>
    </section>
  </legis-body>
</bill>
</doc>