<doc>
  <docmeta id="113hr5250ih">
    <bill congress="113" type="hr" number="5250" version="ih"/>
    <revision size="9444" annotations="0" status="complete" id="6" commit-time="2014-08-06T22:14:36Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113hr5250ih/6.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H70CA1BF997E84115AD7D999259F4BE08" public-private="public">
	<metadata>
<dublinCore>
<dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">113 HR 5250 IH: Restore Opportunity, Strengthen, and Improve the Economy Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">2014-07-29</dc:date>
<dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>113th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>2d Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 5250</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20140729">July 29, 2014</action-date>
			<action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>
      </action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To use Federal purchasing power to create good jobs, rebuild the middle class, address income
			 inequality, stimulate the economy, and to achieve other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H227A988F954B4C86B57207D19FF943A4" style="OLC">
		<section id="H0C5BEB6546934BA590230E62A2E29C71" section-type="section-one">
      <enum>1.</enum>
      <header>Short title</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote>
          <short-title>
            <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Restore Opportunity, Strengthen, and Improve the Economy Act" proposed="true">Restore Opportunity, Strengthen, and Improve the Economy Act</cato:entity-ref>
          </short-title>
        </quote>.</text>
		</section>
    <section id="HB741321E66354817B4C98667D63953E9">
      <enum>2.</enum>
      <header>Findings and purposes</header>
			<subsection id="H581EA41CF9944F32A92238C45905D2EF">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Findings</header>
        <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="0001" entity-type="federal-body">Congress of the United States</cato:entity-ref> finds the following:</text>
				<paragraph id="HC78A40E53A8D485080CF54C1BD44F9E7">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>The disappearance of good jobs, the shrinking of the middle class, and growing income inequality
			 are the greatest domestic challenges confronting the Nation.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H4DC011F914A64F4786B800C4C5570108">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>The United States Government is the largest purchaser of goods and services in the Nation’s
			 private-sector economy, spending over $1.5 trillion dollars annually at
			 firms that employ a quarter of American workers.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HED570E0A09CA46379040A72276229EA3">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
					<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H5FFBBD91E0EE47BF880827C64062A027">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>Federal purchasing power is currently creating millions of poverty-level jobs, subsidizing labor
			 law-breakers, and funding ballooning executive compensation.</text>
					</subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H857872812C9B4E939DD355B9DF4F35C9" indent="up1">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>The Federal Government is the Nation’s leading creator of low-wage jobs in the private sector,
			 funding more than 2,000,000 jobs paying under $12 per hour.</text>
					</subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H8EF15EBF2854469A8151C857AB78706A" indent="up1">
            <enum>(C)</enum>
            <text>The Federal Government awards taxpayer dollars to a substantial number of firms that violate
			 Federal labor, employment, and occupational safety laws.</text>
					</subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="HE46E78631DC54F2CB2EB24171D06F2D2" indent="up1">
            <enum>(D)</enum>
            <text>Federal Government purchasing subsidizes the excessive salaries of private-sector executives who do
			 business with the American people.</text>
					</subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H323FDC4610A34AA8817899C05D3442D5">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
          <text>When Federal purchasing power is used in such a manner, workers have less to spend on the
			 necessities of life and are forced to rely on public assistance. Lack of
			 working purchasing power hurts job creation and undermines economic
			 growth, ultimately imposing significant costs on American taxpayers.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H4E8B8750EA054C9DB81F37BB3F5554ED">
          <enum>(5)</enum>
					<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H7850A92749994F31BD2B8AEF9770B3CB">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>Federal purchasing power should be used to create good jobs, rebuild the middle class, and curb
			 rising income inequality.</text>
					</subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H025D00F28435422C96F3ACB9A4A907B2" indent="up1">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>Federal purchasing power should be used to create good jobs for America. Good jobs allow workers
			 and their families to live in dignity without relying on public assistance
			 or private charity. Good jobs pay enough to provide for subsistence,
			 health care, education, housing, and savings, as well as enough disposable
			 income to allow workers to enjoy quality time off with their loved ones.</text>
					</subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="HCAB8373D7B784246A94A8934C2A7275C" indent="up1">
            <enum>(C)</enum>
            <text>Federal purchasing power should be used to rebuild the middle class. A strong middle class
			 stimulates the economy by increasing consumer spending and job growth.</text>
					</subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="HE0043ED74ED846CD9E11756ECC782CFA" indent="up1">
            <enum>(D)</enum>
            <text>Federal purchasing power should be used to narrow the growing gulf between the richest one percent
			 of the population and ordinary working families that is threatening the
			 survival of participatory democracy.</text>
					</subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="HDBF04A7C0D50437A870925B8F4B5CC18">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Purposes</header>
        <text>The purposes of this Act are the following:</text>
				<paragraph commented="no" id="H3F1CE86ED62F42C391CD914EE2B848CB">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>To use Federal purchasing power to incentivize private-sector firms.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph commented="no" id="H66F1B9FAD12B4F66B81CD23198D2637B">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>To create good jobs for America’s workers.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph commented="no" id="H0E8A81E7557848248A408CDAE6D518DA">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <text>To rebuild America’s middle class.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph commented="no" id="H019FC22210724F1BA48A5EEFBA319421">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
          <text>To address America’s crisis of income inequality.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph commented="no" id="H78B0F1FB21A943A493778A46B45A5198">
          <enum>(5)</enum>
          <text>To invigorate the economy by increasing the purchasing power of working Americans.</text>
				</paragraph>
      </subsection>
    </section>
    <section id="HFDE6D84D49874E5ABAAEEA36B2E13DA5">
      <enum>3.</enum>
      <header>Good jobs model employer standards</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">For purposes of this Act, a Good Jobs Model Employer is one which meets the following standards:</text>
			<paragraph id="HB31694D2DE4D4A14A1D3C8932B6B7E61">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text>Respects employees’ rights to bargain collectively with their employers without being forced to
			 take strike action to win better wages and working conditions.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H71F11E7B9FBA44CF808EF70006D469E8">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text>Offers to each employee living wages, decent benefits including health care, paid leave for
			 sickness and caregiving, and fair work schedules that are predictable and
			 stable.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H47569AD32E3E4451997AED5D91FFAC00">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <text>Affirmatively demonstrates an exemplary standard of compliance with workplace protection laws,
			 including laws governing labor relations, wages and hours, and health and
			 safety, as well as other applicable labor laws.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H3D878429DFD94621B452B75E66F22433">
        <enum>(4)</enum>
        <text>Limits executive compensation to 50 times the median salary paid to the company’s workers.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H27E347FEB6AA49F08DE7E6C5D52D904C">
        <enum>(5)</enum>
        <text>Employs a workforce not less than 35 percent of which reside within one or more Historically
			 Underutilized Business Zones.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H306515D0D2FF49B39E16558225074AF9">
        <enum>(6)</enum>
        <text>Subcontracts only with other Good Jobs Model Employers.</text>
			</paragraph>
    </section>
    <section id="H442F04DE0FF24F2C8CB35E645D9E07F6">
      <enum>4.</enum>
      <header>Application to Federal contracts and assistance</header>
			<subsection id="HBB1826A72E4C45D89607E8533278FAD3">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Eligibility for award of procurement contracts</header>
        <text>In the award of a contract for the acquisition of supplies or services, an executive agency may not
			 award the contract to a source that is not a Good Jobs Model Employer,
			 unless there is no offer from a source that is a Good Jobs Model Employer.</text>
			</subsection>
      <subsection id="H81C4713150B048C09CC3F9694BA89DB0">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Eligibility for award of financial and nonfinancial assistance</header>
        <text>An executive agency may not provide other forms of financial or nonfinancial assistance to entities
			 that are not model employers when there is a similarly situated Good Jobs
			 Model Employer that could receive the assistance, unless doing so would
			 substantially undermine the value of the assistance to the public good.</text>
			</subsection>
      <subsection id="HC14C190214164B958160D4698CBFB968">
        <enum>(c)</enum>
        <header>Incorporation into future Federal contracts and assistance agreements</header>
        <text>Beginning on January 1, 2015, executive agencies shall incorporate into each new contract,
			 contract-like instrument, or assistance agreement a clause requiring the
			 contractor or recipient to conduct itself as a Good Jobs Model Employer
			 for the duration of the contract.</text>
			</subsection>
      <subsection id="H2C99ECEDA294461C9D868D0D89B1AFBE">
        <enum>(d)</enum>
        <header>Exclusions</header>
        <text>None of the provisions of this section shall be interpreted to apply to—</text>
				<paragraph id="HAADC505EF9CE4D809ADDF147E15AA54F">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>direct Federal statutory entitlements;</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HACE22AE1CCAF428D99C980F101FC4786">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>mandatory awards;</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H9D78865F122A4F58869CFA0B57E6E954">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <text>direct awards to foreign governments or public international organizations;</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H1F123E14B3F84669A37E862B72A28A30">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
          <text>benefits to an individual as a personal entitlement; or</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H32E61CCD10444D56B960874617EF362C">
          <enum>(5)</enum>
          <text>Federal employment.</text>
				</paragraph>
      </subsection>
    </section>
    <section id="HBB31B2DA831145A3A6C5F4BAF66DE400">
      <enum>5.</enum>
      <header>Implementation</header>
			<subsection id="HECD58525502E40B6840C181F9B3DCC66">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Good jobs model employer standards</header>
        <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1600" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of Labor</cato:entity-ref> shall promulgate regulations implementing the Good Jobs Model Employer
			 Standards of <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Restore Opportunity, Strengthen, and Improve the Economy Act/s:3/ss:a" proposed="true">section 3(a)</cato:entity-ref> so as to effect the policy and purposes of this
			 Act within 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act. The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1600" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary
			 of Labor</cato:entity-ref> shall amend these regulations as necessary so that they continue
			 to effect the policy and purposes of this Act.</text>
			</subsection>
      <subsection id="H4D4F0745FCB94425B3CA28E8F5917624">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Procurement policy</header>
        <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="4700" entity-type="federal-body">Administrator of General Services</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="9700" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of Defense</cato:entity-ref>, and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="8000" entity-type="federal-body">Administrator of the
			 National Aeronautics and Space Administration</cato:entity-ref>, in coordination with the
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1103" value="Office of Federal Procurement Policy">Office of Federal Procurement Policy</cato:entity-ref>, shall amend the Federal Acquisition
			 Regulation within 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act to
			 effect the policy and purposes of this Act, and subsequently as necessary
			 to continue to effect the policy and purposes of this Act.</text>
			</subsection>
      <subsection id="HF585821B0F4B4D94AE11156BEA408EE3">
        <enum>(c)</enum>
        <header>Debarment or suspension</header>
				<paragraph id="HBF4A44CE384B45FEBF6B04CE1D5F437F">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>An organization which acquires any form of financial or nonfinancial benefit or a contract from an
			 executive agency through the operation of the procedure described in
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Restore Opportunity, Strengthen, and Improve the Economy Act/s:4" proposed="true">section 4</cato:entity-ref> shall be placed on the Excluded Parties List enacted by
			 Executive Orders 12549 and 12689 for a period of at least 2 years if it
			 fails to remain a model employer for the duration of the benefit.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HCE190AE437294278959715583411FC6D">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>An organization which violates a Good Job Model Employer clause in a contract or agreement required
			 by <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Restore Opportunity, Strengthen, and Improve the Economy Act/s:4/ss:c" proposed="true">section 4(c)</cato:entity-ref> shall be placed on the Excluded Parties List enacted by
			 Executive Orders 12549 and 12689 for a period of 3 years.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HC5775E9BEA4740BEABE79315C011FFD0">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <text>Parties which are suspended multiple times may be debarred permanently.</text>
				</paragraph>
      </subsection>
    </section>
    <section id="H0A58BA23EBF94F9FAEF03A28CC439574">
      <enum>6.</enum>
      <header>Severability</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">If any provision of this Act, or applying such provision to any person or circumstance, is held to
			 be invalid, the remainder of this Act and the application of the
			 provisions of such to any person or circumstance shall not be affected
			 thereby.</text>
		</section>
  </legis-body>
</bill>
</doc>