<doc>
  <docmeta id="113hr3922ih">
    <bill congress="113" type="hr" number="3922" version="ih"/>
    <revision size="33729" annotations="0" status="complete" id="5" commit-time="2014-02-18T23:27:00Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113hr3922ih/5.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H9F7849F6A69149F08152992BE6CBB7C1" public-private="public">
  <metadata>
<dublinCore>
<dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">98 HR 3922 IH: Wild Olympics Wilderness and Wild and Scenic Rivers Act of 2014</dc:title>
<dc:publisher xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">2014-01-17</dc:date>
<dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
    <congress>113th CONGRESS</congress>
    <session>2d Session</session>
    <legis-num>H. R. 3922</legis-num>
    <current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
    <action>
      <action-date date="20140117">January 17, 2014</action-date>
      <action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="K000381">Mr. Kilmer</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name>
      </action-desc>
    </action>
    <legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
    <official-title>To designate and expand wilderness areas in Olympic National Forest in the State of Washington, and to designate certain rivers in Olympic National Forest and Olympic National Park as wild and scenic rivers, and for other purposes.</official-title>
  </form>
  <legis-body id="H7AC9B39FD27C4A348311C4E051C8D51A" style="OLC">
    <section id="H58B85A0A3B2640009ED155562801894D" section-type="section-one">
      <enum>1.</enum>
      <header>Short title</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote>
          <short-title>
            <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Wild Olympics Wilderness and Wild and Scenic Rivers Act of 2014" proposed="true">Wild Olympics Wilderness and Wild and Scenic Rivers Act of 2014</cato:entity-ref>
          </short-title>
        </quote>.</text>
    </section>
    <section id="H5616FAC2530F46A3A26EC8D64FA0E2FB">
      <enum>2.</enum>
      <header>Findings</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">
        <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> finds that—</text>
      <paragraph id="HCD66F090C872432B96DA6546154B36CF">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text>wilderness and wild and scenic river designations provide myriad benefits to the local community and beyond, including—</text>
        <subparagraph id="H2B48ABEB5D1B4635BA0CAD2D0BEB01A3">
          <enum>(A)</enum>
          <text>recreation, as evidenced by the more than 12,000,000 visitors each year to wilderness areas who participate in recreation activities such as hiking, horseback riding, hunting, fishing, skiing, climbing, camping, and floating and rafting;</text>
        </subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="H04D7847AEB8547288537ABC6F051BAA4">
          <enum>(B)</enum>
          <text>wildlife habitat, by providing permanent and durable protection for habitat for varied wildlife species, including endangered species;</text>
        </subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="HE12BB130CE5B424DBB13D5AB13E23995">
          <enum>(C)</enum>
          <text>clean water for local communities that rely on the Olympic National Forest as the source for clean and safe drinking water;</text>
        </subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="H913A2DD8438C45A0BF1C806E5929EFE8">
          <enum>(D)</enum>
          <text>municipal watersheds for cities such as Port Townsend, Washington;</text>
        </subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="HB830920613294D2A89D120A6BD03F180">
          <enum>(E)</enum>
          <text>the ancient forests, salmon streams, and unique scenery of the Olympic National Forest, which provide local businesses with a competitive edge over other regions in attracting and retaining the talented people required by local companies;</text>
        </subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="HE3B2250FE08845D0932288294977DF4B">
          <enum>(F)</enum>
          <text>the popular National Parks, monuments, wilderness areas, and other public land of the West, which have provided a competitive advantage to the growing high technology and professional services industries of the West, such as health care, education, and business, enabling the West to outperform the rest of the United States economy in key measures of growth, including employment, population, and personal income during the 4 decades immediately preceding the date of enactment of this Act; and</text>
        </subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="H75C7E028DF1C44C7B54B3AAFEFE66B0C">
          <enum>(G)</enum>
          <text>protecting and enhancing local travel, tourism, hunting, fishing, and outdoor recreation industries;</text>
        </subparagraph>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H7E817904B2DF41009AB6275C4CB3AF0D">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text>under the <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Wilderness Act">Wilderness Act</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1131">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/16/1131/etseq">16 U.S.C. 1131 et seq</cato:entity-ref>.</external-xref>)</cato:entity>—</text>
        <subparagraph id="H2DCB3597A7F2499EAA7F481014425A70">
          <enum>(A)</enum>
          <text>land designated as wilderness protects <quote>ecological, geological, or other features of scientific, scenic, or historical value</quote>;</text>
        </subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="H5D7B0C26CE754A4198DF7F84C296360A">
          <enum>(B)</enum>
          <text>Federal agencies retain the ability to use any means necessary to protect and control fire, insects, and diseases, subject to such terms and conditions as the Secretary determines to be appropriate; and</text>
        </subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="HDDA1A97D3DB84790811BCB7B538B26BD">
          <enum>(C)</enum>
          <text>wilderness designations do not apply to private land;</text>
        </subparagraph>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HBDC759F055FE4A31A96EB8D5F900A9C4">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <text>this Act does not designate private land inholdings as wilderness;</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H5DC2B91F28984417853BB1F42742E962">
        <enum>(4)</enum>
        <text>under the <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Wild and Scenic Rivers Act">Wild and Scenic Rivers Act</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1271">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/16/1271/etseq">16 U.S.C. 1271 et seq</cato:entity-ref>.</external-xref>)</cato:entity>—</text>
        <subparagraph id="HDEC3F9B3698241059FBD374FBC66D53F">
          <enum>(A)</enum>
          <text>certain rivers are preserved to safeguard outstanding natural, cultural, and recreational values for current and future generations;</text>
        </subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="H264398F6207A41BCA88ABB4155C71825">
          <enum>(B)</enum>
          <text>designation as a wild and scenic river does not give the Federal Government control over private property and provides no additional authority for expanding designated river segments, except as provided in this Act and other Acts;</text>
        </subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="H93CBA722EA2C4EC7A66A2BCF7C495432">
          <enum>(C)</enum>
          <text>existing water rights are not impacted;</text>
        </subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="HB4536F87DB2A427C8B754A149358EEE7">
          <enum>(D)</enum>
          <text>the jurisdiction of the States and the Federal Government over waters are not impacted, as determined by established principles of law; and</text>
        </subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="H163BED4F84294140ABD803F013123E3B">
          <enum>(E)</enum>
          <text>river segments classified as <quote>scenic</quote> or <quote>recreational</quote> allow construction of new access points, restoration thinning, and motorized access;</text>
        </subparagraph>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HA3D2CBBB8AB749638AE06698BBED0775">
        <enum>(5)</enum>
        <text>the areas protected under this Act unquestionably meet all requirements under Federal law (including regulations), as the areas contain—</text>
        <subparagraph id="H2D0A5B6544B74C7DAA482BAB5A8FBFD0">
          <enum>(A)</enum>
          <text>old growth stands, temperate rain forests, and large swaths of roadless forests, more than 99 percent of which could not be commercially harvested under existing Federal law (including regulations);</text>
        </subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="HE63EEAE302F14CCA82DCF328A05C0E01">
          <enum>(B)</enum>
          <text>the wilderness areas established under this Act are areas that are prized by hikers, hunters, anglers, and others and will be preserved and protected for recreational enjoyment for generations to come; and</text>
        </subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="H83FB1F0768B34D0EA7160F99C9C79F95">
          <enum>(C)</enum>
          <text>rivers and tributaries that—</text>
          <clause id="HC51CA9183B8D4A62BAB433BDC1B57864">
            <enum>(i)</enum>
            <text>are a source of clean water for many communities on the Olympic Peninsula; and</text>
          </clause>
          <clause id="H7B296A7092A24399AF2F86D24AB4D150">
            <enum>(ii)</enum>
            <text>provide important habitat for salmon and other species of fish and supply the cold freshwater that feeds the Puget Sound and creates the necessary conditions for clams, oysters, and mussels, whose growers contribute more than $250,000,000 to the economy and support thousands of jobs in the State of Washington;</text>
          </clause>
        </subparagraph>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HB623860114D34039833A664B11F1237D">
        <enum>(6)</enum>
        <text>as a result of this Act—</text>
        <subparagraph id="HDB8D5E1ACD574B1790EEC07DA3B47148">
          <enum>(A)</enum>
          <text>no roads would be closed;</text>
        </subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="HA996601B71F447E492E4354515E84F93">
          <enum>(B)</enum>
          <text>management decisions by local Forest Service managers as to which roads should be closed, maintained, or remain open for public access will not be impacted and any ongoing travel management processes will continue to be the manner by which those decisions are made, along with public input; and</text>
        </subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="H403FA249DA2B42EF964587A26A5519E9">
          <enum>(C)</enum>
          <text>no private land would be subject to management under the <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Wilderness Act">Wilderness Act</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1131">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/16/1131/etseq">16 U.S.C. 1131 et seq</cato:entity-ref>.</external-xref>)</cato:entity> or the <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Wild and Scenic Rivers Act">Wild and Scenic Rivers Act</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1271">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/16/1271/etseq">16 U.S.C. 1271 et seq</cato:entity-ref>.</external-xref>)</cato:entity>;</text>
        </subparagraph>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HFE3943C549034BBB81ED847E060A2DDA">
        <enum>(7)</enum>
        <text>private property rights are central to the United States and the economy of the United States, and it shall be the policy of the United States to encourage, support, and promote the private ownership of property to ensure that the constitutional and other legal rights of private property owners are not abridged by the Federal Government;</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H6E0D070CD20A402ABEEDA38F901DB7DF">
        <enum>(8)</enum>
        <text>the Olympic Peninsula is home to 8 federally recognized Indian tribes; and</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HEF0C0F95743A4C24B811C99D054EFE43">
        <enum>(9)</enum>
        <text>the United States acknowledges the trust obligations of the Federal Government to Indian tribes and recognizes that—</text>
        <subparagraph id="HBCE47A9CB23E499F9E3D1C9446A1847E">
          <enum>(A)</enum>
          <text>the case styled United States v. Washington (384 F. Supp. 312) guaranteed certain Indian tribes in the State of Washington harvest rights to Pacific salmon, leading to employment opportunities for tribal members;</text>
        </subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="H723E136DF43E4D0E9BCF453525C30D23">
          <enum>(B)</enum>
          <text>tribal governments provide a wide range of critical services to enrolled members, including education and cultural activities;</text>
        </subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="H779CC9BEFBFE43BBB931797BD3F2805B">
          <enum>(C)</enum>
          <text>Indian tribes engage in ongoing efforts to restore and improve salmon populations and habitat across the Olympic Peninsula, frequently in conjunction with Federal, State, and local governments and private stakeholders; and</text>
        </subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="H6E5BF6BDADB74DA19C96E2BD5A0FC491">
          <enum>(D)</enum>
          <text>ongoing tribal efforts to protect and improve salmon habitat and the habitats of other threatened species populations are encouraged and supported in order to support the long-term health of the ecosystem and the economic benefit those resources provide.</text>
        </subparagraph>
      </paragraph>
    </section>
    <section id="HB69CB8914CB3461C93C87490289B2038">
      <enum>3.</enum>
      <header>Designation of Olympic National Forest wilderness areas</header>
      <subsection id="HE864A0A803584211B9ED7CE49F17C77B">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>In General</header>
        <text>In furtherance of the <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Wilderness Act">Wilderness Act</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1131">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/16/1131/etseq">16 U.S.C. 1131 et seq</cato:entity-ref>.</external-xref>)</cato:entity>, the following Federal land in the Olympic National Forest in the State of Washington comprising approximately 126,554 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>Proposed Wild Olympics Wilderness and Wild and Scenic Rivers Act</quote> and dated May 29, 2012 (referred to in this section as the <term>map</term>), is designated as wilderness and as components of the National Wilderness Preservation System:</text>
        <paragraph id="H5893C890FD394B1B99DB0F0A4C7E3078">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>Lost Creek Wilderness</header>
          <text>Certain Federal land managed by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="12C2">Forest Service</cato:entity-ref>, comprising approximately 7,159 acres, as generally depicted on the map, which shall be known as the <term>Lost Creek Wilderness</term>.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H94E924AB1B934DC7AB519C63AE9A399E">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Rugged Ridge Wilderness</header>
          <text>Certain Federal land managed by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="12C2">Forest Service</cato:entity-ref>, comprising approximately 5,956 acres, as generally depicted on the map, which shall be known as the <term>Rugged Ridge Wilderness</term>.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HC2D99E8953704536A95B8A28D048B6DC">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <header>Alckee Creek Wilderness</header>
          <text>Certain Federal land managed by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="12C2">Forest Service</cato:entity-ref>, comprising approximately 1,787 acres, as generally depicted on the map, which shall be known as the <term>Alckee Creek Wilderness</term>.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HFF2EBFD5B1AF40A1AAE71DA88E3E9F5B">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
          <header>Gates of the Elwha Wilderness</header>
          <text>Certain Federal land managed by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="12C2">Forest Service</cato:entity-ref>, comprising approximately 5,669 acres, as generally depicted on the map, which shall be known as the <term>Gates of the Elwha Wilderness</term>.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HA18F5D8A819148FE90E24B1CDBE97037">
          <enum>(5)</enum>
          <header>Buckhorn Wilderness additions</header>
          <text>Certain Federal land managed by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="12C2">Forest Service</cato:entity-ref>, comprising approximately 21,965 acres, as generally depicted on the map, is incorporated in, and shall be managed as part of, the <term>Buckhorn Wilderness</term>, as designated by <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Washington State Wilderness Act of 1984/s:3">section 3 of the Washington State Wilderness Act of 1984</cato:entity-ref> (<cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/16/1132/note">
                <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1132">
              16 U.S.C. 1132
            </external-xref> note</cato:entity-ref>; <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/98/339">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="public-law" value="public-law/98/339">Public Law 98–339</cato:entity-ref>
            </external-xref>)</cato:entity>.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HCCB7D8F4D44C4AA78E96DE5A2E88EA89">
          <enum>(6)</enum>
          <header>Green Mountain Wilderness</header>
          <text>Certain Federal land managed by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="12C2">Forest Service</cato:entity-ref>, comprising approximately 4,790 acres, as generally depicted on the map, which shall be known as the <term>Green Mountain Wilderness</term>.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HEA1926089F1E4576A82B0E38EDF93DBA">
          <enum>(7)</enum>
          <header>The Brothers Wilderness additions</header>
          <text>Certain land managed by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="12C2">Forest Service</cato:entity-ref>, comprising approximately 8,625 acres, as generally depicted on the map, is incorporated in, and shall be managed as part of, the <term>The Brothers Wilderness</term>, as designated by <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Washington State Wilderness Act of 1984/s:3">section 3 of the Washington State Wilderness Act of 1984</cato:entity-ref> (<cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/16/1132/note">
                <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1132">
              16 U.S.C. 1132
            </external-xref> note</cato:entity-ref>; <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/98/339">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="public-law" value="public-law/98/339">Public Law 98–339</cato:entity-ref>
            </external-xref>)</cato:entity>.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H37A09F7F3D444CD9BC0D07E53FDEF6F6">
          <enum>(8)</enum>
          <header>Mount Skokomish Wilderness additions</header>
          <text>Certain land managed by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="12C2">Forest Service</cato:entity-ref>, comprising approximately 8,933 acres, as generally depicted on the map, is incorporated in, and shall be managed as part of, the <term>Mount Skokomish Wilderness</term>, as designated by <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Washington State Wilderness Act of 1984/s:3">section 3 of the Washington State Wilderness Act of 1984</cato:entity-ref> (<cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/16/1132/note">
                <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1132">
              16 U.S.C. 1132
            </external-xref> note</cato:entity-ref>; <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/98/339">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="public-law" value="public-law/98/339">Public Law 98–339</cato:entity-ref>
            </external-xref>)</cato:entity>.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H10328B8DDA4D4E6EA67A1AD4E8C4D893">
          <enum>(9)</enum>
          <header>Wonder Mountain Wilderness additions</header>
          <text>Certain land managed by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="12C2">Forest Service</cato:entity-ref>, comprising approximately 26,517 acres, as generally depicted on the map, is incorporated in, and shall be managed as part of, the <term>Wonder Mountain Wilderness</term>, as designated by <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Washington State Wilderness Act of 1984/s:3">section 3 of the Washington State Wilderness Act of 1984</cato:entity-ref> (<cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/16/1132/note">
                <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1132">
              16 U.S.C. 1132
            </external-xref> note</cato:entity-ref>; <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/98/339">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="public-law" value="public-law/98/339">Public Law 98–339</cato:entity-ref>
            </external-xref>)</cato:entity>.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H848191FE8A5D4C98BA14AEE36FCE1307">
          <enum>(10)</enum>
          <header>Moonlight Dome Wilderness</header>
          <text>Certain Federal land managed by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="12C2">Forest Service</cato:entity-ref>, comprising approximately 9,117 acres, as generally depicted on the map, which shall be known as the <term>Moonlight Dome Wilderness</term>.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H3A2993155CCC4F898F85F0DB65FB9495">
          <enum>(11)</enum>
          <header>South Quinault Ridge Wilderness</header>
          <text>Certain Federal land managed by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="12C2">Forest Service</cato:entity-ref>, comprising approximately 10,887 acres, as generally depicted on the map, which shall be known as the <term>South Quinault Ridge Wilderness</term>.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HA033449CBD6B40E98CC4E64A66377DE4">
          <enum>(12)</enum>
          <header>Colonel Bob Wilderness additions</header>
          <text>Certain Federal land managed by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="12C2">Forest Service</cato:entity-ref>, comprising approximately 353 acres, as generally depicted on the map, is incorporated in, and shall be managed as part of, the <term>Colonel Bob Wilderness</term>, as designated by <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Washington State Wilderness Act of 1984/s:3">section 3 of the Washington State Wilderness Act of 1984</cato:entity-ref> (<cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/16/1132/note">
                <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1132">
              16 U.S.C. 1132
            </external-xref> note</cato:entity-ref>; <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/98/339">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="public-law" value="public-law/98/339">Public Law 98–339</cato:entity-ref>
            </external-xref>)</cato:entity>.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HBA67EC04D73D46F393F92B216A928B0C">
          <enum>(13)</enum>
          <header>Sam’s River Wilderness</header>
          <text>Certain Federal land managed by the Forest Service, comprising approximately 13,418 acres, as generally depicted on the map, which shall be known as the <term>Sam’s River Wilderness</term>.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H5ABFFD1090B243B9B6B7F57E580B45E6">
          <enum>(14)</enum>
          <header>Canoe Creek Wilderness</header>
          <text>Certain Federal land managed by the Forest Service, comprising approximately 1,378 acres, as generally depicted on the map, which shall be known as the <term>Canoe Creek Wilderness</term>.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="H71EA1B9EAD4F4E8DAAFD4DC67AC27F18">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Administration</header>
        <paragraph id="H3A6645EB180E4E91AFFC6B70C2F9EE7D">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>Management</header>
          <text>Subject to valid existing rights, the land designated as wilderness by <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Wild Olympics Wilderness and Wild and Scenic Rivers Act of 2014/s:3/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref> shall be administered by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1200">Secretary of Agriculture</cato:entity-ref> (referred to in this section as the <term>Secretary</term>), in accordance with the <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Wilderness Act">Wilderness Act</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1131">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/16/1131/etseq">16 U.S.C. 1131 et seq</cato:entity-ref>.</external-xref>)</cato:entity>, except that any reference in that Act to the effective date of that Act shall be considered to be a reference to the date of enactment of this Act.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H183D2E2F23984A5597052D9C009E33BD">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Map and description</header>
          <subparagraph id="HE19F579EF7F14680AACC60F021146E81">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <header>In general</header>
            <text>As soon as practicable after the date of enactment of this Act, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1200">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall file a map and a legal description of the land designated as wilderness by <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Wild Olympics Wilderness and Wild and Scenic Rivers Act of 2014/s:3/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref> with—</text>
            <clause id="H0C01BAE477C84368AC7E83F574565AA9">
              <enum>(i)</enum>
              <text>the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="committee" entity-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives</cato:entity-ref>; and</text>
            </clause>
            <clause id="H10F7E7E239CE42FAA90D36A93D019CA3">
              <enum>(ii)</enum>
              <text>the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="committee" entity-id="SSEG00">Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
            </clause>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H9377EC90AF4E4F1B9446140E1326E637">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <header>Effect</header>
            <text>Each map and legal description filed under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Wild Olympics Wilderness and Wild and Scenic Rivers Act of 2014/s:3/ss:b/p:2/sp:A" proposed="true">subparagraph (A)</cato:entity-ref> shall have the same force and effect as if included in this Act, except that the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1200">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> may correct minor errors in the map and legal description.</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="HB12AB60C41B441C3B23C6C9EB08BFB2A">
            <enum>(C)</enum>
            <header>Public availability</header>
            <text>Each map and legal description filed under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Wild Olympics Wilderness and Wild and Scenic Rivers Act of 2014/s:3/ss:b/p:2/sp:A" proposed="true">subparagraph (A)</cato:entity-ref> shall be filed and made available for public inspection in the appropriate office of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="12C2">Forest Service</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="HE63F84716170492DBB1E219B3DEBD505">
        <enum>(c)</enum>
        <header>Potential wilderness</header>
        <paragraph id="H4E99A4D4D8204860A84B4897CB5EE96D">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>In general</header>
          <text>In furtherance of the purposes of the <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Wilderness Act">Wilderness Act</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1131">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/16/1131/etseq">16 U.S.C. 1131 et seq</cato:entity-ref>.</external-xref>)</cato:entity>, certain Federal land managed by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="12C2">Forest Service</cato:entity-ref>, comprising approximately 5,346 acres as identified as <term>Potential Wilderness</term> on the map, is designated as potential wilderness.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H1F69693A7349444398000716C2DF4396">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Designation as wilderness</header>
          <text>On the date on which the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1200">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> publishes in the Federal Register notice that any nonconforming uses in the potential wilderness designated by <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Wild Olympics Wilderness and Wild and Scenic Rivers Act of 2014/s:3/ss:c/p:1" proposed="true">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref> have terminated, the potential wilderness shall be—</text>
          <subparagraph id="H68579DE974D344F3870460B8538E7308">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>designated as wilderness and as a component of the National Wilderness Preservation System; and</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H5B1DC638229E4F1FB7CA6A54BC089539">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>incorporated into the adjacent wilderness area.</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="HC29C542DDCFD429AA20586101881F653">
        <enum>(d)</enum>
        <header>Adjacent management</header>
        <paragraph id="H0D1EA3313D5040B69B3AADA1A2912D1D">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>No protective perimeters or buffer zones</header>
          <text>The designations in this section shall not create a protective perimeter or buffer zone around any wilderness area.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H7CE492DAF6154C63B1EC23908EF9BF09">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Nonconforming uses permitted outside of boundaries of wilderness areas</header>
          <text>Any activity or use outside of the boundary of any wilderness area designated under this section shall be permitted even if the activity or use would be seen or heard within the boundary of the wilderness area.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="HA62C868DFFD9485CA9530434EBD6779D">
        <enum>(e)</enum>
        <header>Fire, insects, and diseases</header>
        <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1200">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> may take such measures as are necessary to control fire, insects, and diseases, in the wilderness areas designated by this section, in accordance with <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Wilderness Act/s:4/ss:d/p:1">section 4(d)(1) of the Wilderness Act</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1133">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/16/1133/d/1">16 U.S.C. 1133(d)(1)</cato:entity-ref>
          </external-xref>)</cato:entity> and subject to such terms and conditions as the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1200">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> determines to be appropriate.</text>
      </subsection>
    </section>
    <section id="H0AFBEF51C6CD408FA91496AEE279A673">
      <enum>4.</enum>
      <header>Wild and scenic river designations</header>
      <subsection id="H8E76F7254C134790B22D409CC46888C5">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>In general</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">
          <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Wild and Scenic Rivers Act/s:3/ss:a">Section 3(a) of the Wild and Scenic Rivers Act</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1274">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/16/1274/a">16 U.S.C. 1274(a)</cato:entity-ref>
          </external-xref>)</cato:entity> is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
        <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC91DF5EA848540CE9D90ACA7BE480977" style="OLC">
          <paragraph id="H9E3777EFF905443B90EF0FF5D2B0803C">
            <enum>(208)</enum>
            <header>Elwha River, Washington</header>
            <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The approximately 29.0-mile segment of the Elwha River and tributaries from the source to Cat Creek, to be administered by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1400">Secretary of the Interior</cato:entity-ref> as a wild river.</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H47313448F38143A2A9061BFD32854771">
            <enum>(209)</enum>
            <header>Dungeness River, Washington</header>
            <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The segment of the Dungeness River from the headwaters to the State of Washington Department of Natural Resources land in T. 29 N., R. 4 W., sec. 12, to be administered by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1200">Secretary of Agriculture</cato:entity-ref>, except that portions of the river within the boundaries of Olympic National Park shall be administered by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1400">Secretary of the Interior</cato:entity-ref>, including the following segments of the mainstem and major tributary the Gray Wolf River, in the following classes:</text>
            <subparagraph id="HB11D91CC32654CC89102C9DC145427E3">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>The approximately 5.8-mile segment from the headwaters to the 2860 Bridge, as a wild river.</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="HC804F8E89F084BB9AF77AF56454B9247">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>The approximately 2.1-mile segment from the 2860 Bridge to Silver Creek, as a scenic river.</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="HDDED69F855014EB4A35BCCC2A3D72278">
              <enum>(C)</enum>
              <text>The approximately 2.7-mile segment from Silver Creek to Sleepy Hollow Creek, as a wild river.</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="HC0838B543EE94DDB939B01D1D36DE353">
              <enum>(D)</enum>
              <text>The approximately 6.3-mile segment from Sleepy Hollow Creek to the Olympic National Forest boundary, as a scenic river.</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H53A5168947C34B11B4B92A7E1DFB61D8">
              <enum>(E)</enum>
              <text>The approximately 1.9-mile segment from the National Forest boundary to the State of Washington Department of Natural Resources land in T. 29 N., R. 4 W., sec. 12, as a recreational river.</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="HF055E566673949D79CECBA92144B6E26">
              <enum>(F)</enum>
              <text>The approximately 16.1-mile segment of the Gray Wolf River from the headwaters to the 2870 Bridge, as a wild river.</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H5B67AFC3AD494AD088721004A79A42E7">
              <enum>(G)</enum>
              <text>The approximately 1.1-mile segment of the Gray Wolf River from the 2870 Bridge to the confluence with the Dungeness River, as a scenic river.</text>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H4000F75D1513449CABA949D7F4A883D1">
            <enum>(210)</enum>
            <header>Big Quilcene River, Washington</header>
            <text>The segment of the Big Quilcene River from the headwaters to the City of Port Townsend water intake facility, to be administered by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1200">Secretary of Agriculture</cato:entity-ref>, in the following classes:</text>
            <subparagraph id="H8FD90A0D8C8A4B769E7722787A4AB024">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>The approximately 4.4-mile segment from the headwaters to the Buckhorn Wilderness boundary, as a wild river.</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="HEC1F27C5C2074A06B7783301F0BB6FCE">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>The approximately 5.3-mile segment from the Buckhorn Wilderness boundary to the City of Port Townsend water intake facility, as a scenic river.</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H8EE191EFB5004FFEB504C34D466F6358">
              <enum>(C)</enum>
              <text>
                <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Wild Olympics Wilderness and Wild and Scenic Rivers Act of 2014/s:7/ss:a" proposed="true">Section 7(a)</cato:entity-ref>, with respect to the licensing of dams, water conduits, reservoirs, powerhouses, transmission lines, or other project works, shall apply to the approximately 5-mile segment from the City of Port Townsend water intake facility to the Olympic National Forest boundary.</text>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H994A3FCB72CE4E9A92BF3E9D5C120098">
            <enum>(211)</enum>
            <header>Dosewallips River, Washington</header>
            <text>The segment of the Dosewallips River from the headwaters to the private land in T. 26 N., R. 3 W., sec. 15, to be administered by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1200">Secretary of Agriculture</cato:entity-ref>, except that portions of the river within the boundaries of Olympic National Park shall by administered by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1400">Secretary of the Interior</cato:entity-ref>, in the following classes:</text>
            <subparagraph id="HB5CCAC7A448E4D8E96F557F42B130DCF">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>The approximately 12.9-mile segment from the headwaters to Station Creek, as a wild river.</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H91ABED0F4C6D4115A23380A10D604CA0">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>The approximately 6.8-mile segment from Station Creek to the private land in T. 26 N., R. 3 W., sec. 15, as a scenic river.</text>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H518B6A4412F24D96B610B10756768826">
            <enum>(212)</enum>
            <header>Duckabush River, Washington</header>
            <text>The segment of the Duckabush River from the headwaters to the private land in T. 25 N., R. 3 W., sec. 1, to be administered by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1200">Secretary of Agriculture</cato:entity-ref>, except that portions of the river within the boundaries of Olympic National Park shall by administered by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1400">Secretary of the Interior</cato:entity-ref>, in the following classes:</text>
            <subparagraph id="HE2AFAA983CF44690A59C72883F3BA645">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>The approximately 19.0-mile segment from the headwaters to the Brothers Wilderness boundary, as a wild river.</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H2EAB6DBF94E94215816053A4FB6C0B38">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>The approximately 1.9-mile segment from the Brothers Wilderness boundary to the private land in T. 25 N., R. 3 W., sec. 1, as a scenic river.</text>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H6B116BE718704E12B3F44A46386D7F94">
            <enum>(213)</enum>
            <header>Hamma Hamma River, Washington</header>
            <text>The segment of the Hamma Hamma River from the headwaters to the eastern edge of the NW<fraction>1/4</fraction> sec. 21, T. 24 N., R. 3 W., to be administered by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1200">Secretary of Agriculture</cato:entity-ref>, in the following classes:</text>
            <subparagraph id="H2251191C4332485C9A0B029FFF34789A">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>The approximately 3.1-mile segment from the headwaters to the Mt. Skokomish Wilderness boundary, as a wild river.</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H879150D9589B46008B0EDA635773B83C">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>The approximately 5.8-mile segment from the Mt. Skokomish wilderness boundary to Lena Creek, as a scenic river.</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="HD7244F938EF446AD888E3E82D7FBBCF7">
              <enum>(C)</enum>
              <text>The approximately 6.8-mile segment from Lena Creek to the eastern edge of the NW<fraction>1/4</fraction> sec. 21, T. 24 N., R. 3 W., as a recreational river.</text>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H9886A7D0588C430F9B2E008855A49828">
            <enum>(214)</enum>
            <header>South Fork Skokomish River, Washington</header>
            <text>The segment of the South Fork Skokomish River from the headwaters to the Olympic National Forest boundary to be administered by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1200">Secretary of Agriculture</cato:entity-ref>, in the following classes:</text>
            <subparagraph id="H89CF6ED26077415EB0797AB4975FBF8B">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>The approximately 6.7-mile segment from the headwaters to Rule Creek, as a wild river.</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="HA04A1682DD1045CB83096F527EDC63F7">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>The approximately 8.3-mile segment from Rule Creek to LeBar Creek, as a scenic river.</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H03E0C985C75C4BBF815A774D9AA74B44">
              <enum>(C)</enum>
              <text>The approximately 4.0-mile segment from LeBar Creek to upper end of gorge in the NW<fraction>1/4</fraction> sec. 21, T. 22 N., R. 5 W., as a recreational river.</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H552EEA07EFE440FCAF86ECEA68C7274A">
              <enum>(D)</enum>
              <text>The approximately 6.0-mile segment from the upper end of the gorge to the Olympic National Forest boundary, as a scenic river.</text>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="HBB621BD766E144C0A14BF493F6DB27EA">
            <enum>(215)</enum>
            <header>Middle Fork Satsop River, Washington</header>
            <text>The approximately 7.9-mile segment of the Middle Fork Satsop River from the headwaters to the Olympic National Forest boundary, to be administered by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1200">Secretary of Agriculture</cato:entity-ref>, as a scenic river.</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H8B7B4F94BB814A96B89D3486B463676D">
            <enum>(216)</enum>
            <header>West Fork Satsop River, Washington</header>
            <text>The approximately 8.2-mile segment of the West Fork Satsop River from the headwaters to the Olympic National Forest boundary, to be administered by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1200">Secretary of Agriculture</cato:entity-ref>, as a scenic river.</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H0D72EE6E8F8344789B31E40EC7A241A1">
            <enum>(217)</enum>
            <header>Wynoochee River, Washington</header>
            <text>The segment of the Wynoochee River from the headwaters to Clark Creek to be administered by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1200">Secretary of Agriculture</cato:entity-ref>, except that portions of the river within the boundaries of Olympic National Park shall by administered by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1400">Secretary of the Interior</cato:entity-ref>, in the following classes:</text>
            <subparagraph id="H6820D363B3DA4D288D96306D6FBB0DBE">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>The approximately 1.7-mile segment from the headwaters to the boundary of the Wonder Mountain Wilderness, as a wild river.</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H7F1AAAAB12DB45B3985AF83EE4B86A03">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>The approximately 8.2-mile segment from the boundary of the Wonder Mountain Wilderness to the head of Wynoochee Reservoir, as a recreational river.</text>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H1E716A0541714D6F8EAA432E4550749D">
            <enum>(218)</enum>
            <header>East Fork Humptulips River, Washington</header>
            <text>The segment of the East Fork Humptulips River from the headwaters to the Olympic National Forest boundary to be administered by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1200">Secretary of Agriculture</cato:entity-ref>, in the following classes:</text>
            <subparagraph id="H31D7FDD9226E45308D266B7F034B7655">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>The approximately 7.4-mile segment from the headwaters to the Moonlight Dome wilderness boundary, as a wild river.</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H438E78A2A8AA4E5590DD5FE94E4A6330">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>The approximately 10.3-mile segment from the Moonlight Dome wilderness boundary to the Olympic National Forest boundary, as a scenic river.</text>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H0EE7DA611CDE4714A99383E95F20D502">
            <enum>(219)</enum>
            <header>West Fork Humptulips River, Washington</header>
            <text>The approximately 21.4-mile segment of the West Fork Humptulips River from the source to the Olympic National Forest Boundary, to be administered by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1200">Secretary of Agriculture</cato:entity-ref>, as a scenic river.</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="HD1190B0D39FC46EA88F0E7F3A90859AC">
            <enum>(220)</enum>
            <header>Quinault River, Washington</header>
            <text>The segment of the Quinault River from the headwaters to private land in T. 24 N., R. 8 W., sec. 33, to be administered by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1400">Secretary of the Interior</cato:entity-ref>, in the following classes:</text>
            <subparagraph id="HBE366F5965C644FCB8253748236B85A9">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>The approximately 16.5-mile segment from the headwaters to Graves Creek, as a wild river.</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="HDC3BC500B69444C69520F4460AB2622A">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>The approximately 6.7-mile segment from Graves Creek to Cannings Creek, as a scenic river.</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H5553D8B6E4964F979284C949C6FE8004">
              <enum>(C)</enum>
              <text>The approximately 1.0-mile segment from Cannings Creek to private land in T. 24 N., R. 8 W., sec. 33, as a recreational river.</text>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H58BC442BC7C745E9BEF3EA3184FAB702">
            <enum>(221)</enum>
            <header>Queets River, Washington</header>
            <text>The segment of the Queets River from the headwaters to the Olympic National Park boundary to be administered by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1400">Secretary of the Interior</cato:entity-ref>, except that portions of the river outside the boundaries of Olympic National Park shall be administered by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1200">Secretary of Agriculture</cato:entity-ref>, including the following segments of the mainstem and certain tributaries in the following classes:</text>
            <subparagraph id="H6055CB1FA41E44C795F4D33426508F3A">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>The approximately 28.6-mile segment of the Queets River from the headwaters to the confluence with Sams River, as a wild river.</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H09AAD1A8EB2A4457BBACF1182D14F540">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>The approximately 16.0-mile segment of the Queets River from the confluence with Sams River to the Olympic National Park boundary, as a scenic river.</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="HD5BF6B94BA1A4EACBCCE27DE67377224">
              <enum>(C)</enum>
              <text>The approximately 15.7-mile segment of the Sams River from the headwaters to the confluence with the Queets River, as a scenic river.</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H31757209B6994A3781114EB30CD429BF">
              <enum>(D)</enum>
              <text>The approximately 17.7-mile segment of Matheny Creek from the headwaters to the confluence with the Queets River, as a scenic river.</text>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="HA6CDEE1F62B443A48153A00EC6BA1453">
            <enum>(222)</enum>
            <header>Hoh River, Washington</header>
            <text>The segment of the Hoh River and the major tributary South Fork Hoh from the headwaters to Olympic National Park boundary, to be administered by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1400">Secretary of the Interior</cato:entity-ref>, in the following classes:</text>
            <subparagraph id="HCD34812867494E3C9F9AC3202CE110D5">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>The approximately 20.7-mile segment of the Hoh River from the headwaters to Jackson Creek, as a wild river.</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H7AEB68A2055A4D9BB9A3B8B9266AE16A">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>The approximately 6.0-mile segment of the Hoh River from Jackson Creek to the Olympic National Park boundary, as a scenic river.</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H3A259752D9304279A8F038DD6BAD6F49">
              <enum>(C)</enum>
              <text>The approximately 13.8-mile segment of the South Fork Hoh River from the headwaters to the National Park boundary, as a wild river.</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="HB20FD457B1454F9BB110C9E0763E8C6C">
              <enum>(D)</enum>
              <text>The approximately 4.6-mile segment of the South Fork Hoh River from the National Park boundary to the Washington State Department of Natural Resources boundary in T. 27 N., R. 10 W., sec. 29, as a recreational river.</text>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H990C86F56A8B431ABD988AF8ADD32A3F">
            <enum>(223)</enum>
            <header>Bogachiel River, Washington</header>
            <text>The approximately 25.6-mile segment of the Bogachiel River from the source to the Olympic National Park boundary, to be administered by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1400">Secretary of the Interior</cato:entity-ref>, as a wild river.</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H33763E532B004970A494D559F4AC7285">
            <enum>(224)</enum>
            <header>South Fork Calawah River, Washington</header>
            <text>The segment of the South Fork Calawah River and the major tributary Sitkum River from the headwaters to Hyas Creek to be administered by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1200">Secretary of Agriculture</cato:entity-ref>, except those portions of the river within the boundaries of Olympic National Park shall by administered by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1400">Secretary of the Interior</cato:entity-ref>, including the following segments in the following classes:</text>
            <subparagraph id="HA99EB337E3C74B8A91B7343AEC2D346D">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>The approximately 15.7-mile segment of the South Fork Calawah River from the headwaters to the Sitkum River, as a wild river.</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H6C3E7A7DD430485BA46A665F3688DAB6">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>The approximately 0.9-mile segment of the South Fork Calawah River from the Sitkum River to Hyas Creek, as a scenic river.</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="HDF0EFF3695E343A982CCC9BED5D58862">
              <enum>(C)</enum>
              <text>The approximately 1.6-mile segment of the Sitkum River from the source to the Rugged Ridge Wilderness boundary, as a wild river.</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H841C53588F9B4816B52B7E90D55068A3">
              <enum>(D)</enum>
              <text>The approximately 11.9-mile segment of the Sitkum River from the Rugged Ridge Wilderness boundary to the confluence with the South Fork Calawah, as a scenic river.</text>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="HD1160656155C4F01AF8EDABAFD1D6AE5">
            <enum>(225)</enum>
            <header>Sol Duc River, Washington</header>
            <text>The segment of the Sol Duc River from the headwaters to the Olympic National Park boundary, including the following segments of the mainstem and certain tributaries in the following classes:</text>
            <subparagraph id="HB9FD878DB171459E84F5B720DA5AFCD5">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>The approximately 7.0-mile segment of the Sol Duc River from the headwaters to the end of Sol Duc Hot Springs Road, as a wild river.</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H4D20F29892964E83B8BE984B6E60825D">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>The approximately 10.8-mile segment of the Sol Duc River from the end of Sol Duc Hot Springs Road to the Olympic National Park boundary, as a scenic river.</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H79A30460C8C54516B6EA2B59AA257D33">
              <enum>(C)</enum>
              <text>The approximately 13.8-mile segment of the North Fork Sol Duc River from the headwaters to the Olympic Hot Springs Road bridge, as a wild river.</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="HC2128AC818F74F6997B39ABD8C9920DB">
              <enum>(D)</enum>
              <text>The approximately 0.2-mile segment of the North Fork Sol Duc River from the Olympic Hot Springs Road bridge to the confluence with the Sol Duc River, as a scenic river.</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H2846CFE6B6304C1693B316E304559AFA">
              <enum>(E)</enum>
              <text>The approximately 8.0-mile segment of the South Fork Sol Duc River from the headwaters to the confluence with the Sol Duc River, as a scenic river.</text>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H94A597014C8F4BBA8D0F2A4B16C31F08">
            <enum>(226)</enum>
            <header>Lyre River, Washington</header>
            <text>The approximately 0.2-mile segment of the Lyre River from Crescent Lake to the Olympic National Park boundary, to be administered by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1400">Secretary of the Interior</cato:entity-ref> as a scenic river.</text>
          </paragraph>
          <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
        </quoted-block>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="HC51BA12D88DF4A048A911426748EC488">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Effect</header>
        <text>The amendment made by <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Wild Olympics Wilderness and Wild and Scenic Rivers Act of 2014/s:4/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref> does not affect valid existing water rights.</text>
      </subsection>
    </section>
    <section id="HF58C91414E5D48E9A7D9952A8FD7B5AE">
      <enum>5.</enum>
      <header>Existing rights and withdrawal</header>
      <subsection id="HCD1AA07B744F459C838CD676BC5B8B61">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>In general</header>
        <text>In accordance with <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Wild and Scenic Rivers Act/s:12/ss:b">section 12(b) of the Wild and Scenic Rivers Act</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1283">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/16/1283/b">16 U.S.C. 1283(b)</cato:entity-ref>
          </external-xref>)</cato:entity>, nothing in this Act or the amendment made by <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Wild Olympics Wilderness and Wild and Scenic Rivers Act of 2014/s:4/ss:a" proposed="true">section 4(a)</cato:entity-ref> affects or abrogates existing rights, privileges, or contracts held by private parties.</text>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="H46DBF673880F4649B3EF4AF62C440B40">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Withdrawal</header>
        <text>Subject to valid existing rights, the Federal land within the boundaries of the river segments designated by this Act and the amendment made by <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Wild Olympics Wilderness and Wild and Scenic Rivers Act of 2014/s:4/ss:a" proposed="true">section 4(a)</cato:entity-ref> is withdrawn from all forms of—</text>
        <paragraph id="HD744EA392C924BEFAA84E404AD76CBC4">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>entry, appropriation, or disposal under the public land laws;</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H827B75D2D1C14FBAB20A9626EBBAA372">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>location, entry, and patent under the mining laws; and</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H69CFD738C67B40A1A1D11AB0CEB566E0">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <text>disposition under all laws relating to mineral and geothermal leasing or mineral materials.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
    </section>
    <section id="HE6A809DDE35E4CCA94106A43EA92BD46">
      <enum>6.</enum>
      <header>Treaty rights</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this Act alters, modifies, diminishes, or extinguishes the reserved treaty rights of any Indian tribe with hunting, fishing, gathering, and cultural or religious rights in the Olympic National Forest as protected by a treaty.</text>
    </section>
  </legis-body>
</bill>
</doc>