<doc>
  <docmeta id="113hr3295ih">
    <bill congress="113" type="hr" number="3295" version="ih"/>
    <revision size="12993" annotations="0" status="complete" id="3" commit-time="2013-10-18T21:36:52Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113hr3295ih/3.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H68AD2ACBBF484C8881702DCB3D727F68" public-private="public">
  <metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>113 HR 3295 IH: Eliminating Disparities in Breast Cancer Treatment Act of 2013</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2013-10-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
    <congress>113th CONGRESS</congress>
    <session>1st Session</session>
    <legis-num>H. R. 3295</legis-num>
    <current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
    <action>
      <action-date date="20131016">October 16, 2013</action-date>
      <action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="C001066">Ms. Castor of Florida</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
    </action>
    <legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
    <official-title>To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to eliminate contributing factors to disparities in breast cancer treatment through the development of a uniform set of consensus-based breast cancer treatment performance measures for a 6-year quality reporting system and value-based purchasing system under the Medicare program.</official-title>
  </form>
  <legis-body id="HE209AEC5CA8C43B9B1B69F24C3F826E4" style="OLC">
    <section id="H7D49D859A8DD4B2E833B7C231E37E904" section-type="section-one">
      <enum>1.</enum>
      <header>Short title</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote>
          <short-title>Eliminating Disparities in Breast Cancer Treatment Act of 2013</short-title>
        </quote>.</text>
    </section>
    <section id="H1CF90AD1A2144BDEBC5CE9262D654070">
      <enum>2.</enum>
      <header>Findings</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">
        <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> finds the following:</text>
      <paragraph id="H40D7B62A42244E5694315998FF7A3960">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Delays in receiving care after breast cancer diagnosis are reported to be greater for African-American women than White women.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H733ACAC5946E416490BD0F7FD4A0EF2B">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text>Recent studies indicate that African-American women with breast cancer are less likely to receive standard therapy than White women.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H07903351CDA940938CBF71311BC08843">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <text>African-American and Hispanic patients are significantly more likely than White patients to be diagnosed at a more advanced stage of breast cancer.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H3B7A90CE700341C79B1BC9987AFC259B">
        <enum>(4)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Investigators found that regardless of insurance status, African-American women are 1.9 times more likely to be diagnosed with an advanced stage of breast cancer than White women and Hispanic women are 1.4 times more likely to be diagnosed with an advanced stage of breast cancer than White women.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H600D6FB3C07A44F89DE5CE73E7DAAE4D">
        <enum>(5)</enum>
        <text>African-American women are ten percent more likely not to receive tests to determine if breast cancer has spread to axillary (underarm) lymph nodes. Studies show that health insurance status, race, income, and educational background are directly linked to irregularity in administering this vital screening.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H00E11F08775F47FBB66D8894C01902B2">
        <enum>(6)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">According to American Cancer Society researchers, substantial disparities remain or persist regarding cancer diagnosis and treatment.</text>
      </paragraph>
    </section>
    <section id="HD39C36DE22E04DE0BF4AA4F08594624E">
      <enum>3.</enum>
      <header>Purpose</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">The purpose of this Act is to promote the implementation of standardized health care practices for breast cancer treatment under the Medicare program to eliminate disparities in the provision of care to such patients based on race, level of education, income, and health insurance status of such patients.</text>
    </section>
    <section id="H857FD9C0F02341B4B310B10430C9A695">
      <enum>4.</enum>
      <header>Consensus-based breast cancer treatment performance measures system under Medicare</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">
        <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Social Security Act/t:XVIII">Title XVIII of the Social Security Act</cato:entity-ref> is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text>
      <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCAE0EA641DCB44C18EC6EF49F72D9EDE" style="OLC">
        <section id="HC411A88AFBF74C63A3D30FE2DAAF539A">
          <enum>1899B.</enum>
          <header>Breast cancer treatment performance measures system</header>
          <subsection id="H4D3EAC71259C4413A2914D2B9847F74F">
            <enum>(a)</enum>
            <header>In general</header>
            <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than October 1, 2014, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall establish, in accordance with the provisions of this section, a 6-year breast cancer treatment quality performance system (in this section referred to as the <quote>
                <short-title>system</short-title>
              </quote>) to—</text>
            <paragraph id="HF560F5441E4E41A29B778C45347D19D4">
              <enum>(1)</enum>
              <text>assess and publicly disclose, through the use of quality measures, the quality of care provided for the treatment of breast cancer by specified health care providers; and</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="HE0F643F29E5B4BFD872E1A7B861E45B3">
              <enum>(2)</enum>
              <text>beginning October 1, 2017, base payment under this title to such providers for such treatment on the performance of such providers based on such measures.</text>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection id="HF68B6DCD999048B7A2FAAFBDD7839D57">
            <enum>(b)</enum>
            <header>Specified health care providers</header>
            <paragraph id="H0A88605CBE4446DAAC1D774892411A36">
              <enum>(1)</enum>
              <header>In general</header>
              <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall specify classes of providers of services and suppliers, including hospitals, cancer centers, physicians, primary care providers, and specialty providers, to which the provisions of this section shall apply.</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="H77FADC695DF8461A99C4B5ED7709326B">
              <enum>(2)</enum>
              <header>Definition</header>
              <text>For purposes of this section, the term <term>specified health care provider</term> means a provider of services or supplier specified under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Social Security Act/s:1899B/ss:b/p:1" proposed="true">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection id="HDC6F7875E99A414CB61B8DCF5DEDC4A6">
            <enum>(c)</enum>
            <header>Identification and endorsement of breast cancer treatment performance measures</header>
            <paragraph id="H0CF9F865A86D4A99A87E39B8FB55051D">
              <enum>(1)</enum>
              <header>In general</header>
              <text>Under the system, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall enter into agreements with the National Quality Forum, an organization that operates as a voluntary consensus standards body as defined for purposes of <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
                  <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="National Technology Transfer and Advancement Act of 1995/s:12/ss:d">section 12(d) of the National Technology Transfer and Advancement Act of 1995</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/104/113">
                    <cato:entity-ref entity-type="public-law" value="public-law/104/113">Public Law 104–113</cato:entity-ref>
                  </external-xref>)</cato:entity> and Office of Management and Budget Revised Circular A–119 (published in the Federal Register on February 10, 1998), under which the National Quality Forum shall identify a uniform set of consensus-based performance measures to evaluate the quality of care provided by specified health care providers for the treatment of breast cancer, endorse such set of measures through its multistakeholder consensus development process, and annually update such set of measures.</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="H766186DAF74248C083AB17C558FA9DD4">
              <enum>(2)</enum>
              <header>Measures described</header>
              <text>The set of measures described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Social Security Act/s:1899B/ss:c/p:1" proposed="true">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref> shall include, with respect to the treatment of breast cancer, measures of patient outcomes, the process for delivering medical care related to such treatment, patient counseling and engagement in decisionmaking, patient experience of care, resource use, and practice capabilities, such as care coordination.</text>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection id="HD31DD0DB5837420E92AF64F2C5F82DBF">
            <enum>(d)</enum>
            <header>Reporting process</header>
            <paragraph id="H0CE88E53FAA1406D80EA1CB3407385F7">
              <enum>(1)</enum>
              <header>In general</header>
              <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Under the system, for periods (as specified by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref>) beginning on or after October 1, 2014, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall establish a reporting process, with respect to treatment furnished for breast cancer, that provides for a method for specified health care providers to submit to the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> data on the performance of such providers during each period through use of the performance measures developed pursuant to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Social Security Act/s:1899B/ss:c/p:1" proposed="true">subsection (c)(1)</cato:entity-ref>. Such data shall be submitted in a form and manner and at a time specified by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="H74F341180C6F40B4AB07B8B206C048B0">
              <enum>(2)</enum>
              <header>Voluntary submission during initial 3 years</header>
              <text>The reporting process under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Social Security Act/s:1899B/ss:d/p:1" proposed="true">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref> shall provide for the voluntary submission of data (and incentives for such submission) under the process for periods ending before October 1, 2017.</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="H12026A161A7746DD9CB60148FEDA2F64">
              <enum>(3)</enum>
              <header>Characteristics of data submitted under reporting process</header>
              <text>Data submitted by a specified health care provider under the reporting process under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Social Security Act/s:1899B/ss:d/p:1" proposed="true">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref> shall—</text>
              <subparagraph id="HD6A1A602E056470B8C49B8CACF46EF0C">
                <enum>(A)</enum>
                <text>take into account the quality of breast cancer treatment furnished to all patients of the provider, regardless of the type of health insurance coverage of the patient or whether or not the patient has such coverage; and</text>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="H172B36E11F4E4CE3916B420F264F5FD9">
                <enum>(B)</enum>
                <text>be structured in a manner that allows for comparison according to race, educational level, income, insurance status, and any other category specified by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection id="HF0106F5DEBD044BF960160ACBD649686">
            <enum>(e)</enum>
            <header>Public disclosure</header>
            <text>Under the system, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall establish procedures to require that information with respect to the quality demonstrated by a specified health care provider of treatment furnished for breast cancer during a period (based on the performance measures data submitted pursuant to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Social Security Act/s:1899B/ss:c/p:1" proposed="true">subsection (c)(1)</cato:entity-ref> by the provider for such period) is made available on the official public Internet site of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Department of Health and Human Services</cato:entity-ref> in a clear and understandable form. Such procedures shall ensure that a specified health care provider has the opportunity to review the information that is to be made public with respect to the provider at least 30 days prior to such data being made public and shall provide for an appeals process in the case a provider claims such information to be incorrect or incomplete.</text>
          </subsection>
          <subsection id="HDA3DF375E9DD4AE5ADCE1EF4A0F70372">
            <enum>(f)</enum>
            <header>Value-Based purchasing for periods beginning October 1, 2017</header>
            <paragraph id="H7CBF29CAC940425FACF126D75531711A">
              <enum>(1)</enum>
              <header>In general</header>
              <text>Under the system, for periods beginning on or after October 1, 2017, and ending before October 1, 2020, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall establish and implement, a value-based purchasing program, with respect to specified health care providers that furnish treatment for breast cancer during such a period, under which—</text>
              <subparagraph id="H6781DF71526A41DC9B42FD53A85133F1">
                <enum>(A)</enum>
                <text>in the case of such a provider that does not submit data in accordance with the reporting process under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Social Security Act/s:1899B/ss:d/p:1" proposed="true">subsection (d)(1)</cato:entity-ref> for such treatment furnished during such period, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall reduce the amount that would otherwise be paid to such provider under this title for such treatment by an amount specified by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref>; and</text>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="H3CF65584DE534DFD9DA1882EEF30A892">
                <enum>(B)</enum>
                <text>in the case of such a provider that submits data in accordance with the reporting process under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Social Security Act/s:1899B/ss:d/p:1" proposed="true">subsection (d)(1)</cato:entity-ref> for such treatment furnished during such period—</text>
                <clause id="H0E67687C12B04E2799F016EF07A81DE0">
                  <enum>(i)</enum>
                  <text>subject to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Social Security Act/s:1899B/ss:f/p:1/sp:B/cl:ii" proposed="true">clause (ii)</cato:entity-ref>, if the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> determines such provider furnished low quality care (in accordance with a method specified by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref>) for such treatment, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall reduce the amount that would otherwise be paid to such provider under this title for such treatment by an amount specified by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref>;</text>
                </clause>
                <clause id="HBF11F4FA165F469EAD292AA26904D268">
                  <enum>(ii)</enum>
                  <text>if the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> determines such provider furnished low quality care (in accordance with the method specified under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Social Security Act/s:1899B/ss:f/p:1/sp:B/cl:i" proposed="true">clause (i)</cato:entity-ref>) for such treatment, but the quality of care has improved as compared to the quality of care the provider furnished during the previous period, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall reduce the amount that would otherwise be paid to such provider under this title for such treatment in accordance with an incremental method established by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> that ensures that the amount of such reduction—</text>
                  <subclause id="H89CDE066CCBA486688DC92BD2CFFD302">
                    <enum>(I)</enum>
                    <text>is less than the amount specified by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Social Security Act/s:1899B/ss:f/p:1/sp:B/cl:i" proposed="true">clause (i)</cato:entity-ref>; and</text>
                  </subclause>
                  <subclause id="H1A1444F462F94ACF93871C1A70EBD711">
                    <enum>(II)</enum>
                    <text>is based on the extent of improvement in the quality of care; and</text>
                  </subclause>
                </clause>
                <clause id="H8858264599FC4CD7810E00E3F84B488B">
                  <enum>(iii)</enum>
                  <text>if the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> determines such provider did not furnish low quality care (in accordance with the method specified under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Social Security Act/s:1899B/ss:f/p:1/sp:B/cl:i" proposed="true">clause (i)</cato:entity-ref>) for such treatment, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall provide to such provider the amount to be paid to such provider under this title for such treatment.</text>
                </clause>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="H3203344DC71E46AE9F1D7B425D1AED44">
              <enum>(2)</enum>
              <header>Results-based payments</header>
              <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amount of a reduction under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Social Security Act/s:1899B/ss:f/p:1/sp:A" proposed="true">subparagraph (A)</cato:entity-ref> or <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Social Security Act/s:1899B/ss:f/p:1/sp:B/cl:i" proposed="true">(B)(i) of paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref> shall be determined in accordance with a method established by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection id="HF61582049CAE49299352E40B55AA6DCD">
            <enum>(g)</enum>
            <header>Reports</header>
            <text>Not later than October 1, 2015, and for each 6-month period thereafter (before fiscal year 2021), the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall submit to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> a report that evaluates the development and implementation of the system, including—</text>
            <paragraph id="HF3BBB0DAF7CA4BAF9F6CDE7250CF6A46">
              <enum>(1)</enum>
              <text>an evaluation of the number of specified health care providers that submit data pursuant to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Social Security Act/s:1899B/ss:c/p:1" proposed="true">subsection (c)(1)</cato:entity-ref>;</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="H2227BEC2DB3641E19FF2E80968D4A465">
              <enum>(2)</enum>
              <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an analysis of the effect of such system on reducing disparities in the provision of breast cancer treatment to patients based on race, level of education, income, and health insurance status of such patients; and</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="H8021C6E75C014FF99542CB6618E9D458">
              <enum>(3)</enum>
              <text>recommendations on whether (and to what extent) to extend the system under this section.</text>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection commented="no" id="H226E35023B864310BC7277EB1C92FB88">
            <enum>(h)</enum>
            <header>Application to part C</header>
            <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall provide for a method to apply the provisions of this section to treatment furnished under a plan under part C.</text>
          </subsection>
        </section>
        <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
      </quoted-block>
    </section>
  </legis-body>
</bill>
</doc>