<doc>
  <docmeta id="113hr5283ih">
    <bill congress="113" type="hr" number="5283" version="ih"/>
    <revision size="11375" annotations="0" status="complete" id="4" commit-time="2014-08-13T22:47:56Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113hr5283ih/4.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H83BEE9DA358A4B458EF6A084B8CFF535" public-private="public">
	<metadata>
<dublinCore>
<dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">113 HR 5283 IH: Land-Based Marine Debris Reduction Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">2014-07-30</dc:date>
<dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>113th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>2d Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 5283</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20140730">July 30, 2014</action-date>
			<action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="H001034">Mr. Honda</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>
      </action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To establish national goals for the reduction and recycling of municipal solid waste, to address
			 the growing problem of marine debris, to require the Administrator of the
			 Environmental Protection Agency to promulgate regulations to attain those
			 goals, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="HE3C253ABEA7A4D8D80DD7FEE97AD4F9E" style="OLC">
		<section id="H628C58E0F001402DA80391E827C5ABB5" section-type="section-one">
      <enum>1.</enum>
      <header>Short title</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote>
          <short-title>
            <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Land-Based Marine Debris Reduction Act" proposed="true">Land-Based Marine Debris Reduction Act</cato:entity-ref>
          </short-title>
        </quote>.</text>
		</section>
    <section id="H2B4CFAE920AB49AF8ADDEAAB60A70269" section-type="subsequent-section">
      <enum>2.</enum>
      <header>Findings</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds and declares the following:</text>
			<paragraph id="H7102B5DA1BE94FA28DFF12B4F5AA34FA">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text>Because the United States has the largest Exclusive Economic Zone of all nations, it has a
			 disproportionate economic interest in a healthy ocean.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H9D088985B3534035AAB2BF202F07749C">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text>The United States has a strategic interest in healthy fisheries, marine ecosystems, and a strong
			 ocean economy.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HAB424CB7836C441499120434F596E42D">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <text>Solid waste is littering the Nation’s waterways, including streams, rivers, and lakes, most notably
			 the Great Lakes, and much of this marine debris is collecting in the
			 oceans.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H5E490587B9F64EECB70DE257F6852641">
        <enum>(4)</enum>
        <text>An estimated 80 percent of litter that ends up in the oceans comes from land-based sources, and
			 litter in the Nation’s waterways has numerous detrimental effects.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H6B1C1A41AE634760B5DBE528FCD1681B">
        <enum>(5)</enum>
        <text>Marine debris injures wildlife, sometimes resulting in death, degrades ecosystems, interferes with
			 navigation, threatens public health and safety, and creates additional
			 expenditures for shipping, fishing, tourism, and coastal communities.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H687B2C688EA0451BB95AB5FD6A3B9BE8">
        <enum>(6)</enum>
        <text>Only about 46 percent of the Nation’s waste is recycled or composted, including through
			 waste-to-energy.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HE51ADF9AD3994D7B929E37D3D00F6261">
        <enum>(7)</enum>
        <text>Successful solid waste management requires creative use of the entire hierarchy of solid waste
			 management, waste reduction, recycling, waste-to-energy operations, and
			 landfilling.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HDFADDE2EA6AD4ED88E08BE75BE79AA4F">
        <enum>(8)</enum>
        <text>Recycling can play a significant role in reducing municipal waste and marine debris.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HBAAD1DC2DCCF460F935F5761CDB8E6F4">
        <enum>(9)</enum>
        <text>The failure to recycle and reuse materials is a significant and unnecessary waste of important
			 national energy and material resources.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H8144D6D795D94739860AB4D8176574B4">
        <enum>(10)</enum>
        <text>Comprehensive, multi-material recycling programs represent the most cost-effective and efficient
			 method of meeting recycling goals and reducing marine debris.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H92B2B2D6E59F4DA7AAEE2A9328954954">
        <enum>(11)</enum>
        <text>The responsibility to recycle should be shared by all consumers of recyclable goods including
			 individual households, municipalities, and commercial and institutional
			 establishments.</text>
			</paragraph>
    </section>
    <section id="H5CB5C6E1740A4B70916545659A668F35">
      <enum>3.</enum>
      <header>National goals for waste reduction and recycling</header>
			<subsection id="H16B6AD2272EA42CEBC52CB70E1C322CB">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Source reduction</header>
        <text>Congress declares it to be the national goal of the United States that there shall be no increase
			 in the generation of solid waste sent to landfills above the level of
			 solid waste generated and sent to landfills in the year of the enactment
			 of this Act (as determined by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="6800">Administrator</cato:entity-ref>).</text>
			</subsection>
      <subsection id="HA1CFCE9E7A7B44CFB119E1225C3643F8">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Waste recycling</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Congress declares it to be the national goal of the United States that at least 50 percent of the
			 municipal solid waste stream shall be recycled by the end of 2020, and 65
			 percent of such waste stream shall be recycled by the end of 2030 (as
			 determined by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="6800">Administrator</cato:entity-ref>).</text>
			</subsection>
      <subsection id="H6D538AB934CE4B348A14DC891DBF8EC2">
        <enum>(c)</enum>
        <header>Marine debris reduction</header>
        <text>Congress declares it to be the national goal of the United States that there shall be no increase
			 in the flow of marine debris into the ocean above the level of such flow
			 in the year of the enactment of this Act (as determined by the
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="6800">Administrator</cato:entity-ref>).</text>
			</subsection>
    </section>
    <section id="H0D1529521DC44CD5810C38B32D207741">
      <enum>4.</enum>
      <header>Annual report</header>
			<subsection id="H1BE98A3719DD474E9E8B2DFB1B4681D1">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Requirement</header>
        <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="6800">Administrator</cato:entity-ref> shall report to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> each year the following:</text>
				<paragraph id="H8CE40913AE224121B9526D1F11D31A57">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>The amount and composition of municipal solid waste generated in the United States.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HA873CA27FDD74F37994BF43222C19CCB">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>The amount and composition of municipal solid waste generated in the United States that enters the
			 ocean.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HE752A06B47ED4AD3AB3C23DB7E8481C7">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <text>The methods used to manage such waste.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HE14CACB133024A5AB2517E6477E17D5B">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
          <text>The progress made in achieving the source reduction, recycling, and marine debris reduction goals
			 of this Act, the impediments to the attainment of such goals, and
			 recommendations on the regulatory or legislative initiatives necessary to
			 attain such goals.</text>
				</paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="H35425A2A70544FCCBF3E44F68C3D46AE">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>First report</header>
        <text>The first report under this section shall be submitted not later than 18 months after the date of
			 the enactment of this Act.</text>
			</subsection>
    </section>
    <section id="HF69E82893A6C4DAAAEB94C633DE0EA63">
      <enum>5.</enum>
      <header>Report on primary leakage paths of marine debris into the ocean</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of this Act, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="6800">Administrator</cato:entity-ref> shall provide
			 to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> a report that includes the following:</text>
			<paragraph id="H299394C0FBD544F19E18C07E0C512824">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text>Identification of the pathways through which marine debris reaches the ocean, such as consumer
			 discards, flawed waste management designs, and infrastructural leaks, as
			 determined in consultation with experts, including waste management,
			 consumer goods, and infrastructure experts.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H82185EBF9FBF40CEAF17C8C5143725C9">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text>Best practices that may be used at the Federal, State, and local level to reduce or eliminate such
			 pathways, including methods to address infrastructural leaks, regulation,
			 or economic incentives.</text>
			</paragraph>
    </section>
    <section id="H0C28A6C7D5524201BC80FA24B6A75565">
      <enum>6.</enum>
      <header>Products and packaging requirements</header>
			<subsection id="HBB3585E9B4694F99BD267E0AE857015D">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>List and recycling determinations</header>
				<paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H094E975468354D53A8E46170C94BC929">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>Not later than 2 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="6800">Administrator</cato:entity-ref>, in
			 consultation with the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1300" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of Commerce</cato:entity-ref>, shall develop a list of
			 categories of commonly used products and packaging which are discarded
			 into the municipal solid waste stream. With respect to each category on
			 the list, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="6800">Administrator</cato:entity-ref> shall determine the following:</text>
					<subparagraph id="H5B2AFBAEE79943CA91EA94FAEF150D22">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>The percentage of recovered materials used in the manufacture of products or packaging in each
			 category.</text>
					</subparagraph>
          <subparagraph commented="no" id="H2BFA0FB026FF43F1A49BD99E770951B2">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The source reduction and recovery efficiency of products or packaging in each category.</text>
					</subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="HA282F4D8001C4BFC8E894C0A2FACF3CB">
            <enum>(C)</enum>
            <text>The percentage of products or packaging in each category that is recycled upon discard.</text>
					</subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="HC8BBCDAE13864CF182D758BB162C48E9">
            <enum>(D)</enum>
            <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The percentage of products or packaging in each category that enters the ocean upon discard or is
			 otherwise littered.</text>
					</subparagraph>
          <subparagraph commented="no" id="HDDF3006AE6844D2CBC6C11A5F796958F">
            <enum>(E)</enum>
            <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The life cycle environmental effects associated with the products or packaging in each category
			 compared to product or packaging alternatives, using standard life cycle
			 assessment methodologies and categories of environmental impacts,
			 including climate change, human health, eutrophication, acidification,
			 water use, land use, and ecosystems toxicity.</text>
					</subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HCCA52A755E2740FC972B6EBD7751E959">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>Upon completion of the list and determinations required under paragraph (1), the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="6800">Administrator</cato:entity-ref>
			 shall identify categories of products or packaging that shall be targeted
			 for regulatory action under subsection (b). The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="6800">Administrator</cato:entity-ref> shall target
			 a category based upon high overall life cycle impact of the product or
			 package compared to the alternatives, considering categories of
			 environmental impacts, recovered material content, recyclability, and high
			 volume in the waste stream.</text>
				</paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="HAE53A50CBC4C4438865FC393BD5757BB">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Regulatory action</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to each category of product or packaging identified under subsection (a)(2), the
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="6800">Administrator</cato:entity-ref> may take the following actions:</text>
				<paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4556382CB4034807A13B7A90053381E8">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="6800">Administrator</cato:entity-ref> may promulgate regulations to require the manufacturer of the product or
			 packaging to use recovered materials of that or another category in the
			 product or packaging. In promulgating regulations under this paragraph,
			 the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="6800">Administrator</cato:entity-ref> shall, to the extent practicable, consider the potential
			 life cycle impacts of requiring recovered material content in a product or
			 packaging on increasing greenhouse gases and water usage, current
			 regulations regarding the use of recovered materials, and potential market
			 disruptions to recovered materials.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H62F511A89AA2410A9136BF087F2C02CE">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="6800">Administrator</cato:entity-ref> may phase in any of the actions taken under paragraph (1) if the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="6800">Administrator</cato:entity-ref>
			 determines it to be necessary for economic reasons.</text>
				</paragraph>
      </subsection>
    </section>
    <section id="HA14116A0980F46F8AD7D65CA72682316">
      <enum>7.</enum>
      <header>Packaging standards</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="6800">Administrator</cato:entity-ref> and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1300" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of Commerce</cato:entity-ref>, in consultation with affected industries, experts
			 in package design and marketing, companies engaged in collecting and
			 processing products and packages, and environmental organizations, shall
			 develop a voluntary system of packaging standards with respect to
			 materials contained within the packaging and the recyclability of the
			 packaging upon discard, which may include implementation of an existing
			 labeling standard where appropriate. The standards shall provide that
			 packaging that meets the standards shall be eligible to use a label
			 indicating compliance with the standards for promotion and educational
			 purposes.</text>
		</section>
    <section id="H6FA174539F38421094BF1479EAA74895">
      <enum>8.</enum>
      <header>Report on landfill closures</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="6800">Administrator</cato:entity-ref> shall submit
			 to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> a report analyzing the costs and difficulties encountered by
			 States and local communities in closing landfills. The report shall
			 include recommendations on the types and levels of Federal assistance
			 (including technical guidance and funds) that should be provided to States
			 and local communities for such purpose.</text>
		</section>
    <section id="H8205893CE97042F1929666E5ADE7C737">
      <enum>9.</enum>
      <header>Definitions</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">For purposes of this Act:</text>
			<paragraph id="HE988589BDFB24F448514E0E0FF2882F3">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text>The term <term>Administrator</term> means the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="6800" entity-type="federal-body">Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph commented="no" id="HE27123BDD8F04E6084D49BCC24FB0B68">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text>The term <term>marine debris</term> is human-created waste that has been discharged into the coastal or marine environment, including
			 any anthropogenic, manufactured, or processed solid material (regardless
			 of size) discarded, disposed of, or abandoned in the environment,
			 including all materials discarded into the ocean, on the shore, or brought
			 indirectly to the ocean by rivers, sewage, storm water, waves, or wind.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HEEEE447026924B18800018BCD2CCBEEC">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <text>The term <term>recovered material</term> has the meaning given that term in <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Solid Waste Disposal Act/s:1004">section 1004 of the Solid Waste Disposal Act</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/6903">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/42/6903">42 U.S.C. 6903</cato:entity-ref>
          </external-xref>)</cato:entity>.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HCE8CCBD27FA64A04B8A069289542D096">
        <enum>(4)</enum>
        <text>The term <term>recycled</term> means reused, recovered, or reclaimed from solid waste through any means, including
			 remanufacturing, reprocessing, and waste-to-energy technologies.</text>
			</paragraph>
    </section>
  </legis-body>
</bill>
</doc>