<doc>
  <docmeta id="113hr5000ih">
    <bill congress="113" type="hr" number="5000" version="ih"/>
    <revision size="27655" annotations="0" status="complete" id="4" commit-time="2014-07-23T20:52:37Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113hr5000ih/4.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H786961F4C4B94BECB36C76730219B43B" public-private="public">
	<metadata>
<dublinCore>
<dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">113 HR 5000 IH: Working Families Child Care Act of 2014</dc:title>
<dc:publisher xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">2014-06-26</dc:date>
<dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes"> I</distribution-code>
		<congress>113th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>2d Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 5000</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20140626">June 26, 2014</action-date>
			<action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="F000462">Ms. Frankel of Florida</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="M001160">Ms. Moore</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C000714">Mr. Conyers</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000911">Ms. Brown of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000009">Ms. Kaptur</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000187">Mrs. Negrete McLeod</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001101">Ms. Clark of Massachusetts</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000551">Ms. Lee of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001050">Ms. Hanabusa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000002">Mr. Nadler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001163">Ms. Matsui</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000216">Ms. DeLauro</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001137">Mr. Meeks</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001038">Mr. Crowley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000565">Mr. Loebsack</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001143">Ms. McCollum</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001034">Mr. Honda</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001068">Mr. Cohen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001177">Mr. Sablan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000579">Mr. Lowenthal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001145">Ms. Schakowsky</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000126">Ms. Eddie Bernice Johnson of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000559">Mr. Langevin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000515">Mr. Rush</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000292">Mr. Enyart</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001251">Mr. Butterfield</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000053">Mr. Rangel</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001188">Ms. Meng</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000468">Ms. Titus</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001286">Mrs. Bustos</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001080">Ms. Chu</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H000324">Mr. Hastings of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001084">Mr. Cicilline</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000556">Mr. Grayson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000551">Mr. Grijalva</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Y000062">Mr. Yarmuth</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000559">Mr. Garamendi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000610">Mr. Deutch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001066">Ms. Castor of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000290">Ms. Edwards</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001285">Ms. Brownley of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000597">Ms. Pingree of Maine</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000480">Ms. Slaughter</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000469">Mr. Tonko</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001270">Ms. Bass</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001063">Ms. Hahn</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000808">Ms. Wilson of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000368">Mrs. Kirkpatrick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001185">Ms. Sewell of Alabama</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001185">Mr. Sean Patrick Maloney of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000797">Ms. Wasserman Schultz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001170">Ms. Shea-Porter</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001067">Ms. Clarke of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000130">Mr. Vargas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000455">Ms. Fudge</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000312">Mr. McGovern</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000293">Ms. Esty</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000288">Mr. Ellison</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000266">Mr. Tierney</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000375">Mr. Keating</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson of Indiana</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000397">Ms. Lofgren</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="L000480">Mrs. Lowey</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and the Workforce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To provide for child care services for families with infants or toddlers, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H6517CE5F1B0C4089BFC07D4C1AAD5C82" style="OLC">
		<section id="HC08A8F6A156E4B62AE8EE69FA49A6406" section-type="section-one">
      <enum>1.</enum>
      <header>Short title</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote>
          <short-title>
            <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Working Families Child Care Act of 2014" proposed="true">Working Families Child Care Act of 2014</cato:entity-ref>
          </short-title>
        </quote>.</text>
		</section>
    <section id="H80D7DC7F27154329813668029412E35D">
      <enum>2.</enum>
      <header>Findings</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text>
			<paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6C1ECCD13C6D4558BE26FA6A4748CB1B">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text>Child care for infants and toddlers is often difficult to access or afford. Only about a third of
			 child care centers serve infants. While 70 percent of centers serve
			 toddlers, only a third of teachers report that they care for children
			 under age 3. About half of all requests to child care resource and
			 referral agencies concern care for infants and toddlers.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H48397A01920B4F76AB5A595AAE971B83">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text>Child care is second only to the family as the setting in which early development takes place for
			 many infants and toddlers. Sixty-one percent of mothers with children
			 younger than 3 years of age are in the labor force and over 6,000,000
			 children younger than 3 years of age are cared for by someone other than
			 their parents for some part or all of the day. Therefore, the relationship
			 between the child and the child care provider often plays a significant
			 role in child development.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H3EF1CB1570DE4C3DB9FB4B37FB60B671">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <text>Dramatic brain development in a child’s first 3 years of life, shaped by the quality of early
			 experiences and relationships with trusted adults, builds the foundational
			 architecture for thinking, reasoning, language, emotion, and
			 self-regulation.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H064EC98B536D437BAF51E654A9A57E9A">
        <enum>(4)</enum>
        <text>Early adverse experiences, such as economic hardship, unstable housing, poor nutrition, abuse or
			 neglect, or parental mental health or substance abuse problems, affect
			 brain development, with effects on long-term productivity and health that
			 can last a life-time. Children with such hardships early in life often
			 experience high levels of chronic stress, which can alter the brain’s
			 architecture and undermine developing biological systems. Almost half of
			 all infants and toddlers live in low-income families, and 61 percent have
			 at least one risk factor for poor health or developmental outcomes.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H96C1F3D8DE5F4222AF929AB9874B5BF6">
        <enum>(5)</enum>
        <text>Teachers serving infants and toddlers receive wages that are 28 percent lower than those of
			 teachers serving 3–5 year olds. Some difference remains even when
			 education is taken into account. The median hourly wage for a teacher with
			 a BA degree serving infants and toddlers is $11.30 compared with $15.50
			 for teachers serving 3–5 year-olds.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H8AFE451BA2214E74BF4BA945E274D743">
        <enum>(6)</enum>
        <text>Low reimbursement rates to providers make it extremely challenging to offer high quality care to
			 low-income children. In 2013, just three states set their reimbursement
			 rates at the 75th percentile of current market rates. Many states set
			 their rates substantially below the 75th percentile.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H4569F5314A454B7DBDCF6D8CC3481214">
        <enum>(7)</enum>
        <text>Research shows that high-quality child care can mitigate some of the effects of adverse
			 experiences, including poverty, and that low-income children in particular
			 can benefit from high-quality child care that provides nurturing,
			 child-centered teachers and a safe, predictable environment. Yet, at-risk
			 children younger than 3 years of age often receive low-quality child care
			 that can lead to poor developmental outcomes.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HBAAA75E0BB5143EBBB0749B2CCEF8CB4">
        <enum>(8)</enum>
        <text>High-quality child care has been shown to promote positive cognitive, language, and social and
			 emotional development, and contribute to academic success. Specifically,
			 high-quality child care can also help improve a child’s communication
			 skills, behavioral skills, math and language assessment scores, and verbal
			 intelligence.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H324BA75DD9164685B5019245043593B1">
        <enum>(9)</enum>
        <text>Research has found strong connections between provider education and training levels and child care
			 quality, including positive caregiving that can improve child outcomes.
			 More than a quarter of infant-toddler teachers have only a high school
			 education, twice the rate for teachers of preschool age children. 19
			 percent of infant-toddler teachers have a bachelor’s degree compared with
			 45 percent of teachers of 3–5 year olds. Twenty-seven States have an
			 infant-toddler credential defining the particular knowledge and skills
			 needed to work with children younger than 3 years of age, but only 17
			 States require specific qualifications for infant-toddler staff.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H5B3E92CF97FC4F8B9C17C8D9EBC06839">
        <enum>(10)</enum>
        <text>Twenty-four percent of infants and toddlers receiving CCDBG subsidies are cared for in family child
			 care homes. Family child care networks that create a supportive
			 relationship with a specially trained coordinator and provide on-site
			 training and mentoring have been shown to improve the quality of family
			 child care providers.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H1CD34C65EF0A443F89B181D243378994">
        <enum>(11)</enum>
        <text>Twenty-seven States use infant and toddler specialist networks as the structure for providing
			 training and technical assistance, using research-based training and
			 techniques such as mentoring and on-site coaching, to all types of
			 providers of child care for infants or toddlers.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H4C5089542D314645867E439870348BF8">
        <enum>(12)</enum>
        <text>Infants and toddlers have unique needs that differ from those of older children in areas such as
			 health and safety, interaction with teachers and caregivers, and learning,
			 yet not all States recognize those differences in their Quality Rating and
			 Improvement Systems. Just 16 States have infant and toddler standards in
			 their Quality Rating and Improvement Systems.</text>
			</paragraph>
    </section>
    <section id="HDFD00EB4E74C46A39FBF5EEA177F956F">
      <enum>3.</enum>
      <header>Mandatory child care funding for families with infants or toddlers</header>
			<text display-inline="no-display-inline">
        <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
          <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Social Security Act/s:418">Section 418 of the Social Security Act</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/618">
          <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/42/618">42 U.S.C. 618</cato:entity-ref>
        </external-xref>)</cato:entity> is amended by adding at the end the
			 following:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2F9A7848C1B74071834087D885B137AA" style="OLC">
				<subsection id="HD62E99B3AE6F45A8A2C96C04FF58D2E0">
          <enum>(e)</enum>
          <header>Supplemental entitlement for child care assistance for families with infants or toddlers</header>
					<paragraph id="H5CF3E42D77DB47C695D36D0167EC963B">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <header>In general</header>
            <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each State to which an amount is required to be paid under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Social Security Act/s:418/ss:a/p:2">subsection (a)(2)</cato:entity-ref>(C) for a fiscal year
			 shall, for the purpose of providing child care assistance for families
			 with a child who has not attained 3 years of age, be entitled to payments
			 for the fiscal year under a grant made under this subsection.</text>
					</paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H3853619BD3F145A580009611FA0F42EE">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <header>Federal matching of state expenditures</header>
            <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amount of the grant payable to a State under this subsection for a fiscal year shall be the
			 lesser of—</text>
						<subparagraph id="HD54D9A179AEE4A25B46888BE146D1A8B">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>the allotment of the State under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Social Security Act/s:418/ss:e/p:3" proposed="true">paragraph (3)</cato:entity-ref> for the fiscal year; or</text>
						</subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H0D32E6C8A91345B2941CEC5D30A7C9E2">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>the Federal medical assistance percentage for the State for the fiscal year (as defined in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Social Security Act/s:1905/ss:b">section
			 1905(b)</cato:entity-ref>, as such section was in effect on September 30, 1995) of the total
			 amount of the State's expenditures for child care in the fiscal year not
			 taken into account under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Social Security Act/s:418/ss:a/p:2">subsection (a)(2)</cato:entity-ref> for the fiscal year.</text>
						</subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="HBED8EE9624C645128C9D027FB0AFF7A8">
            <enum>(3)</enum>
            <header>Allotments to states</header>
            <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The allotment of a State under this paragraph for a fiscal year shall be—</text>
						<subparagraph id="HE7C557E3B1BF43519F6838F106C0B2F6">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>the total amount available for payments to States under this subsection for the fiscal year, after
			 making the reservation required by <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Social Security Act/s:418/ss:e/p:6" proposed="true">paragraph (6)</cato:entity-ref>; multiplied by</text>
						</subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="HD08C2EA1A5944AE6926C4885980546E9">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
							<clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H616FB443C4F0493E80EA952FF3AD5012">
                <enum>(i)</enum>
                <text>the number of children who have not attained 3 years of age who reside in the State; divided by</text>
							</clause>
              <clause id="H6AB226308D054691B1785CAEEFB1203A" indent="up1">
                <enum>(ii)</enum>
                <text>the total number of such children who reside in all States.</text>
							</clause>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H56EED6EF4379454D8908E34551A1082D">
            <enum>(4)</enum>
            <header>Redistribution</header>
						<subparagraph id="H98A37B3F9FF740B0B326B0226DA2AF27">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <header>In general</header>
              <text>The 1st sentence of <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Social Security Act/s:418/ss:a/p:2/sp:D/cl:i">subsection (a)(2)(D)(i)</cato:entity-ref> shall apply with respect to amounts appropriated under
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Social Security Act/s:418/ss:e/p:5" proposed="true">paragraph (5) of this subsection</cato:entity-ref> in the same manner in which that sentence
			 applies with respect to amounts appropriated under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Social Security Act/s:418/ss:a/p:3">subsection (a)(3)</cato:entity-ref>. The
			 amounts available for redistribution by reason of the preceding sentence
			 shall be redistributed to a State based on the formula set forth in
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Social Security Act/s:418/ss:e/p:3/sp:B" proposed="true">paragraph (3)(B) of this subsection</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
						</subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="HF57D36FDA2474E5586813D049C7ED814">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <header>Time of determination and distribution</header>
              <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">
                <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Social Security Act/s:418/ss:a/p:2/sp:D/cl:ii">Subsection (a)(2)(D)(ii)</cato:entity-ref> shall apply with respect to amounts appropriated under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Social Security Act/s:418/ss:e/p:5" proposed="true">paragraph (5) of
			 this subsection</cato:entity-ref> in the same manner in which <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Social Security Act/s:418/ss:a/p:2/sp:D/cl:ii">subsection (a)(2)(D)(ii)</cato:entity-ref>
			 applies with respect to amounts appropriated under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Social Security Act/s:418/ss:a/p:3">subsection (a)(3)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
						</subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H5B0EEFDAE19447DB9FEEE95AF2585D8D">
            <enum>(5)</enum>
            <header>Appropriation</header>
            <text>
              <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="auth-approp">
                <cato:property name="purpose">For grants under <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Social Security Act/s:418/ss:e" proposed="true">this subsection</cato:entity-ref>
                </cato:property>, there are appropriated <cato:funds-and-year amount="2000000000">$2,000,000,000 for each fiscal year</cato:funds-and-year>.</cato:entity>
            </text>
					</paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H5ECCFCCCCC2F48BAA61B55162E02DA2A">
            <enum>(6)</enum>
            <header>Indian tribes</header>
            <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall reserve not less than 1 percent, and not more than 2 percent, of the aggregate
			 amount appropriated to carry out this section in each fiscal year for
			 payments to Indian tribes and tribal organizations.</text>
					</paragraph>
          <paragraph id="HF943C8B01569473C8FE6346D41D467E5">
            <enum>(7)</enum>
            <header>Use of funds</header>
            <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Social Security Act/s:418/ss:c">subsection (c)</cato:entity-ref>, <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Social Security Act/s:418/ss:b">subsection (b)</cato:entity-ref> shall apply with respect to amounts appropriated
			 under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Social Security Act/s:418/ss:e/p:5" proposed="true">paragraph (5) of this subsection</cato:entity-ref> in the same manner in which
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Social Security Act/s:418/ss:b">subsection (b)</cato:entity-ref> applies with respect to amounts appropriated under
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Social Security Act/s:418/ss:a/p:3">subsection (a)(3)</cato:entity-ref>, except that amounts received by a State under this
			 subsection shall be used—</text>
						<subparagraph id="HE08B632E245E4D3DB7089D939987CB36">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>to provide child care assistance only to families described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Social Security Act/s:418/ss:e/p:1" proposed="true">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref> of this subsection who
			 are not otherwise receiving child care assistance under this section; and</text>
						</subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H0FE57CB0D62543C98955EEDCBF8057FA">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>to increase reimbursement rates to providers of child care services to such families.</text>
						</subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
      </quoted-block>
		</section>
    <section id="H1130BAAC567144E1A94E3154ED0ABDE9">
      <enum>4.</enum>
      <header>High-quality infant and toddler child care program</header>
			<subsection id="H883ADFE491FB4F7FA1636354F35521D8">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>High-Quality infant and toddler care program</header>
        <text>
          The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Child Care and Development Block Grant Act of 1990">Child Care and Development Block Grant Act of 1990</cato:entity-ref> is amended by inserting after <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Child Care and Development Block Grant Act of 1990/s:658G">section 658G</cato:entity-ref>
			 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/9858e">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/42/9858e">42 U.S.C. 9858e</cato:entity-ref>
          </external-xref>)</cato:entity> the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H430CAE6E2C47400DA5A65392BC64EBE4" style="OLC">
					<section id="H907CD16276EC4A61B1BA8505E394E430">
            <enum>658H.</enum>
            <header>High-quality infant and toddler care program</header>
						<subsection id="H5EA42617CA8649FC9200A6B35A4503EE">
              <enum>(a)</enum>
              <header>Definitions</header>
              <text>In this section:</text>
							<paragraph id="HC0816A7C07BC436CB76A38DA0F607841">
                <enum>(1)</enum>
                <header>Eligible infant or toddler care provider</header>
                <text>The term <term>eligible infant or toddler care provider</term> means an eligible child care provider, consistent with <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Child Care and Development Block Grant Act of 1990/s:658P">section 658P</cato:entity-ref>, who provides care to an
			 infant or toddler.</text>
							</paragraph>
              <paragraph id="HB50042C442CE40A68AF511B8C922158A">
                <enum>(2)</enum>
                <header>Infant or toddler</header>
                <text>The term <term>infant or toddler</term> means an individual under 3 years of age.</text>
							</paragraph>
              <paragraph id="H62F147CCFF5B40F8B7F9D94AE8F3B6C6">
                <enum>(3)</enum>
                <header>Infant or toddler with a developmental delay or disability</header>
								<subparagraph id="HA67AEA8150EC4E85A25F47C5BBA2B513">
                  <enum>(A)</enum>
                  <header>In general</header>
                  <text>The term <term>infant or toddler with a developmental delay or disability</term> has the meaning given the term <term>infant or toddler with a disability</term> in <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
                      <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Individuals with Disabilities Education Act/s:632">section 632 of the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1432">
                      <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/20/1432">20 U.S.C. 1432</cato:entity-ref>
                    </external-xref>)</cato:entity>.</text>
								</subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="H68304EA9C93E467E87BDB4EEBC033C9E">
                  <enum>(B)</enum>
                  <header>Plural form</header>
                  <text>The term <term>infants and toddlers with developmental delays or disabilities</term> means more than 1 infant or toddler with a developmental delay or disability.</text>
								</subparagraph>
              </paragraph>
              <paragraph id="HD23BBDD3123C4C8FA1C9950672EA43BB">
                <enum>(4)</enum>
                <header>Dual language learner</header>
                <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>dual language learner</term> means an individual who is limited English proficient as defined in <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
                    <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Head Start Act/s:637">section 637 of the Head Start
			 Act</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/9832">
                    <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/42/9832">42 U.S.C. 9832</cato:entity-ref>
                  </external-xref>)</cato:entity>.</text>
							</paragraph>
              <paragraph id="H0C773755908D4A2C995486475C7B1FF7">
                <enum>(5)</enum>
                <header>Low-income community</header>
                <text>The term <term>low-income community</term> shall be defined by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
							</paragraph>
              <paragraph id="H69276A3F867A491BB89B4854FB20FDFC">
                <enum>(6)</enum>
                <header>Low-income family</header>
                <text>The term <term>low-income family</term> means a family with a family income described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Child Care and Development Block Grant Act of 1990/s:658P/p:4/sp:B">section 658P(4)(B)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
							</paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="H84D5ED66E8A6403B973B96E6646B2FD3">
              <enum>(b)</enum>
              <header>Grants</header>
							<paragraph id="H6D6893EFBD244B848E5BA01E207BAD8E">
                <enum>(1)</enum>
                <header>In general</header>
                <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall make grants to eligible States, from allotments described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Child Care and Development Block Grant Act of 1990/s:658H/ss:b/p:2" proposed="true">paragraph (2)</cato:entity-ref>, to
			 enable the States to improve the quality of care for infants and toddlers.</text>
							</paragraph>
              <paragraph id="H38821B931D6947C194FCA95EEE632EE7">
                <enum>(2)</enum>
                <header>Allotments</header>
								<subparagraph id="H08D647DF5FAE43C49EFCD930FE216572">
                  <enum>(A)</enum>
                  <header>Amounts reserved</header>
									<clause id="H451F3E0691FA45669B51C63948D06F06">
                    <enum>(i)</enum>
                    <header>Territories and possessions</header>
                    <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall reserve an amount not to exceed 0.5 percent of the amount appropriated under
			 this section for each fiscal year for payments to Guam, American Samoa,
			 the United States Virgin Islands, and the Commonwealth of the Northern
			 Mariana Islands, to be allotted in accordance with their respective needs.</text>
									</clause>
                  <clause id="H6E7EDC4449FE434B8DE950186938F8C3">
                    <enum>(ii)</enum>
                    <header>Indian tribes</header>
                    <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall reserve not less than 1 percent, and not more than 2 percent, of the amount
			 appropriated under this section for each fiscal year for payments to
			 Indian tribes and tribal organizations with applications approved under
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Child Care and Development Block Grant Act of 1990/s:658O/ss:c">section 658O(c)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
									</clause>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="HEEB35D3396C34919B5EB9D21796053A9">
                  <enum>(B)</enum>
                  <header>Allotments to states</header>
                  <text>After making reservations under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Child Care and Development Block Grant Act of 1990/s:658H/ss:b/p:2/sp:A" proposed="true">subparagraph (A)</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall use the remainder of the
			 amount appropriated under this section for a fiscal year to allot to each
			 State an amount that bears the same relationship to that remainder as the
			 amount allotted to the State under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Child Care and Development Block Grant Act of 1990/s:658O">section 658O</cato:entity-ref> for that fiscal year bears
			 to the amount allotted to all States under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Child Care and Development Block Grant Act of 1990/s:658O">section 658O</cato:entity-ref> for that fiscal
			 year.</text>
								</subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="H869E3BC432514B80A8B71FBD0599F7BD">
                  <enum>(C)</enum>
                  <header>State</header>
                  <text>In this paragraph, the term <term>State</term> does not include Guam, American Samoa, the United States Virgin Islands, or the Commonwealth of
			 the Northern Mariana Islands.</text>
								</subparagraph>
              </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="HD0A40958FC1D482CBD90D75D31AB8449">
              <enum>(c)</enum>
              <header>Amendment to State plans</header>
              <text>A State that receives a grant under this section shall include in the State's plan under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Child Care and Development Block Grant Act of 1990/s:658E">section
			 658E</cato:entity-ref>, a description of how the State will use funds provided under this
			 section to improve the quality of infant and toddler care.</text>
						</subsection>
            <subsection id="H98F01354BFF147BD90560151E17C2566">
              <enum>(d)</enum>
              <header>Use of funds</header>
							<paragraph id="HD9B4549155DD4F44A7C0B08CFED6DC67">
                <enum>(1)</enum>
                <header>In general</header>
                <text>A State that receives a grant under this section shall use the funds made available through the
			 grant to carry out 1 or more of the activities described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Child Care and Development Block Grant Act of 1990/s:658H/ss:d/p:2..7" proposed="true">paragraphs (2)
			 through (7)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
							</paragraph>
              <paragraph id="HA58633EB24E04EEAA0C6B4D95BA98042">
                <enum>(2)</enum>
                <header>Increasing high-quality infant and toddler care</header>
								<subparagraph id="H79B0F0C6285446A0BBEC14F9243E586E">
                  <enum>(A)</enum>
                  <header>In general</header>
                  <text>A State may use the funds described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Child Care and Development Block Grant Act of 1990/s:658H/ss:d/p:1" proposed="true">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref> to make grants to eligible entities to be
			 resources for eligible infant and toddler care providers, to improve the
			 quality of early care and development services provided to infants and
			 toddlers in the community from low-income families and to help such
			 providers serving low-income families improve their capacity to offer
			 high-quality care to such families.</text>
								</subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="HF4732CE5A8A94623AACE1783C89B50A6">
                  <enum>(B)</enum>
                  <header>Eligible entity</header>
                  <text>To be eligible to receive a grant under this paragraph, an entity shall be an eligible child care
			 provider that—</text>
									<clause id="H4E1BED0D3AC740ADAF60FD126C13243D">
                    <enum>(i)</enum>
                    <text>serves infants and toddlers from low-income families; and</text>
									</clause>
                  <clause id="H4B9A3AEBF8E34F809E2FE2FDD6C25587">
                    <enum>(ii)</enum>
										<subclause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H8D4F1126F7BF4256B1C8804F848BCA8A">
                      <enum>(I)</enum>
                      <text>is ranked at the top level of the State’s Quality Rating and Improvement System or similar rating
			 system or accredited by a national accrediting body recognized, before the
			 date of enactment of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Infant and Toddler Care Improvement Act">Infant and Toddler Care Improvement Act</cato:entity-ref>, for
			 high-quality program standards that are valid and reliable; or</text>
										</subclause>
                    <subclause id="H9A37BCB981EF4EF5A8157C8D7A349E73" indent="up1">
                      <enum>(II)</enum>
                      <text>is an Early Head Start agency under <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
                          <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Head Start Act/s:645A">section 645A of the Head Start Act</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/9840a">
                          <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/42/9840a">42 U.S.C. 9840a</cato:entity-ref>
                        </external-xref>)</cato:entity> that is in
			 full compliance with the performance standards applicable to such an
			 agency under the <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
                          <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Head Start Act">Head Start Act</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/9831">
                          <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/42/9831/etseq">42 U.S.C. 9831 et seq.</cato:entity-ref>
                        </external-xref>)</cato:entity>.</text>
										</subclause>
                  </clause>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="H334D4D92B3F5487E9AFAD4F96AFC96D2">
                  <enum>(C)</enum>
                  <header>Priority</header>
                  <text>In making grants under this paragraph, a State—</text>
									<clause id="HA6E5EB86CB9A4C50A763F38E55A1DC1F">
                    <enum>(i)</enum>
                    <text>shall give priority to entities that will serve significant populations of low-income families; and</text>
									</clause>
                  <clause id="HF5B1567F2A10428ABB8644C7FA8A4901">
                    <enum>(ii)</enum>
                    <text>may give priority to entities that—</text>
										<subclause id="H6DE48969D4674B4AB3A2D6813947E9F2">
                      <enum>(I)</enum>
                      <text>are located in low-income communities;</text>
										</subclause>
                    <subclause id="HA1500F2AA3BC48748E9C7246CF80E915">
                      <enum>(II)</enum>
                      <text>will serve communities with significant populations of families with children who are dual language
			 learners; or</text>
										</subclause>
                    <subclause id="H4BDC893A613247368D039CA28A40C831">
                      <enum>(III)</enum>
                      <text>will increase the ability of caregivers to provide appropriate services and coordinate activities
			 with State and local systems providing services under <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
                          <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Individuals with Disabilities Education Act/pt:C">part C of the
			 Individuals with Disabilities Education Act</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1431">
                          <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/20/1431/etseq">20 U.S.C. 1431 et seq.</cato:entity-ref>
                        </external-xref>)</cato:entity> for
			 children with developmental delays or disabilities, including such
			 children in the child welfare system of the State.</text>
										</subclause>
                  </clause>
                </subparagraph>
              </paragraph>
              <paragraph id="H11CF67E089CA4D83968F621AF9930379">
                <enum>(3)</enum>
                <header>Staffed family child care networks or systems</header>
								<subparagraph id="H71138921CAD84652897E005489D8356C">
                  <enum>(A)</enum>
                  <header>In general</header>
                  <text>A State may use the funds described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Child Care and Development Block Grant Act of 1990/s:658H/ss:d/p:1" proposed="true">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref> to make grants to organizations with expertise
			 in providing child care and related technical assistance, to establish new
			 staffed family child care networks (new as of the date of amendment of the
			 State plan under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Child Care and Development Block Grant Act of 1990/s:658H/ss:c" proposed="true">subsection (c)</cato:entity-ref>) or to operate existing staffed family
			 child care networks or systems that offer, to family child care providers
			 who are eligible infant and toddler care providers, technical assistance,
			 training, administrative support, or direct services including monitoring
			 visits to providers.</text>
								</subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="HD39D3BD679B4492AAACEBFFFB16D3B0B">
                  <enum>(B)</enum>
                  <header>Priority</header>
                  <text>In making grants under this paragraph, a State—</text>
									<clause id="HBB1F66C4EAA744EA97ADF4180987C8E9">
                    <enum>(i)</enum>
                    <text>shall give priority to organizations described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Child Care and Development Block Grant Act of 1990/s:658H/ss:d/p:2/sp:C/cl:i" proposed="true">paragraph (2)(C)(I)</cato:entity-ref>; and</text>
									</clause>
                  <clause id="H65356876446449DE835AF4846B34A672">
                    <enum>(ii)</enum>
                    <text>may give priority to organizations that have 1 or more of the 3 characteristics described in
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Child Care and Development Block Grant Act of 1990/s:658H/ss:d/p:2/sp:C/cl:ii" proposed="true">paragraph (2)(C)(ii)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
									</clause>
                </subparagraph>
              </paragraph>
              <paragraph id="H8E6C56F7F23C4F8795B4759BC661B64F">
                <enum>(4)</enum>
                <header>Statewide network of infant and toddler specialists</header>
								<subparagraph id="H5A1FE33FB0744B6991DA49AC677699F3">
                  <enum>(A)</enum>
                  <header>In general</header>
                  <text>A State may use the funds described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Child Care and Development Block Grant Act of 1990/s:658H/ss:d/p:1" proposed="true">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref> to support, or to make a grant to an
			 organization with expertise in providing child care technical assistance
			 to support, a statewide network of specialists who are eligible infant and
			 toddler care providers, that shall—</text>
									<clause id="HF4EF62BD69704777B1DD540A91D655AC">
                    <enum>(i)</enum>
                    <text>provide individual or group training and intensive consultation services to eligible infant and
			 toddler care providers, including relative caregivers, on strategies to
			 improve the quality of care for infants and toddlers; and</text>
									</clause>
                  <clause id="H865D508C6EF845B5B447B5C400202A0D">
                    <enum>(ii)</enum>
                    <text>assist eligible infant and toddler care providers in coordinating activities with other offices
			 responsible for child care, including Early Head Start programs and Head
			 Start programs carried out under the <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
                        <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Head Start Act">Head Start Act</cato:entity-ref> (<cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/42/9831/etseq">42 U.S.C. 9831 et
			 seq.</cato:entity-ref>)</cato:entity>.</text>
									</clause>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="HF341EAD124964212AD9FE6924554B332">
                  <enum>(B)</enum>
                  <header>Priority</header>
                  <text>In delivering services or making grants under this paragraph, a State—</text>
									<clause id="H11013898812B4C12B0725384C598A984">
                    <enum>(i)</enum>
                    <text>shall give priority to networks that deliver support to providers described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Child Care and Development Block Grant Act of 1990/s:658H/ss:d/p:2/sp:C/cl:i" proposed="true">paragraph (2)(C)(i)</cato:entity-ref>;
			 and</text>
									</clause>
                  <clause id="HE5E0A65104FF4F1A83C1B6457E3178C2">
                    <enum>(ii)</enum>
                    <text>may give priority to networks that deliver support to providers that have 1 or more of the 3
			 characteristics described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Child Care and Development Block Grant Act of 1990/s:658H/ss:d/p:2/sp:C/cl:ii" proposed="true">paragraph (2)(C)(ii)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
									</clause>
                </subparagraph>
              </paragraph>
              <paragraph id="HAB708726CC9C4062A509F00E06DE9CD8">
                <enum>(5)</enum>
                <header>State workforce quality initiatives</header>
								<subparagraph id="H99B211E6E2294007B72704049E2D4EA6">
                  <enum>(A)</enum>
                  <header>In general</header>
                  <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A State may use the funds described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Child Care and Development Block Grant Act of 1990/s:658H/ss:d/p:1" proposed="true">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref> to support initiatives to improve the quality
			 of the workforce of eligible infant and toddler care providers, including
			 activities that are culturally and linguistically competent to support a
			 diverse workforce reflecting the race and ethnicity of children served,
			 such as—</text>
									<clause id="H8E81A0A7487945EE8A79DFF0C80AF7B6">
                    <enum>(i)</enum>
                    <text>providing relevant training, professional development, or mentoring to eligible infant and toddler
			 care providers, including linking the training, development, or mentoring
			 to career pathways for eligible infant and toddler care providers;</text>
									</clause>
                  <clause id="H8CF4813BBF0146918A2265E8F1D16AE0">
                    <enum>(ii)</enum>
                    <text>providing scholarships or other financial support to eligible infant and toddler care providers to
			 advance their education and training;</text>
									</clause>
                  <clause id="H5C46BC9653B64CB5A3E658A6E8CC5FB6">
                    <enum>(iii)</enum>
                    <text>coordinating activities with the State’s higher education system to expand the availability and
			 quality of coursework for infant and toddler care providers, including
			 developing career pathways for eligible infant and toddler care providers;
			 or</text>
									</clause>
                  <clause id="HC7C26906D34445719F4FF780AC9B56A0">
                    <enum>(iv)</enum>
                    <text>improving the State credentialing of eligible infant and toddler care providers.</text>
									</clause>
                </subparagraph>
              </paragraph>
              <paragraph id="H31A5E785821744FCAA352FDA54BD1D32">
                <enum>(6)</enum>
                <header>Systems quality</header>
                <text>A State may use the funds described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Child Care and Development Block Grant Act of 1990/s:658H/ss:d/p:1" proposed="true">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref> to—</text>
								<subparagraph id="HC40A61E5B884455EAA5B3E2FE530FF87">
                  <enum>(A)</enum>
                  <text>develop infant and toddler components for the State's Quality Rating and Improvement System or
			 similar rating system, child care licensing regulations, or voluntary
			 early learning guidelines;</text>
								</subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="H6DB3A168F3104F48A56B768B23F3F834">
                  <enum>(B)</enum>
                  <text>improve the ability of parents to obtain information about high-quality infant and toddler care; or</text>
								</subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="H3631869D389449EF9DE61DD2A86CFB21">
                  <enum>(C)</enum>
                  <text>assist eligible infant and toddler care providers seeking to improve the quality of their infant
			 and toddler care by increasing their ranking on the State’s Quality Rating
			 and Improvement System or similar rating system, meeting performance
			 standards applicable to an Early Head Start agency under the <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
                      <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Head Start Act">Head Start
			 Act</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/9831">
                      <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/42/9831/etseq">42 U.S.C. 9831 et seq.</cato:entity-ref>
                    </external-xref>)</cato:entity>, or becoming accredited by a national
			 accrediting body described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Child Care and Development Block Grant Act of 1990/s:658H/ss:d/p:2/sp:B/cl:ii" proposed="true">paragraph (2)(B)(ii)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
								</subparagraph>
              </paragraph>
              <paragraph id="H6F41C50B54B84FCDA3D93DEE76A859F6">
                <enum>(7)</enum>
                <header>Other high-quality initiatives</header>
                <text>A State may use the funds described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Child Care and Development Block Grant Act of 1990/s:658H/ss:d/p:1" proposed="true">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref> to carry out other activities determined by
			 the State to improve the quality of infant and toddler care provided in
			 the State and for which there is evidence that the activities will lead to
			 improved infant and toddler safety, infant and toddler development, or
			 infant and toddler well-being.</text>
							</paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="H7A6746255C5A4D879F2A9C19F58E69B2">
              <enum>(e)</enum>
              <header>Reporting</header>
              <text>A State that receives a grant under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Child Care and Development Block Grant Act of 1990/s:658H/ss:b" proposed="true">subsection (b)</cato:entity-ref> shall submit in the State's annual reports
			 required under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Child Care and Development Block Grant Act of 1990/s:658K/ss:a/p:2">section 658K(a)(2)</cato:entity-ref>, information on how the State is using
			 the funding provided under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Child Care and Development Block Grant Act of 1990/s:658H/ss:b" proposed="true">subsection (b)</cato:entity-ref> to improve the quality of infant
			 and toddler care and the effect such funding is having on the quality of
			 infant and toddler care in the State.</text>
						</subsection>
            <subsection id="H657287996F2E4F56AE75F54102519507">
              <enum>(f)</enum>
              <header>Authorization of appropriations</header>
              <text>
                <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="auth-auth-approp">There are authorized to be appropriated <cato:property name="purpose">to carry out <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Child Care and Development Block Grant Act of 1990/s:658H" proposed="true">this section</cato:entity-ref>
                  </cato:property> <cato:funds-and-year amount="500000000" year="2015">$500,000,000 for fiscal year 2015</cato:funds-and-year>
			 and <cato:funds-and-year amount="500000000" year="2016,..">$500,000,000 for each subsequent fiscal year.</cato:funds-and-year>
                </cato:entity>
              </text>
            </subsection>
          </section>
          <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
        </quoted-block>
			</subsection>
      <subsection id="HF385E216D87B429F84B1288DB27BF32D">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Conforming amendments</header>
				<paragraph id="H3D4E9D88A03245629ECA297AF3CDBFB4">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>Authorization</header>
          <text>
            <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Child Care and Development Block Grant Act of 1990/s:658B">Section 658B of the Child Care and Development Block Grant Act of 1990</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/9858">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/42/9858">42 U.S.C. 9858</cato:entity-ref>
            </external-xref>)</cato:entity> is amended
			 by inserting <quote>(other than <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Child Care and Development Block Grant Act of 1990/s:658H" proposed="true">section 658H</cato:entity-ref>)</quote> after <quote>subchapter</quote>.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph commented="no" id="HFA74DF42782043E986EFDBB06CB7FF71">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Allotment</header>
          <text>
            <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Child Care and Development Block Grant Act of 1990/s:658O/ss:a/p:1">Section 658O(a)(1) of such Act</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/9858m">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/42/9858m/a/1">42 U.S.C. 9858m(a)(1)</cato:entity-ref>
            </external-xref>)</cato:entity> is amended by striking <quote>this subchapter</quote> and inserting <quote>
              <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Child Care and Development Block Grant Act of 1990/s:658B">section 658B</cato:entity-ref>
            </quote>.</text>
				</paragraph>
      </subsection>
    </section>
  </legis-body>
</bill>
</doc>