<doc>
  <docmeta id="113hr3400ih">
    <bill congress="113" type="hr" number="3400" version="ih"/>
    <revision size="5179" annotations="0" status="complete" id="3" commit-time="2013-11-07T23:00:40Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113hr3400ih/3.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H8267483651354AAAAF7B899569D37A83" public-private="public">
  <metadata>
<dublinCore>
<dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">113 HR 3400 IH: National Bison Legacy Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">2013-10-30</dc:date>
<dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
    <congress>113th CONGRESS</congress>
    <session>1st Session</session>
    <legis-num>H. R. 3400</legis-num>
    <current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
    <action>
      <action-date date="20131030">October 30, 2013</action-date>
      <action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="C001049">Mr. Clay</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="F000449">Mr. Fortenberry</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000248">Mr. Serrano</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="N000184">Mrs. Noem</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>
      </action-desc>
    </action>
    <legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
    <official-title>To adopt the North American bison as the national mammal of the United States.</official-title>
  </form>
  <legis-body id="HEFDBD79C1C1E4F28B33C230C4A61BF45" style="OLC">
    <section id="H68DD620E8C3A4D64A3F3C88D9AD014F1" section-type="section-one">
      <enum>1.</enum>
      <header>Short title</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote>
          <short-title>National Bison Legacy Act</short-title>
        </quote>.</text>
    </section>
    <section id="H50D1A416D2444875AFA1FB81153575FD">
      <enum>2.</enum>
      <header>Findings</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">
        <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> finds that—</text>
      <paragraph id="H1B34A121724143E7992E9BEB699AD451">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text>bison are considered to be a historical symbol of the United States;</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HADE2571130AC46C3A7A51ADEFD98B26A">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text>bison were integrally linked with the economic and spiritual lives of many Indian tribes through trade and sacred ceremonies;</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HFB3E4AF3FAE843D893AE3248764C8B47">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <text>there are more than 60 Indian tribes participating in the Intertribal Buffalo Council;</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H3E7749C5BC0A4BB699DD9AA8D7E0EEB2">
        <enum>(4)</enum>
        <text>numerous members of Indian tribes—</text>
        <subparagraph id="HAECEFF8C512A4EC0B6342E392C818085">
          <enum>(A)</enum>
          <text>are involved in bison restoration on tribal land; and</text>
        </subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="H890FCA50B9354362826120E3D6E52B62">
          <enum>(B)</enum>
          <text>have a combined herd on more than 1,000,000 acres of tribal land;</text>
        </subparagraph>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H9C88D5D24F1A427C9CE0FD25CCDC467B">
        <enum>(5)</enum>
        <text>the Intertribal Buffalo Council is a tribal organization incorporated pursuant to <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Indian Reorganization Act/s:17" official-title="true">section 17 of the Act of June 18, 1934</cato:entity-ref> (commonly known as <term>
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Indian Reorganization Act">Indian Reorganization Act</cato:entity-ref>
            </term>) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/477">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/25/477">25 U.S.C. 477</cato:entity-ref>
            </external-xref>)</cato:entity>;</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H519827056FCF42099A556DE07C8690D3">
        <enum>(6)</enum>
        <text>bison play an ecologically important role in modifying and improving the types of grasses found in landscapes to the benefit of grassland ecosystems;</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H39998E90A65E47E4B619B5B3C0B5793A">
        <enum>(7)</enum>
        <text>a small group of ranchers helped save bison from extinction in the late 1800s by gathering the remnants of the decimated herds;</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H0D0CC8091A0042EB82F793EF011CCE1B">
        <enum>(8)</enum>
        <text>bison hold significant economic value for private producers and rural communities;</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HFC9EBB0E73FA452FBDBD879D18FC59A0">
        <enum>(9)</enum>
        <text>as of 2007, 200,000 head of bison were under the stewardship of private producers, creating jobs and providing a sustainable and healthy meat source contributing to the food security of the United States;</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H55EA546F66F74F0C8D0DB03B1044BADF">
        <enum>(10)</enum>
        <text>on December 8, 1905, William Hornaday, Theodore Roosevelt and others formed the American Bison Society in response to the near extinction of bison in the United States;</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HC68796D75726426BB5754CF1650B167B">
        <enum>(11)</enum>
        <text>on October 11, 1907, the American Bison Society sent 15 captive-bred bison from the New York Zoological Park, now the Bronx Zoo, to the first wildlife refuge in the United States, which was known as the <term>Wichita Mountains Wildlife Refuge</term>, resulting in the first successful reintroduction of a mammal species on the brink of extinction back into its natural habitat;</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H7CF1AC65529C46178C383160566BEEC5">
        <enum>(12)</enum>
        <text>in 2005, the American Bison Society was reestablished, bringing together bison ranchers, managers from Indian tribes, Federal and State agencies conservation organizations, and natural and social scientists from the United States, Canada, and Mexico to create a vision for the North American bison in the 21st century;</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H7C03BAF44EC140E58E8E518B891ACD28">
        <enum>(13)</enum>
        <text>the buffalo nickel played an important role in modernizing the currency of the United States;</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H995087447E134F9281054C6273137D50">
        <enum>(14)</enum>
        <text>a bison has been depicted on the official seal of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1400">Department of the Interior</cato:entity-ref> almost continuously since 1912, is portrayed on 2 State flags, has been adopted by 3 States as the official mammal or animal of those States, and has been adopted as a mascot by several sports teams, which highlights the iconic significance of bison in the United States;</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H61CA854043254E6E91F1C19B804890E7">
        <enum>(15)</enum>
        <text>there are bison herds in National Wildlife Refuges and National Parks;</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H3F25E568A1A1478EA758EAA75A881DAB">
        <enum>(16)</enum>
        <text>there are bison in State-managed herds across 11 States;</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HB9A8E799996D40A78FDB1D38D003E16F">
        <enum>(17)</enum>
        <text>there is a growing effort to celebrate and officially recognize the historical, cultural, and economic significance of the North American bison to the heritage of the United States;</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H7A517027F74245CA90D6E4461FB80710">
        <enum>(18)</enum>
        <text>in the 1st session of the 113th Congress, 22 United States Senators led a successful effort to enact a resolution to designate November 2, 2013, as the second annual National Bison Day; and</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H28143FD35691453CAC3229904FE12EEA">
        <enum>(19)</enum>
        <text>members of Indian tribes, bison producers, conservationists, sportsmen, educators, and other public and private partners have participated in the annual National Bison Day celebration at several events across the United States and are committed to continuing this tradition annually on the first Saturday of November.</text>
      </paragraph>
    </section>
    <section id="H2899ED246F91464094A7FA1D1F7A8378">
      <enum>3.</enum>
      <header>Establishment and adoption of the North American bison as the national mammal</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">The mammal commonly known as the <term>North American bison</term> is adopted as the national mammal of the United States.</text>
    </section>
  </legis-body>
</bill>
</doc>