<doc>
  <docmeta id="113hres191ih">
    <bill congress="113" type="hres" number="191" version="ih"/>
    <revision size="3373" annotations="0" status="complete" id="6" commit-time="2013-05-19T15:54:57Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113hres191ih/6.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <resolution xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" dms-id="HB137662309EF421CBD9A178F5E494EA1" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H">
    <metadata>
      <dublinCore>
        <title>113 HRES 191 IH: Honoring Jacoby Dickens, the successful, community-oriented African-American financier and philanthropist in Chicago, Illinois.</title>
        <publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</publisher>
        <date>2013-04-26</date>
        <format>text/xml</format>
        <language>EN</language>
        <rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</rights>
      </dublinCore>
    </metadata>
    <form>
      <distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code>
      <congress display="yes">113th CONGRESS</congress>
      <session display="yes">1st Session</session>
      <legis-num>H. RES. 191</legis-num>
      <current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
      <action display="yes">
        <action-date date="20130426">April 26, 2013</action-date>
        <action-desc>
          <sponsor name-id="H000324">Mr. Hastings of Florida</sponsor>submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the<committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>
        </action-desc>
      </action>
      <legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
      <official-title display="yes">Honoring Jacoby Dickens, the successful, community-oriented African-American financier and philanthropist in Chicago, Illinois.</official-title>
    </form>
    <preamble>
      <whereas>
        <text>Whereas Jacoby Dickens has become a prominent representation of the American Dream through his remarkable growth from humble beginnings in Florida to renowned financier of Seaway Bank &amp; Trust Co.;</text>
      </whereas>
      <whereas>
        <text>Whereas Dickens has distinguished himself as much for his philanthropic efforts as for his entrepreneurial successes, constantly investing into the African-American community;</text>
      </whereas>
      <whereas>
        <text>Whereas Jacoby D. Dickens was born in Panama City, Florida, on June 19, 1931, one of six children, in a low-income household and went on to complete his high school education at Wendell Phillips High School in the South Side of Chicago;</text>
      </whereas>
      <whereas>
        <text>Whereas Mr. Dickens began saving money while working as a building engineer and used his savings to invest in real estate;</text>
      </whereas>
      <whereas>
        <text>Whereas Mr. Dickens used the returns of his successful investments in real estate to invest in multiple bowling alleys across Chicago, and gained exposure as a financial up-and-comer;</text>
      </whereas>
      <whereas>
        <text>Whereas Mr. Dickens became chairman of Seaway Bank &amp; Co. in 1983, just 4 years after joining their board;</text>
      </whereas>
      <whereas>
        <text>Whereas Seaway was one of very few banks willing to provide loans in tough neighborhoods in the South Side of Chicago, primarily due to the Mr. Dickens’ model of success;</text>
      </whereas>
      <whereas>
        <text>Whereas Mr. Dickens built a $500,000,000 organization while focusing on dedicating his services to African-Americans in lower income communities, at a time when many were unwilling to take such risks;</text>
      </whereas>
      <whereas>
        <text>Whereas countless businesses, families, and communities at large were impacted by Mr. Dickens’ trust in people;</text>
      </whereas>
      <whereas>
        <text>Whereas Mr. Dickens believed that people are equal and deserve the opportunity to better themselves; and</text>
      </whereas>
      <whereas>
        <text>Whereas Seaway &amp; Co. was originally only one of few banks in Chicago owned by African-Americans, but is now one of the largest and most successful banks in the city: Now, therefore, be it</text>
      </whereas>
    </preamble>
    <resolution-body style="traditional" id="HE8BF2A1DAD194CA6BF2E49C0F5ED1DDA">
      <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="HFC28B5096D3F4583AA2BFA9AF230611E">
        <text>That the<cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0050">House of Representatives</cato:entity-ref>—</text>
        <paragraph id="H24B1D57E068F465EA6561A6F3B62B92A">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">honors Jacoby Dickens, the successful, community-oriented African-American financier and philanthropist in Chicago, Illinois, for his dedication to increasing equity amongst lower income African-Americans;</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HE5164B9102FD483DB9E98D3463983285">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>joins Jacoby Dickens and other philanthropic entrepreneurs in promoting equal access to financial betterment for underprivileged communities; and</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H322A2D62A5F7499699FCF94DCFB43AD7">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <text>believes that the fruit of thoughtful risk taking is the backbone of success in the United States; and</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H7C7CC91F6F11480E830583C33E45E8A3">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
          <text>encourages each individual’s pursuit of life, liberty, and happiness.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </section>
    </resolution-body>
  </resolution>
</doc>