<doc>
  <docmeta id="113hr2203ih">
    <bill congress="113" type="hr" number="2203" version="ih"/>
    <revision size="12189" annotations="0" status="complete" id="5" commit-time="2013-07-03T15:17:54Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113hr2203ih/5.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H04C05782A25B4206BE75A7EC06C8F021" public-private="public">
	<metadata>
<dublinCore>
<title>113 HR 2203 IH: To provide for the award of a gold medal on behalf of Congress to Jack Nicklaus, in recognition of his service to the Nation in promoting excellence, good sportsmanship, and philanthropy.</title>
<publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</publisher>
<date>2013-05-23</date>
<format>text/xml</format>
<language>EN</language>
<rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>113th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 2203</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20130523">May 23, 2013</action-date>
			<action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="T000462">Mr. Tiberi</sponsor> (for
			 himself and <cosponsor name-id="R000583">Mr. Rooney</cosponsor>) introduced the
			 following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial
			 Services</committee-name>
      </action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To provide for the award of a gold medal on behalf of
		  Congress to Jack Nicklaus, in recognition of his service to the Nation in
		  promoting excellence, good sportsmanship, and philanthropy.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="HC7D1692577474911AA43CFBD4C1037EA" style="OLC">
		<section id="H16BC0689F41C4B97B6BE3F14D1733E7C" section-type="section-one">
      <enum>1.</enum>
      <header>Findings</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">
        <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> finds the following:</text>
			<paragraph id="H37D69ABD11F7477DBB3123188A556BEB">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text>Jack Nicklaus is a
			 world-famous golf professional, a highly successful business executive, a
			 prominent advertising spokesman, a passionate and dedicated philanthropist, a
			 devoted husband, father, and grandfather, and a man with a common touch that
			 has made him one of the most popular and accessible public figures in
			 history.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H6E6BE24D9B624B5EAC9E14133AB8EED5">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text>Jack Nicklaus
			 amassed 120 victories in professional competition of national or international
			 stature, 73 of which came on the Professional Golf Association (in this Act
			 referred to as the <term>PGA</term>) Tour, and professional major-championship
			 titles. His record 18 professional majors, the first of which he won 50 years
			 ago with his win at the 1962 U.S. Open as a 22-year-old rookie, remains the
			 standard by which all golfers are measured. He is the only player in golf
			 history to have won each major championship at least three times, and is the
			 only player to complete a career <term>Grand Slam</term> on both the regular
			 and senior tours. He also owns the record for most major championships as a
			 senior, with eight.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H315979A2082641C0BF61FF7D5AF71632">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <text>Jack Nicklaus’
			 magnetic personality and unfailing sense of kindness and thoughtfulness have
			 endeared him to millions throughout the world.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H324F2D01EC8A4ACDB91AA88E96FDF754">
        <enum>(4)</enum>
        <text>Jack Nicklaus has
			 been the recipient of countless athletic honors, including being named
			 Individual Male Athlete of the Century by Sports Illustrated, one of the 10
			 Greatest Athletes of the Century by ESPN, and Golfer of the Century or Golfer
			 of the Millennium by every major national and international media outlet. He
			 received the Muhammad Ali Sports Legend Award and the first-ever ESPY Lifetime
			 Achievement Award. He became the first golfer and only the third athlete to
			 receive the Vince Lombardi Award of Excellence, and is also a five-time winner
			 of the PGA Player of the Year Award. He was inducted into the World Golf Hall
			 of Fame at the age of 34.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HC64AC93096ED4DBC8545A86A91468796">
        <enum>(5)</enum>
        <text>Jack Nicklaus has
			 received numerous honors outside of the world of sports, including several golf
			 industry awards for his work and contributions as a golf course designer, such
			 as the Old Tom Morris Award, which is the highest honor given by the Golf
			 Course Superintendents Association of America, and both the Donald Ross Award
			 given by the American Society of Golf Course Architects and the Don A. Rossi
			 Award given by the Golf Course Builders Association of America. Golf Inc.
			 Magazine named him the Most Powerful Person in Golf for a record six
			 consecutive years, due to his impact on various aspects of the industry through
			 his course design work, marketing and licensing business, his ambassadorial
			 role in promoting and growing the game of golf worldwide, and his involvement
			 on a national and global level with various charitable causes.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HA646CFB353CA4E62B311D219CF71F5C7">
        <enum>(6)</enum>
        <text>Jack Nicklaus has
			 been involved in the design of more than 290 golf courses worldwide, and his
			 business, Nicklaus Design, has close to 380 courses open for play in 36
			 countries and 39 States.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HD265B1CD3D394B6DA021D7D73A103B6E">
        <enum>(7)</enum>
        <text>Jack Nicklaus
			 served as the Global Ambassador for a campaign to include golf in the Olympic
			 Games, which was achieved and will begin in the 2016 Olympic program.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H9499C62E6C104215A0F484F1501D0163">
        <enum>(8)</enum>
        <text>Jack Nicklaus was
			 honored by President George W. Bush in 2005 by receiving the Presidential Medal
			 of Freedom, the highest honor given to any United States civilian.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H0DD9DE0E0DB5499F9BB6FAC639818EA0">
        <enum>(9)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Jack Nicklaus has a long-standing
			 commitment to numerous charitable causes, such as his founding, along with wife
			 Barbara, of the Nicklaus Children’s Health Care Foundation, which provides
			 pediatric health care services throughout South Florida and in other parts of
			 the country. The Foundation has raised close to $24,000,000 since it was formed
			 in 2004, and has provided health assistance and services to more than 4,000
			 children and their families through—</text>
				<subparagraph id="HA2EFEB3B484D4380BD265BDA1273B5B9">
          <enum>(A)</enum>
          <text>Child Life
			 programs (supporting therapeutic interventions for children with chronic and
			 acute conditions during hospitalization);</text>
				</subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="HCADEECFF5F5E4BDA840668C494A68E2A">
          <enum>(B)</enum>
          <text>Miami Children’s
			 Hospital Nicklaus Care Centers (to offer a new option to Palm Beach County-area
			 families with children who require pediatric specialty care); and</text>
				</subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="HB11C16C504B14ABD9D216A225E6D497E">
          <enum>(C)</enum>
          <text>Safe Kids Program
			 (aimed at keeping children injury-free and offering safety education in an
			 effort to decrease accidental injuries in children).</text>
				</subparagraph>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HD6A125127B0A4CD89741FEFC530F4E6F">
        <enum>(10)</enum>
        <text>In October 2012,
			 the Miami Children’s Hospital Nicklaus Outpatient Center was opened to provide
			 pediatric urgent care, diagnostic services, and rehabilitation services in Palm
			 Beach County.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H453D410E88944C2A8476A8208601CB00">
        <enum>(11)</enum>
        <text>Jack Nicklaus
			 also established an annual pro-am golf tournament called <quote>The
			 Jake</quote> to honor his 17-month-old grandson who passed away in 2005, and it
			 serves as a primary fundraiser for the Nicklaus Children’s Health Care
			 Foundation. The event alone has raised well over $43,000,000 over the last
			 several years.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HB1E76C29C97441E6A31F1875D5E3CC96">
        <enum>(12)</enum>
        <text>Nicklaus has been
			 a tireless supporter of numerous junior golf initiatives, working with the PGA
			 of America Junior Golf Foundation over the course of four decades, including
			 the establishment of the Barbara and Jack Nicklaus Junior Golf Endowment Fund
			 and the PGA-Nicklaus First Tee Teaching Grants. He also is a spokesperson for
			 several PGA of America and USGA growth-of-the-game initiatives. He continues to
			 support several scholarship foundations, other children’s hospitals, and other
			 causes, including spinal-cord research, pancreatic cancer issues, and Florida
			 Everglades restoration.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H0DFA8BD7DD7C4DE9AD68447B37F31E2D">
        <enum>(13)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In 2013, Jack Nicklaus, with the support of
			 the National Park and Recreation Association (NRPA), launched the Jack Nicklaus
			 Learning Leagues, taking team-concept golf to our parks system for children,
			 ages 5 to 12. A non-profit foundation called Global Outreach for Learning
			 Foundation (GOLF) was created to underwrite the program. By the end of 2013,
			 they hope to have the program in more than 100 locations and reach close to
			 25,000 children.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HC350F768AF7E4A15A88E1D0630DC82B8">
        <enum>(14)</enum>
        <text>Jack Nicklaus
			 continues to manage the Memorial Tournament in his home State of Ohio, in which
			 contributions generated through the aid of over 2,600 volunteers are given to
			 support Nationwide Children’s Hospital and close to 75 other Central Ohio
			 charities. This has garnered more than $5,700,000 for programs and services at
			 Nationwide Children’s Hospital since 1976, so that Central Ohio will continue
			 to have one of the best children’s hospitals in the United States.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H959B0627BB9B4A77824FA06AC507B85D">
        <enum>(15)</enum>
        <text>Jack Nicklaus
			 serves as an honorary chairs of the American Lake Veterans Golf Course in
			 Tacoma, Washington, which neighbors a Veterans Administration hospital and is
			 designed for the rehabilitation of wounded and disabled veterans. Nicklaus has
			 donated his design services for the improvement of the course, and raised
			 contributions for the addition of nine new holes (the <term>Nicklaus
			 Nine</term>), the construction of the Rehabilitation and Learning Center, and
			 the upgrade of the maintenance facilities. The course is considered the only
			 one in the United States designed solely for the use of disabled veterans. It
			 served over 30,000 veterans and their families in 2011 to use the healing
			 powers of golf to help them rehabilitate and recreate. The hope is that
			 American Lake will serve as a pilot program for the more than 150 Veterans
			 Administration hospitals nationwide.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph commented="no" id="HEC68BD93E8814B64A60C5A52A9451485">
        <enum>(16)</enum>
        <text>Jack Nicklaus
			 serves as a spokesperson and Trustee for the First Tee program, which brings
			 golf to children who would not otherwise be exposed to it, and teaches them
			 valuable, character-building life lessons through the game of golf, and is a
			 national co-chair of the organization’s More Than a Game campaign.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H5F3BD98ABAF045D99EE87ED84F80F1ED">
        <enum>(17)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Jack Nicklaus remains active in tournament
			 golf, although he retired from major championship competition in 2005, when he
			 played his final British Open and his final Masters Tournament, and led the
			 United States to a thrilling victory in the President's Cup. He consults often
			 with the PGA Tour, and no fewer than 95 Nicklaus courses have hosted a combined
			 total of almost 700 professional tournaments. In 2013 alone, Nicklaus courses
			 will host 17 PGA Tour-sanctioned events. His Muirfield Village Golf Club in
			 Ohio will be hosting the Presidents Cup in October 2013, making it the only
			 club in history to have hosted all three of the game’s most prominent
			 international team competitions—the Ryder Cup, Solheim Cup and Presidents Cup.
			 It is also expected that his course at the Jack Nicklaus Golf Club Korea in New
			 Songdo City, South Korea, will be named the host venue for the 2015 Presidents
			 Cup—the first time that country has hosted an international team competition of
			 this stature</text>
			</paragraph>
    </section>
    <section id="H047F6A975A544E3CB89EB6FB8906B759">
      <enum>2.</enum>
      <header>Congressional
			 gold medal</header>
			<subsection id="HDB716EAE9011437BAA8052B6D3A807B2">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Authorization</header>
        <text>The
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Speaker of the House of Representatives" entity-parent-id="0050">Speaker of the House of Representatives</cato:entity-ref> and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="President pro tempore of the Senate" entity-parent-id="0010" proposed="true">President pro tempore of the
			 Senate</cato:entity-ref> shall make appropriate arrangements for the presentation, on behalf of
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref>, of a gold medal of appropriate design to Jack Nicklaus in recognition
			 of his service to the Nation in promoting excellence and good
			 sportsmanship.</text>
			</subsection>
      <subsection id="HA3CD6B5495544A41967ADCA6A3DF3FB6">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Design and
			 striking</header>
        <text>For the purpose of the presentation referred to in
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="113 HR 2203/s:2/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary of the Treasury</cato:entity-ref> shall strike a gold medal with
			 suitable emblems, devices, and inscriptions to be determined by the
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
			</subsection>
    </section>
    <section id="HCD8BD303A4404F3680D1EE34294CFB5A">
      <enum>3.</enum>
      <header>Duplicate
			 medals</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Under such regulations
			 as the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary of the Treasury</cato:entity-ref> may prescribe, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> may strike
			 duplicate medals in bronze of the gold medal struck pursuant to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="113 HR 2203/s:2" proposed="true">section 2</cato:entity-ref> and
			 sell such duplicate medals at a price sufficient to cover the costs of the
			 duplicate medals (including labor, materials, dies, use of machinery, overhead
			 expenses) and the cost of the gold medal.</text>
		</section>
    <section id="HE900DA0A334A41B8B887A4CBF09F659F">
      <enum>4.</enum>
      <header>National
			 medals</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">The medals struck under
			 this Act are national medals for purposes of <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc-chapter/31/51">
          <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/31/51">chapter 51</external-xref> of title 31, United
			 States Code</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
		</section>
    <section id="H4228B23A74734D08A8CE40579A4DA071">
      <enum>5.</enum>
      <header>Funding</header>
			<subsection id="HDC3888A008194E1488C8562C2D7A78DF">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Authorization of
			 appropriations</header>
        <text>
          <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="auth-auth-approp">There is authorized to be charged against the
			 <cato:property name="funds-source">United States Mint Public Enterprise Fund</cato:property> an amount not to exceed <cato:funds-and-year amount="30000">$30,000</cato:funds-and-year> <cato:property name="purpose">to
			 pay for the cost of the medals authorized by <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="113 HR 2203" proposed="true">this Act</cato:entity-ref>
            </cato:property>.</cato:entity>
        </text>
			</subsection>
      <subsection id="H395C1B9B0C2F445FA808331993F598F9">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Proceeds of
			 sale</header>
        <text>Amounts received from the sale of duplicate bronze medals
			 under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="113 HR 2203/s:3" proposed="true">section 3</cato:entity-ref> shall be deposited in the United States Mint Public Enterprise
			 Fund.</text>
			</subsection>
    </section>
  </legis-body>
</bill>
</doc>