<doc>
  <docmeta id="113hr3690ih">
    <bill congress="113" type="hr" number="3690" version="ih"/>
    <revision size="15067" annotations="0" status="complete" id="5" commit-time="2013-12-30T15:47:09Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113hr3690ih/5.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H3F87E5CD9BC44536BE1A48B8E1386659" public-private="public">
  <metadata>
<dublinCore>
<dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">113 HR 3690 IH: STEM Gateways Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">2013-12-10</dc:date>
<dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
    <congress>113th CONGRESS</congress>
    <session>1st Session</session>
    <legis-num>H. R. 3690</legis-num>
    <current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
    <action>
      <action-date date="20131210">December 10, 2013</action-date>
      <action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="K000379">Mr. Kennedy</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="H001034">Mr. Honda</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and the Workforce</committee-name>
      </action-desc>
    </action>
    <legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
    <official-title>To increase the participation of women, girls, and underrepresented minorities in STEM fields, to encourage and support students from all economic backgrounds to pursue STEM career opportunities, and for other purposes.</official-title>
  </form>
  <legis-body id="H0BBC972F6DD745248B05E8936683FE7A" style="OLC">
    <section id="H760D28C0AFE94485B938301D40F19FBC" section-type="section-one">
      <enum>1.</enum>
      <header>Short title</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote>
          <short-title>STEM Gateways Act</short-title>
        </quote>.</text>
    </section>
    <section id="H310FD63A1A09461DBD49780F8FB9E416">
      <enum>2.</enum>
      <header>Findings</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">
        <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> finds the following:</text>
      <paragraph id="HD2D5412A040A49988887A8C7297BEFD9">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">According to a 2013 Census Bureau study, women’s representation in STEM occupations has increased since the 1970s, but women remain significantly underrepresented in engineering and computing occupations that make up more than 80 percent of all STEM employment. Women’s representation in computer occupations has declined since the 1990s. In 2011, 26 percent of STEM workers were women and 74 percent were men. According to the National Action Council for Minorities in Engineering, Inc. (NACME), the number of engineering degrees awarded to African-American women has steadily declined since the late 1990s.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H5AB4B7CF7FD047EC80C1203355900222">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">According to the Brookings Institution 2013 report, <quote>The Hidden STEM Economy</quote>, half of all STEM jobs are available to workers without a 4-year college degree, and these jobs pay $53,000 per year on average. This sector of the STEM economy offers job opportunities for many workers with qualified certificates or associate’s degrees, drawing from high schools, workforce training programs, vocational schools, and community colleges. Despite these opportunities, only one-fifth of the $4.3 billion spent annually by the Federal Government on STEM education and training goes towards supporting sub-bachelor’s level training.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H60BAFC64922E468790214AB3079B6096">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <text>According to a 2011 report by the Department of Commerce, underrepresented minorities account for only 3 out of 10 professionals in STEM fields.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H6CDF3BAB0B4343CDB4F8D0B1622859BC">
        <enum>(4)</enum>
        <text>STEM workers in all demographic groups earn more than their non-STEM counterparts.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H713EC187BF4B483589066621E590C641">
        <enum>(5)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">According to the America After 3pm report, children from African-American, Hispanic, and Native American populations participate in afterschool programs in greater numbers than the average. Girls also participate in equal numbers to boys in such programs. Afterschool learning thus represents an intervention point to engage with populations currently underrepresented in STEM fields and careers.</text>
      </paragraph>
    </section>
    <section id="HF613A7EF44604D979B20C0A4C42C1863">
      <enum>3.</enum>
      <header>Grant program authorized</header>
      <subsection id="HC05E456BE219462AB054928FA7DA4955">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Program authorized</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">From the amounts appropriated to carry out this section, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="9100">Secretary of Education</cato:entity-ref> shall award grants to eligible entities, on a competitive basis, to enable such eligible entities to carry out programs described in <internal-xref idref="H2F9A7FB041E14687B327F4973EA46850" legis-path="3.(d)">
            <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="STEM Gateways Act/s:3/ss:d" proposed="true">subsection (d)</cato:entity-ref>
          </internal-xref> to achieve, with respect to women and girls, underrepresented minorities, and individuals from all economic backgrounds, (including economically disadvantaged individuals and individuals living in economically distressed areas), one or more of the following goals:</text>
        <paragraph id="H030FEF89F90845A0A3086584BA39CD19">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Encourage interest in the STEM fields at the elementary school or secondary school levels.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H90D621BD0E584D56855CDBB8F5C8F9CE">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Motivate engagement in STEM fields by providing relevant hands-on learning opportunities at the elementary school and secondary school levels.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HDA993278D57A47E38C139927BD898316">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Support classroom success in STEM disciplines at the elementary school or secondary school levels.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H6B498F6E37D74F038762898217046DBE">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
          <text>Support workforce training and career preparation in STEM fields at the secondary school level.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H3C5C297392DE4B409FD998F6060F0DF7">
          <enum>(5)</enum>
          <text>Improve access to career and continuing education opportunities in STEM fields at the secondary school level.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="H4DE47E02AD6F43CAA3D0E49EFFBA01EC">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Limitation</header>
        <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="9100">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> may award grants under this section for not more than a 5-year period.</text>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="H8E52CABE6CF94BBFAE9753839B2008BB">
        <enum>(c)</enum>
        <header>Application</header>
        <paragraph id="H1C0E6B9BD765447DBA04B730BD295463">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>In general</header>
          <text>Each eligible entity that desires to receive a grant under this section shall submit an application to the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="9100">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="9100">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> may reasonably require.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H4B6F895A90824D8E9352FFA69CB976BB">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Contents</header>
          <text>An application submitted under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="STEM Gateways Act/s:3/ss:c/p:1" proposed="true">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref> shall contain—</text>
          <subparagraph id="H4332486CB33846468641CFDD7057AC48">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>in the case of an eligible entity that plans to use the grant funds at the elementary school level—</text>
            <clause id="H7904C77BB921449BACACFBD8B3BC6E32">
              <enum>(i)</enum>
              <text>a description of the programs the eligible entity will carry out to achieve one or more of the goals described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="STEM Gateways Act/s:3/ss:a/p:1..3" proposed="true">paragraphs (1) through (3) of subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref> at the elementary school level, including the content of the programs and research and models used to design the programs; and</text>
            </clause>
            <clause id="HDFB6EAC965444D64B978FC93295CF545">
              <enum>(ii)</enum>
              <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a description of how the programs described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="STEM Gateways Act/s:3/ss:c/p:2/sp:A/cl:i" proposed="true">clause (i)</cato:entity-ref> will support the success of women and girls, underrepresented minorities, and individuals from all economic backgrounds (including economically disadvantaged individuals and individuals living in economically distressed areas) in STEM education, such as—</text>
              <subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H93E1EED15506457DB9C26C0BA9ADBB0C">
                <enum>(I)</enum>
                <text>recruiting such individuals to participate in the programs; <italic/>
                </text>
              </subclause>
              <subclause commented="no" id="H4D8DD0E6A9874D8FA655C7AD3228169A">
                <enum>(II)</enum>
                <text>supporting educators who will lead the programs, and participants in the programs;</text>
              </subclause>
              <subclause id="H089376077C4A40A5A10A53B16B689D96">
                <enum>(III)</enum>
                <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">encouraging partnerships between in-school and out-of-school educators, such as afterschool providers, science centers, and museums;</text>
              </subclause>
              <subclause commented="no" id="HBF0662FAC0404A1594852105854BFC1E">
                <enum>(IV)</enum>
                <text>identifying public and private partners that are able to support the programs; and</text>
              </subclause>
              <subclause id="HBB32C864D2BC406490A801B78EE331F0">
                <enum>(V)</enum>
                <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">planning for sustaining the programs financially beyond the grant period; and</text>
              </subclause>
            </clause>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H9E8DFE42304D43C191BFFE93FD720705">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>in the case of an eligible entity that plans to use the grant funds at the secondary school level—</text>
            <clause id="HC1CD99A0EC6942AA92F2E10CA9C5437E">
              <enum>(i)</enum>
              <text>a description of the programs the eligible entity will carry out to achieve one or more of the goals described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="STEM Gateways Act/s:3/ss:a/p:1..5" proposed="true">paragraphs (1) through (5) of subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref> at the secondary school level, including the content of the programs and research and models used to design the programs;</text>
            </clause>
            <clause id="HE78768EB34F24A0DBFA815E86D825536">
              <enum>(ii)</enum>
              <text>a description of how the programs described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="STEM Gateways Act/s:3/ss:c/p:2/sp:B/cl:i" proposed="true">clause (i)</cato:entity-ref> will support the success of women and girls, underrepresented minorities, and individuals from all economic backgrounds (including economically disadvantaged individuals and individuals living in economically distressed areas) in STEM education and workforce training that prepares such individuals to take advantage of employment opportunities in STEM fields, such as—</text>
              <subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H047ED6A6E5674FBB8C55A076A47EB323">
                <enum>(I)</enum>
                <text>recruiting such individuals to participate in the programs; <italic/>
                </text>
              </subclause>
              <subclause commented="no" id="HFDDDF36397CD4BD681B3AA7A0F6A379D">
                <enum>(II)</enum>
                <text>supporting educators who will lead such programs, and participants in the programs;</text>
              </subclause>
              <subclause commented="no" id="H2E86F709C41A4E59BED94CE7BBBFF180">
                <enum>(III)</enum>
                <text>identifying public and private partners that are able to support the programs;</text>
              </subclause>
              <subclause id="H5A9D65AAB5524E0C8C594FF884389644">
                <enum>(IV)</enum>
                <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">partnering with institutions of higher education or institutions providing informal science education, such as afterschool programs and science centers and museums;</text>
              </subclause>
              <subclause id="H874C87DDD5A54D6D8E4AA3BCC4FD7465">
                <enum>(V)</enum>
                <text>partnering with institutions of higher education; and</text>
              </subclause>
              <subclause id="H689B41990E184227B52E1D2831342784">
                <enum>(VI)</enum>
                <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">planning for sustaining the programs financially beyond the grant period;</text>
              </subclause>
            </clause>
            <clause id="HA728BC92E82F4BCFB43A071D52617E65">
              <enum>(iii)</enum>
              <text>a review of the industry and business workforce needs, including the demand for workers with knowledge or training in a STEM field; and</text>
            </clause>
            <clause id="H6CF2D97B79D2428DB54CD99C7B34625C">
              <enum>(iv)</enum>
              <text>an analysis of job openings that require knowledge or training in a STEM field.</text>
            </clause>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="H2F9A7FB041E14687B327F4973EA46850">
        <enum>(d)</enum>
        <header>Use of funds</header>
        <paragraph id="H7E96D2584303404889408824E0980A99">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>Required use of funds</header>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An eligible entity that receives a grant under this section shall use such grant funds to carry out programs to achieve one or more of the goals described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="STEM Gateways Act/s:3/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref> at the elementary school or secondary school levels, with respect to women and girls, underrepresented minorities, and students from all economic backgrounds (including economically disadvantaged individuals, and students living in economically distressed areas).</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H789068C5337E4DC1A34F0DEF14424AEF">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Authorized use of funds</header>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The programs described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="STEM Gateways Act/s:3/ss:d/p:1" proposed="true">
              <internal-xref idref="H7E96D2584303404889408824E0980A99" legis-path="4.(d)(1)">paragraph (1)</internal-xref>
            </cato:entity-ref> may include any of the following activities, with respect to the individuals described in <internal-xref idref="H7E96D2584303404889408824E0980A99" legis-path="4.(d)(1)">
              <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="STEM Gateways Act/s:3/ss:d/p:1" proposed="true">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref>
            </internal-xref>:</text>
          <subparagraph commented="no" id="H304BAE3E1A044B56BC476FCFF92490C5">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>Carrying out the activities described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="STEM Gateways Act/s:3/ss:d/p:2/sp:A/cl:ii" proposed="true">subparagraph (A)(ii)</cato:entity-ref> or <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="STEM Gateways Act/s:3/ss:d/p:2/sp:B/cl:ii" proposed="true">(B)(ii)</cato:entity-ref>, as appropriate.</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="HBF57384C219D481F9AFC4EE8716EBCBF">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Providing professional development for teachers, afterschool providers, and other school personnel in elementary schools or secondary schools, including professional development to encourage, through academic instruction and support, such individuals to pursue advanced classes and careers in STEM fields.</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="HD6586B33DA714347A0D6EE42D005B3FA">
            <enum>(C)</enum>
            <text>Providing tutoring and mentoring programs in STEM fields.</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H306BDF2AEC5C4186BB389167080625CD">
            <enum>(D)</enum>
            <text>Establishing partnerships with institutions of higher education, potential employers, and other industry stakeholders that expose such individuals to professionals in STEM fields, or providing opportunities for postsecondary academic credits or credentials.</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H98977635A3F343C9A19041CAAA5BF55B">
            <enum>(E)</enum>
            <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Providing after-school activities and other informal learning opportunities designed to encourage interest and develop skills in STEM fields.</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="HD9DC6480ADF3425FBBCF961E6C382B42">
            <enum>(F)</enum>
            <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Providing summer programs to extend learning time and to deepen the skills and interest in STEM fields of such individuals.</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H341164D8EB684C62AB8E0B41719AE14F">
            <enum>(G)</enum>
            <text>Purchasing and utilizing—</text>
            <clause id="HECB5AEA59DB845C08F7087CE940989D9">
              <enum>(i)</enum>
              <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">educational or instructional materials that are designed to improve educational outcomes in STEM fields, and will serve to deepen the skills and interest in STEM fields of such individuals; or</text>
            </clause>
            <clause id="H69E49896B4A749AC8D5B427C24C49B16">
              <enum>(ii)</enum>
              <text>equipment, instrumentation, or hardware used to teach and encourage interest in STEM fields.</text>
            </clause>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph commented="no" id="HC3260751C8F34955B4B289B732975957">
            <enum>(H)</enum>
            <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Internships or opportunities for experiential learning in STEM fields.</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="HCC0832D71C994431BAD78078465A8D03">
        <enum>(e)</enum>
        <header>Report</header>
        <paragraph id="HD5512006ED314EAA9CD4C8613DDC9C87">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>Eligible entities</header>
          <text>Each eligible entity receiving a grant under this Act shall, on an annual basis, submit a report to the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="9100">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> on the use of funds and the number of students who participated in the programs carried out with the grant funds.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HE79E5393057B47608CED4F6630A96A36">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Secretary</header>
          <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="9100">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall, on an annual basis, and using the reports received under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="STEM Gateways Act/s:3/ss:e/p:1" proposed="true">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref>, report to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> on the overall impact and effectiveness of the grant program under this Act.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
    </section>
    <section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC632B286D350479E947F4D6BB08703A2" section-type="subsequent-section">
      <enum>4.</enum>
      <header>Definitions</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text>
      <paragraph id="HB2D3A8300D5A459385D4AE3A484BA427">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <header>ESEA definitions</header>
        <text>The terms <term>educational service agency</term>, <term>local educational agency</term>, <term>institution of higher education</term>, <term>Secretary</term>, and <term>State</term> have the meanings given the terms in <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965/s:9101">section 9101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7801">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/20/7801">20 U.S.C. 7801</cato:entity-ref>
          </external-xref>)</cato:entity>.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H26D23783ECD54DB0984B2CEC85A3EC77">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <header>Community college</header>
        <text>The term <term>community college</term> has the meaning given the term <term>junior or community college</term> in <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Higher Education Act of 1965/s:312">section 312 of the Higher Education Act of 1965</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1058">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/20/1058">20 U.S.C. 1058</cato:entity-ref>
          </external-xref>)</cato:entity>.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H58DA8644B7824FF29E7A005D8B91F6D1">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <header>Economically disadvantaged individual</header>
        <text>The term <term>economically disadvantaged individual</term> has the meaning given the term in <external-xref legal-doc="regulation" parsable-cite="cfr/34/400.4">section 400.4</external-xref> of title 34, Code of Federal Regulations, as such section is in effect on the date of enactment of this Act.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HCE53D6B323BA4B5185405FEC81BA0D20">
        <enum>(4)</enum>
        <header>Economically distressed area</header>
        <text>The term <term>economically distressed area</term> means a county or equivalent division of local government of a State in which, according to the most recently available data from the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1323">Bureau of the Census</cato:entity-ref>, 40 percent or more of the residents have an annual income that is at or below the poverty level.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H72FA4DA9A54843BEB6EB34EA7627F8DA">
        <enum>(5)</enum>
        <header>Eligible entity</header>
        <text>The term <term>eligible entity</term> means—</text>
        <subparagraph id="H8BE7CB7B305D4ED1B3AEA05F35F477F2">
          <enum>(A)</enum>
          <text>a local educational agency;</text>
        </subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="HE0EF09C063D24E1D9F1CE6503BA1C1B4">
          <enum>(B)</enum>
          <text>an educational service agency serving more than 1 local educational agency;</text>
        </subparagraph>
        <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0459DBE293E543AD847A76DA0AA6A57A">
          <enum>(C)</enum>
          <text>a consortium of local educational agencies;</text>
        </subparagraph>
        <subparagraph commented="no" id="H6428F65B27D34C1DA09EF6B298EBFB0A">
          <enum>(D)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">nonprofit organizations that—</text>
          <clause commented="no" id="H320BF56552EE430DB2133F71D52ABF83">
            <enum>(i)</enum>
            <text>work with elementary schools, secondary schools, or institutions of higher education; and</text>
          </clause>
          <clause commented="no" id="H3926A8E7E2C445ECB2C927CA1357C081">
            <enum>(ii)</enum>
            <text>have demonstrated a commitment to achieving the goals described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="STEM Gateways Act/s:3/ss:a/p:1..4" proposed="true">paragraphs (1) through (4) of section 3(a)</cato:entity-ref>; or</text>
          </clause>
        </subparagraph>
        <subparagraph commented="no" id="HBBF8B1FDA1654A569051B01474850417">
          <enum>(E)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">community colleges working in partnership with secondary schools to create opportunities for dual enrollment, credit transfer, or accelerated post-secondary credentialing.</text>
        </subparagraph>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H30B8CA4022DA49AB95815F322C60D476">
        <enum>(6)</enum>
        <header>Partners</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>partners</term> means organizations who employ workers in STEM-related careers or organizations with demonstrated expertise in identifying, scaling, and implementing successful practices in STEM education and workforce development.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H44F120CD8623457781F550B7ACBFBE5C">
        <enum>(7)</enum>
        <header>STEM</header>
        <text>The term <term>STEM</term> means science, technology, engineering, and mathematics.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2DBE6F9D76974B3DA755C60D498F96E5">
        <enum>(8)</enum>
        <header>Underrepresented minority</header>
        <text>The term <term>underrepresented minority</term> has the meaning given the term <term>minority</term> in <external-xref legal-doc="regulation" parsable-cite="cfr/34/637.4">section 637.4(b)</external-xref> of title 34, Code of Federal Regulations, as such section is in effect on the date of enactment of this Act.</text>
      </paragraph>
    </section>
  </legis-body>
</bill>
</doc>