<doc>
  <docmeta id="113hres395ih">
    <bill congress="113" type="hres" number="395" version="ih"/>
    <revision size="3972" annotations="0" status="complete" id="3" commit-time="2013-11-13T18:05:06Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113hres395ih/3.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <resolution xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" dms-id="H35851EB9EA37404D80B7AD69EA4CAF85" key="H" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print">
  <metadata>
<dublinCore>
<dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">113 HRES 395 IH: Recognizing Birmingham, Alabama, as home to the first and longest-running celebration of Veterans Day and home of the National Veteran Award.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">2013-10-30</dc:date>
<dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code>
    <congress display="yes">113th CONGRESS</congress>
    <session display="yes">1st Session</session>
    <legis-num>H. RES. 395</legis-num>
    <current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
    <action display="yes">
      <action-date date="20131030">October 30, 2013</action-date>
      <action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="B000013">Mr. Bachus</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S001185">Ms. Sewell of Alabama</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans’ Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Armed Services</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
    </action>
    <legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
    <official-title display="yes">Recognizing Birmingham, Alabama, as home to the first and longest-running celebration of Veterans Day and home of the National Veteran Award.</official-title>
  </form>
  <preamble>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas November 11, 2013, is the 66th anniversary of National Veterans Day in Birmingham, Alabama;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas National Veterans Day in Birmingham is the longest-running celebration of Veterans Day in the United States;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas on November 11, 1946, World War II veteran Raymond Weeks presented General Eisenhower a program design proposing <term>National Veterans Day 1947</term> to honor veterans of all wars fought by the United States, replacing Armistice Day;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the first celebration was held in Birmingham by the National Veterans Day organization in 1947 and included a World Peace Dinner keynoted by General Omar Bradley, a memorial service, and a parade, among other events;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas President Eisenhower signed into law on June 1, 1954, the Act proclaiming November 11 as Veterans Day (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/83/380">
          <cato:entity-ref entity-type="public-law" value="public-law/83/380">Public Law 83–380</cato:entity-ref>
        </external-xref>);</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas in 1954, the National Veterans Day organization, started by Raymond Weeks, expanded to include an annual presentation of the National Veteran Award in Birmingham;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the 60th National Veteran Award in 2013 honors the Tuskegee Airmen, heroes of flight in World War II;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the National Veteran Award reception and banquet, memorial service, World Peace Luncheon, and parade have been held every year since 1954;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the briefing for President Reagan by Elizabeth Dole for the Presidential Citizens Medals cited Raymond Weeks as the <term>Father of Veterans Day</term>;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas President Reagan recognized Raymond Weeks as the <term>driving force</term> behind Veterans Day while presenting Mr. Weeks the Presidential Citizens Medal on November 11, 1982, at the White House;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas Raymond Weeks should be remembered for his 40 years of loyal service to create a national commemoration to honor the great men and women who have served the United States; and</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas Birmingham, Alabama, should be recognized for its contributions to the institution of National Veterans Day, the National Veteran Award, and the World Peace Luncheon: Now, therefore, be it</text>
    </whereas>
  </preamble>
  <resolution-body id="HE14E412E4919443CA57AD58F34F6820A" style="traditional">
    <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HA5340B3AD86B49749A8A2275864FD064" section-type="undesignated-section">
      <enum/>
      <text>That the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0050">House of Representatives</cato:entity-ref>—</text>
      <paragraph id="HDC8061012DCE4EE9A4BD86E3A38ECCE8">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text>recognizes Birmingham, Alabama, as home to the first and longest-running national celebration of Veterans Day;</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H5498F52E33774A3B9980985A4F872A21">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text>recognizes Raymond Weeks for his 40 years of patriotic and pioneering efforts establishing Veterans Day and the National Veteran Award;</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HCC1C1D6C0CF04F8390DF998A9DAE41B3">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <text>congratulates the Tuskegee Airmen for receiving the National Veteran Award;</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HC51DEB2B63C54C8EB8A0B66CE997D5D0">
        <enum>(4)</enum>
        <text>honors the veterans of the United States and their families for providing freedom of life and liberty; and</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H4223549C467F4924A3F46210F0FE9FF1">
        <enum>(5)</enum>
        <text>pays tribute to the men and women of the United States in uniform who risk life and limb at home and overseas.</text>
      </paragraph>
    </section>
  </resolution-body>
</resolution>
</doc>