<doc>
  <docmeta id="113hres493ih">
    <bill congress="113" type="hres" number="493" version="ih"/>
    <revision size="4589" annotations="0" status="complete" id="3" commit-time="2014-03-19T17:21:24Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113hres493ih/3.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <resolution xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" dms-id="H1432DECC7DC648C9938CA2B9D53C1EC4" key="H" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print">
	<metadata>
<dublinCore>
<dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">113 HRES 493 IH: Expressing support for the designation of February 28, 2014, as “Rare Disease Day”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">2014-02-27</dc:date>
<dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">113th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session display="yes">2d Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. RES. 493</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20140227">February 27, 2014</action-date>
			<action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson of Indiana</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="C001038">Mr. Crowley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000567">Mr. Lance</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C000380">Mrs. Christensen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000096">Mr. Pascrell</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001157">Mr. McCaul</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>
      </action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">Expressing support for the designation of February 28, 2014, as <quote>Rare Disease Day</quote>.</official-title>
	</form>
	<preamble>
		<whereas>
      <text>Whereas rare diseases and disorders are those which affect small patient populations, typically
			 populations smaller than 200,000 individuals in the United States;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas nearly 7,000 rare diseases affect nearly 30,000,000 people in the United States and their
			 families;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas over half of all rare diseases affect children;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas many rare diseases are serious, life-threatening, and lack an effective treatment;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas one-third of treatments approved by the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7524">Food and Drug Administration</cato:entity-ref> in 2013 were orphan
			 products intended to treat rare diseases;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas rare diseases and conditions cross the medical spectrum and include a broad range of
			 diseases such as epidermolysis bullosa, progeria, sickle cell anemia,
			 Tay-Sachs, cystic fibrosis, most childhood cancers, and fibrodysplasia
			 ossificans progressiva;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas people with rare diseases experience challenges that include difficulty in obtaining an
			 accurate diagnosis, limited treatment options, and difficulty finding
			 physicians or treatment centers with expertise in their disease;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the rare disease community made great strides in 2013, including passing the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="National Pediatric Research Network Act">National
			 Pediatric Research Network Act</cato:entity-ref> which sets up a network housed within the
			 <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7529">NIH</cato:entity-ref> that facilitates greater collaboration amongst research into pediatric
			 diseases;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas challenges to reimbursement for life-altering and often life-saving treatments still exist,
			 such as in reimbursement for medical foods that treat rare metabolic
			 disorders;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas great strides have been made in research and treatment for rare diseases as a result of the
			 <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Orphan Drug Act">Orphan Drug Act</cato:entity-ref> and amendments made by that Act;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7524">Food and Drug Administration</cato:entity-ref> has taken great strides in involving the patient in the
			 drug review process as part of its Patient-Focused Drug Development
			 program, an initiative that originated in the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Food and Drug Administration Safety and Innovation Act">Food and Drug Administration
			 Safety and Innovation Act</cato:entity-ref>;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas both the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7524">Food and Drug Administration</cato:entity-ref> and the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7529">National Institutes of Health</cato:entity-ref> have
			 established special offices to advocate for rare disease research and
			 treatments;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the National Organization for Rare Disorders, an organization established in 1983 to
			 provide services to, and advocate on behalf of, patients with rare
			 diseases, was a primary force behind the enactment of the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Orphan Drug Act">Orphan Drug Act</cato:entity-ref>
			 and remains a critical public voice for people with rare diseases;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas 2013 marked the 30th anniversary of the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Orphan Drug Act">Orphan Drug Act</cato:entity-ref> and the National Organization for
			 Rare Disorders;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the National Organization for Rare Disorders sponsors <quote>Rare Disease Day</quote> in the United States to increase public awareness of rare diseases;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas <quote>Rare Disease Day</quote> is a global event occurring annually on the last day of February;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas <quote>Rare Disease Day</quote> was observed in the United States for the first time on February 28, 2009; and</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas <quote>Rare Disease Day</quote> is anticipated to continue to be observed globally in years to come, providing hope and
			 information for rare disease patients around the world: Now, therefore, be
			 it</text>
    </whereas>
  </preamble>
	<resolution-body id="H2CB76F1205474157A7E3166F127BB752" style="traditional">
		<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H269326A9091F4939BED91710C7B262B4" section-type="undesignated-section">
      <enum/>
      <text>That the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0050">House of Representatives</cato:entity-ref>—</text>
			<paragraph id="HB96DE3C3071A4BBEBD0403F51DE3C71C">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">supports the designation of <quote>Rare Disease Day</quote>;</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H8C6748AF308447C2A09433BAE035AFE9">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text>recognizes the importance of improving awareness and encouraging accurate and early diagnosis of
			 rare diseases and disorders; and</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H8E543CCAF6184D2D91814098BB09424A">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <text>supports a national and global commitment to improving access to, and developing new treatments,
			 diagnostics, and cures for, rare diseases and disorders.</text>
			</paragraph>
    </section>
  </resolution-body>
</resolution>
</doc>