<doc>
  <docmeta id="113hr3972ih">
    <bill congress="113" type="hr" number="3972" version="ih"/>
    <revision size="14941" annotations="0" status="complete" id="4" commit-time="2014-02-07T21:09:07Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113hr3972ih/4.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H29049A2019CB4887B7D54813987FE6C2" public-private="public">
  <metadata>
<dublinCore>
<dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">113 HR 3972 IH: Fair Employment Opportunity Act of 2014</dc:title>
<dc:publisher xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">2014-01-29</dc:date>
<dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
    <congress>113th CONGRESS</congress>
    <session>2d Session</session>
    <legis-num>H. R. 3972</legis-num>
    <current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
    <action>
      <action-date date="20140129">January 29, 2014</action-date>
      <action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="D000216">Ms. DeLauro</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and the Workforce</committee-name>
      </action-desc>
    </action>
    <legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
    <official-title>To prohibit discrimination in employment on the basis of an individual’s status or history of unemployment.</official-title>
  </form>
  <legis-body id="HB453F1A2348F4F119DB4D6B5645BAB2A" style="OLC">
    <section id="HEC94DDF30618422C9EE25FCB01480E01" section-type="section-one">
      <enum>1.</enum>
      <header>Short title</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote>
          <short-title>
            <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Fair Employment Opportunity Act of 2014" proposed="true">Fair Employment Opportunity Act of 2014</cato:entity-ref>
          </short-title>
        </quote>.</text>
    </section>
    <section id="H8E9D52BBC4874492B3DB6F6FEA71F768">
      <enum>2.</enum>
      <header>Findings and purpose</header>
      <subsection id="HB145CBC845B54F1A8FF8119EBDA8C507">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Findings</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">
          <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> finds that denial of employment opportunities to individuals because they are or have been unemployed is discriminatory and burdens commerce by—</text>
        <paragraph id="HC738EE01274E46EC8F0F63CA455EDFB2">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>reducing personal consumption and undermining economic stability and growth;</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H714F7AEAEECC41A29FB208A42410FEEF">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>squandering human capital essential to the Nation’s economic vibrancy and growth;</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H9568129D539B4F8ABE69DAA96B4F03E8">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <text>increasing demands for State and Federal unemployment insurance benefits, reducing trust fund assets, and leading to higher payroll taxes for employers, cuts in benefits for jobless workers, or both;</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H79AF62E5D66E453B8D0ED333CC8165CC">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
          <text>imposing additional burdens on publicly funded health and welfare programs; and</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H15C73FB4222D4DE8A4C1CE7176A7B4E1">
          <enum>(5)</enum>
          <text>depressing income, property, and other tax revenues that States, localities and the Federal Government rely on to support operations and institutions essential to commerce.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="H4EE6F3A4F3384D299A9ADF81BC04752A">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Purpose</header>
        <text>The purpose of this Act is to prohibit consideration of an individual’s status as unemployed in screening for or filling positions except where a requirement related to employment status is a bona fide occupational qualification reasonably necessary to successful performance in the job and to eliminate the burdens imposed on commerce by excluding such individuals from employment.</text>
      </subsection>
    </section>
    <section id="H27B56308FD6644D08433E43377D5C01A">
      <enum>3.</enum>
      <header>Definitions</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">As used in this Act—</text>
      <paragraph id="H74E4869C14F549A188CF9AE9DC8A46A8">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text>the term <term>employer</term> means any person engaged in commerce or any industry or activity affecting commerce who has 15 or more employees for each working day in each of 20 or more calendar weeks in the current or preceding calendar year, and includes—</text>
        <subparagraph id="H31C3CEA563EC485C94E8F244489C3197">
          <enum>(A)</enum>
          <text>any person who acts, directly or indirectly, in the interest of an employer with respect to employing individuals to work for the employer; and</text>
        </subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="HDB084864679F409A87D27FA009CB12BD">
          <enum>(B)</enum>
          <text>any successor in interest of an employer;</text>
        </subparagraph>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H1B3320A68E954AEAB193891C58FE059D">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <term>employment agency</term> means any person regularly undertaking with or without compensation to procure employees for an employer or to procure for individuals opportunities to work for an employer and includes an agent of such a person, and includes any person who maintains an Internet website that publishes advertisements or announcements of job openings;</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H0B7BBD0D3AD04FF4850F53E9E73607E6">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <term>affected individual</term> means any person who was refused consideration for employment or was not hired by an employer because of the person’s current employment status, or any person who was not considered, screened, or referred for employment opportunities by an employment agency because of the person’s current employment status;</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph commented="no" id="HEF3A747E6B2847D68542E3C25996B5F5">
        <enum>(4)</enum>
        <text>the term <term>status as unemployed</term> means an individual’s present or past unemployment regardless of the length of time such individual was unemployed; and</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H224DD9E974EC48EDBAFAD21D0AB73BBD">
        <enum>(5)</enum>
        <text>the term <term>Secretary</term> means the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1600">Secretary of Labor</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
      </paragraph>
    </section>
    <section id="HDE8048DB87434D0E949B426525BFAAD2">
      <enum>4.</enum>
      <header>Prohibited acts</header>
      <subsection id="HBA8314D3DDCB4DCBB667212CE9725434">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Employers</header>
        <text>It shall be an unlawful practice for an employer to—</text>
        <paragraph id="H65D548CA7D534F6C89CC2433CA093D7C">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>refuse to consider for employment or refuse to offer employment to an individual because of the individual’s status as unemployed;</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HDEFD865D7E46463E8C4A9FD7E2C12FA3">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>publish in print, on the Internet, or in any other medium, an advertisement or announcement for any job that includes—</text>
          <subparagraph id="HD5EC8484FEE5462387448F88E1702604">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any provision stating or indicating that an individual’s status as unemployed disqualifies the individual for a job; and</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="HAC6A9E1495AC4BA6987516E8A196406D">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any provision stating or indicating that an employer will not consider an applicant for employment based on that individual’s status as unemployed; and</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H65E4ED1DC95F40CBBE446778F4986AD7">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">direct or request that an employment agency take an individual’s status as unemployed into account in screening or referring applicants for employment.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="H493131F4DF2646B3AD5C0BEE853238FD">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Employment agencies</header>
        <text>It shall be an unlawful practice for an employment agency to—</text>
        <paragraph id="HE6D77FE496084E2AA0284379F3CBF5B7">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">refuse to consider or refer an individual for employment based on the individual’s status as unemployed;</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H64668C9BBB164D298F961B06674B1B85">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">limit, segregate, or classify individuals in any manner that may limit their access to information about jobs or referral for consideration of jobs because of their status as unemployed; or</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HF70CA701A91B4137823D67A8722D7C6B">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <text>publish, in print or on the Internet or in any other medium, an advertisement or announcement for any job vacancy that includes—</text>
          <subparagraph id="HE6A4ECB3FD764CF9983893F4760D0A4B">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any provision stating or indicating that an individual’s status as unemployed disqualifies the individual for a job; and</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="HB8B10D6A8C7A4DE8A9C037E8B806E42D">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any provision stating or indicating that an employer will not consider individuals for employment based on that individual’s status as unemployed.</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="H62512F784218460A8656E901E8A55769">
        <enum>(c)</enum>
        <header>Interference with rights, proceedings or inquiries</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It shall be unlawful for any employer or employment agency to—</text>
        <paragraph id="HE3B223034D694D73A41A8C0C846DCC12">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>interfere with, restrain, or deny the exercise of or the attempt to exercise, any right provided under this Act; or</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HD8B410E6ED7E4F2D8DC363ACA9675A85">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">refuse to hire, to discharge, or in any other manner to discriminate against any individual because such individual—</text>
          <subparagraph id="H1D68F015EC6D4461BB2AF4177E7AEF15">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>opposed any practice made unlawful by this Act;</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="HDB773EBDF55A4F3B970AC3593AEE688F">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>has filed any charge, or has instituted or caused to be instituted any proceeding, under or related to this Act;</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="HF44F946E42F341D99ABA3D15AD7EDD5F">
            <enum>(C)</enum>
            <text>has given, or is about to give, any information in connection with any inquiry or proceeding relating to any right provided under this Act; or</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H7D5F98C6DB4F474EA66599FB4A3983EA">
            <enum>(D)</enum>
            <text>has testified, or is about to testify, in any inquiry or proceeding relating to any right provided under this Act.</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="H7AB4A35F36A542819E3AED8FD9E9C294">
        <enum>(d)</enum>
        <header>Bona fide occupational qualification</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of this Act, consideration by an employer or employment agency of an individual’s status as unemployed shall not be an unlawful employment practice where an individual’s employment in a similar or related job for a period of time reasonably proximate to the hiring of such individual is a bona fide occupational qualification reasonably necessary to successful performance of the job that is being filled.</text>
      </subsection>
    </section>
    <section id="HBA53F403F02E46CC8BE845576554FADF">
      <enum>5.</enum>
      <header>Enforcement</header>
      <subsection id="H63071066F2124F13904903FA92C926C3">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Civil action by individual</header>
        <paragraph id="HDB0DF7A2D77E47599BDF45CB10F4B7D9">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>Liability for employers and employment agencies</header>
          <text>Any employer or employment agency that violates <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Fair Employment Opportunity Act of 2014/s:4/ss:a" proposed="true">sections 4(a)</cato:entity-ref> and <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Fair Employment Opportunity Act of 2014/s:4/ss:b" proposed="true">(b)</cato:entity-ref> shall be liable to any affected individual—</text>
          <subparagraph id="H1FDAAE5D86864DDCA7C42BC784CD5155">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>for actual damages equal to—</text>
            <clause id="H3FB9DFC91DD04B968526F13FB7A90240">
              <enum>(i)</enum>
              <text>the amount of—</text>
              <subclause id="HF59D0598B3894C34ABE7F96888901454">
                <enum>(I)</enum>
                <text>any wages, salary, employment benefits, or other compensation denied or lost to such individual by reason of the violation; or</text>
              </subclause>
              <subclause id="HF1EA1344F69C4469B8260F1B584CC476">
                <enum>(II)</enum>
                <text>in a case in which wages, salary, employment benefits, or other compensation have not been denied or lost to the individual, any actual monetary losses sustained by the individual as a direct result of the violation or a civil penalty of $1,000 per violation per day, whichever is greater;</text>
              </subclause>
            </clause>
            <clause id="H8480074EB0A948D1A681058BD1E14427">
              <enum>(ii)</enum>
              <text>the interest on the amount described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Fair Employment Opportunity Act of 2014/s:5/ss:a/p:1/sp:A/cl:i" proposed="true">clause (i)</cato:entity-ref> calculated at the prevailing rate; and</text>
            </clause>
            <clause id="HB182196E85CB4740ADDC923E8FC06D0E">
              <enum>(iii)</enum>
              <text>an additional amount as liquidated damages equal to the sum of the amount described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Fair Employment Opportunity Act of 2014/s:5/ss:a/p:1/sp:A/cl:i" proposed="true">clause (i)</cato:entity-ref> and the interest described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Fair Employment Opportunity Act of 2014/s:5/ss:a/p:1/sp:A/cl:ii" proposed="true">clause (ii)</cato:entity-ref>, except that if an employer or employment agency that has violated <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Fair Employment Opportunity Act of 2014/s:4" proposed="true">section 4</cato:entity-ref> proves to the satisfaction of the court that the act or omission that violated <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Fair Employment Opportunity Act of 2014/s:4" proposed="true">section 4</cato:entity-ref> was in good faith and that the employer had reasonable grounds for believing that the act or omission was not a violation of <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Fair Employment Opportunity Act of 2014/s:4" proposed="true">section 4</cato:entity-ref>, such court may, in its discretion, reduce the amount of the liability to the amount and interest determined under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Fair Employment Opportunity Act of 2014/s:5/ss:a/p:1/sp:A/cl:i" proposed="true">clauses (i)</cato:entity-ref> and <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Fair Employment Opportunity Act of 2014/s:5/ss:a/p:1/sp:A/cl:ii" proposed="true">(ii)</cato:entity-ref>, respectively; and</text>
            </clause>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="HC1F45CAFE568412F855BE8132F5A4570">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>for such equitable relief as may be appropriate, including employment and compensatory and punitive damages.</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H82EC7F0A3D9A4F668D9241F345C2C78E">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Right of action</header>
          <text>An action to recover the damages or equitable relief prescribed in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Fair Employment Opportunity Act of 2014/s:5/ss:a/p:1" proposed="true">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref> of this subsection may be maintained against any employer or employment agency in any Federal or State court of competent jurisdiction by any one or more persons for and in behalf of—</text>
          <subparagraph id="H56E99646401D4362828B5A302B340DC3">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>the affected individual; or</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H41F1CC1A16384163A072FDC6A9CC6E9C">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>the affected individual and other individuals similarly situated.</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HF35F24B9A6514029B3D3301C4E19CE36">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <header>Fees and costs</header>
          <text>The court in such an action shall, in addition to any judgment awarded to the plaintiff, allow a reasonable attorney’s fee, reasonable expert witness fees, and other costs of the action to be paid by the defendant.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HE671250E1F8446C6A9992BA861A4FD1A">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
          <header>Limitations</header>
          <text>The right provided by <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Fair Employment Opportunity Act of 2014/s:5/ss:a/p:2" proposed="true">paragraph (2)</cato:entity-ref> of this subsection to bring an action by or on behalf of any affected individual shall terminate—</text>
          <subparagraph id="H166F2BC0179443CF90DDB0A05A15F6B8">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>on the filing of a complaint by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1600">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> in an action under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Fair Employment Opportunity Act of 2014/s:5/ss:d" proposed="true">subsection (d)</cato:entity-ref> in which restraint is sought of any violation of <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Fair Employment Opportunity Act of 2014/s:4" proposed="true">section 4</cato:entity-ref>; or</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H6438B9BE70014B198DCCA2152345A7FA">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>on the filing of a complaint by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1600">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> in an action under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Fair Employment Opportunity Act of 2014/s:5/ss:b" proposed="true">subsection (b)</cato:entity-ref> in which a recovery is sought of the damages described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Fair Employment Opportunity Act of 2014/s:5/ss:a/p:1/sp:A" proposed="true">paragraph (1)(A)</cato:entity-ref> owing to an affected individual by an employer or employment agency liable under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Fair Employment Opportunity Act of 2014/s:5/ss:a/p:1" proposed="true">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref>, unless the action described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Fair Employment Opportunity Act of 2014/s:5/ss:a/p:3/sp:A" proposed="true">subparagraph (A)</cato:entity-ref> or <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Fair Employment Opportunity Act of 2014/s:5/ss:a/p:3/sp:B" proposed="true">(B)</cato:entity-ref> is dismissed without prejudice on motion of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1600">Secretary</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="HD6AF0DD953F049CD8FA022F10A217200">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Action by the Secretary</header>
        <paragraph id="HFAB4E13E0A674566ACE67855B5E789B2">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>Administrative action</header>
          <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1600">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall receive, investigate, and attempt to resolve complaints of violations of <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Fair Employment Opportunity Act of 2014/s:4" proposed="true">section 4</cato:entity-ref> in the same manner that the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1600">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> receives, investigates, and attempts to resolve complaints of violations of <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938/s:6">sections 6</cato:entity-ref> and <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938/s:7">7 of the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938</cato:entity-ref> (<cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc/29/206">29 U.S.C. 206</cato:entity-ref> and <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc/29/207">207</cato:entity-ref>).</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HB9A11CC2E8B347838E4738A3293B933D">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Civil action</header>
          <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1600">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> may bring an action in any court of competent jurisdiction—</text>
          <subparagraph id="H073B7D4029C1463998346E7AD43DDEBA">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>to enjoin violations of this title and seek other relief going forward necessary to prevent future violations; and</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H531CBD0FB2A2419485CD42D43F6DA0C6">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>to recover—</text>
            <clause id="HE8EF5D74A2BA4FAEB765820C614E305C">
              <enum>(i)</enum>
              <text>the damages described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Fair Employment Opportunity Act of 2014/s:5/ss:a/p:1/sp:A" proposed="true">subsection (a)(1)(A)</cato:entity-ref>;</text>
            </clause>
            <clause id="H83018793B6A34C918CED92C7322B3BE6">
              <enum>(ii)</enum>
              <text>in the case of a violation of <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Fair Employment Opportunity Act of 2014/s:4/ss:c" proposed="true">section 4(c)</cato:entity-ref>, a civil penalty of not less than $250 per violation; or</text>
            </clause>
            <clause id="H94CC0926F830444B9448BD0A4AEB437A">
              <enum>(iii)</enum>
              <text>such other equitable relief the Court deems appropriate.</text>
            </clause>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H823B78B8843D4433B62F9549D4117453">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <header>Sums recovered</header>
          <text>Any sums recovered by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1600">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> pursuant to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Fair Employment Opportunity Act of 2014/s:5/ss:b/p:2/sp:A" proposed="true">paragraph (2)(A)</cato:entity-ref> shall be held in a special deposit account and shall be paid, on order of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1600">Secretary</cato:entity-ref>, directly to each affected individual. Any such sums recovered pursuant to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Fair Employment Opportunity Act of 2014/s:5/ss:b/p:2/sp:A" proposed="true">paragraph (2)(A)</cato:entity-ref> that are not paid to an affected individual because of inability to do so within a period of 3 years and any sums recovered pursuant to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Fair Employment Opportunity Act of 2014/s:5/ss:b/p:2/sp:B" proposed="true">paragraph (2)(B)</cato:entity-ref> shall be deposited into the Treasury of the United States as miscellaneous receipts.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="H6C866AE286674B54BC77EDEF83FD88EB">
        <enum>(c)</enum>
        <header>Limitation</header>
        <paragraph id="H087AC12C22F44DC991677C35C284C0A8">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>In general</header>
          <text>Except as provided in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Fair Employment Opportunity Act of 2014/s:5/ss:c/p:2" proposed="true">paragraph (2)</cato:entity-ref>, an action under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Fair Employment Opportunity Act of 2014/s:5/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref> may be brought not later than 2 years after the date of the last event constituting the alleged violation for which the action is brought, provided that the limitations for filing an action shall be tolled during the period that the Secretary is considering a complaint against any defendant named in a complaint filed with the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1600">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Fair Employment Opportunity Act of 2014/s:5/ss:b/p:1" proposed="true">subsection (b)(1)</cato:entity-ref> above.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HF5A1F9BF1E8D4B69AE55381D36CB6886">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Willful violation</header>
          <text>In the case of such action brought for a willful violation of <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Fair Employment Opportunity Act of 2014/s:4" proposed="true">section 4</cato:entity-ref>, such action may be brought within 3 years of the date of the last event constituting the alleged violation for which such action is brought, provided that the limitations for filing an action by an individual shall be tolled during the period that the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1600">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> is considering a complaint pursuant to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Fair Employment Opportunity Act of 2014/s:5/ss:b/p:1" proposed="true">subsection (b)(1)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H6752C4447CA041CC912CBAEB41F44E24">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <header>Commencement</header>
          <text>In determining when an action is commenced by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1600">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> under this section for the purposes of this subsection, it shall be considered to be commenced on the date when the Secretary files a complaint in a court of competent jurisdiction.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="H732DAFB11AAE40DEA850C4542E1C25C8">
        <enum>(d)</enum>
        <header>Action for injunction by Secretary</header>
        <text>The district courts of the United States shall have jurisdiction, for cause shown, in an action brought by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1600">Secretary</cato:entity-ref>—</text>
        <paragraph id="HF2E1A87C113C473CA4871A8FEF5A052C">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>to restrain violations of <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Fair Employment Opportunity Act of 2014/s:4" proposed="true">section 4</cato:entity-ref>; and</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H3F26E3EA2CA9407FA5B7C6CE7961B2EE">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>to award such other equitable relief as may be appropriate, including employment and monetary damages.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="H1948EBF64DFD497F94280C5A201D3ED3">
        <enum>(e)</enum>
        <header>Solicitor of Labor</header>
        <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1603">Solicitor of Labor</cato:entity-ref> may appear for and represent the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1600">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> on any litigation brought under this section.</text>
      </subsection>
    </section>
  </legis-body>
</bill>
</doc>