<doc>
  <docmeta id="113hr3983ih">
    <bill congress="113" type="hr" number="3983" version="ih"/>
    <revision size="23240" annotations="0" status="complete" id="6" commit-time="2014-02-06T14:56:07Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113hr3983ih/6.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H9B20027F0EBF4C0A8A051110D79EE4B6" public-private="public">
  <metadata>
<dublinCore>
<dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">113 HR 3983 IH: Total Learning Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">2014-02-03</dc:date>
<dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
    <congress>113th CONGRESS</congress>
    <session>2d Session</session>
    <legis-num>H. R. 3983</legis-num>
    <current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
    <action>
      <action-date date="20140203">February 3, 2014</action-date>
      <action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="H001047">Mr. Himes</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="E000293">Ms. Esty</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="L000557">Mr. Larson of Connecticut</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and the Workforce</committee-name>
      </action-desc>
    </action>
    <legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
    <official-title>To establish a competitive grant program assisting the development of innovative early learning curricula for low-income children.</official-title>
  </form>
  <legis-body id="H62A66E3226A945A1AEAE50BFFB3BCDBC" style="OLC">
    <section id="H2BED0B70952F4982A9BC5A8C882817D2" section-type="section-one">
      <enum>1.</enum>
      <header>Short title</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote>
          <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" proposed="true" value="Total Learning Act" entity-type="act">
            <short-title>Total Learning Act</short-title>
          </cato:entity-ref>
        </quote>.</text>
    </section>
    <section id="HA991663C9CFB4D38B04BE3C6E01F4FFC">
      <enum>2.</enum>
      <header>Findings</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> finds as follows:</text>
      <paragraph id="H695138574F4E405298A54E413CA064DA">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Research conducted by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1323">Census Bureau</cato:entity-ref> suggests that 21.8 percent of children under the age of 18 are living in poverty.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H4B2052DD6BCB49E2B02D34D793502F3C">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text>Research conducted by the Bureau of the Census of the Department of Commerce shows that socioeconomic status and family background characteristics are highly correlated with educational outcomes, with a concentration of low-performing schools in low-income and underserved communities.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HFCC39E308BF1494DB94A800F3F366A0C">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <text>As an example of an innovative early learning curriculum producing tangible results for low-income children, an independent evaluation of the Total Learning Curriculum developed by Action for Bridgeport Community Development, Inc., in cooperation with the Dr. Edward Zigler of the Yale Child Study Center and implemented in Bridgeport, Connecticut, has demonstrated that students who received all the elements of the Total Learning Curriculum made an average 2-point gain on the Diagnostic Reading Assessment (DRA) compared to an average 1.76-point gain on such assessment by those students who did not participate in the Total Learning Curriculum.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H9CC11D93EB46478BBF01C6EA652C3985">
        <enum>(4)</enum>
        <text>Such independent evaluation also showed that students who received all elements of Total Learning Curriculum have an average score of 22.35 points on the Concept of Print assessment, compared to an average score of 20.82 points on such assessment by those students who did not participate in the Total Learning Curriculum.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H06D9A51CDB9248C89C0FEF14EA8F39E1">
        <enum>(5)</enum>
        <text>According to the findings of such independent evaluation, children with low initial DRA scores, high-family risk levels, low parental involvement, have special needs, or who are English-language-learners or participate in extended-day programs, make significant DRA gains after receiving all the elements of the Total Learning Curriculum.</text>
      </paragraph>
    </section>
    <section id="H4326C9D3851C438FA075A340224BCC77">
      <enum>3.</enum>
      <header>Purpose</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the purpose of this Act to promote academic success for children living in poverty by—</text>
      <paragraph id="H75B5F19A99BB477E90E11D5C690543DF">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text>improving and promoting school readiness by enhancing the cognitive, social, and emotional development of children from birth;</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H5E38D476D122497B86115AE74D7F0B9A">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text>focusing such enhancements on low-income children who are at the greatest risk of negative educational outcomes; and</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H07A054B22AF242F1BC42708429C2223D">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <text>harnessing the most current developmentally appropriate educational methods to improve the public education system, including—</text>
        <subparagraph id="H14349289C8A74E3CBA315C6B2CA1CF30">
          <enum>(A)</enum>
          <text>educational interventions beginning as close to birth as possible;</text>
        </subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="H41A85F78320A4F52B5037508C37F245C">
          <enum>(B)</enum>
          <text>a child-initiated learning process with time for independent inquiry and play;</text>
        </subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="HBF7534984827447BBDA55B4CE41C4DEE">
          <enum>(C)</enum>
          <text>access to wraparound social services, including support for nutrition, housing, and family literacy;</text>
        </subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="HAAAB48417D644C8C9EC81BDC180D8FB3">
          <enum>(D)</enum>
          <text>professional development for instructional staff, including elementary school teachers, paraprofessionals, and pre-school teachers;</text>
        </subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="HD2644C2660FE411EA87BAD3E2B2307BB">
          <enum>(E)</enum>
          <text>an extended school day and school year;</text>
        </subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="HE79DEA667A394493A9FF4E65694A91E3">
          <enum>(F)</enum>
          <text>parent development, which includes providing parents with the knowledge and skills needed to be able to support a child’s growth and academic progress;</text>
        </subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="H0444D8415FC44A959E1EF95EB0FDCD29">
          <enum>(G)</enum>
          <text>child-to-staff ratios of at least 1 early childhood or elementary educator for every 7 children; and</text>
        </subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="H5BFAE135438F40E1A5B4DC6918FBE037">
          <enum>(H)</enum>
          <text>an enhanced transition from pre-kindergarten to elementary school, so that the cognitive and social gains of the pre-kindergarten program are sustained through the remainder of a child’s educational career.</text>
        </subparagraph>
      </paragraph>
    </section>
    <section id="H439380F956F74B2B92BB38D1833410A3">
      <enum>4.</enum>
      <header>Grant program to close the achievement gap</header>
      <subsection id="H3977C7F1E7564F9BBD06E503FB2D0432">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Grant program authorized</header>
        <text>From the amount appropriated under section 10, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="9100" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall award grants, on a competitive basis, to eligible partnerships to implement innovative early learning curricula in early childhood education programs and elementary schools in high-need communities for children from birth through age 9.</text>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="H17C66F35C86D485BBAFC32DFDE1923FA">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Grant period</header>
        <text>A grant under this section shall be awarded for a 5-year period and may be renewed for an additional 5-year period upon a showing of adequate progress, as determined by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="9100" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="H204A8F92C3AC445682BA457FF33F56E4">
        <enum>(c)</enum>
        <header>Application</header>
        <text>To be eligible to receive a grant under this section, an eligible partnership shall submit to the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="9100" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> a grant application at such time and in such manner as the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="9100" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall require, and containing the following information:</text>
        <paragraph id="HD27984107D604CD2985396FBF6380F12">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>A description of the high-need community to be served by the eligible partnership, including the number and percent of English-language learners that will be served and other demographic and socioeconomic information as the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="9100" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> may request.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HCA0B100F9282400A90E4704941103FFE">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>An assessment of the need for such a grant in the high-need community, including—</text>
          <subparagraph id="H638B5BE9F7B345E682664E6918869309">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>the number of low-income families; and</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="HB52893EB6C14485B977D08CE155287A8">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>the number of and percent of elementary school children performing below grade level for reading and math on State assessments described in <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
                <cato:entity-ref value="Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965/s:1111/ss:b/p:3" entity-type="act">section 1111(b)(3) of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/6311">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/20/6311/b/3">20 U.S.C. 6311(b)(3)</cato:entity-ref>
              </external-xref>)</cato:entity>.</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HD14AAAB539464C32AF363F7569007A92">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <text>A detailed description of a plan to carry out the implementation of the innovative early learning curriculum in the high-need community, including—</text>
          <subparagraph id="H098EB56C101B4B929D03586D440AA180">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>how children and families will be selected to participate, taking into account the need for continuity and stability for all participating children and families;</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H8411B03073684A9A9CB1089F9E4C06F9">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>how the implementation will coordinate and build on, and will not supplant or duplicate, professional development activities available to the staff of the innovative early learning curriculum in the high-need community;</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H0B1EAD6DFA2244898B3173D871C93716">
            <enum>(C)</enum>
            <text>how the implementation will train instructional staff in the innovative early learning curriculum to provide developmentally appropriate school-readiness services that are based on the best available child development and education research;</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H661C4312349342E586A9C04E2D88031D">
            <enum>(D)</enum>
            <text>how the implementation will train instructional staff in the innovative early learning curriculum to meet the diverse educational needs of children in the high-need community, including children who have limited English proficiency, children with disabilities, or children with other special needs; and</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="HA3D75E17CE04495BBE253B1DC99F383B">
            <enum>(E)</enum>
            <text>how the implementation will train instructional staff in the innovative early learning curriculum to identify and prevent behavioral problems in children or working with children identified as or suspected to be victims of abuse.</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HF974A3FE71C64679A057C3530429BC50">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
          <text>A description of the plan for continuing the innovative early learning curriculum after the end of the grant period.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H14AA861D103B46A4AA476ACAC828F8E3">
          <enum>(5)</enum>
          <text>The proposed allocation and use of grant funds to implement the innovative early learning curriculum in the high-need community.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H06735AEFC93B47C7B2DF470F5E7398D0">
          <enum>(6)</enum>
          <text>A description of the roles and responsibilities of the eligible partnership in implementing the innovative early learning curriculum in the high-need community.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H2BDAC619481241A38BAA9397AA552293">
          <enum>(7)</enum>
          <text>An assurance, if applicable, that the eligible partnership will provide appropriate professional development to volunteers working directly with young children, as well as to paid staff.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="HE0ABE88CE2BE4A4DBBCD3BFA34D773FA">
        <enum>(d)</enum>
        <header>Use of grant funds</header>
        <paragraph id="HDEE97DB4171A412EAF85073E6C4E8D30">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>Required uses</header>
          <text>A grant awarded under this Act shall be used to cover costs associated with implementing the innovative early learning curriculum, including—</text>
          <subparagraph id="H78BCCC3E1E9D45DD8A28222B9D8056D6">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>costs for extended school hours and days;</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="HADE0498EEF194429BA12FF35A3A562BE">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>costs associated with professional development, staff compensation, and retention;</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="HFF4F12FBAF4F4072A7E227C3D42029AB">
            <enum>(C)</enum>
            <text>costs for all comprehensive child and family support services; and</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="HCA9158D913CF47DBBD84F18B31AD0DA6">
            <enum>(D)</enum>
            <text>for any other activities needed to fulfill the purpose of this Act, as the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="9100">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> deems appropriate.</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H836DD389D82C49BDA3DDCF5D58DC12E6">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Permissible uses</header>
          <text>Not more 5 percent of a grant awarded under this Act may be used to pay the administrative costs (including supplies, office and classroom space, supervision, mentoring, and transportation stipends as necessary and appropriate) related to the implementation of the innovative early learning curriculum.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="H7D518265E1FA406FB4684579261E1B83">
        <enum>(e)</enum>
        <header>Distribution of grants</header>
        <text>In awarding grants under this Act, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="9100" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall—</text>
        <paragraph id="HDCFA086C256D4D22A7FE5AED54766BE5">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>award the first 5 grants to eligible partnerships from 5 different States; and</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H7BEF2B88EAE54DB7B80A79B3FDE377C0">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>award not less than 1 grant to an applicant serving—</text>
          <subparagraph id="H09FA035F526D40F782C8E6FA279FCC77">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>a school operated by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1450" entity-type="federal-body">Bureau of Indian Affairs</cato:entity-ref>;</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="HF241C8FED9FC4C3B92A928CE64614107">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>a tribal educational agency; or</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="HA7BE52E3D8B64C039FC108FECC82357F">
            <enum>(C)</enum>
            <text>a high-need community located in a rural area.</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="HE08451EE5D0D41AC83FCFD304CDB7BF1">
        <enum>(f)</enum>
        <header>Priority</header>
        <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="9100" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall give priority to an eligible partnership that—</text>
        <paragraph id="HFE0FE750115C4B08B47A1AAAB6FCDC42">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>proposes to use the grant funds to carry out the innovative early learning curriculum in areas served by local educational agencies with a higher percentage of students from low-income families and English-language learners not meeting the proficient level of achievement on State assessments described in <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
              <cato:entity-ref value="Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965/s:1111/ss:b/p:3" entity-type="act">section 1111(b)(3) of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/6311">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/20/6311/b/3">20 U.S.C. 6311(b)(3)</cato:entity-ref>
            </external-xref>)</cato:entity> in comparison to other grant applicants; and</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H628D65C358E84A8EB9886946C11C0686">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>demonstrates the availability of local infrastructure in the high-need community to be served by such eligible partnership to implement the innovative early learning curriculum, including the availability of—</text>
          <subparagraph id="H8954E674F7EF417F9A64129B68C1CC9A">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>public elementary schools serving a high percentage of students from low-income families; and</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="HF504A94E04F6485A9FA6C5E9C07997A0">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>public or non-profit social service providers, including providers of health-related services or early childhood education services.</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="H9BFDF3EDF7054C5883A5F9E949A5396B">
        <enum>(g)</enum>
        <header>Reporting requirements</header>
        <text>Each eligible partnership that receives a grant under this section shall submit an annual report to the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="9100" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> on the progress of implementing the innovative early learning curriculum. Such report shall include a description of—</text>
        <paragraph id="H6D91E39865DB40FF9AFEA4532BAD8DDE">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>the actual service delivery provided through grant funds, including characteristics of the participating students (including descriptive information on the population of children and families served), and how the innovative early learning curriculum was implemented;</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H887430087DBB438486C0834D9BD9FC9A">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>an estimate of the annual implementation costs of the program;</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HFD9777ED6E4D42FFB36B60DC4A9086F8">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <text>outcomes that are consistent with the purpose of the grant program, including—</text>
          <subparagraph id="HCC41507B47554C51A46CAD6E3FECC3F7">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>improvements in student achievement;</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="HFDDE411E44954454B799161103E825EF">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>improvements in language skills of children from birth to 3 years of age;</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H3E8A804D493244A5A0428822E19D6AE5">
            <enum>(C)</enum>
            <text>improvements in social-emotional outcomes for children at the greatest risk of needing behavioral or psychological intervention; and</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="HBB70710C3233493399C9D98B694B1F21">
            <enum>(D)</enum>
            <text>improvements in health for children, including nutrition and access to stable high-quality health services;</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H5CFCFCE264E945E8BEB8B95A01AE207F">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
          <text>the types of instruction, materials, and activities being funded under the grant program; and</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HA9A1A22EEB8D4E1A9E828C61C4CE75E0">
          <enum>(5)</enum>
          <text>the effectiveness of any training and ongoing professional development provided—</text>
          <subparagraph id="HA738B91615194B73AB20710E19EB0E65">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>to the faculty, administration, and staff of early childhood and elementary educators within the eligible partnership receiving a grant under this Act; and</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H3475C7D79405487081627E8E2D3AD848">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>to the broader community of providers of social, emotional, behavioral, and related support to students participating in the program and to those who train such providers.</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="H175DEC01279842E394C11B406127628F">
        <enum>(h)</enum>
        <header>Evaluations</header>
        <paragraph id="H7615AB426C0448DC82EAFC2AC3CA1F0A">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>Interim evaluations</header>
          <text>From the amount appropriated under section 10, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="9100" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> may conduct interim evaluations to determine whether each eligible partnership receiving a grant under this Act is making adequate progress as the Secretary considers appropriate. The contents of the annual report submitted to the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="9100" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" proposed="true" value="Total Learning Act/s:4/ss:g" entity-type="act">subsection (g)</cato:entity-ref> may be used by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="9100" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> to determine whether an eligible grantee receiving a grant is demonstrating adequate progress.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HEDB9BBF68DCD413F86083BBDD6221DCE">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Final evaluation</header>
          <text>Not later than 4 years, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="9100" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall report the results of a final evaluation of each innovative early learning curriculum being implemented by an eligible partnership receiving a grant under this Act to—</text>
          <subparagraph id="H1D85E1A9925F431898CA826B3FCC6B81">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>determine the effectiveness of such innovative early learning curriculum; and</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H55FCDDC82C8D41C095E9200C00EF7B3D">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>compare the relative effectiveness of each of the various activities described by <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" proposed="true" value="Total Learning Act/s:4/ss:d/p:1" entity-type="act">subsection (d)(1)</cato:entity-ref> for which grant funds are used.</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H4BFA40EBD5294BF2B3280DE85D3ADDC4">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <header>Report</header>
          <text>Not sooner than 5 years, and not later than 6 years, after the date of enactment of this Act, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="9100" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall submit to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> a report containing the findings of the evaluation conducted under 
              <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" value="Total Learning Act/s:4/ss:h/p:2" entity-type="act" proposed="true">paragraph (2)</cato:entity-ref>
            , and such recommendations as the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="9100">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> considers appropriate.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
    </section>
    <section id="H3A6A7A07A28448D9890DA04B04592D8D">
      <enum>5.</enum>
      <header>Training program authorized</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">From the amount appropriated under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" proposed="true" value="Total Learning Act/s:10" entity-type="act">section 10</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="9100" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall award funds to a public or private nonprofit organization with demonstrated expertise in an innovative early learning curriculum demonstrating the principles outlined in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" proposed="true" value="Total Learning Act/s:3" entity-type="act">section 3</cato:entity-ref>, for the purpose of training, and providing technical assistance to, eligible partnerships on implementing the innovative early learning curriculum.</text>
    </section>
    <section id="HB9D0AEF6081C402A9AF1180926C7439C">
      <enum>6.</enum>
      <header>Supplement not supplant</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Funds made available under this Act shall be used to supplement, not supplant, Federal, State, or local funds that, in the absence of such availability, would have been expended for the activities described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" proposed="true" value="Total Learning Act/s:4/ss:d" entity-type="act">section 4(d)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
    </section>
    <section id="HA9A5941948DA4E1594C6CF4E2A6C4441">
      <enum>7.</enum>
      <header>Future designation study</header>
      <subsection id="H50F05CA2656A46DB8B0A111696D892EF">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>In general</header>
        <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="9100" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall provide information about the grant program under this Act to potential grant applicants that may be eligible to receive a grant under this Act based on the latest available data on—</text>
        <paragraph id="HDFB624EB44054488AD034392E1CE17F9">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>the number of residents under the age of 18 in an area served by a local educational agency;</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H847C42199C214092BB8185D289C57302">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>the percentage of residents with an income below the poverty line in an area served by a local educational agency;</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H1C6BCAA6D5334FE59108174BF1F2009F">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <text>the percentage of residents age 18 or older with high school diplomas in an area served by a local educational agency;</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HD1F8E47691D546CB91C57C26CB9298DC">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
          <text>the percentage of students identified as eligible for special education services in an area served by a local educational agency;</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H1A92B25AAA584204820F352FA852EC4E">
          <enum>(5)</enum>
          <text>the youth crime rate in an area served by a local educational agency; and</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HB92B5676DEF84051836D9B97668BD4DD">
          <enum>(6)</enum>
          <text>such other criteria as the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="9100">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> considers appropriate.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="HB95075A2891F4DEB9FBBB3E0807FD6AA">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Report</header>
        <text>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="9100">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall submit to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> a list of high-need communities that, pursuant to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" proposed="true" value="Total Learning Act/s:7/ss:a" entity-type="act">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref>, received information about the grant program under this Act.</text>
      </subsection>
    </section>
    <section id="H1F405FE807CF4B4F9529EC8185DFCE6A">
      <enum>8.</enum>
      <header>Rule of construction</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this Act shall be construed to abrogate or alter any valid and existing collective bargaining agreement.</text>
    </section>
    <section id="HCAC2DC6C55624558BC464E4B35C6A914">
      <enum>9.</enum>
      <header>Definitions</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">For purposes of this Act:</text>
      <paragraph id="H1CBF42784C0E47CD9109745924FCB364">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <header>In general</header>
        <text>The terms <term>State educational agency</term>, <term>local educational agency</term>, <term>highly qualified</term>, and <term>poverty line</term> have the meanings given such terms in <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
            <cato:entity-ref value="Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965/s:9101" entity-type="act">section 9101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7801">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/20/7801">20 U.S.C. 7801</cato:entity-ref>
          </external-xref>)</cato:entity>.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H09E74C4BDB174E6799891746E48D89E6">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <header>Eligible partnership</header>
        <text>The term <term>eligible partnership</term> means—</text>
        <subparagraph id="HED2F959E1C9D4330B070C19052237308">
          <enum>(A)</enum>
          <text>a full-service community school; or</text>
        </subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="HEE6140984F3B4F99877393413BC74CFA">
          <enum>(B)</enum>
          <text>a partnership between a local educational agency and one of the following:</text>
          <clause id="H31FAF772A5D64D2A834794A0B1A7E855">
            <enum>(i)</enum>
            <text>A public or non-profit social service provider, including a provider of health-related services or early childhood education services.</text>
          </clause>
          <clause id="HA5F1EB25EAF0439A81D712AF2E2EDA7D">
            <enum>(ii)</enum>
            <text>A full-service community school.</text>
          </clause>
        </subparagraph>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H3217A81E2EB645EDB48929410CA605EA">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <header>Extended school day</header>
        <text>The term <term>extended school day</term> means a school day for children from birth to age 9 of not less than 9 hours, except in the case where an eligible partnership cannot accommodate a 9-hour day.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HB1B99C4825614AC8BD76945C92468F7C">
        <enum>(4)</enum>
        <header>Extended school year</header>
        <text>The term <term>extended school year</term> means a school year for children from birth to age 9 of not less than 220 calendar days, except in the case where an eligible partnership cannot accommodate a 220-calendar-day school year.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H87456B1732164E59ADC758AB18F39B35">
        <enum>(5)</enum>
        <header>Full-service community school</header>
        <text>The term <term>full-service community school</term> means a public school which coordinates educational, developmental, family, health, and other comprehensive services through community-based organizations and public and private partnerships, and provides access to such services to students enrolled in such school, families of such students, and the community where such school is located.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HD4646D489D5F4EE797D15FF5D0C03338">
        <enum>(6)</enum>
        <header>High-need community</header>
        <subparagraph id="H0E51ED67B07F451C83AAB3CF6C98C066">
          <enum>(A)</enum>
          <header>In general</header>
          <text>The term <term>high-need community</term> means—</text>
          <clause id="HCF5F7E18EB9A45C38E2432380419396E">
            <enum>(i)</enum>
            <text>a political subdivision of a State, or a portion of a political subdivision of a State, in which at least 50 percent of the children are from low-income families; or</text>
          </clause>
          <clause id="H9A7A701D4B334743B84C46351FEA9727">
            <enum>(ii)</enum>
            <text>a political subdivision of a State that is among the top 10 percent of political subdivisions of a State having the greatest numbers of such children.</text>
          </clause>
        </subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="HEC165DA596F84B84A2D5CB6878009226">
          <enum>(B)</enum>
          <header>Determination</header>
          <text>In determining which communities qualify as a high-need community under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Total Learning Act/s:9/p:6/sp:A" proposed="true">subparagraph (A)</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="9100">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall use such data as the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="9100">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> determines are most accurate and appropriate.</text>
        </subparagraph>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HA5FC770CE7924B2AB0B1EACD9B6655C4">
        <enum>(7)</enum>
        <header>Low-income family</header>
        <text>The term <term>low-income family</term> means a family with an income below the poverty line for the most recent fiscal year for which satisfactory data are available.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HFFAC0B24BBA04E4C8DA44A3FF9A1609F">
        <enum>(8)</enum>
        <header>Secretary</header>
        <text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Education.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H06458A214B2E4E8CBE7557B4BBDDE556">
        <enum>(9)</enum>
        <header>innovative early learning curriculum</header>
        <text>The term <term>innovative early learning curriculum</term> means a comprehensive model of early childhood education, including the following principles as articulated by Dr. Edward Zigler of the Yale Child Study Center, which incorporate—</text>
        <subparagraph id="H52F9A4893C3C4C2086CF35CBAC728FA3">
          <enum>(A)</enum>
          <text>educational interventions beginning as close to birth as possible;</text>
        </subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="H704F730C76374DE59CFA41E174760082">
          <enum>(B)</enum>
          <text>a child-initiated learning process with time for independent inquiry and play;</text>
        </subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="H92769932D7804C29B3A8A88522D78601">
          <enum>(C)</enum>
          <text>access to wraparound social services, including support for nutrition, housing, and family literacy;</text>
        </subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="H2D2BEC0F9BA44F499D55ABF7D1C30F64">
          <enum>(D)</enum>
          <text>professional development for instructional staff, including elementary school teachers, paraprofessionals, and pre-school teachers;</text>
        </subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="H06645BB5259A47678AD72FDD0A4B65EC">
          <enum>(E)</enum>
          <text>an extended school day and school year;</text>
        </subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="HEB55412DE4B943B592928C5D794E3BD7">
          <enum>(F)</enum>
          <text>parent development, which includes providing parents with the knowledge and skills needed to be able to support a child’s growth and academic progress;</text>
        </subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="H7744EA3A9E4A4D5C92C4D41AD71CED4E">
          <enum>(G)</enum>
          <text>child-to-staff ratios of at least 1 early childhood or elementary educator for every 7 children; and</text>
        </subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="H325205BCBAE343EA8F2963A644FEEFB4">
          <enum>(H)</enum>
          <text>an enhanced transition from pre-kindergarten to elementary school, so that the cognitive and social gains of the pre-kindergarten program are sustained through the remainder of a child’s educational career.</text>
        </subparagraph>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H188B84E7CCCC48CFB1EA79A5975AEADD">
        <enum>(10)</enum>
        <header>Wraparound social services</header>
        <text>The term <term>wraparound social services</term> means comprehensive health and social services provided to a child and the child’s family to supplement the child’s educational needs.</text>
      </paragraph>
    </section>
    <section id="HDC4D821E3B65465A8E5F45F37086E6F6">
      <enum>10.</enum>
      <header>Authorization of appropriations</header>
      <subsection id="H8153EDB02CB14C81B5D32FB54F0C4380">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>In general</header>
        <text>
          <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="auth-auth-approp">There is authorized to be appropriated <cato:property name="purpose">to carry out <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Total Learning Act" proposed="true">this Act</cato:entity-ref>
            </cato:property> <cato:funds-and-year amount="50000000" year="2015, 2016, 2017, 2018, 2019, 2020, 2021">$50,000,000 for each of the fiscal years 2015 to 2021</cato:funds-and-year>
          </cato:entity>.</text>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="H034EA4EE2FCD42BE81EFD3DB4E38DAFC">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Reservations</header>
        <text>Of the amount appropriated under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" value="Total Learning Act/s:10/ss:b/p:1" entity-type="act" proposed="true">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref> each fiscal year, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="9100" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall reserve—</text>
        <paragraph id="HDB400303D6944DCA91ECC2AD4C3862FA">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>not more than 3 percent for evaluations under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" proposed="true" value="Total Learning Act/s:4/ss:h" entity-type="act">section 4(h)</cato:entity-ref>;</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H47028B04757049C596A0EC01DE2E54C1">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>between 2 percent and 5 percent for the training program under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" proposed="true" value="Total Learning Act/s:5" entity-type="act">section 5</cato:entity-ref>; and</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H744697D85A2E4DC695E83CA5CDB3D1F7">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <text>not more than 3 percent to carry out the study in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" proposed="true" value="Total Learning Act/s:7" entity-type="act">section 7</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
    </section>
  </legis-body>
</bill>
</doc>