<doc>
  <docmeta id="113hr4116ih">
    <bill congress="113" type="hr" number="4116" version="ih"/>
    <revision size="1717" annotations="0" status="complete" id="3" commit-time="2014-03-06T15:16:49Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113hr4116ih/3.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HECE69AF06ABD4E15BF85F0FBCFC87728" public-private="public">
	<metadata>
<dublinCore>
<dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">113 HR 4116 IH: To direct the Librarian of Congress to obtain a stained glass panel depicting the seal of the District of Columbia and install the panel among the stained glass panels depicting the seals of States which overlook the Main Reading Room of the Library of Congress Thomas Jefferson Building.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">2014-02-27</dc:date>
<dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>113th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>2d Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 4116</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20140227">February 27, 2014</action-date>
			<action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHA00">Committee on House Administration</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To direct the Librarian of Congress to obtain a stained glass panel depicting the seal of the
			 District of Columbia and install the panel among the stained glass panels
			 depicting the seals of States which overlook the Main Reading Room of the
			 Library of Congress Thomas Jefferson Building.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H1EC50BC988D74AEDB1D08C6B57E209FA" style="OLC">
		<section id="HBE93DCF39C9A4285A8CBFD7BC27163E2" section-type="section-one">
      <enum>1.</enum>
      <header>Including stained glass panel depicting seal of District of Columbia in Library of Congress Thomas
			 Jefferson Building</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0300">Librarian of Congress</cato:entity-ref> shall obtain a stained glass panel depicting the seal of the District of
			 Columbia and install the panel among the panels depicting the seals of
			 States which overlook the Main Reading Room of the Library of Congress
			 Thomas Jefferson Building.</text>
		</section>
  </legis-body>
</bill>
</doc>