<doc>
  <docmeta id="113hr644ih">
    <bill congress="113" type="hr" number="644" version="ih"/>
    <revision size="16849" annotations="0" id="7" commit-time="2013-04-17T23:28:18+00:00" committer="favila" doc="113hr644ih/7.xml" status="complete">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HCF5148EF5AF946B3AAF46A180CF8AD60" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<form> 
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>113th CONGRESS</congress>
<session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. R. 644</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20130213">February 13, 2013</action-date> 
<action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="C001083">Mr. Carney</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="A000210">Mr. Andrews</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001090">Mr. Cartwright</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000604">Mr. Dent</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000451">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000564">Mr. Gibson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001032">Mr. Holt</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000554">Mr. LoBiondo</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001181">Mr. Meehan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000594">Mr. Runyan</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S001162">Ms. Schwartz</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To direct the Secretary of the Interior to establish a program to build on and help coordinate funding for restoration and protection efforts of the 4-State Delaware River Basin region, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H0E4031B5E190416CA0535D5CB9C9DB11" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HE8C1ED4CC99244AA890CE73E2C616FAF" section-type="section-one">
      <enum>1.</enum>
      <header>Short title</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote>
          <short-title>Delaware River Basin Conservation Act of 2013</short-title>
        </quote>.</text> </section> 
<section id="H1C5B630710E94C278467F3777263A9C5">
      <enum>2.</enum>
      <header>Findings</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">
        <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> finds that—</text> 
<paragraph id="H740A724AB8424986B7D1E3D327590F2A">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text>the Delaware River Basin is a national treasure of great cultural, environmental, and ecological importance;</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9C70168C80384B388CB5354FB895AC44">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text>the Basin contains over 12,500 square miles of land in the States of Delaware, New Jersey, New York, and Pennsylvania, including nearly 800 square miles of bay and more than 2,000 tributary rivers and streams;</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDD45ACB634794F198497CC7177341744">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Basin is home to more than 8,000,000 people who depend on the Delaware River and the Delaware Bay as an economic engine, a place of recreation, and a vital habitat for fish and wildlife;</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H61E79303366843C585FDE2FE1F21FAD1">
        <enum>(4)</enum>
        <text>the Basin provides clean drinking water to more than 15,000,000 people, including New York City, which relies on the Basin for approximately half of the drinking water supply of the city, and Philadelphia, whose most significant threat to the drinking water supply of the city is forest clearing in the Upper Basin, according to a study conducted by the Philadelphia Water Department;</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3B62D512232B44FFA61232CE5DE898B9">
        <enum>(5)</enum>
        <text>almost 180 species of fish and wildlife are considered special status species in the Basin due to habitat loss and degradation, particularly sturgeon, eastern oyster, and red knots, which have been identified as unique species in need of habitat improvement;</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB48CC91416A3442794B50DEDB4E2E361">
        <enum>(6)</enum>
        <text>the Basin provides habitat for over 200 resident and migrant fish species, includes significant recreational fisheries, and is a prolific source of eastern oyster, blue crab, and the largest population of the American horseshoe crab;</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4CDA2CA896E6474794D9BB156B0BF11C">
        <enum>(7)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the annual value of commercial Eastern oyster landings for the Delaware Estuary is $3,700,000 per year in 2010 dollars, making it the fourth-most lucrative fishery in the Delaware River Basin watershed, and oyster populations are rebounding despite many years of below-average biological recruitment due, in part, to pollution and disease;</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5ACC1E8FE013447CA0CC197FE5908685">
        <enum>(8)</enum>
        <text>the Delaware Bay has the second largest concentration of shorebirds in North America and is designated as 1 of the 4 most important shorebird migration sites in the world;</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA6B68F0589BC4920A1FAA74EC6EDD820">
        <enum>(9)</enum>
        <text>the Basin, 50 percent of which is forested, also has 1,000,000 acres of wetland, more than 126,000 acres of which are recognized as internationally important, resulting in a landscape that provides essential ecosystem services, including recreation, commercial, and water quality benefits;</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA3E907E3731A423691D0D508603CCD9F">
        <enum>(10)</enum>
        <text>much of the remaining exemplary natural landscape in the Basin is vulnerable to further degradation, as the Basin gains approximately 14 square miles of developed land annually, and with new development, urban watersheds are increasingly covered by impervious surfaces, amplifying the quantity of polluted runoff into rivers and streams;</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1CE0C7EB2D9D49A2B23518D97EF3ADBB">
        <enum>(11)</enum>
        <text>the Delaware River is the longest undammed river east of the Mississippi, and a critical component of the National Wild and Scenic Rivers System in the Northeast;</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8668ED6B2AC44E03B6F1E207F494F44B">
        <enum>(12)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">management of water volume in the Basin is critical to flood mitigation and habitat for fish and wildlife, and following 3 major floods along the Delaware River since 2004, the Governors of the States of Delaware, New Jersey, New York, and Pennsylvania have called for natural flood damage reduction measures to combat the problem, including restoring the function of riparian corridors;</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H86FC6FD5790243C6AD7421356917B337">
        <enum>(13)</enum>
        <text>the Delaware River Port Complex (including docking facilities in the States of Delaware, New Jersey, and Pennsylvania) is one of the largest freshwater port in the world, the Port of Philadelphia handles the largest volume of international tonnage and 70 percent of the oil shipped to the East Coast, and the Port of Wilmington, a full-service deepwater port and marine terminal, is the busiest terminal on the Delaware River, handling more than 400 vessels per year with an annual import/export cargo tonnage of more than 4,000,000 tons;</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF8BEDD0DA1604415BB4407B1F1835035">
        <enum>(14)</enum>
        <text>the Delaware Estuary, where freshwater from the Delaware River mixes with saltwater from the Atlantic Ocean, is 1 of the largest and most complex of the 28 estuaries in the National Estuary Program, and the Partnership for the Delaware Estuary works to improve the environmental health of the Delaware Estuary;</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3A454D8CAC204D47B2A374B995333673">
        <enum>(15)</enum>
        <text>the Delaware River Basin Commission is a Federal-interstate compact government agency charged with overseeing a unified approach to managing the river system and implementing important water resources management projects and activities throughout the Basin that are in the national interest; </text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H77B664EE07A546F09876F6C85173B303">
        <enum>(16)</enum>
        <text>restoration activities in the Basin are supported through several Federal and State agency programs, and funding for those important programs should continue and complement the establishment of the Delaware River Basin Restoration Program, which is intended to build on and help coordinate restoration and protection funding mechanisms at the Federal, State, regional, and local levels; and</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0D3061E901AD40D9B8CB9338950EEE4A">
        <enum>(17)</enum>
        <text>the existing and ongoing voluntary conservation efforts in the Delaware River Basin necessitate improved efficiency and cost-effectiveness, as well as increased private-sector investments and coordination of Federal and non-Federal resources.</text> </paragraph>
    </section> 
<section id="H9EE97384AC43427AA788AF28962945DA">
      <enum>3.</enum>
      <header>Definitions</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> 
<paragraph id="HA57CF8DD82004AC08EB2875FC40C51F8">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <header>Basin</header>
        <text>The term <term>Basin</term> means the 4–State Delaware Basin region, including all of Delaware Bay and portions of the States of Delaware, New Jersey, New York, and Pennsylvania located in the Delaware River watershed.</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4A0E80A87EE74F8C8179D9FBEC94870F">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <header>Basin State</header>
        <text>The term <term>Basin State</term> means each of the States of Delaware, New Jersey, New York, and Pennsylvania.</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBD3A82FE6A344D6B8EC7A866B78A6997">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <header>Director</header>
        <text>The term <term>Director</term> means the Director of the United States Fish and Wildlife Service.</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0E27AA1F18684CECB494A64CF6FFF51C">
        <enum>(4)</enum>
        <header>Foundation</header>
        <text>The term <term>Foundation</term> means the National Fish and Wildlife Foundation, a congressionally chartered foundation established by <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="National Fish and Wildlife Foundation Establishment Act/s:2">section 2 of the National Fish and Wildlife Foundation Establishment Act</cato:entity-ref> (<cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/16/3701">16 U.S.C. 3701</cato:entity-ref>)</cato:entity>.</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HAF52CFE42EF34C6DBCF116F117798591">
        <enum>(5)</enum>
        <header>Grant program</header>
        <text>The term <term>grant program</term> means the Delaware River Basin restoration grant program established under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Delaware River Basin Conservation Act of 2013/s:5" proposed="true">section 5</cato:entity-ref>.</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE5BBE29F0DAB442A8450C789A6D148C5">
        <enum>(6)</enum>
        <header>Program</header>
        <text>The term <term>program</term> means the Delaware River Basin restoration program established under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Delaware River Basin Conservation Act of 2013/s:4" proposed="true">section 4</cato:entity-ref>.</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6F1043053BF3423AB4EAB56B8586FD58">
        <enum>(7)</enum>
        <header>Restoration and protection</header>
        <text>The term <term>restoration and protection</term> means the conservation, protection, and enhancement of fish and wildlife, as well as the habitats of fish and wildlife.</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H790ED55DBE844BC4B1D9221E095873C1">
        <enum>(8)</enum>
        <header>Secretary</header>
        <text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Director.</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBF78702650484A619F8E704EC89EC29E">
        <enum>(9)</enum>
        <header>Service</header>
        <text>The term <term>Service</term> means the United States Fish and Wildlife Service.</text> </paragraph>
    </section> 
<section id="HC4A1993D983B4CDF8AB259F090A2066C">
      <enum>4.</enum>
      <header>Program establishment</header> 
<subsection id="H78A3046B5F654C4A9456775E382F2FBF">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Establishment</header>
        <text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1400">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall establish a program to be known as the <quote>Delaware River Basin restoration program</quote>.</text> </subsection> 
<subsection id="H9C844732BD6D4817A5219AE9CD2893CA">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Duties</header>
        <text>In carrying out the program, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1400">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall—</text> 
<paragraph id="HDEE2DEFBDE28498FB3543BC623FAFF5B">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>draw on existing and new management plans for the Basin, or portions of the Basin, and work in consultation with applicable management entities, including representatives of the Partnership for the Delaware Estuary, the Delaware River Basin Commission, the Federal Government, and other State and local governments, and regional and nonprofit organizations, as appropriate, to identify, prioritize, and implement restoration and protection activities within the Basin;</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB66BF6453F354B32ADA3FF8F098E1212">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">adopt a basin-wide strategy that—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H06239FC4E6654C1E9646882B8CD4C93C">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">supports the implementation of a shared set of science-based restoration and protection activities developed in accordance with <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Delaware River Basin Conservation Act of 2013/s:4/ss:b/p:1" proposed="true">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref>;</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H8B6D9CDAB91E4A6483A7DF73396DCB14">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">targets cost-effective conservation projects; </text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H300BD0DF35014E32BEDB0ABAA08518D1">
            <enum>(C)</enum>
            <text>supports measurable conservation efforts; and</text>
          </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H7F9AC4F19DA94B93993AD8DD6F17655C">
            <enum>(D)</enum>
            <text>maximizes conservation outcomes with no net gain of Federal full-time equivalent employees;</text> </subparagraph>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H85651C2DBA7444A8B6A47C6E19B9D57A">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <text>establish the grant program in accordance with <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Delaware River Basin Conservation Act of 2013/s:5" proposed="true">section 5</cato:entity-ref>; and</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H858E87F6A3D84120B4C2CC98188864E1">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
          <text>provide for technical assistance in accordance with this Act.</text> </paragraph>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="HA361B771349A47BDADCD64F1891B4B77">
        <enum>(c)</enum>
        <header>Coordination</header>
        <text>In establishing the program, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1400">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall consult, as appropriate, with—</text> 
<paragraph id="HB91B500A8C0A40BC8C7436CD76201616">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the heads of Federal agencies, including—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HCD73BE40FD3E41AFA0E34400D8884786">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="6800">Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency</cato:entity-ref>;</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H7745FDB46F9E4D3C958B95C98C2A88CB">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1330">Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration</cato:entity-ref>;</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA4A179DB5576476AAA73255BD32A6A8C">
            <enum>(C)</enum>
            <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="12C3">Chief of the Natural Resource Conservation Service</cato:entity-ref>;</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H1E95E9713B1848A3B2B21E18FB058632">
            <enum>(D)</enum>
            <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="21CE">Chief of Engineers of the Corps of Engineers</cato:entity-ref>; and</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HFFDDB9C6E7974CE9BE9604F6B529FB96">
            <enum>(E)</enum>
            <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the head of any other applicable agency;</text> </subparagraph>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE429A01BD1AD48F5BDA18A559BC8F456">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Governors of the Basin States;</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4112F31230F942AC942F534BA3105EFB">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <text>the Partnership for the Delaware Estuary;</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF7985E34B84743B887C1ACE0418EAE43">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
          <text>the Delaware River Basin Commission;</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9B46FAEE376B447F99112EEF1640069E">
          <enum>(5)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">fish and wildlife joint venture partnerships; and</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6A7D8ABCC8F74B30BB61D8456186AB45">
          <enum>(6)</enum>
          <text>other public agencies and organizations with authority for the planning and implementation of conservation strategies in the Basin.</text> </paragraph>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="H38F988B6F4094E17A6547253A2D73FA7">
        <enum>(d)</enum>
        <header>Purposes</header>
        <text>The purposes of the program include—</text> 
<paragraph id="H4C55274C53804F1B89FE6F0B0BA8FF57">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>coordinating restoration and protection activities among Federal, State, local, and regional entities and conservation partners throughout the Basin;</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H518808621A6945DD97CF0E6EBBD677ED">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>carrying out coordinated restoration and protection activities throughout the Basin and Basin States—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H286E1B69A25542EF9871C1466AFA8117">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>to sustain and enhance fish and wildlife habitat restoration and protection activities;</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H29E7A2D2146F4947B3CC0BB8C320F4EC">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>to improve and maintain water quality to support fish and wildlife, as well as the habitats of fish and wildlife;</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6437DEC357A84D0F9F67C9279BE2F926">
            <enum>(C)</enum>
            <text>to sustain and enhance water management and flood damage mitigation improvements to benefit fish and wildlife habitat;</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H708003C1921D402CB532AA4D5AFB2DFF">
            <enum>(D)</enum>
            <text>to improve opportunities for public access and recreation in the Basin;</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H05913DA8CF6D4CF99FCF764A18226EC1">
            <enum>(E)</enum>
            <text>to encourage environmentally sensitive land use planning and development;</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB686769C4CBE4E5987933087C044AD4C">
            <enum>(F)</enum>
            <text>to increase the capacity to implement coordinated restoration and protection activities in the Basin by conducting public outreach and education and promoting citizen involvement; and</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H0C81B86B6A894D25BF62DD9A491CF8AD">
            <enum>(G)</enum>
            <text>to increase scientific capacity to support the planning, monitoring, and research activities necessary to carry out coordinated restoration and protection activities; and</text> </subparagraph>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9BFB483B249745728F8E1639FD2661C8">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <text>providing competitive grants for technical assistance to carry out restoration and protection activities in the Basin, with priority given to activities with multiple benefits, as described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Delaware River Basin Conservation Act of 2013/s:4/ss:d/p:2" proposed="true">paragraph (2)</cato:entity-ref>.</text> </paragraph>
      </subsection>
    </section> 
<section id="H27E324F6F6724E308F6AAF9BD5A9CBC5">
      <enum>5.</enum>
      <header>Grants and assistance</header> 
<subsection id="H90B45F774B744EEDA8E9B3A060F72202">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Delaware river basin restoration program</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To the extent that funds are available to carry out this section, the Secretary shall establish a grant program to be known as the <quote>Delaware River Basin restoration grant program</quote> to provide competitive matching grants of varying amounts to State and local governments, nonprofit organizations, community organizations, institutions of higher education, and other eligible entities to carry out activities described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Delaware River Basin Conservation Act of 2013/s:4/ss:d" proposed="true">section 4(d)</cato:entity-ref>.</text> </subsection> 
<subsection id="H46A289B600764924BB8029B97F72C3A1">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Criteria</header>
        <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1400">Secretary</cato:entity-ref>, in consultation with the organizations described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Delaware River Basin Conservation Act of 2013/s:4/ss:c" proposed="true">section 4(c)</cato:entity-ref>, shall develop criteria for the grant program to help ensure that activities funded under this section accomplish 1 or more of the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H2952CEB07CD74EECA51B2AB5F6707C72">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>Restoration or protection of fish and wildlife and the habitats of fish and wildlife.</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC357AB958C454FD6A0FDE7FC97F6572A">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>Improvement or protection of water quality by reducing pollutants and restoring headwater areas and drinking water basins.</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFDFFC15039EB4AF69773887E133C9C35">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Improvement of the management of water volume and mitigation of flood damage to support the ecological needs of fish and wildlife and the habitats of fish and wildlife.</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDA8C37A32E75494B9FB3257290F3ED9F">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
          <text>Inclusion of priority needs or actions identified in the basin-wide strategy adopted under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Delaware River Basin Conservation Act of 2013/s:4/ss:b/p:2" proposed="true">section 4(b)(2)</cato:entity-ref>.</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1349480836DD4CE7B55687C8CB88FD48">
          <enum>(5)</enum>
          <text>Inclusion of restoration and protection activities with multiple benefits in the Basin, including habitat, water quality, and flood damage mitigation.</text> </paragraph>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="H6A2774E740A54AF59520496BEC7E3D33">
        <enum>(c)</enum>
        <header>Cost sharing</header> 
<paragraph id="H93FAB7B207F14EAC8F2A532CE4FB753A">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>Federal share</header>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Federal share of the cost of a project funded under the grant program shall not exceed 50 percent of the total cost of the activity, as determined by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1400">Secretary</cato:entity-ref>.</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF389AF916F5B430B9D885020837FB6A9">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Non-Federal share</header>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The non-Federal share of the cost of a project funded under the grant program may be provided in cash or in the form of an in-kind contribution of services or materials.</text> </paragraph>
      </subsection> 
<subsection commented="no" id="H8417FC20A2954038B6C8E24AA3554911">
        <enum>(d)</enum>
        <header>Administration</header> 
<paragraph commented="no" id="HD45D489B27A34B93BEF3D9C90EDF3443">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>In general</header>
          <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1400">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> may enter into an agreement to manage the grant program with the National Fish and Wildlife Foundation or a similar organization that offers grant management services.</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" id="H2459FAF77A534639A075FA8ED891D58B">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Funding</header>
          <text>If the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1400">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> enters into an agreement under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Delaware River Basin Conservation Act of 2013/s:5/ss:d/p:1" proposed="true">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref>, the organization selected shall—</text> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H41A1611CAC2544D297A8A1C56B893D06">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>for each fiscal year, receive amounts to carry out this section in an advance payment of the entire amount on October 1, or as soon as practicable thereafter, of that fiscal year;</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="HE1C29D1A9432453584782AAD81E871E6">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>invest and reinvest those amounts for the benefit of the grant program; and</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H43F8E2CD40654CFCB22DC41D83C9596F">
            <enum>(C)</enum>
            <text>otherwise administer the grant program to support partnerships between the public and private sectors in accordance with this Act.</text> </subparagraph>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" id="H63C84FD6510244FABFD6275FB77721F7">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <header>Requirements</header>
          <text>If the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1400">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> enters into an agreement with the Foundation under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Delaware River Basin Conservation Act of 2013/s:5/ss:d/p:1" proposed="true">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref>, any amounts received by the Foundation under this section shall be subject to the <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="National Fish and Wildlife Foundation Establishment Act">National Fish and Wildlife Foundation Establishment Act</cato:entity-ref> (<cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/16/3701/etseq">16 U.S.C. 3701 et seq.</cato:entity-ref>)</cato:entity>, excluding <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="National Fish and Wildlife Foundation Establishment Act/s:10/ss:a">section 10(a) of that Act</cato:entity-ref> (<cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/16/3709/a">16 U.S.C. 3709(a)</cato:entity-ref>)</cato:entity>.</text> </paragraph>
      </subsection> 
<subsection commented="no" id="H4E96786F39614B6EACB83CAD8BE95907">
        <enum>(e)</enum>
        <header>Technical assistance</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1400">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> may provide, or provide for, technical assistance to carry out this section, on a nonreimbursable basis, to—</text> 
<paragraph commented="no" id="HE9586C41BAC54FB88F4E61EB18FB8BD5">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">other Federal agencies;</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" id="H94E8FCE104884584BA81293A4E2BAFF0">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">State and local governments;</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" id="H4EFFE03E917E4856AABECF934C70F1CE">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">nonprofit organizations;</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" id="H0410E307B66848BD9C2CC5763A89F037">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">community organizations;</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" id="H0097E98C1FA64537A638D74E8A9EDAD2">
          <enum>(5)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">institutions of higher education; or</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" id="H9B80172E60E14ECEBC79DDB1084290F5">
          <enum>(6)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">other entities, as the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1400">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> determines to be appropriate.</text> </paragraph>
      </subsection>
    </section> 
<section commented="no" id="H00A492FD5E384816A788333024A8E8BE">
      <enum>6.</enum>
      <header>Annual reports</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act and annually thereafter, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1400">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall submit to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> a report on the implementation of this Act, including a description of each project that has received funding under this Act.</text>
    </section> 
<section id="HF965BA03E25844358AC235BA5D19994B">
      <enum>7.</enum>
      <header>Authorization of Appropriations</header> 
<subsection id="HD5AC5B264CD446CCB127F17895847929">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>In general</header>
        <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1448">United States Fish and Wildlife Service</cato:entity-ref> shall use funds within its existing budgetary authority to carry out this Act.</text> </subsection> 
<subsection id="H491EE5AAF17148C7974D4A25B08F46F5">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Use</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Of any amount made available each fiscal year to carry out this Act, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1400">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall use at least 75 percent to carry out the grant program under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Delaware River Basin Conservation Act of 2013/s:5" proposed="true">section 5</cato:entity-ref> including to provide, or provide for, technical assistance under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Delaware River Basin Conservation Act of 2013/s:5/ss:e" proposed="true">section 5(e)</cato:entity-ref>.</text> </subsection>
    </section> 
</legis-body> 
</bill>
</doc>