<doc>
  <docmeta id="113hres214ih">
    <bill congress="113" type="hres" number="214" version="ih"/>
    <revision size="3869" annotations="0" status="complete" id="3" commit-time="2013-06-27T17:08:00Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113hres214ih/3.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <resolution xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" dms-id="H79DC1149821A447E91ABE210786B8001" key="H" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>113 HRES 214 IH: Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives that extensive scientific and technical studies and analyses by the Department of State and other Federal agencies have affirmed that the proposed Keystone XL pipeline is an environmentally sound project.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2013-05-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">113th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session display="yes">1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. RES. 214</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20130515">May 15, 2013</action-date>
			<action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="W000814">Mr. Weber of Texas</sponsor>
			 (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S000583">Mr. Smith of Texas</cosponsor>,
			 <cosponsor name-id="H000067">Mr. Hall</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000182">Mr. Neugebauer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000244">Mr.
			 Sensenbrenner</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000937">Mr.
			 Stockman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001096">Mr. Cramer</cosponsor>,
			 <cosponsor name-id="S001183">Mr. Schweikert</cosponsor>, and
			 <cosponsor name-id="S001192">Mr. Stewart</cosponsor>) submitted the following
			 resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Committee on Science, Space, and
			 Technology</committee-name>
      </action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">Expressing the sense of the House of
		  Representatives that extensive scientific and technical studies and analyses by
		  the Department of State and other Federal agencies have affirmed that the
		  proposed Keystone XL pipeline is an environmentally sound
		  project.</official-title>
	</form>
	<preamble>
		<whereas>
      <text>Whereas safe and responsible production, transportation,
			 and use of oil and petroleum products provide the foundation of America’s
			 energy economy, helping to secure and advance our economic prosperity, national
			 security, and overall quality of life;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Department of State</cato:entity-ref> assessments found that the
			 Keystone XL pipeline <quote>is not likely to impact the amount of crude oil
			 produced from the oil sands</quote> and that <quote>approval or denial of the
			 proposed Project is unlikely to have a substantial impact on the rate of
			 development in the oil sands</quote>;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas commented="no">
      <text>Whereas the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Department of State</cato:entity-ref> found that
			 the incremental life-cycle greenhouse gas emissions associated with the
			 Keystone XL project are estimated in the range of 0.07 to 0.83 million metric
			 tons of carbon dioxide equivalents, with the upper end of this range
			 representing twelve one-thousandths of one percent of the 6,702 million metric
			 tons of carbon dioxide emitted in the United States in 2011;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas after extensive evaluation of potential impacts to
			 land and water resources along the Keystone XL pipeline’s 875 mile proposed
			 route, the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Department of State</cato:entity-ref> found that <quote>The analyses of potential
			 impacts associated with construction and normal operation of the proposed
			 Project suggest that there would be no significant impacts to most resources
			 along the proposed Project route (assuming Keystone complies with all laws and
			 required conditions and measures).</quote>;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas transportation of oil via pipeline has a record of
			 unmatched safety and environmental protection, and the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Department of State</cato:entity-ref>
			 found that <quote>Spills associated with the proposed Project that enter the
			 environment are expected to be rare and relatively small</quote>, and that
			 <quote>there is no evidence of increased corrosion or other pipeline threat due
			 to viscosity</quote> of diluted bitumen oil that will be transported by the
			 Keystone XL pipeline; and</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas plans to incorporate 57 project-specific special
			 conditions related to the design, construction, and operations of the Keystone
			 XL pipeline led the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Department of State</cato:entity-ref> to find that the pipeline will have
			 <quote>a degree of safety over any other typically constructed domestic oil
			 pipeline</quote>: Now, therefore, be it</text>
		</whereas>
  </preamble>
	<resolution-body id="H083C45E55DEA46DDA2DE2843B26E941D" style="traditional">
		<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H24D7EF9BE6D04370B348A1B350D88605" section-type="undesignated-section">
      <enum/>
      <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That it is the sense of the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0050">House of
			 Representatives</cato:entity-ref> that the Federal Government’s exhaustive scientific and
			 technical analysis of the potential environmental impacts of the Keystone XL
			 pipeline have repeatedly affirmed the environmental soundness and safety of the
			 proposed project.</text>
		</section>
  </resolution-body>
</resolution>
</doc>