<doc>
  <docmeta id="113hr2335ih">
    <bill congress="113" type="hr" number="2335" version="ih"/>
    <revision size="6890" annotations="0" status="complete" id="4" commit-time="2013-07-05T15:16:13Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113hr2335ih/4.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HCE51B3E100C74B018F2214DDE3B90BE6" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>113 HR 2335 IH: Pay Your Bills or Lose Your Pay Act of 2013</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2013-06-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>113th CONGRESS</congress>
<session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. R. 2335</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20130612">June 12, 2013</action-date> 
<action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="M000404">Mr. McDermott</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHA00">Committee on House Administration</committee-name>
      </action-desc>
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To prohibit Members of Congress from receiving pay when the Federal Government is unable to make payments or meet obligations because the public debt limit has been reached.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="HC0543F621BE243A18866CE3FD5BEB48E" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H124552E6C845497C926736283D0D88DF" section-type="section-one">
      <enum>1.</enum>
      <header>Short title</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote>
          <short-title>Pay Your Bills or Lose Your Pay Act of 2013</short-title>
        </quote>.</text>
    </section>
<section id="H2120927306A8484980A905EAC0C53481">
      <enum>2.</enum>
      <header>Findings</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">
        <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> finds the following:</text>
<paragraph id="H9B5525055804471E87E9DB971FCB05E3">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text>It is an American value to meet all obligations.</text>
      </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H0E682CCCFBE04EAEAA28EC0C00F55603">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text>A AAA credit rating is essential to the economic standing of the United States in the world.</text>
      </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H9805E2E53BA6440E9ED374F3E538AC89">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <text>The statutory debt limit was increased—</text>
<subparagraph id="HACC2DBDFF31A40AF80FF508F76DE397C">
          <enum>(A)</enum>
          <text>18 times during the presidency of Ronald Reagan;</text>
        </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H75869486A5284D08A3C62EF151CE04E0">
          <enum>(B)</enum>
          <text>4 times during the presidency of George H. W. Bush;</text>
        </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H1060FCC24C0840CD8C8972AD5D1F0D44">
          <enum>(C)</enum>
          <text>6 times during the presidency of William J. Clinton; and</text>
        </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HCE0E2BC0801C45D5B900A76299C50F16">
          <enum>(D)</enum>
          <text>7 times during the presidency of George W. Bush.</text>
        </subparagraph>
      </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HF04B154719234B80AD00CF1EACF495B1">
        <enum>(4)</enum>
        <text>Section 4 of the 14th Amendment of the United States Constitution states <quote>the validity of the public debt of the United States, authorized by law, including debts incurred for payment of pensions and bounties for services in suppressing insurrection or rebellion, shall not be questioned</quote>.</text>
      </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H1DCC2E7173304FE39046F1CF38181473">
        <enum>(5)</enum>
        <text>The statutory debt limit is increased by Congress to pay financial obligations authorized by Congress.</text>
      </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HEAEEB127828B46BAA222F9581AA62886">
        <enum>(6)</enum>
        <text>The ratings agency Moody’s has called for the public debt limit to be eliminated.</text>
      </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HB0600E71573F4479BBFE105BA9CFAD09">
        <enum>(7)</enum>
        <text>The United States is one of the few nations in the world with a public debt limit.</text>
      </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HB361B0A1578248FAAA819AAD191D8CD6">
        <enum>(8)</enum>
        <text>The annual budget resolution, voted on by members of the Senate and House of Representatives, specifies the appropriate level of the public debt for each fiscal year covered by the resolution.</text>
      </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H2A3E9A6F51114A22B4B0449348AE35D1">
        <enum>(9)</enum>
        <text>At times the statutory debt limit must be increased to honor financial obligations authorized and appropriated by Congress and the President of the United States.</text>
      </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H2B1695AC2EAA4871B67AF44EB43D9C09">
        <enum>(10)</enum>
        <text>The credit rating agency Standard and Poor’s downgraded the credit rating of the United States for the first time in its history on August 5, 2011, citing <quote>political brinksmanship</quote> as a primary reason for its action.</text>
      </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H1AABF498EBB1494A8B3A8AFD1C20E332">
        <enum>(11)</enum>
        <text>In July 2012, the Government Accountability Office estimated that the 2011 debt limit standoff cost taxpayers $1,300,000,000 in fiscal year 2011, and the Government Accountability Office further noted that <quote>Congress should consider ways to … avoid potential disruptions to the Treasury market and to help inform the fiscal policy debate in a timely way.</quote>.</text>
      </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HD5A95BA4BCE5460F89D801E74FBD158D">
        <enum>(12)</enum>
        <text>In January 2013, the Bipartisan Policy Center estimated that the 10-year cost to taxpayers of the 2011 debt limit standoff is $18,900,000,000.</text>
      </paragraph>
    </section>
<section id="HFE0959700AB04C66BC3289F38C5ADC80">
      <enum>3.</enum>
      <header>Holding salaries of Members of Congress in escrow upon failure to meet debt obligations</header>
<subsection id="H35E7E058E7B34EF3927892E5CBD30882">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Holding salaries in escrow</header>
<paragraph id="H173E9329A5C441EC869B69D052FFCACE">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>In general</header>
          <text>If the Federal Government is unable to make payments or meet obligations because the public debt limit under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc/31/3101">
              <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/31/3101">section 3101</external-xref> of title 31, United States Code</cato:entity-ref>, has been reached, during the period described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Pay Your Bills or Lose Your Pay Act of 2013/s:3/ss:a/p:2" proposed="true">paragraph (2)</cato:entity-ref> the payroll administrator of each House of Congress shall deposit in an escrow account all payments otherwise required to be made during such period for the compensation of Members of Congress who serve in that House of Congress, and shall release such payments to such Members only upon the expiration of such period.</text>
        </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H93EE6ABD94A74617BAB4643F3D531EF5">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Period described</header>
          <text>The period described in this paragraph is the period beginning on the date on which the Federal Government is unable to make payments or meet obligations because the public debt limit under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc/31/3101">
              <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/31/3101">section 3101</external-xref> of title 31, United States Code</cato:entity-ref>, has been reached, and ending on the earlier of—</text>
<subparagraph id="H12F90CA2DFF94D1ABE48B4FD075379B7">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>the date on which the House of Representatives and the Senate present a bill to the President under article I, section 7 of the Constitution of the United States, to increase the public debt limit under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc/31/3101">
                <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/31/3101">section 3101</external-xref> of title 31, United States Code</cato:entity-ref>; or</text>
          </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H2549B5F5801746A5B134ECEC330AE420">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>the last day of the One Hundred Thirteenth Congress.</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HE8C68C6983AD4CFDB429AA8C50013829">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <header>Withholding and remittance of amounts from payments held in escrow</header>
          <text>The payroll administrator of each House of Congress shall provide for the same withholding and remittance with respect to a payment deposited in an escrow account under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Pay Your Bills or Lose Your Pay Act of 2013/s:3/ss:a/p:1" proposed="true">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref> that would apply to the payment if the payment were not subject to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Pay Your Bills or Lose Your Pay Act of 2013/s:3/ss:a/p:1" proposed="true">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
        </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H08697F2571984723B8F9D0ECFE9AF245">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
          <header>Release of amounts at end of congress</header>
          <text>In order to ensure that this section is carried out in a manner that shall not vary the compensation of Senators or Representatives in violation of the 27th Amendment to the Constitution of the United States, the payroll administrator of a House of Congress shall release for payments to Members of that House of Congress any amounts remaining in any escrow account under this section on the last day of the One Hundred Thirteenth Congress.</text>
        </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H9784DF55429E46A8AA12A5C2987D4DAE">
          <enum>(5)</enum>
          <header>Role of Secretary of the Treasury</header>
          <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary of the Treasury</cato:entity-ref> shall
			 provide the payroll administrators of the Houses of Congress with such
			 assistance as may be necessary to enable the payroll administrators to carry
			 out this section.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
<subsection id="H177E19B9199D415A9C192B5CC20C281F">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Treatment of delegates as members</header>
        <text>In this section, the term <term>Member</term> includes a Delegate or Resident Commissioner to Congress.</text>
      </subsection>
<subsection id="H715D65C25BE54B7CB569CB2CF112C2C2">
        <enum>(c)</enum>
        <header>Payroll Administrator defined</header>
        <text>In this section, the <term>payroll administrator</term> of a House of Congress means—</text>
<paragraph id="HD46FF57A06B440E3A462A4B606715C9F">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>in the case of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0050">House of Representatives</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Chief Administrative Officer" entity-parent-id="0050">Chief Administrative Officer of the House of Representatives</cato:entity-ref>, or an employee of the Office of the Chief Administrative Officer who is designated by the Chief Administrative Officer to carry out this section; and</text>
        </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HE6BD4C0ECFD44996B0D2FC7873151E58">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>in the case of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0010">Senate</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Secretary of the Senate" entity-parent-id="0010">Secretary of the Senate</cato:entity-ref>, or an employee of the Office of the Secretary of the Senate who is designated by the Secretary to carry out this section.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
    </section> 
</legis-body> 
</bill>
</doc>