<doc>
  <docmeta id="113hr1797eh">
    <bill congress="113" type="hr" number="1797" version="eh"/>
    <revision size="13781" annotations="0" status="complete" id="6" commit-time="2013-10-02T01:11:13Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113hr1797eh/6.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <bill bill-stage="Engrossed-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H019CA332E63D4993BDB1B24EA4DE0FB3" public-private="public" stage-count="1"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>113 HR 1797 EH: Pain-Capable Unborn Child Protection Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date/>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="no">IB</distribution-code> 
<congress display="yes">113th CONGRESS</congress> <session display="yes">1st Session</session> 
<legis-num>H. R. 1797</legis-num> 
<current-chamber display="no">IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type> 
<official-title display="yes">To amend title 18, United States Code, to protect pain-capable unborn children, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H295DE854DD83425082DBF58A8A381CD4" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H272D7FBA034743D08B07C16778E46C45" section-type="section-one">
      <enum>1.</enum>
      <header>Short title</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote>
          <short-title>
            Pain-Capable Unborn Child Protection Act
          </short-title>
        </quote>.</text>
    </section> 
<section id="HD5310810BF044F5CA55295DE06FC22BC" section-type="subsequent-section">
      <enum>2.</enum>
      <header>Legislative findings and declaration of constitutional authority for enactment</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">
        <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> finds and declares the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H3555091FB8144E90942D7DE38227DDE4">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text>Pain receptors (nociceptors) are present throughout the unborn child’s entire body and nerves link these receptors to the brain’s thalamus and subcortical plate by no later than 20 weeks after fertilization.</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H609B511F905C4090B643E7B03B776FB7">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text>By 8 weeks after fertilization, the unborn child reacts to touch. After 20 weeks, the unborn child reacts to stimuli that would be recognized as painful if applied to an adult human, for example, by recoiling.</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2465BEC62A684E418145507C726D66F1">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <text>In the unborn child, application of such painful stimuli is associated with significant increases in stress hormones known as the stress response.</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7FA31015DC104998AB10F1C272AF3F58">
        <enum>(4)</enum>
        <text>Subjection to such painful stimuli is associated with long-term harmful neurodevelopmental effects, such as altered pain sensitivity and, possibly, emotional, behavioral, and learning disabilities later in life.</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6D7AE0708B844CEEBCA9292F85DDF808">
        <enum>(5)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For the purposes of surgery on unborn children, fetal anesthesia is routinely administered and is associated with a decrease in stress hormones compared to their level when painful stimuli are applied without such anesthesia. In the United States, surgery of this type is being performed by 20 weeks after fertilization and earlier in specialized units affiliated with children’s hospitals.</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H00AB4D1D7B7A4FA3AA7F38B144618035">
        <enum>(6)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The position, asserted by some physicians, that the unborn child is incapable of experiencing pain until a point later in pregnancy than 20 weeks after fertilization predominately rests on the assumption that the ability to experience pain depends on the cerebral cortex and requires nerve connections between the thalamus and the cortex. However, recent medical research and analysis, especially since 2007, provides strong evidence for the conclusion that a functioning cortex is not necessary to experience pain.</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDA43B62E158A45D3BCDE3C02B316BF09">
        <enum>(7)</enum>
        <text>Substantial evidence indicates that children born missing the bulk of the cerebral cortex, those with hydranencephaly, nevertheless experience pain.</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H68446AEEEC5B46FFB4EF30633B90EEDB">
        <enum>(8)</enum>
        <text>In adult humans and in animals, stimulation or ablation of the cerebral cortex does not alter pain perception, while stimulation or ablation of the thalamus does.</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF692E6601795450D906C52658CAA8BD0">
        <enum>(9)</enum>
        <text>Substantial evidence indicates that structures used for pain processing in early development differ from those of adults, using different neural elements available at specific times during development, such as the subcortical plate, to fulfill the role of pain processing.</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA9515CC010C14C17A9672B55507A5ECE">
        <enum>(10)</enum>
        <text>The position, asserted by some commentators, that the unborn child remains in a coma-like sleep state that precludes the unborn child experiencing pain is inconsistent with the documented reaction of unborn children to painful stimuli and with the experience of fetal surgeons who have found it necessary to sedate the unborn child with anesthesia to prevent the unborn child from engaging in vigorous movement in reaction to invasive surgery.</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3E08571087C14C2693849FF00E853D99">
        <enum>(11)</enum>
        <text>Consequently, there is substantial medical evidence that an unborn child is capable of experiencing pain at least by 20 weeks after fertilization, if not earlier.</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H90970BFF77C447E98004D97D6B22E13E">
        <enum>(12)</enum>
        <text>It is the purpose of the Congress to assert a compelling governmental interest in protecting the lives of unborn children from the stage at which substantial medical evidence indicates that they are capable of feeling pain.</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4DB56024DFE040DFA6A4F0B4B9F9649B">
        <enum>(13)</enum>
        <text>The compelling governmental interest in protecting the lives of unborn children from the stage at which substantial medical evidence indicates that they are capable of feeling pain is intended to be separate from and independent of the compelling governmental interest in protecting the lives of unborn children from the stage of viability, and neither governmental interest is intended to replace the other.</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H29A819C55E364F5783591134797E720F" display-inline="no-display-inline">
        <enum>(14)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Congress has authority to extend protection to pain-capable unborn children under the Supreme Court's Commerce Clause precedents and under the Constitution's grants of powers to Congress under the Equal Protection, Due Process, and Enforcement Clauses of the Fourteenth Amendment.</text>
      </paragraph>
    </section> 
<section id="H6C748C8516CD47F9B5548A3825853E2E" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section">
      <enum>3.</enum>
      <header>Pain-capable unborn child protection</header> 
<subsection id="H023FAC03E9D64F4FB422CB18B0EFB28B">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>In general</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">
          
            <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc-chapter/18/74">
              <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/74">
                Chapter 74
              </external-xref> of title 18, United States Code</cato:entity-ref>, is amended by inserting after <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/18/1531">
              <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc/18/1531">section 1531</cato:entity-ref>
            </external-xref>
           the following:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC77A6A0553F4499F8DF01A7740586F25" style="USC"> 
<section id="H86B4286227C44FBC968CBE382381765C">
            <enum>1532.</enum>
            <header>Pain-capable unborn child protection</header> 
<subsection id="HABF1CE9B5FDA4335B7CCA51F9FD2F26C">
              <enum>(a)</enum>
              <header>Unlawful conduct</header>
              <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, it shall be unlawful for any person to perform an abortion or attempt to do so, unless in conformity with the requirements set forth in <internal-xref idref="HC33BAA2751804D83AB69D83C0E40605C" legis-path="1532.(b)">
                  <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc/18/1532/b" proposed="true">subsection (b)</cato:entity-ref>
                </internal-xref>.</text>
            </subsection> 
<subsection id="HC33BAA2751804D83AB69D83C0E40605C">
              <enum>(b)</enum>
              <header>Requirements for abortions</header> 
<paragraph id="HEAECD6B4A58240FBAECD7E62F6B84622">
                <enum>(1)</enum>
                <text>The physician performing or attempting the abortion shall first make a determination of the probable post-fertilization age of the unborn child or reasonably rely upon such a determination made by another physician. In making such a determination, the physician shall make such inquiries of the pregnant woman and perform or cause to be performed such medical examinations and tests as a reasonably prudent physician, knowledgeable about the case and the medical conditions involved, would consider necessary to make an accurate determination of post-fertilization age.</text>
              </paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" id="HFB30D6A0C2D14B46A02928CC9748F079">
                <enum>(2)</enum> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H081F4C646DF54961AFF6CF51E2A64B14">
                  <enum>(A)</enum>
                  <text>Except as provided in <internal-xref idref="H92BE206020C14DD2A612EC260564EA18" legis-path="1532.(b)(2)(B)">
                      <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc/18/1532/b/2/B" proposed="true">subparagraph (B)</cato:entity-ref>
                    </internal-xref>, the abortion shall not be performed or attempted, if the probable post-fertilization age, as determined under <internal-xref idref="HEAECD6B4A58240FBAECD7E62F6B84622" legis-path="1532.(b)(1)">
                      <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc/18/1532/b/1" proposed="true">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref>
                    </internal-xref>, of the unborn child is 20 weeks or greater.</text>
                </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H92BE206020C14DD2A612EC260564EA18" indent="up1">
                  <enum>(B)</enum>
                  <text>Subject to <internal-xref idref="H57CB541263A94A8498CB6737288A0147" legis-path="1532.(b)(2)(C)">
                      <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc/18/1532/b/2/C" proposed="true">subparagraph (C)</cato:entity-ref>
                    </internal-xref>, <internal-xref idref="H081F4C646DF54961AFF6CF51E2A64B14" legis-path="1532.(b)(2)(A)">
                      <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc/18/1532/b/2/A" proposed="true">subparagraph (A)</cato:entity-ref>
                    </internal-xref> does not apply if—</text> 
<clause id="HE6AF2DBE297B44059A4DCC073C783645">
                    <enum>(i)</enum>
                    <text>in reasonable medical judgment, the abortion is necessary to save the life of a pregnant woman whose life is endangered by a physical disorder, physical illness, or physical injury, including a life-endangering physical condition caused by or arising from the pregnancy itself, but not including psychological or emotional conditions; or</text>
                  </clause> 
<clause id="H054A837B67A144A1A21E8E5D2E82C1E0">
                    <enum>(ii)</enum>
                    <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the pregnancy is the result of rape, or the result of incest against a minor, if the rape has been reported at any time prior to the abortion to an appropriate law enforcement agency, or if the incest against a minor has been reported at any time prior to the abortion to an appropriate law enforcement agency or to a government agency legally authorized to act on reports of child abuse or neglect.</text>
                  </clause>
                </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H57CB541263A94A8498CB6737288A0147" indent="up1">
                  <enum>(C)</enum>
                  <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding the definitions of <quote>abortion</quote> and <quote>attempt an abortion</quote> in this section, a physician terminating or attempting to terminate a pregnancy under an exception provided by <internal-xref idref="H92BE206020C14DD2A612EC260564EA18" legis-path="1532.(b)(2)(B)">
                      <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc/18/1532/b/2/B" proposed="true">subparagraph (B)</cato:entity-ref>
                    </internal-xref> may do so only in the manner which, in reasonable medical judgment, provides the best opportunity for the unborn child to survive, unless, in reasonable medical judgment, termination of the pregnancy in that manner would pose a greater risk of—</text> 
<clause id="H85F66684D3F24247B2FEA0B390B3F363">
                    <enum>(i)</enum>
                    <text>the death of the pregnant woman; or</text>
                  </clause> 
<clause id="HE1A698FA83BD48A4898744C65C6470AC">
                    <enum>(ii)</enum>
                    <text>the substantial and irreversible physical impairment of a major bodily function, not including psychological or emotional conditions, of the pregnant woman;</text>
                  </clause>
                  <continuation-text continuation-text-level="subparagraph">than would other available methods.</continuation-text>
                </subparagraph>
              </paragraph>
            </subsection> 
<subsection id="HCACADF155D4D4BC0A675F47D88A366AE">
              <enum>(c)</enum>
              <header>Criminal penalty</header>
              <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whoever violates <internal-xref idref="HABF1CE9B5FDA4335B7CCA51F9FD2F26C" legis-path="1532.(a)">
                  <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc/18/1532/a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref>
                </internal-xref> shall be fined under this title or imprisoned for not more than 5 years, or both.</text>
            </subsection> 
<subsection id="HDF5B599783E14C9FBBABC0DE3F486D56">
              <enum>(d)</enum>
              <header>Bar to prosecution</header>
              <text>A woman upon whom an abortion in violation of <internal-xref idref="HABF1CE9B5FDA4335B7CCA51F9FD2F26C" legis-path="1532.(a)">
                  <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc/18/1532/a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref>
                </internal-xref> is performed or attempted may not be prosecuted under, or for a conspiracy to violate, <internal-xref idref="HABF1CE9B5FDA4335B7CCA51F9FD2F26C" legis-path="1532.(a)">
                  <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc/18/1532/a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref>
                </internal-xref>, or for an offense under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc/18/2">section 2</cato:entity-ref>, <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc/18/3">3</cato:entity-ref>, or <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc/18/4">4 of this title</cato:entity-ref> based on such a violation.</text>
            </subsection> 
<subsection id="HF943DDBBF85C4102B56E9AEFA5171EF9">
              <enum>(e)</enum>
              <header>Definitions</header>
              <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section the following definitions apply:</text> 
<paragraph id="HA420F31E5CA64604BE5DFD6B2D3ADBC1">
                <enum>(1)</enum>
                <header>Abortion</header>
                <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>abortion</term> means the use or prescription of any instrument, medicine, drug, or any other substance or device—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H890EB0B0D33B4A78B6CBBB948289A2C6">
                  <enum>(A)</enum>
                  <text>to intentionally kill the unborn child of a woman known to be pregnant; or</text>
                </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HDE706EA2E45C432CB6161940FC6D6668">
                  <enum>(B)</enum>
                  <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to intentionally terminate the pregnancy of a woman known to be pregnant, with an intention other than—</text> 
<clause id="H717464F3C5914F2E9BB1D9FF86991592">
                    <enum>(i)</enum>
                    <text>after viability to produce a live birth and preserve the life and health of the child born alive; or</text>
                  </clause> 
<clause id="H47A9293D209A4D96BB4A400E13EE85C7">
                    <enum>(ii)</enum>
                    <text>to remove a dead unborn child.</text>
                  </clause>
                </subparagraph>
              </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H04F7376A223B4072BE58FF2DB37D4E60">
                <enum>(2)</enum>
                <header>Attempt an abortion</header>
                <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>attempt</term>, with respect to an abortion, means conduct that, under the circumstances as the actor believes them to be, constitutes a substantial step in a course of conduct planned to culminate in performing an abortion.</text>
              </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8EB3E9F8CC6243CCA145F3FCDDBF2051">
                <enum>(3)</enum>
                <header>Fertilization</header>
                <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>fertilization</term> means the fusion of human spermatozoon with a human ovum.</text>
              </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H53A961A78CC04B688015069FBAA6E8A2">
                <enum>(4)</enum>
                <header>Perform</header>
                <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>perform</term>, with respect to an abortion, includes induce an abortion through a medical or chemical intervention including writing a prescription for a drug or device intended to result in an abortion.</text>
              </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFE9BF98D248A409795C92FE63B6C1253">
                <enum>(5)</enum>
                <header>Physician</header>
                <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>physician</term> means a person licensed to practice medicine and surgery or osteopathic medicine and surgery, or otherwise legally authorized to perform an abortion.</text>
              </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD68D75A0162D4FF09C5ACC4989648863">
                <enum>(6)</enum>
                <header>Post-fertilization age</header>
                <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>post-fertilization age</term> means the age of the unborn child as calculated from the fusion of a human spermatozoon with a human ovum.</text>
              </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE7D15813831D44CEA42B7368E9545557">
                <enum>(7)</enum>
                <header>Probable post-fertilization age of the unborn child</header>
                <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>probable post-fertilization age of the unborn child</term> means what, in reasonable medical judgment, will with reasonable probability be the postfertilization age of the unborn child at the time the abortion is planned to be performed or induced.</text>
              </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H23E10863C38445C58EFA71F6EFEF61AA">
                <enum>(8)</enum>
                <header>Reasonable medical judgment</header>
                <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>reasonable medical judgment</term> means a medical judgment that would be made by a reasonably prudent physician, knowledgeable about the case and the treatment possibilities with respect to the medical conditions involved.</text>
              </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H726C4E783F1A48B18AD3F3DC74B8AF51">
                <enum>(9)</enum>
                <header>Unborn child</header>
                <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>unborn child</term> means an individual organism of the species homo sapiens, beginning at fertilization, until the point of being born alive as defined in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc/1/8/b">
                    <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/1/8">
                    section 8(b)
                  </external-xref> of title 1</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
              </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H686F234AE39446A1983E83223EBA85CC">
                <enum>(10)</enum>
                <header>Woman</header>
                <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>woman</term> means a female human being whether or not she has reached the age of majority.</text>
              </paragraph>
            </subsection>
          </section>
          <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
        </quoted-block>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="H71C06AC3292D4B2BAD07A4D73FE50CA7">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Clerical amendment</header>
        <text>The table of sections at the beginning of <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc-chapter/18/74">
            <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/74">
              chapter 74
            </external-xref> of title 18, United States Code</cato:entity-ref>, is amended by adding at the end the following new item:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H25D382675D7043FA942343D6A1E55780" style="USC"> 
<toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> 
<toc-entry level="section">1532. Pain-capable unborn child protection.</toc-entry>
          </toc>
          <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
        </quoted-block>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="H774CF3CEBB394B8A95AF241E0B204E29">
        <enum>(c)</enum>
        <header>Chapter heading amendments</header> 
<paragraph id="H92956FC40C4640568646E48CB59A024E">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>Chapter heading in chapter</header>
          <text>The chapter heading for <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc-chapter/18/74">
              <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/74">
                chapter 74
              </external-xref> of title 18, United States Code</cato:entity-ref>, is amended by striking <quote>
              <header-in-text level="chapter" style="USC">Partial-Birth Abortions</header-in-text>
            </quote> and inserting <quote>
              <header-in-text level="chapter" style="USC">Abortions</header-in-text>
            </quote>.</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE3D6A00BE7FF459E8BAD1943CAD85A7E">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Table of chapters for part I</header>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The item relating to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc-chapter/18/74">chapter 74</cato:entity-ref> in the table of chapters at the beginning of <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc/18">part I of title 18, United States Code</cato:entity-ref>, is amended by striking <quote>Partial-Birth Abortions</quote> and inserting <quote>Abortions</quote>.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
    </section> 
</legis-body> <attestation>
    <attestation-group>
      <attestation-date date="20130618" chamber="House">Passed the House of Representatives June 18, 2013.</attestation-date>
      <attestor display="no">Karen L. Haas,</attestor>
      <role>Clerk.</role>
    </attestation-group>
  </attestation> 
<endorsement display="yes"/> 
</bill>
</doc>