<doc>
  <docmeta id="113hres117ih">
    <bill congress="113" type="hres" number="117" version="ih"/>
    <revision size="3515" annotations="0" id="4" commit-time="2013-04-13T22:35:18+00:00" committer="favila" doc="113hres117ih/4.xml" status="complete">
      <description/>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <resolution xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" dms-id="H56D002B4920A48B892B82F0BE5FE93A4" key="H" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print">
	<metadata>
<dublinCore>
<title>113 HRES 117 IH: Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives that the Federal Government should not bail out State and local government employee pension plans or other plans that provide post-employment benefits to State and local government retirees.</title>
<publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</publisher>
<date>2013-03-14</date>
<format>text/xml</format>
<language>EN</language>
<rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">113th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session display="yes">1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. RES. 117</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20130314">March 14, 2013</action-date>
			<action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="C001076">Mr. Chaffetz</sponsor>
			 submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the
			 <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and the
			 Workforce</committee-name>
      </action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">Expressing the sense of the House of
		  Representatives that the Federal Government should not bail out State and local
		  government employee pension plans or other plans that provide post-employment
		  benefits to State and local government retirees.</official-title>
	</form>
	<preamble>
		<whereas>
      <text>Whereas the Federal Government is operating at a huge
			 annual deficit and is rapidly increasing its outstanding debt every
			 year;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the Federal Government, as of December 2012, is
			 carrying more than $16.0 trillion in debt, of which $11.6 trillion is owed to
			 the public and $4.8 trillion is owed to Social Security and other trust
			 funds;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the Federal Government borrowed 31 cents for every
			 dollar it spent in 2012;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas foreign governments, individuals, and corporations
			 as of September 2012 own 48 percent of Federal debt owned by the public;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas Social Security's unfunded liabilities in 2012 are
			 $8.6 trillion over 75 years and $20.5 trillion over the infinite
			 horizon;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the Federal debt is expected to increase by more
			 than $6 trillion from 2013 to 2022 according to the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0800">Congressional Budget
			 Office</cato:entity-ref>;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas State and local governments are heavily dependent
			 on Federal revenues;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas more than 16 percent of the entire Federal budget
			 goes directly to States and local governments;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas more than 20 percent of total State and local
			 government general revenue comes from the Federal Government according to
			 <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1323">Census Bureau's</cato:entity-ref> latest Annual Survey of State and Local Government
			 Finance;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas numerous State and local government employee
			 pension plans have offered overly generous retirement benefits to its employees
			 and are in dire financial situations with combined unfunded liabilities up to
			 $4.4 trillion;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas many State and local government pension plans have
			 understated liabilities and overstated asset growth rates and have employed
			 methodologies that private sector plans are prohibited from using by Federal
			 law; and</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas several State and local pension plans are expected
			 to fully exhaust their funds within ten years: Now, therefore, be it</text>
		</whereas>
  </preamble>
	<resolution-body id="H70F364648C664BF7BADEFEFBC1256849" style="traditional">
		<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H040FB587BBFF474DB52B23D3922DA4A7" section-type="undesignated-section">
      <enum/>
      <text>That it is the sense of the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0050">House of
			 Representatives</cato:entity-ref> that—</text>
			<paragraph id="H9D77A2CF1EF34F24B954CC4BAB882AA8">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Federal Government should not bailout
			 State and local government employee pension plans and other post-employment
			 benefit plans; and</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HB5B2B23F4C374A6D8AD0168C2B4C6D76">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">State and local governments should
			 immediately institute reforms to their employee pension plans, including
			 replacing defined benefit plans with defined contribution plans.</text>
			</paragraph>
    </section>
  </resolution-body>
</resolution>
</doc>