<doc>
  <docmeta id="113hres410ih">
    <bill congress="113" type="hres" number="410" version="ih"/>
    <revision size="2709" annotations="0" status="complete" id="3" commit-time="2013-11-15T17:27:39Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113hres410ih/3.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <resolution xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" dms-id="HE2445920409547F7958005A628BFB70D" key="H" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print">
  <metadata>
<dublinCore>
<dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">113 HRES 410 IH: Expressing support for the designation of a “Small Business Saturday” and supporting efforts to increase awareness of the value of locally owned small businesses.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">2013-11-13</dc:date>
<dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code>
    <congress display="yes">113th CONGRESS</congress>
    <session display="yes">1st Session</session>
    <legis-num>H. RES. 410</legis-num>
    <current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
    <action display="yes">
      <action-date date="20131113">November 13, 2013</action-date>
      <action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="G000546">Mr. Graves of Missouri</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="C001084">Mr. Cicilline</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="H001056">Ms. Herrera Beutler</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HSM00">Committee on Small Business</committee-name>
      </action-desc>
    </action>
    <legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
    <official-title display="yes">Expressing support for the designation of a <quote>Small Business Saturday</quote> and supporting efforts to increase awareness of the value of locally owned small businesses.</official-title>
  </form>
  <preamble>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas small businesses represent 99.7 percent of all businesses having employees (commonly referred to as <quote>employer firms</quote>) in the United States;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas small businesses employ over 49 percent of the employees in the private sector in the United States;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas small businesses pay over 42 percent of the total payroll of the employees in the private sector in the United States;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas small businesses are responsible for more than 46 percent of the private, nonfarm product of the gross domestic product;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas small businesses generated 64 percent of net new jobs created between 1993 and 2011;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas 87 percent of consumers in the United States agree that the success of small businesses is critical to the overall economic health of the United States;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas 89 percent of consumers in the United States agree that small businesses contribute positively to the local community by supplying jobs and generating tax revenue;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas 93 percent of consumers in the United States agree that it is important to support the small businesses in their community; and</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas November 30, 2013, would be an appropriate date to designate as <quote>Small Business Saturday</quote>: Now, therefore, be it</text>
    </whereas>
  </preamble>
  <resolution-body id="HE1DF48F4AAFA45FFADE3838D002E3891" style="traditional">
    <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H49FED9DDA4FC4F18BA8CDAB860B2B8AF" section-type="undesignated-section">
      <enum/>
      <text>That the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0050">House of Representatives</cato:entity-ref>—</text>
      <paragraph id="H6B27CB6B8522458D8092211915F45B40">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">supports the designation of a <quote>Small Business Saturday</quote>; and</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HAB89EAC0AC3E49DA9612E26D38698056">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text>supports efforts—</text>
        <subparagraph id="H619D32B85FB44536AC4BE319C102EE42">
          <enum>(A)</enum>
          <text>to encourage consumers to shop locally; and</text>
        </subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="H3589A7B6DE184F2ABABFF06473751EAC">
          <enum>(B)</enum>
          <text>to increase awareness of the value of locally owned small businesses and the impact of locally owned small businesses on the economy of the United States.</text>
        </subparagraph>
      </paragraph>
    </section>
  </resolution-body>
</resolution>
</doc>