<doc>
  <docmeta id="113hr3175ih">
    <bill congress="113" type="hr" number="3175" version="ih"/>
    <revision size="2080" annotations="0" status="complete" id="5" commit-time="2013-10-03T19:59:17Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113hr3175ih/5.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H4C89F7E7353F442C8777B0038844A632" public-private="public">
  <metadata>
<dublinCore>
<title>113 HR 3175 IH: Making appropriations for fiscal year 2014 to ensure that members of the Armed Forces, including reserve components thereof, continue to receive pay and allowances for active service performed during a Government shutdown.</title>
<publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</publisher>
<date>2013-09-25</date>
<format>text/xml</format>
<language>EN</language>
<rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
    <congress>113th CONGRESS</congress>
    <session>1st Session</session>
    <legis-num>H. R. 3175</legis-num>
    <current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
    <action>
      <action-date date="20130925">September 25, 2013</action-date>
      <action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="A000367">Mr. Amash</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAP00">Committee on Appropriations</committee-name>
      </action-desc>
    </action>
    <legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
    <official-title>Making appropriations for fiscal year 2014 to ensure that members of the Armed Forces, including reserve components thereof, continue to receive pay and allowances for active service performed during a Government shutdown.</official-title>
  </form>
  <legis-body id="H45BB5834DD1C46DF93103292F1E0F0D1" style="OLC">
    <section id="H53CDF8711D984D1287E0BC00CE303D82" section-type="section-one">
      <enum>1.</enum>
      <header>Emergency appropriation of funds to provide pay and allowances for members of the Armed Forces during Government shutdown</header>
      <subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H275E7B3B4F7D4A92BB52020C6857F93A">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Appropriation of funds for military pay and allowances</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a funding gap occurs during fiscal year 2014 impacting the Armed Forces, amounts are hereby appropriated, out of any money in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, at a rate for operations as provided for military personnel accounts by the <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
            <cato:entity-ref value="Department of Defense Appropriations Act, 2013" entity-type="act">Department of Defense Appropriations Act, 2013</cato:entity-ref> (<cato:entity-ref value="public-law/113/6/d:C" entity-type="public-law">division C of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/113/6">Public Law 113–6</external-xref>
            </cato:entity-ref>)</cato:entity>, for the purpose of providing pay and allowances (without interruption) to members of the Army, Navy, Air Force, Marine Corps, and Coast Guard, including reserve components thereof, who perform active service during the funding gap.</text>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="H59219CD74B654AB584170D7E442B2660">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Funding gap defined</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <term>funding gap</term> means any period of time after September 30, 2013, for which interim or full-year appropriations for the military personnel accounts of the Armed Forces for fiscal year 2014 have not been enacted by a law other than this Act.</text>
      </subsection>
    </section>
  </legis-body>
</bill>
</doc>