<doc>
  <docmeta id="113hconres73ih">
    <bill congress="113" type="hconres" number="73" version="ih"/>
    <revision size="3538" annotations="0" status="complete" id="5" commit-time="2014-01-15T23:10:59Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113hconres73ih/5.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <resolution xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" dms-id="HE7F992D3642F415F8DDE7EB35C908480" key="H" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" resolution-type="house-concurrent" star-print="no-star-print">
  <metadata>
<dublinCore>
<dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">113 HCON 73 IH: Expressing the sense of Congress that a commemorative postage stamp should be issued by the United States Postal Service honoring the 1915 Panama-California Exposition, and that the Citizens' Stamp Advisory Committee should recommend to the Postmaster General that such a stamp be issued.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">2014-01-09</dc:date>
<dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code>
    <congress display="yes">113th CONGRESS</congress>
    <session display="yes">2d Session</session>
    <legis-num>H. CON. RES. 73</legis-num>
    <current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
    <action display="yes">
      <action-date date="20140109">January 9, 2014</action-date>
      <action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="D000598">Mrs. Davis of California</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="F000030">Mr. Farr</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000397">Ms. Lofgren</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000130">Mr. Vargas</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="P000608">Mr. Peters of California</cosponsor>) submitted the following concurrent resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>
      </action-desc>
    </action>
    <legis-type>CONCURRENT RESOLUTION</legis-type>
    <official-title display="yes">Expressing the sense of Congress that a commemorative postage stamp should be issued by the United States Postal Service honoring the 1915 Panama-California Exposition, and that the Citizens' Stamp Advisory Committee should recommend to the Postmaster General that such a stamp be issued.</official-title>
  </form>
  <preamble>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas San Diego played host to the Panama-California Exposition from January 1, 1915, until January 1, 1917;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the Panama-California Exposition recognized the historic completion of the Panama Canal, which revolutionized transcontinental trade;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas, on May 22, 1911, the <cato:entity-ref entity-id="0050" entity-type="federal-body">House of Representatives</cato:entity-ref> passed a congressional resolution endorsing San Diego’s Panama-California Exposition and called on President William Howard Taft to invite our Central and South American partner nations as exposition participants;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas seven States—California, Utah, New Mexico, Nevada, Washington, Montana, and Kansas—participated in that exposition and highlighted the unrealized potential of the American West;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas San Diego has realized that potential over the past 100 years, growing to become the second largest city in California, the eighth largest city in our Nation, and a world leader in biomedical and technology research that was unimaginable a hundred years ago;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas architects John and Frederick Olmsted of Massachusetts, Frank P. Allen, Jr., of Washington State, and Bertram Grosvenor Goodhue of New York collaborated to transform a little-used public park into a forward-looking urban landmark to host the exposition;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas commented="no">
      <text>Whereas that park, known as Balboa Park, has since continued to host internationally recognized artistic performances, educational exhibits, and, during both World Wars, served as an active military installation;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the <cato:entity-ref entity-id="1443" entity-type="federal-body">National Park Service</cato:entity-ref> recognized this rich history when it designated Balboa Park as a National Historic Landmark in 1977; and</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas Balboa Park will celebrate its centennial beginning in 2015 with a year of festivities that showcase San Diego’s intellectual capital, imaginative spirit, and exceptional quality of life: Now, therefore, be it</text>
    </whereas>
  </preamble>
  <resolution-body id="H81F7C9DE602F49BBAB75231A96AF177D" style="traditional">
    <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H7588DE24C2D84061BEB3F0DB45EE4F94" section-type="undesignated-section">
      <enum/>
      <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That it is the sense of the <cato:entity-ref entity-id="0001" entity-type="federal-body">Congress</cato:entity-ref> that—</text>
      <paragraph id="H954F0A310AAA4A60B3DD02B07E3C51B4">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text>a commemorative postage stamp should be issued by the <cato:entity-ref entity-id="1800" entity-type="federal-body">United States Postal Service</cato:entity-ref> honoring the 1915 Panama-California Exposition; and</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H49A21BCE22A340B49DD27CD6065DACB7">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text>the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1865">Citizens’ Stamp Advisory Committee</cato:entity-ref> should recommend to the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1800">Postmaster General</cato:entity-ref> that such a stamp be issued.</text>
      </paragraph>
    </section>
  </resolution-body>
</resolution>
</doc>