<doc>
  <docmeta id="113hr2638ih">
    <bill congress="113" type="hr" number="2638" version="ih"/>
    <revision size="18519" annotations="0" status="complete" id="4" commit-time="2013-08-18T05:12:58Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113hr2638ih/4.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H4EF67E8CB60F41CCA8CEE3CC32046499" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>113 HR 2638 IH: Foreign Aid Transparency and Accountability Act of 2013</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2013-07-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>113th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 2638</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20130710">July 10, 2013</action-date>
			<action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="P000592">Mr. Poe of Texas</sponsor> (for
			 himself and <cosponsor name-id="C001078">Mr. Connolly</cosponsor>) introduced
			 the following bill; which was referred to the
			 <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign
			 Affairs</committee-name>
      </action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To direct the President to establish guidelines for
		  United States foreign assistance, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H407EC24577A34D3ABE821CA9C85364AB" style="OLC">
		<section id="H96FF3B85223345A9BF364C0B3BFAF2F6" section-type="section-one">
      <enum>1.</enum>
      <header>Short title</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the
			 <quote>
          <short-title>Foreign Aid Transparency and
			 Accountability Act of 2013</short-title>
        </quote>.</text>
		</section>
    <section id="H58D453BB14FB47CB998DEFFE03356546">
      <enum>2.</enum>
      <header>Guidelines for
			 United States foreign assistance</header>
			<subsection id="H2AD03982A74341B7A8AF6065B9D9E644">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Purpose</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The purpose of this section is to evaluate
			 the performance of United States foreign assistance and its contribution to
			 policy, strategies, projects, program goals, and priorities undertaken by the
			 United States, to foster and promote innovative programs to improve the
			 effectiveness of United States foreign assistance, and to coordinate the
			 monitoring and evaluation processes of Federal departments and agencies that
			 administer United States foreign assistance.</text>
			</subsection>
      <subsection id="H8999788850154CC2BDC538EAE46C8DD2">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Establishment of
			 guidelines</header>
        <text>Not later than 18 months after the date of the
			 enactment of this Act, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> shall establish guidelines regarding the
			 establishment of measurable goals, performance metrics, and monitoring and
			 evaluation plans that can be applied with reasonable consistency to United
			 States foreign assistance. Such guidelines should be established according to
			 best practices of monitoring and evaluation studies and analyses.</text>
			</subsection>
      <subsection id="HB6351327B7994FFF8B528D30BAA604C2">
        <enum>(c)</enum>
        <header>Objectives of
			 guidelines</header>
				<paragraph id="HB28C15A326944841B85FAF56FC780450">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>In
			 general</header>
          <text>The guidelines established under this section shall
			 provide direction to Federal departments and agencies that administer United
			 States foreign assistance on how to develop the complete range of activities
			 relating to the monitoring of resources, the evaluation of projects, the
			 evaluation of program impacts, and analysis that is necessary for the
			 identification of findings, generalizations that can be derived from those
			 findings, and their applicability to proposed project and program
			 design.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H9AF77E106E444492BBA95F97FA7F3143">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Objectives</header>
          <text>Specifically,
			 the guidelines shall provide direction on how to achieve the following
			 objectives for monitoring and evaluation of programs:</text>
					<subparagraph id="H19D4BD1F25BE477FBCAD61D4A7A56383">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Building measurable goals, performance
			 metrics, and monitoring and evaluation into program design, to be tracked
			 against an established baseline at the outset, including the provision of
			 sufficient program resources to conduct monitoring and evaluation.</text>
					</subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H5330A7EA4DF14652969268DC2F640317">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>Disseminating
			 guidelines for the development and implementation of monitoring and evaluation
			 programs to all personnel, especially in the field, who are responsible for the
			 design, implementation, and management of United States foreign assistance
			 programs.</text>
					</subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="HD3B05B967CA6448EB0C4FB44FA2EB6F4">
            <enum>(C)</enum>
            <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Developing a clearinghouse capacity for the
			 collection and dissemination of knowledge and lessons learned that serve as
			 benchmarks to guide future programs for United States development
			 professionals, implementing partners, the international aid community, and aid
			 recipient governments, and as a repository of knowledge on lessons
			 learned.</text>
					</subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="HFF387AA006B1417D9E0A4BB0178485E1">
            <enum>(D)</enum>
            <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Distributing evaluation reports internally
			 and making the reports available online to the public. In addition, providing a
			 summary of each evaluation, including a description of the evaluation
			 methodology, and key findings and recommendations made in the evaluation, to
			 the public online in a fully searchable form, within 90 days after the
			 completion of the evaluation. Any material made available online under this
			 subparagraph may not include any classified or proprietary information of
			 nongovernmental organizations, contractors, or private sector entities.</text>
					</subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="HDD767E04E5404A9C8138DC2E52A31DA0">
            <enum>(E)</enum>
            <text>Establishing
			 annual monitoring and evaluation agendas and objectives.</text>
					</subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="HCB31D8E4C79D4217A739F0DBDFCF41C8">
            <enum>(F)</enum>
            <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Applying rigorous monitoring and evaluation
			 methodologies to focus on learning, accountability, and policymaking, choosing
			 from among a wide variety of qualitative, quantitative, summative, and
			 formative methods common in the field of social scientific inquiry, including
			 impact evaluations, a simple grading system providing a clear evaluation of
			 outcomes, and analysis of project logic that includes inputs, activities,
			 outputs, intermediate outcomes, and end outcomes.</text>
					</subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H72210C4CCCA642A19C61BB9C24688524">
            <enum>(G)</enum>
            <text>Partnering with
			 the academic community, implementing partners, and national and international
			 institutions that have expertise in monitoring and evaluation and analysis when
			 such partnerships will provide needed expertise or will significantly improve
			 the evaluation and analysis.</text>
					</subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="HC9B8CD688B0241F2AA0FF29F58767584">
            <enum>(H)</enum>
            <text>Developing and
			 implementing a training plan for appropriate aid personnel on the proper
			 conduct of monitoring and evaluation programs.</text>
					</subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H2529711C1C754924AA1BF9BB80EE768C">
            <enum>(I)</enum>
            <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Providing relevant and useful evaluation
			 questions that meet the needs of decision makers, an appropriate and feasible
			 design for the evaluation questions, and criteria that permit objective
			 assessment and valid conclusions on the evaluation questions.</text>
					</subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="HFB7B24E51A94473E87F9DFA91A642E13">
            <enum>(J)</enum>
            <text>Ensuring
			 sufficient, credible, and reliable measures and data in the evaluation of the
			 effectiveness of foreign assistance programs, including an assessment of
			 assumptions and limitations made in such evaluation.</text>
					</subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H8D96D8DF6808402C8A49E074298870D5">
            <enum>(K)</enum>
            <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Ensuring that generally accepted standards
			 such as independence, professional judgment, competence, and quality control
			 and assurance are followed in the monitoring and evaluation of programs.</text>
					</subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="H2E5E4707F9CE44D4AC52A277E552CD22">
        <enum>(d)</enum>
        <header>Implementation
			 of Guidelines</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Beginning not
			 later than one year after the date on which the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> establishes the
			 guidelines under this section, the head of each Federal department or agency
			 that administers United States foreign assistance shall administer the United
			 States foreign assistance in accordance with the guidelines.</text>
			</subsection>
      <subsection id="H9B3A6B6FBF18474084CDEE6D20D35BE8">
        <enum>(e)</enum>
        <header>Presidential
			 report</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 18
			 months after the date of the enactment of this Act, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> shall submit
			 to the appropriate congressional committees a report that contains a detailed
			 description of the guidelines that have been developed on measurable goals,
			 performance metrics, and monitoring and evaluation plans for United States
			 foreign assistance established under this section. The report shall be
			 submitted in unclassified form to the maximum extent possible, but may include
			 a classified annex.</text>
			</subsection>
      <subsection id="H99CEDD2C639B4949B113064246BE66A3">
        <enum>(f)</enum>
        <header>Implementation
			 not required for certain security sector assistance</header>
				<paragraph id="HF14CD62C3DAD4D4CBAF24B1AA17460D4">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>In
			 general</header>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref> shall not be required to
			 administer any United States foreign assistance program relating to United
			 States security sector assistance in accordance with the guidelines established
			 under this section if the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref> makes a determination that the
			 administration of such program in accordance with the guidelines would be
			 detrimental to the national interests of the United States.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HC399514C5AAF444DA22E7A10F6CADB53">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Briefings or
			 report</header>
          <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref> shall provide briefings or submit a
			 written report to the appropriate congressional committees explaining any
			 determination made under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Foreign Aid Transparency and Accountability Act of 2013/s:2/ss:f/p:1" proposed="true">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref>. Any such report may be submitted to the
			 appropriate congressional committees in classified form.</text>
				</paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection commented="no" id="H18D1E913A8B14363AF2FEAD781F46F86">
        <enum>(g)</enum>
        <header>Comptroller
			 General reports</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0500">Comptroller General of the United States</cato:entity-ref> shall—</text>
				<paragraph commented="no" id="HC61A352075214BB4B8CFFBA56C8EBBA9">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not later than 1 year after the date of the
			 enactment of this Act, submit to the appropriate congressional committees a
			 report that contains an analysis of the actions that the major Federal
			 departments and agencies that administer United States foreign assistance have
			 taken to ensure that the evaluation of United States foreign assistance is
			 planned, conducted, and utilized effectively;</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph commented="no" id="H6307CC01177A44209AC227E0DC42E03D">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>not later than 3
			 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, submit to the appropriate
			 congressional committees a report that contains an analysis of—</text>
					<subparagraph commented="no" id="HBABD5519674F4D4587673007EDEA4A71">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>the guidelines
			 established pursuant to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Foreign Aid Transparency and Accountability Act of 2013/s:2/ss:b" proposed="true">subsection (b)</cato:entity-ref>; and</text>
					</subparagraph>
          <subparagraph commented="no" id="HA623C82F6A76405AB67EFDB2BC244155">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the implementation of the guidelines by the
			 major Federal departments and agencies that administer United States foreign
			 assistance; and</text>
					</subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HD82281D5A5E1445BBFFFD8559B93DA54">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not later than 5 years after the date of
			 the enactment of this Act, and biennially thereafter for 8 years, submit to the
			 appropriate congressional committees a report that contains an analysis of the
			 implementation of the guidelines by the major Federal departments and agencies
			 that administer United States foreign assistance.</text>
				</paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="H87EC2B3E916D43AA8B651CCDCD7F4160">
        <enum>(h)</enum>
        <header>Evaluation
			 defined</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the
			 term <term>evaluation</term> means, with respect to a United States foreign
			 assistance program, the systematic collection and analysis of information about
			 the characteristics and outcomes of the program and projects under the program
			 as a basis for judgments, to improve effectiveness, and to inform decisions
			 about current and future programming.</text>
			</subsection>
    </section>
    <section id="HFC037BDE4F274EC8BE59DD0DA5ECE3D9" section-type="subsequent-section">
      <enum>3.</enum>
      <header>Revision to Internet
			 website to make publicly available comprehensive, timely, comparable, and
			 accessible information on United States foreign assistance programs</header>
			<subsection id="H1C369CB712914BC5A0D08A2FAABE1E73">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Revision;
			 information sharing and updates; feedback mechanism</header>
				<paragraph id="H2888C9278563447CBC6C0EB5FFCB0BE1">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>In
			 general</header>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 30
			 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> shall direct
			 the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref> to revise the Department of State’s Internet website
			 <quote>ForeignAssistance.gov</quote> to make publicly available in unclassified
			 form comprehensive, timely, comparable, and accessible information on United
			 States foreign assistance.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H298348EAAC8344E8A2F582AAFF2F0436">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Information
			 sharing and updates</header>
					<subparagraph id="H146B5A7704554910B3B45C61A06689E5">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <header>Information
			 sharing</header>
            <text>The head of each Federal department or agency that
			 administers United States foreign assistance shall, not later than 2 years
			 after the date of the enactment of this Act, and every 90 days thereafter,
			 provide to the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref> such information with respect to the United
			 States foreign assistance programs carried out by such Federal department or
			 agency.</text>
					</subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H4D2705275308483D81149B042D5D6F28">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <header>Updates</header>
            <text>The
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref> shall publish not later than 2 years after the date of the
			 enactment of this Act and thereafter update on a quarterly basis on the
			 Internet website the information provided under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Foreign Aid Transparency and Accountability Act of 2013/s:3/ss:a/p:2/sp:A" proposed="true">subparagraph (A)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
					</subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HD29036D59DAF4652B17F6AE274ECE586">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <header>Feedback
			 mechanism</header>
          <text>The website described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Foreign Aid Transparency and Accountability Act of 2013/s:3/ss:a/p:1" proposed="true">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref> shall include a
			 feedback mechanism through which individuals are able to provide comments on
			 any United States foreign assistance program.</text>
				</paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="HAC147C36D5744CCE8FE6F617CFB5D460">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Matters To be
			 included</header>
				<paragraph id="HC35692D521B54CC0915F3871B15D51A3">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>In
			 general</header>
          <text>The information described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Foreign Aid Transparency and Accountability Act of 2013/s:3/ss:a/p:1" proposed="true">subsection (a)(1)</cato:entity-ref> shall be
			 published on a detailed program-by-program basis and country-by-country
			 basis.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H4957B972647D4FA6A1DF36C72A2933F9">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Types of
			 information</header>
          <text>To ensure transparency, accountability, and
			 effectiveness of United States foreign assistance, such information shall
			 include country assistance strategies, annual budget documents, congressional
			 budget justifications, obligations, expenditures, and reports and evaluations,
			 including those developed pursuant to the guidelines established under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Foreign Aid Transparency and Accountability Act of 2013/s:2" proposed="true">section
			 2</cato:entity-ref>, for United States foreign assistance programs and projects under such
			 programs. Each type of information described in this paragraph shall be
			 published or updated on the Internet website not later than 90 days after the
			 date on which the information is issued.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H7CF65DEFAF9944F0A00770FBC9663543">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <header>Report in lieu
			 of inclusion</header>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If—</text>
					<subparagraph id="H8B9B7B0A81594AA9B18AE97B571DF289">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>the head of a
			 Federal department or agency makes a determination that the inclusion of a
			 required item of information on the Internet website under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Foreign Aid Transparency and Accountability Act of 2013/s:3/ss:a/p:1" proposed="true">subsection (a)(1)</cato:entity-ref>
			 would jeopardize the health or security of an implementing partner or program
			 beneficiary, or</text>
					</subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H231BB5B6D42E48C8BEE7E432173EC180">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Secretary of
			 State</cato:entity-ref> makes a determination that the inclusion of a required item of
			 information on the Internet website under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Foreign Aid Transparency and Accountability Act of 2013/s:3/ss:a/p:1" proposed="true">subsection (a)(1)</cato:entity-ref> would be
			 detrimental to the national interests of the United States,</text>
					</subparagraph>
          <continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph">then the
			 head of such Federal department or agency or the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref>, as the
			 case may be, shall provide briefings to the appropriate congressional
			 committees on the item of information or submit to the appropriate
			 congressional committees the item of information in a written report in lieu of
			 it being included on the Internet website, along with the reasons for it not
			 being included on the Internet website. Any such item of information may be
			 submitted to the appropriate congressional committees in classified
			 form.</continuation-text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="H946140142560421598AF5D9F923BDDB2">
        <enum>(c)</enum>
        <header>Scope of
			 information</header>
				<paragraph id="HEE6760679636490EBB27A2E2B8866579">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>In
			 general</header>
          <text>The Internet website shall contain the information
			 described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Foreign Aid Transparency and Accountability Act of 2013/s:3/ss:b" proposed="true">subsection (b)</cato:entity-ref> as follows:</text>
					<subparagraph id="H530540764F3B4983B315ED59E7B9F207">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>For fiscal year
			 2013, the information relating to such fiscal year and each of the immediately
			 preceding 2 fiscal years.</text>
					</subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H2D7B77426C7040E4A3C747A10706CC9F">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>For fiscal year
			 2014, the information relating to such fiscal year and each of the immediately
			 preceding 3 fiscal years.</text>
					</subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="HB26B06F0B8834B1FA3D2B4AE69279ED7">
            <enum>(C)</enum>
            <text>For fiscal year
			 2015, the information relating to such fiscal year and each of the immediately
			 preceding 4 fiscal years.</text>
					</subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="HBCC56AE40A3049D7BC72BE19493C743A">
            <enum>(D)</enum>
            <text>For fiscal year
			 2016 and each fiscal year thereafter, the information relating to such fiscal
			 year and each of the immediately preceding 5 fiscal years.</text>
					</subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph commented="no" id="HA1FB003744F54ED3881DACA53A1BD99D">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Older
			 information</header>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For fiscal year 2017 and each fiscal year thereafter,
			 the Internet website shall also contain a link to a searchable database
			 available to the public containing information described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Foreign Aid Transparency and Accountability Act of 2013/s:3/ss:b" proposed="true">subsection (b)</cato:entity-ref>
			 relating to fiscal years prior to the immediately preceding 5 fiscal years but
			 subsequent to fiscal year 2010.</text>
				</paragraph>
      </subsection>
    </section>
    <section commented="no" id="H721CF2F4A72C43AFBCB1625432C99FE0">
      <enum>4.</enum>
      <header>Congressional
			 briefings if requirements of section 3 are not met</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">If
			 the information described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Foreign Aid Transparency and Accountability Act of 2013/s:3/ss:b" proposed="true">section 3(b)</cato:entity-ref> with respect to a United States
			 foreign assistance program is not provided as required under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Foreign Aid Transparency and Accountability Act of 2013/s:3" proposed="true">section 3</cato:entity-ref>, then
			 the head of the relevant Federal department or agency shall provide briefings
			 to the appropriate congressional committees, along with a detailed explanation
			 of why the requirements for publication on the Internet have not been met and
			 when they will be met, with respect to each month for which such information is
			 not published on the Internet.</text>
		</section>
    <section id="HD8420D2634334436BFA66D19E1A4CE7F">
      <enum>5.</enum>
      <header>Offset</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Of the amounts authorized to be appropriated
			 for United States foreign assistance programs of a Federal department or agency
			 that administers such programs for a fiscal year, up to 5 percent of such
			 amounts are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this Act with respect to
			 such programs for such fiscal year.</text>
		</section>
    <section commented="no" id="H75BC26000C624C0A808C0A8D0AA7FA38">
      <enum>6.</enum>
      <header>Definitions</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text>
			<paragraph id="H2BEEF744F85546A38D87D5F74FB66406">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <header>Appropriate
			 congressional committees</header>
        <text>The term <quote>appropriate
			 congressional committees</quote> means—</text>
				<subparagraph commented="no" id="H289CF4CD47704E31AEF7B44904096C40">
          <enum>(A)</enum>
          <text>the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="committee" entity-id="HFA00">Committee on
			 Foreign Affairs</cato:entity-ref> and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="committee" entity-id="HAP00">Committee on Appropriations of the House of
			 Representatives</cato:entity-ref>; and</text>
				</subparagraph>
        <subparagraph commented="no" id="H0639311CF98E4337A170003E5EE31136">
          <enum>(B)</enum>
          <text>the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="committee" entity-id="SSFR00">Committee on
			 Foreign Relations</cato:entity-ref> and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="committee" entity-id="SSAP00">Committee on Appropriations of the Senate</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
				</subparagraph>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph commented="no" id="H9736D084368340FC9D314E651139683B">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <header>United States
			 foreign assistance</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term
			 <quote>United States foreign assistance</quote> means any tangible or
			 intangible item provided by gift, loan, sale, credit, guaranty, or other means
			 by any agency of the United States Government to a foreign country, including
			 any training, service, or technical advice, any item of real, personal, or
			 mixed property, any agricultural commodity, United States dollars, and any
			 currencies of any foreign country which are owned by the United States
			 Government.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph commented="no" id="H5A7C5284D4554DCBB8A737D2BE2DC2C9">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <header>United States
			 security sector assistance</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>United States security
			 sector assistance</quote>—</text>
				<subparagraph commented="no" id="H67AEB30B445A4253A0D3B885B6091272">
          <enum>(A)</enum>
          <text>means policies,
			 programs, and activities that the United States Government employs to engage
			 with foreign partners in the use of force to protect both the foreign state and
			 its citizens at home or abroad, maintain international peace and security, and
			 to enforce the law and provide oversight of security institutions and forces;
			 and</text>
				</subparagraph>
        <subparagraph commented="no" id="H411DD5C3B1064274B743D336944805A3">
          <enum>(B)</enum>
          <text>includes helping
			 foreign partners build and sustain the capacity and effectiveness of
			 institutions to provide security, safety, and justice for their people and to
			 contribute to efforts that address common security challenges.</text>
				</subparagraph>
      </paragraph>
    </section>
  </legis-body>
</bill>
</doc>