<doc>
  <docmeta id="113hres538ih">
    <bill congress="113" type="hres" number="538" version="ih"/>
    <revision size="4308" annotations="0" status="complete" id="4" commit-time="2014-07-30T21:29:34Z" committer="zwilliams" doc="113hres538ih/4.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <resolution xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" dms-id="H42B8EF310E5D46F3B21DDA1B141DD6D5" key="H" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print">
	<metadata>
<dublinCore>
<dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">113 HRES 538 IH: Expressing support for designation of May as “National Bladder Cancer Awareness Month”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">2014-04-03</dc:date>
<dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">113th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session display="yes">2d Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. RES. 538</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20140403">April 3, 2014</action-date>
			<action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="C001090">Mr. Cartwright</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="R000572">Mr. Rogers of Michigan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001068">Mr. Cohen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001078">Mr. Connolly</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000055">Mr. Aderholt</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M000312">Mr. McGovern</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>
      </action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">Expressing support for designation of May as <quote>National Bladder Cancer Awareness Month</quote>.</official-title>
	</form>
	<preamble>
		<whereas>
      <text>Whereas 500,000 families in the United States live with bladder cancer;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas more than 72,000 people are expected to be diagnosed with bladder cancer and 15,000 people
			 are expected to die from the disease in 2013 alone;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas bladder cancer affects people of all ages and backgrounds and is among the top 10 cancers
			 with the highest incidence rates in the United States;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas bladder cancer is known as one of the most expensive cancers to treat on a per patient
			 basis with a recurrence rate of approximately 50 to 80 percent, requiring
			 lifelong surveillance;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas bladder cancer symptoms, such as blood in the urine, are easily recognized, however, many
			 are unaware of the threat of bladder cancer, often prolonging time to
			 diagnosis;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas if diagnosed early, bladder cancer is treatable;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas military veterans are twice as likely as non-veterans to be diagnosed with bladder cancer;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas women are often diagnosed at a later stage in the development of bladder cancer, and when
			 diagnosed at the same stage as men, women have a worse prognosis;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas if diagnosis and treatment are delayed, the life expectancy of an individual with bladder
			 cancer decreases;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the quality of life of a person with bladder cancer will depend on future treatment and
			 diagnosis developments, which will rely on research advancements;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas there have been no new treatments developed for bladder cancer in more than 20 years;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas research advancements for bladder cancer are limited by lack of awareness about the disease
			 within the medical community and general public;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas increased awareness will promote early diagnosis and increase chances of survival;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas increased awareness will bolster public support of the disease and thus increase funding
			 for innovative research and the development of new treatment options and
			 diagnostic tools;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas traditionally on the first Saturday in May, survivors, caregivers, and loved ones walk
			 together throughout the United States to raise awareness of bladder
			 cancer;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the Bladder Cancer Advocacy Network and its community of patients, caregivers, and
			 specialists, seek to foster a community of hope and support, fund and
			 conduct research for innovative treatments and diagnostic tools, and
			 increase public awareness and understanding of bladder cancer; and</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas May would be an appropriate month to designate as <quote>National Bladder Cancer Awareness Month</quote>: Now, therefore, be it</text>
    </whereas>
  </preamble>
	<resolution-body id="H28E1A35E166E4AAB94F807A478D01EDC" style="traditional">
		<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HC71F0D1B62E14C6B839DCABDCE82F810" section-type="undesignated-section">
      <enum/>
      <text>That the <cato:entity-ref entity-id="0050" entity-type="federal-body">House of Representatives</cato:entity-ref>—</text>
			<paragraph id="HE8A94E81EED74D7486977DF01FF08609">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">supports the designation of <quote>National Bladder Cancer Awareness Month</quote>;</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HA96450F2E23544238272F5A6CC7F9BEE">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text>supports the goals and ideals of <quote>National Bladder Cancer Awareness Month</quote>; and</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HCD622E2CA1A44938884DA4BF6D139621">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <text>calls on the people of the United States, interested groups, and affected persons to—</text>
				<subparagraph id="H3791E33572A44D299B23242207C5288B">
          <enum>(A)</enum>
          <text>promote awareness of bladder cancer and to foster understanding of the impact of the disease on
			 patients and their families and caregivers;</text>
				</subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="H5E3A4F6E59124DDF931037365C9B9D91">
          <enum>(B)</enum>
          <text>take an active role in the fight to end bladder cancer; and</text>
				</subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="HB7ED04D3DA824E1E891DD70ABEC3AB87">
          <enum>(C)</enum>
          <text>observe <quote>National Bladder Cancer Awareness Month</quote> with appropriate ceremonies and activities.</text>
				</subparagraph>
      </paragraph>
    </section>
  </resolution-body>
</resolution>
</doc>