<doc>
  <docmeta id="113hres226ih">
    <bill congress="113" type="hres" number="226" version="ih"/>
    <revision size="2765" annotations="0" status="complete" id="3" commit-time="2013-06-27T18:08:46Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113hres226ih/3.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <resolution xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" dms-id="H7C0C854CD82D422B8629D1B03677EA3B" key="H" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>113 HRES 226 IH: Expressing support for the designation of the fourth week in April as “Every Kid Healthy Week”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2013-05-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">113th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session display="yes">1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. RES. 226</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20130520">May 20, 2013</action-date>
			<action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="D000096">Mr. Danny K. Davis of
			 Illinois</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was referred to
			 the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and
			 Commerce</committee-name>
      </action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">Expressing support for the designation of
		  the fourth week in April as <quote>Every Kid Healthy
		  Week</quote>.</official-title>
	</form>
	<preamble>
		<whereas>
      <text>Whereas childhood obesity, undernourishment, and physical
			 inactivity are national epidemics, and schools can help to address these
			 problems by becoming healthier places so kids can live healthier lives;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas 1 in 3 of the Nation’s children are overweight or
			 obese which puts those children at a high risk for developing heart disease,
			 cancer, asthma, and diabetes;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas only 8 percent of elementary school students and 6
			 percent of middle and high school students have daily physical
			 education;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas every child needs a healthy diet consisting of
			 nutritious foods in appropriate portion sizes based on age and
			 development;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas children who eat poorly or who engage in too
			 little physical activity do not perform as well as they should
			 academically;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the primary goal of <quote>Every Kid Healthy
			 Week</quote> is for schools to host events that will engage volunteers to
			 improve school health environments by making sustainable changes that encourage
			 students to eat better and be active every day;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas <quote>Every Kid Healthy Week</quote> will act as
			 a focal point for year-round programing related to the Nation’s childhood
			 obesity epidemic as well as its solutions, including sound nutrition, regular
			 physical activity, and health-promoting school programs; and</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the fourth week in April would be an appropriate
			 week to designate as <quote>Every Kid Healthy Week</quote> to bring national
			 attention to the importance of keeping kids fit and healthy, and to provide an
			 opportunity to emphasize the significance of making the choices necessary to
			 sustain a healthy and physically active lifestyle: Now, therefore, be it</text>
		</whereas>
  </preamble>
	<resolution-body id="HE433A8C4DA6642C6B65C6E9F749B7A0A" style="traditional">
		<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H90FFFE1BA41B423E8ECAC59239DE4A7A" section-type="undesignated-section">
      <enum/>
      <text>That the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0050">House of
			 Representatives</cato:entity-ref>—</text>
			<paragraph id="HAADC2EECC28148488472318710151D1D">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">supports the designation of <quote>Every
			 Kid Healthy Week</quote>; and</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HC9B66546DD154F3CA20E78CB7EA1B404">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text>honors and
			 recognizes the importance of promoting healthy lifestyles for children.</text>
			</paragraph>
    </section>
  </resolution-body>
</resolution>
</doc>