<doc>
  <docmeta id="113hr4041ih">
    <bill congress="113" type="hr" number="4041" version="ih"/>
    <revision size="9716" annotations="0" status="complete" id="6" commit-time="2014-02-18T16:32:52Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113hr4041ih/6.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HB2782D7E91914A6EA4785DC10FB6ECBE" public-private="public">
	<metadata>
<dublinCore>
<dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">113 HR 4041 IH: To award a Congressional Gold Medal to the Freedom Riders, collectively, in recognition of their unique contribution to Civil Rights, which inspired a revolutionary movement for equality in interstate travel.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">2014-02-11</dc:date>
<dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>113th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>2d Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 4041</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20140211">February 11, 2014</action-date>
			<action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="C001093">Mr. Collins of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C000714">Mr. Conyers</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000515">Mr. Rush</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000002">Mr. Nadler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001049">Mr. Clay</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000032">Ms. Jackson Lee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001137">Mr. Meeks</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001063">Ms. Hahn</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000053">Mr. Rangel</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001281">Mrs. Beatty</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001068">Mr. Cohen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000373">Mr. Pitts</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H000636">Mr. Hinojosa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000551">Mr. Grijalva</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001251">Mr. Butterfield</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson of Indiana</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000469">Mr. Tonko</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000355">Mr. Dingell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001185">Ms. Sewell of Alabama</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C000984">Mr. Cummings</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000911">Ms. Brown of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000551">Ms. Lee of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C000380">Mrs. Christensen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001160">Ms. Moore</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H000324">Mr. Hastings of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000808">Ms. Wilson of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000290">Ms. Edwards</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000187">Ms. Waters</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001145">Ms. Schakowsky</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000574">Mr. Blumenauer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000096">Mr. Danny K. Davis of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000490">Mr. Bishop of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000128">Mr. Van Hollen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000604">Mr. Payne</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000288">Mr. Ellison</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000043">Mr. Fattah</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000588">Mr. Richmond</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000385">Ms. Kelly of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001270">Ms. Bass</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000535">Mr. Gutiérrez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001067">Ms. Clarke of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000131">Mr. Veasey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000193">Mr. Thompson of Mississippi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C000537">Mr. Clyburn</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000215">Ms. Eshoo</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000009">Ms. Kaptur</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000455">Ms. Fudge</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000126">Ms. Eddie Bernice Johnson of Texas</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="J000294">Mr. Jeffries</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HHA00">House Administration</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To award a Congressional Gold Medal to the Freedom Riders, collectively, in recognition of their
			 unique contribution to Civil Rights, which inspired a revolutionary
			 movement for equality in interstate travel.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H32600F0A98474E3090A1E2C41C4C77B9" style="OLC">
		<section id="H44DA055F579B4F88A9ECE31A70706A71" section-type="section-one">
      <enum>1.</enum>
      <header>Findings</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> finds the following:</text>
			<paragraph id="H7E451E3B340F48CD811653F7F3FE7F21">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text>In 1960, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1001">Supreme Court</cato:entity-ref> ruled in Boynton v. Virginia that segregated bus and rail stations were
			 unconstitutional.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H2D7E0FFF313D4D2893C3C58D2A60239C">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The rigid system of racial segregation that prevailed in the United States during the 1960s did not
			 permit a Black person to sit next to a White person on any bus traveling
			 through interstate commerce and in most locations in the South. Bus
			 stations had <quote>Whites Only</quote> waiting areas and Blacks were not permitted to wait in those areas despite the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1001">Supreme Court</cato:entity-ref>
			 making it the law of the land.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HDE1BD67032434528B1A3C9A6329F6353">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Freedom Riders, with the intent to end segregation in public transportation throughout the
			 South, paved the way for full racial integration of the United States
			 transit system. They overcame prejudice, discrimination, and violence.
			 They sparked a movement that changed our Nation.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H289340B6033845F2B4D7940DF9847417">
        <enum>(4)</enum>
        <text>The Congress of Racial Equality (C.O.R.E.) selected thirteen volunteers for nonviolent response
			 training to join in the Freedom Rides from Washington, DC, to New
			 Orleans, LA. The Freedom Riders used their strategies of nonviolence
			 throughout the South to challenge the region’s Jim Crow laws directly and
			 enforce the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1001">Supreme Court</cato:entity-ref> decision in Boynton.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HCC05DE7475644086ABE3134488C6E2D5">
        <enum>(5)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">On the morning of May 4, 1961, the Freedom Riders, comprised of seven Blacks and six Whites,
			 boarded two buses, with Blacks and Whites seated together. Those thirteen
			 Freedom Riders were: Genevieve Hughes Houghton, Charles Person, Hank
			 Thomas, John Lewis, Edward Blankenheim, James Farmer, Walter Bergman,
			 Frances Bergman, Joseph Perkins, Jimmy McDonald, Mae Francis Moultrie,
			 Benjamin Elton Cox, and Albert Bigelow. Most segregated States considered
			 even this level of integration a crime. At various stops along the way,
			 the Freedom Riders would enter areas designated <quote>Whites</quote> and <quote>Colored</quote> and would eat together at segregated lunch counters to defy local laws.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HB873F26A69AB4357A39AE712EF7C4736">
        <enum>(6)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Initially, the Freedom Riders had encountered only minor clashes until a stop in South Carolina. In
			 Rock Hill, an angry mob severely beat <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="person" entity-id="L000287">John Lewis</cato:entity-ref>, now a Congressman from
			 the 5th District of Georgia, when he entered the bus station. Henry <quote>Hank</quote> Thomas was jailed when he entered the bus station in Winnsboro. Authorities delivered him to a
			 waiting mob long after the station had closed that evening. A local Black
			 minister rescued Thomas, enabling him to rejoin the group in Columbia.
			 However, Lewis was so badly beaten he could not continue the Freedom
			 Rides.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HCF5A854860DC44BBA430411D2958BC91">
        <enum>(7)</enum>
        <text>Dr. Martin Luther King, Jr., and other civil rights leaders met with the group in Atlanta to
			 dissuade their continuance through the Deep South due to death threats.
			 Despite these warnings, more Freedom Riders joined in Atlanta. Dedicated
			 to their mission to end segregation in the South and trained in nonviolent
			 movements, the Freedom Riders continued on their journey.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H620662C448EC446E95F9BE302DE87E31">
        <enum>(8)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">On Mother’s Day, May 14, 1961, the Freedom Riders were on two different buses. An angry mob in
			 Anniston, Alabama, firebombed the first bus. When the Freedom Riders
			 rushed
			 out, still choking from the thick smoke of the burning bus, the waiting
			 angry mob beat them with lead pipes and baseball bats as the bus exploded.
			 Ambulances refused to transport the Black Freedom Riders to the hospital.
			 The mob beat the Freedom Riders on the second bus and forced them to sit
			 in the back. As they journeyed to Birmingham, another mob savagely beat
			 the Freedom Riders.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H3DBB6232E29F4190ADE06CE7B44CAF8A">
        <enum>(9)</enum>
        <text>The Nashville (TN) Student Group, a local group of students who had been successful in
			 desegregating the lunch counters and movie theaters in Nashville (TN),
			 vowed not to let these acts of violence curtail the goal of the Freedom
			 Rides. They sent their members to continue the Freedom Rides and called
			 out to other student groups to do the same.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HF63E55F0CCA44EA28BB1C3813E226FBE">
        <enum>(10)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">As the violence grew, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1500">Attorney General</cato:entity-ref> of the United States called in the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2130">National Guard</cato:entity-ref> and
			 the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1544">U.S. Marshals</cato:entity-ref> to protect the Freedom Riders as they journeyed through
			 Alabama. This protection was short-lived. The Federal authorities turned
			 the Freedom Riders over to the local authorities in Mississippi who then
			 arrested the Freedom Riders for disturbing the peace.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H00AB09F4F2CA4B8D98CCB606AD45184C">
        <enum>(11)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The government of Mississippi imprisoned many of the Freedom Riders in Parchman Prison known for
			 its horrific conditions, such as subjecting the Freedom Riders to strip
			 searches, work on chain gangs, and light shining in their cells 24 hours a
			 day. Despite these conditions, the Freedom Riders refused bail because
			 they were determined to spread the message of their nonviolent movement.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H518B21DB030848A0B8B4D1BB890791DF">
        <enum>(12)</enum>
        <text>Five months after the first Freedom Rides left on their historic ride, the Interstate Commerce
			 Commission in conjunction with the U.S. <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1500">Attorney General</cato:entity-ref> Robert Kennedy
			 issued a Federal order banning segregation at all interstate public
			 facilities based upon <quote>race, color or creed</quote>. The law became effective on November 1, 1961.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H4F2ABA13508C40E9BB63BA16CAFA0276">
        <enum>(13)</enum>
        <text>In 2011, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1101">President of the United States</cato:entity-ref> paid tribute to the Freedom Riders with a Presidential
			 Proclamation honoring the 50th Anniversary of the first Freedom Ride by
			 brave Americans whose selfless act of courage helped pave the way for
			 others to continue on the road to Civil Rights in America.</text>
			</paragraph>
    </section>
    <section id="H7ECFA1E64B884C829F96DB79428026C4">
      <enum>2.</enum>
      <header>Congressional Gold Medal</header>
			<subsection id="H76453AB5C1C049D396D89A7DF2F8EC43">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Presentation authorization</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Speaker of the House of Representatives" entity-parent-id="0050">Speaker of the House of Representatives</cato:entity-ref>
           and the 
            <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="President pro tempore of the Senate" entity-parent-id="0010">President pro tempore
           of the Senate</cato:entity-ref> shall make
			 appropriate arrangements for the presentation, on behalf of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref>,
			 of a gold medal of appropriate design to the Freedom Riders, collectively,
			 in recognition of their unique contribution to Civil Rights, which
			 inspired a revolutionary movement to equality in interstate travel.</text>
			</subsection>
      <subsection id="HFB7BD0CFBD6942E79E3F2EE42EFFDC3B">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Design and striking</header>
        <text>For the purposes of the award referred to in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="113 HR 4041/s:2/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary of the Treasury</cato:entity-ref>
			 (hereafter in this Act referred to as the <quote>Secretary</quote>) shall strike a gold medal with suitable emblems, devices, and inscriptions, to be determined by
			 the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
			</subsection>
      <subsection id="HE9B9062DDEA043C58D8B640D66AB73E4">
        <enum>(c)</enum>
        <header>Smithsonian Institution</header>
				<paragraph id="H0FD8CD3A3CB64BE29C191D696A489A34">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>In general</header>
          <text>Following the award of the gold medal under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="113 HR 4041/s:2/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref>, the gold medal shall be given to the
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="3300">Smithsonian Institution</cato:entity-ref>, where it will be available for display as
			 appropriate and available for research.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H8350797179F44821BBA0A47FE707883C">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Sense of the Congress</header>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It is the sense of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> that the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="3300">Smithsonian Institution</cato:entity-ref> should make the gold medal awarded
			 pursuant to this Act available for display elsewhere, particularly at
			 appropriate locations associated with the Freedom Riders.</text>
				</paragraph>
      </subsection>
    </section>
    <section id="HD7F15CC23C32468EB2617E9D541EED16">
      <enum>3.</enum>
      <header>Duplicate medals</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> may strike and sell duplicates in bronze of the gold medal struck pursuant to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="113 HR 4041/s:2" proposed="true">section
			 2</cato:entity-ref> under such regulations as the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> may prescribe, at a price
			 sufficient to cover the cost thereof, including labor, materials, dies,
			 use of machinery, and overhead expenses, and the cost of the gold medal.</text>
		</section>
    <section id="H93E04207CE5449B8A918DC00C9C3ABC4">
      <enum>4.</enum>
      <header>National medals</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Medals struck pursuant to this Act are national medals for the purposes of <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc-chapter/31/51">
          <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/31/51">chapter 51</external-xref> of title 31,
			 United States Code</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
		</section>
  </legis-body>
</bill>
</doc>