<doc><docmeta id="113hr624ih">
    <bill congress="113" type="hr" number="624" version="ih"/>
    <revision id="14" commit-time="2013-03-25T21:36:31+00:00" comitter="/users/favila.xml" doc="/docs/113hr624ih/14.xml" status="complete"><description/></revision>
</docmeta><bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HD35AD47A746D4E5EA3254F0E0C1C18D8" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<form> 
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>113th CONGRESS</congress> <session>1st Session</session> 
<legis-num>H. R. 624</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20130213">February 13, 2013</action-date> 
<action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="R000572">Mr. Rogers of Michigan</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="R000576">Mr. Ruppersberger</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="">Select Committee on Intelligence (Permanent Select)</committee-name>
      </action-desc> 
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To provide for the sharing of certain cyber threat intelligence and cyber threat information between the intelligence community and cybersecurity entities, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H97B8A21C00894C8E9689BC959926B3FF" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H2F3F60667DDD4EC39FC93A94BD393EA4" section-type="section-one">
      <enum>1.</enum>
      <header>Short title</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote>
          <short-title>Cyber Intelligence Sharing and Protection Act</short-title>
        </quote>.</text>
    </section> 
<section id="HE2E328CD71974D2DAE418897066C75A3">
      <enum>2.</enum>
      <header>Cyber threat intelligence and information sharing</header> 
<subsection id="H78594E07FBDD49DFB7AD6655570B3236">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>In general</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">
          <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="National Security Act of 1947/t:XI">Title XI of the National Security Act of 1947</cato:entity-ref> (<cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/50/442/etseq">50 U.S.C. 442 et seq.</cato:entity-ref>)</cato:entity> is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3A0A3FD1D73C4CAF997C88D8DB244FC5" style="traditional"> 
<section id="H3C344576DE444E45A6634A2B0C4FA252">
            <enum>1104.</enum>
            <header>Cyber threat intelligence and information sharing</header> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H186E8D6A8C114F7B85AD765C42B72999">
              <enum>(a)</enum>
              <header>Intelligence community sharing of cyber threat intelligence with private sector and utilities</header> 
<paragraph id="H9DECA48D521048B6B67FB35C10AD9183">
                <enum>(1)</enum>
                <header>In general</header>
                <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director of National Intelligence shall establish procedures to allow elements of the intelligence community to share cyber threat intelligence with private-sector entities and utilities and to encourage the sharing of such intelligence.</text>
              </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HEF926181B52C4579BC9ABABCF40DD8E0">
                <enum>(2)</enum>
                <header>Sharing and use of classified intelligence</header>
                <text>The procedures established under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="National Security Act of 1947/s:1104/ss:a/p:1" proposed="true">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref> shall provide that classified cyber threat intelligence may only be—</text> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="HE1409415A9F943E68F8A05790EFA2B86">
                  <enum>(A)</enum>
                  <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shared by an element of the intelligence community with—</text> 
<clause id="H5231C41592934E7083A05F2C087F8545">
                    <enum>(i)</enum>
                    <text>a certified entity; or</text>
                  </clause> 
<clause id="HBD496353D3A34FEDBFF7E8D19C48CD5E">
                    <enum>(ii)</enum>
                    <text>a person with an appropriate security clearance to receive such cyber threat intelligence;</text>
                  </clause>
                </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB752814E54A4473BA96C3AF9ACBD0C17">
                  <enum>(B)</enum>
                  <text>shared consistent with the need to protect the national security of the United States; and</text>
                </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H0B33F8F17F374161BA26D01405A0C3F0">
                  <enum>(C)</enum>
                  <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">used by a certified entity in a manner which protects such cyber threat intelligence from unauthorized disclosure.</text>
                </subparagraph>
              </paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" id="H8A6FF421AAFA4AA18536C6B6423AB616">
                <enum>(3)</enum>
                <header>Security clearance approvals</header>
                <text>The Director of National Intelligence shall issue guidelines providing that the head of an element of the intelligence community may, as the head of such element considers necessary to carry out this subsection—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HAC74CD4BAB6F4E6DB0F913A34856382C">
                  <enum>(A)</enum>
                  <text>grant a security clearance on a temporary or permanent basis to an employee or officer of a certified entity;</text>
                </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA301CEBB2B2D49F597C00E22734C90FD">
                  <enum>(B)</enum>
                  <text>grant a security clearance on a temporary or permanent basis to a certified entity and approval to use appropriate facilities; and</text>
                </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HAFD36C7E1BEA44A9BC3CAA60DA5921EB">
                  <enum>(C)</enum>
                  <text>expedite the security clearance process for a person or entity as the head of such element considers necessary, consistent with the need to protect the national security of the United States.</text>
                </subparagraph>
              </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA057D5E915BA4EF4B5CF32AB1E8D169D">
                <enum>(4)</enum>
                <header>No right or benefit</header>
                <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The provision of information to a private-sector entity or a utility under this subsection shall not create a right or benefit to similar information by such entity or such utility or any other private-sector entity or utility.</text>
              </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2E38129F784848E4A10446904A3D30F5">
                <enum>(5)</enum>
                <header>Restriction on disclosure of cyber threat intelligence</header>
                <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, a certified entity receiving cyber threat intelligence pursuant to this subsection shall not further disclose such cyber threat intelligence to another entity, other than to a certified entity or other appropriate agency or department of the Federal Government authorized to receive such cyber threat intelligence.</text>
              </paragraph>
            </subsection> 
<subsection id="H3F3BFBB764914169BA0FEB86FEDD01A5">
              <enum>(b)</enum>
              <header>Use of cybersecurity systems and sharing of cyber threat information</header> 
<paragraph id="H83B5591E2E9F4B73848C5A0FC141FEA6">
                <enum>(1)</enum>
                <header>In general</header> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="HE51C9F2932CB49BEAD5B18C104570F32">
                  <enum>(A)</enum>
                  <header>Cybersecurity providers</header>
                  <text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, a cybersecurity provider, with the express consent of a protected entity for which such cybersecurity provider is providing goods or services for cybersecurity purposes, may, for cybersecurity purposes—</text> 
<clause commented="no" id="H4F03A65D060A4220BA9A6BC24650C288">
                    <enum>(i)</enum>
                    <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">use cybersecurity systems to identify and obtain cyber threat information to protect the rights and property of such protected entity; and</text>
                  </clause> 
<clause commented="no" id="H2183E150AB704C55B3A0E4AC0C330D91">
                    <enum>(ii)</enum>
                    <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">share such cyber threat information with any other entity designated by such protected entity, including, if specifically designated, the Federal Government.</text>
                  </clause>
                </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H758C70D2B1D74A04A8AB02FF8464AE08">
                  <enum>(B)</enum>
                  <header>Self-protected entities</header>
                  <text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, a self-protected entity may, for cybersecurity purposes—</text> 
<clause id="HA1EFA2C937C84972A946397A9C41B33C">
                    <enum>(i)</enum>
                    <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">use cybersecurity systems to identify and obtain cyber threat information to protect the rights and property of such self-protected entity; and</text>
                  </clause> 
<clause id="HA35BA112B82349248D5CC6A6ACB5C431">
                    <enum>(ii)</enum>
                    <text>share such cyber threat information with any other entity, including the Federal Government.</text>
                  </clause>
                </subparagraph>
              </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H71204E7A19F14C92B0081C329ABEADF5" display-inline="no-display-inline">
                <enum>(2)</enum>
                <header>Sharing with the Federal Government</header> 
<subparagraph id="HCFB219FA4B2C4A03A48A430B16BA8880">
                  <enum>(A)</enum>
                  <header>Information shared with the National Cybersecurity and Communications Integration Center of the Department of Homeland Security</header>
                  <text>Subject to the use and protection of information requirements under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="National Security Act of 1947/s:1104/ss:b/p:3" proposed="true">paragraph (3)</cato:entity-ref>, the head of a department or agency of the Federal Government receiving cyber threat information in accordance with <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="National Security Act of 1947/s:1104/ss:b/p:1" proposed="true">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref> shall provide such cyber threat information to the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7000">National Cybersecurity and Communications Integration Center of the Department of Homeland Security</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
                </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H46658C1BFC504A5FBCD278D4DA459C9E">
                  <enum>(B)</enum>
                  <header>Request to share with another department or agency of the Federal Government</header>
                  <text>An entity sharing cyber threat information that is provided to the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7000">National Cybersecurity and Communications Integration Center of the Department of Homeland Security</cato:entity-ref> under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="National Security Act of 1947/s:1104/ss:a/p:1/sp:A" proposed="true">subparagraph (A)</cato:entity-ref> or <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="National Security Act of 1947/s:1104/ss:a/p:1" proposed="true">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref> may request the head of such Center to, and the head of such Center may, provide such information to another department or agency of the Federal Government.</text>
                </subparagraph>
              </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H11F23E848D2C49B69E8FEB59A3C8AFFA">
                <enum>(3)</enum>
                <header>Use and protection of information</header>
                <text>Cyber threat information shared in accordance with <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="National Security Act of 1947/s:1104/ss:a/p:1" proposed="true">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref>—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H9BF87DB5561A4AC691249CC3CC202418">
                  <enum>(A)</enum>
                  <text>shall only be shared in accordance with any restrictions placed on the sharing of such information by the protected entity or self-protected entity authorizing such sharing, including appropriate anonymization or minimization of such information;</text>
                </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5FDDD711180647A8B50D703CBCF61C70">
                  <enum>(B)</enum>
                  <text>may not be used by an entity to gain an unfair competitive advantage to the detriment of the protected entity or the self-protected entity authorizing the sharing of information;</text>
                </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H8F3D75073EAB49D6898DEE363C5972FB">
                  <enum>(C)</enum>
                  <text>if shared with the Federal Government—</text> 
<clause id="H35EF632EC1DA4CDCAFC5786DCE25D3DA">
                    <enum>(i)</enum>
                    <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall be exempt from disclosure under section <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc/5">552 of title 5, United States Code</cato:entity-ref> (commonly known as the <quote>
                        <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Freedom of Information Act">Freedom of Information Act</cato:entity-ref>
                      </quote>);</text>
                  </clause> 
<clause commented="no" id="HDFB211316B064E81A41900210A96A506">
                    <enum>(ii)</enum>
                    <text>shall be considered proprietary information and shall not be disclosed to an entity outside of the Federal Government except as authorized by the entity sharing such information;</text>
                  </clause> 
<clause id="H4189088B65234000B82E7C53BFA78165">
                    <enum>(iii)</enum>
                    <text>shall not be used by the Federal Government for regulatory purposes;</text>
                  </clause> 
<clause id="HD6E5CC6815CF464280542696DAFFE30D">
                    <enum>(iv)</enum>
                    <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall not be provided by the department or agency of the Federal Government receiving such cyber threat information to another department or agency of the Federal Government under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="National Security Act of 1947/s:1104/ss:a/p:2/sp:A" proposed="true">paragraph (2)(A)</cato:entity-ref> if—</text> 
<subclause id="HD2AB81675C7B45C0B9381C4B8104CF21">
                      <enum>(I)</enum>
                      <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the entity providing such information determines that the provision of such information will undermine the purpose for which such information is shared; or</text>
                    </subclause> 
<subclause id="H6ABC5703A8F344B38703918206981DB9">
                      <enum>(II)</enum>
                      <text>unless otherwise directed by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref>, the head of the department or agency of the Federal Government receiving such cyber threat information determines that the provision of such information will undermine the purpose for which such information is shared; and</text>
                    </subclause>
                  </clause> 
<clause id="H7876946A36C94027BA904C3211814D86">
                    <enum>(v)</enum>
                    <text>shall be handled by the Federal Government consistent with the need to protect sources and methods and the national security of the United States; and</text>
                  </clause>
                </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA8CF47A91AC349D6A920E721BA7F3D78" display-inline="no-display-inline">
                  <enum>(D)</enum>
                  <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall be exempt from disclosure under a State, local, or tribal law or regulation that requires public disclosure of information by a public or quasi-public entity.</text>
                </subparagraph>
              </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H92307FF06EE74B1786A3B3CE12419D59">
                <enum>(4)</enum>
                <header>Exemption from liability</header>
                <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No civil or criminal cause of action shall lie or be maintained in Federal or State court against a protected entity, self-protected entity, cybersecurity provider, or an officer, employee, or agent of a protected entity, self-protected entity, or cybersecurity provider, acting in good faith—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HE6228563B916455FBFA7ECC9A7936873">
                  <enum>(A)</enum>
                  <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for using cybersecurity systems to identify or obtain cyber threat information or for sharing such information in accordance with this section; or</text>
                </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE4366F4734BA484E8EDBF47A5851CC84">
                  <enum>(B)</enum>
                  <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for decisions made based on cyber threat information identified, obtained, or shared under this section.</text>
                </subparagraph>
              </paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" id="H6C43668C16554DBE81CBB79F50B0C094">
                <enum>(5)</enum>
                <header>Relationship to other laws requiring the disclosure of information</header>
                <text>The submission of information under this subsection to the Federal Government shall not satisfy or affect—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H39ECF20C1E434996804114433DAE254B">
                  <enum>(A)</enum>
                  <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any requirement under any other provision of law for a person or entity to provide information to the Federal Government; or</text>
                </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF9BF92CE2E8D437AA9827B34D8FEC569">
                  <enum>(B)</enum>
                  <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the applicability of other provisions of law, including <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc/5/552">section 552 of title 5, United States Code</cato:entity-ref> (commonly known as the <quote>
                      <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Freedom of Information Act">Freedom of Information Act</cato:entity-ref>
                    </quote>), with respect to information required to be provided to the Federal Government under such other provision of law.</text>
                </subparagraph>
              </paragraph>
            </subsection> 
<subsection id="H3997F7CCDBFE4A58B202267544C92436">
              <enum>(c)</enum>
              <header>Federal Government use of information</header> 
<paragraph id="HE27D77D59CA4424BB7EEC3449C466BA5">
                <enum>(1)</enum>
                <header>Limitation</header>
                <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Federal Government may use cyber threat information shared with the Federal Government in accordance with <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="National Security Act of 1947/s:1104/ss:b" proposed="true">subsection (b)</cato:entity-ref>—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H7710CFABA7764B64ABD76EBA0B5DF7C6">
                  <enum>(A)</enum>
                  <text>for cybersecurity purposes;</text>
                </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H63F4AF445E1F44D584C252CC74394675">
                  <enum>(B)</enum>
                  <text>for the investigation and prosecution of cybersecurity crimes;</text>
                </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H83390582317B43169FFEFD2EA240DCE1">
                  <enum>(C)</enum>
                  <text>for the protection of individuals from the danger of death or serious bodily harm and the investigation and prosecution of crimes involving such danger of death or serious bodily harm;</text>
                </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA0965396ABFE4B9B8B77C716AF962726">
                  <enum>(D)</enum>
                  <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for the protection of minors from child pornography, any risk of sexual exploitation, and serious threats to the physical safety of minors, including kidnapping and trafficking and the investigation and prosecution of crimes involving child pornography, any risk of sexual exploitation, and serious threats to the physical safety of minors, including kidnapping and trafficking, and any crime referred to in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc/18/2258A/a/2">section 2258A(a)(2) of title 18, United States Code</cato:entity-ref>; or</text>
                </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H4746D00900F94034B400A98F7AA3D62A">
                  <enum>(E)</enum>
                  <text>to protect the national security of the United States.</text>
                </subparagraph>
              </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H46416BA1794642B39E7814BA4F81A723">
                <enum>(2)</enum>
                <header>Affirmative search restriction</header>
                <text>The Federal Government may not affirmatively search cyber threat information shared with the Federal Government under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="National Security Act of 1947/s:1104/ss:b" proposed="true">subsection (b)</cato:entity-ref> for a purpose other than a purpose referred to in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="National Security Act of 1947/s:1104/ss:b/p:1/sp:B" proposed="true">paragraph (1)(B)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
              </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H49DBCF61A2C849B99E82D4C0F8B0AC47">
                <enum>(3)</enum>
                <header>Anti-tasking restriction</header>
                <text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to permit the Federal Government to—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H91B277C9B05148B6A818FD34C80DFE87">
                  <enum>(A)</enum>
                  <text>require a private-sector entity to share information with the Federal Government; or</text>
                </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HBDC6EAE0EF86469EBF2E6E375965AE8F">
                  <enum>(B)</enum>
                  <text>condition the sharing of cyber threat intelligence with a private-sector entity on the provision of cyber threat information to the Federal Government.</text>
                </subparagraph>
              </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9BC7920E356A4BB3A7406F78BCF421E1" commented="no">
                <enum>(4)</enum>
                <header>Protection of sensitive personal documents</header>
                <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Federal Government may not use the following information, containing information that identifies a person, shared with the Federal Government in accordance with <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="National Security Act of 1947/s:1104/ss:b" proposed="true">subsection (b)</cato:entity-ref>:</text> 
<subparagraph id="H7AB1279DDC8F4F58A9836E28A69E5EF9" commented="no">
                  <enum>(A)</enum>
                  <text>Library circulation records.</text>
                </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H32164532A38C4049A1537051FAE8D95A" commented="no">
                  <enum>(B)</enum>
                  <text>Library patron lists.</text>
                </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H4306660550794B1E836D0D5D3B4C7EDC" commented="no">
                  <enum>(C)</enum>
                  <text>Book sales records.</text>
                </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H54EE27FECFB0497B94EDCD19239BC0F3" commented="no">
                  <enum>(D)</enum>
                  <text>Book customer lists.</text>
                </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H0B06366D36214581B5518B6C145F0186" commented="no">
                  <enum>(E)</enum>
                  <text>Firearms sales records.</text>
                </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H387D2B20CDD24EE8AC7C9941DCF907D1" commented="no">
                  <enum>(F)</enum>
                  <text>Tax return records.</text>
                </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H4DBE68AC78854CE8A05AD7D7A942B589" commented="no">
                  <enum>(G)</enum>
                  <text>Educational records.</text>
                </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H4C752077881143DD8027622015BEFBBE" commented="no">
                  <enum>(H)</enum>
                  <text>Medical records.</text>
                </subparagraph>
              </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H03665CE8B0BE49888BF802FE6CFB89AD">
                <enum>(5)</enum>
                <header>Notification of non-cyber threat information</header>
                <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a department or agency of the Federal Government receiving information pursuant to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="National Security Act of 1947/s:1104/ss:b/p:1" proposed="true">subsection (b)(1)</cato:entity-ref> determines that such information is not cyber threat information, such department or agency shall notify the entity or provider sharing such information pursuant to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="National Security Act of 1947/s:1104/ss:b/p:1" proposed="true">subsection (b)(1)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
              </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3CAA9AA7C9894434B8B6F444B253176D">
                <enum>(6)</enum>
                <header>Retention and use of cyber threat information</header>
                <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No department or agency of the Federal Government shall retain or use information shared pursuant to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="National Security Act of 1947/s:1104/ss:b/p:1" proposed="true">subsection (b)(1)</cato:entity-ref> for any use other than a use permitted under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="National Security Act of 1947/s:1104/ss:c/p:1" proposed="true">subsection (c)(1)</cato:entity-ref>. </text>
              </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H11D0A1FD8DF347E69BE20D10EED0F42D">
                <enum>(7)</enum>
                <header>Protection of individual information</header>
                <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Federal Government may, consistent with the need to protect Federal systems and critical information infrastructure from cybersecurity threats and to mitigate such threats, undertake reasonable efforts to limit the impact on privacy and civil liberties of the sharing of cyber threat information with the Federal Government pursuant to this subsection.</text>
              </paragraph>
            </subsection> 
<subsection id="H7F6DCF2ACBA149038E0C6CE49836C397" display-inline="no-display-inline">
              <enum>(d)</enum>
              <header>Federal Government liability for violations of restrictions on the disclosure, use, and protection of voluntarily shared information</header> 
<paragraph id="H2C3B21C550E346C0A95B1DC691F622C5">
                <enum>(1)</enum>
                <header>In general</header>
                <text>If a department or agency of the Federal Government intentionally or willfully violates <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="National Security Act of 1947/s:1104/ss:b/p:3/sp:C" proposed="true">subsection (b)(3)(C)</cato:entity-ref> or <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="National Security Act of 1947/s:1104/ss:c" proposed="true">subsection (c)</cato:entity-ref> with respect to the disclosure, use, or protection of voluntarily shared cyber threat information shared under this section, the United States shall be liable to a person adversely affected by such violation in an amount equal to the sum of—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H39E3DE8D4AFE4A6E8CF1A64D1D976F8E">
                  <enum>(A)</enum>
                  <text>the actual damages sustained by the person as a result of the violation or $1,000, whichever is greater; and</text>
                </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H4C49E2E787E64EB3BE16FDB6E6AE1C81">
                  <enum>(B)</enum>
                  <text>the costs of the action together with reasonable attorney fees as determined by the court.</text>
                </subparagraph>
              </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB8B578C052DC44AE9A8DCE1175078685">
                <enum>(2)</enum>
                <header>Venue</header>
                <text>An action to enforce liability created under this subsection may be brought in the district court of the United States in—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H5D21258B57224BC7A5F6A51F32ACD37C">
                  <enum>(A)</enum>
                  <text>the district in which the complainant resides;</text>
                </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB99CEC1DFCC54F3C92523EDF176292D2">
                  <enum>(B)</enum>
                  <text>the district in which the principal place of business of the complainant is located;</text>
                </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC5CF64B279B64F55BDBD96E797896281">
                  <enum>(C)</enum>
                  <text>the district in which the department or agency of the Federal Government that disclosed the information is located; or</text>
                </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HEB7F2DDEE8AC4CEB83FB8061909E2FC6">
                  <enum>(D)</enum>
                  <text>the District of Columbia.</text>
                </subparagraph>
              </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5022F0003ADC46EFA6A237E9F1C39AC7">
                <enum>(3)</enum>
                <header>Statute of limitations</header>
                <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No action shall lie under this subsection unless such action is commenced not later than two years after the date of the violation of <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="National Security Act of 1947/s:1104/ss:b/p:3/sp:C" proposed="true">subsection (b)(3)(C)</cato:entity-ref> or <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="National Security Act of 1947/s:1104/ss:c" proposed="true">subsection (c)</cato:entity-ref> that is the basis for the action.</text>
              </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1FE8801FE0F74DE39B3BE3C2BB40B8F2">
                <enum>(4)</enum>
                <header>Exclusive cause of action</header>
                <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A cause of action under this subsection shall be the exclusive means available to a complainant seeking a remedy for a violation of <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="National Security Act of 1947/s:1104/ss:b/p:3/sp:C" proposed="true">subsection (b)(3)(C)</cato:entity-ref> or <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="National Security Act of 1947/s:1104/ss:c" proposed="true">subsection (c)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
              </paragraph>
            </subsection> 
<subsection id="H4F69B4D6609F4A15A9D367CDDA9576FE">
              <enum>(e)</enum>
              <header>Report on information sharing</header> 
<paragraph id="HC988CAB8CF5444CFAB294796A810BEAC">
                <enum>(1)</enum>
                <header>Report</header>
                <text>The Inspector General of the Intelligence Community shall annually submit to the congressional intelligence committees a report containing a review of the use of information shared with the Federal Government under this section, including—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HD494D468A3A64AE4B90E0970F7496A28">
                  <enum>(A)</enum>
                  <text>a review of the use by the Federal Government of such information for a purpose other than a cybersecurity purpose;</text>
                </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6ECEAD57C09A4722AE3285F3FCD4F818">
                  <enum>(B)</enum>
                  <text>a review of the type of information shared with the Federal Government under this section;</text>
                </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HCAB4F1812BE3460192F02B8088329267">
                  <enum>(C)</enum>
                  <text>a review of the actions taken by the Federal Government based on such information;</text>
                </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H4A06CD4CD4DA4E0EA92602C0B3FA3B93">
                  <enum>(D)</enum>
                  <text>appropriate metrics to determine the impact of the sharing of such information with the Federal Government on privacy and civil liberties, if any;</text>
                </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC60B0EBD4B1944208904E16C146175F5" commented="no">
                  <enum>(E)</enum>
                  <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a list of the departments or agencies receiving such information;</text>
                </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF6D345F06CE347989D24FFAFC3C3AFD2">
                  <enum>(F)</enum>
                  <text>a review of the sharing of such information within the Federal Government to identify inappropriate stovepiping of shared information; and</text>
                </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2481CF8FCAA246CDA35F5E09B3AFC897">
                  <enum>(G)</enum>
                  <text>any recommendations of the Inspector General for improvements or modifications to the authorities under this section.</text>
                </subparagraph>
              </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H07020A927A324D979235E22789A12A2B">
                <enum>(2)</enum>
                <header>Form</header>
                <text>Each report required under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="National Security Act of 1947/s:1104/ss:e/p:1" proposed="true">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref> shall be submitted in unclassified form, but may include a classified annex.</text>
              </paragraph>
            </subsection> 
<subsection id="HBF81B067BE7B4ED7ACA752A42EFE7F1F">
              <enum>(f)</enum>
              <header>Federal preemption</header>
              <text>This section supersedes any statute of a State or political subdivision of a State that restricts or otherwise expressly regulates an activity authorized under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="National Security Act of 1947/s:1104/ss:b" proposed="true">subsection (b)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
            </subsection> 
<subsection id="HF6300E90CFC943C9AE007C23DC73E5A5">
              <enum>(g)</enum>
              <header>Savings clauses</header> 
<paragraph id="HF8CE99C7B1D64446AA334AC7A8D56C6F">
                <enum>(1)</enum>
                <header>Existing authorities</header>
                <text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to limit any other authority to use a cybersecurity system or to identify, obtain, or share cyber threat intelligence or cyber threat information.</text>
              </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H92FBB690D4CE492A9195C87AE09527C3">
                <enum>(2)</enum>
                <header>Limitation on military and intelligence community involvement in private and public sector cybersecurity efforts</header>
                <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this section shall be construed to provide additional authority to, or modify an existing authority of, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="9700">Department of Defense</cato:entity-ref> or the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="97CG">National Security Agency</cato:entity-ref> or any other element of the intelligence community to control, modify, require, or otherwise direct the cybersecurity efforts of a private-sector entity or a component of the Federal Government or a State, local, or tribal government.</text>
              </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB303393CC0B342808FCE4979B331DAD9">
                <enum>(3)</enum>
                <header>Information sharing relationships</header>
                <text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H62D06D041C9942B2B7E1796DD57BDAC3">
                  <enum>(A)</enum>
                  <text>limit or modify an existing information sharing relationship;</text>
                </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H8B430626AAD6462B96B72DAC98413452">
                  <enum>(B)</enum>
                  <text>prohibit a new information sharing relationship;</text>
                </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2CBBE21DCC8D4D3C8358EB6B6E3BC99D">
                  <enum>(C)</enum>
                  <text>require a new information sharing relationship between the Federal Government and a private-sector entity; or</text>
                </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB1A025613A014CD09C002039111F170E">
                  <enum>(D)</enum>
                  <text>modify the authority of a department or agency of the Federal Government to protect sources and methods and the national security of the United States.</text>
                </subparagraph>
              </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H41A1A25004FD48C4B00339CFA51D561E">
                <enum>(4)</enum>
                <header>Limitation on Federal Government use of cybersecurity systems</header>
                <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this section shall be construed to provide additional authority to, or modify an existing authority of, any entity to use a cybersecurity system owned or controlled by the Federal Government on a private-sector system or network to protect such private-sector system or network.</text>
              </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H65B449255F02474B8631CF0651BA3EA2" commented="no">
                <enum>(5)</enum>
                <header>No liability for non-participation</header>
                <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this section shall be construed to subject a protected entity, self-protected entity, cyber security provider, or an officer, employee, or agent of a protected entity, self-protected entity, or cybersecurity provider, to liability for choosing not to engage in the voluntary activities authorized under this section.</text>
              </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC590B402B26C45BD8E665D1737019809">
                <enum>(6)</enum>
                <header>Use and retention of information</header>
                <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this section shall be construed to authorize, or to modify any existing authority of, a department or agency of the Federal Government to retain or use information shared pursuant to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="National Security Act of 1947/s:1104/ss:b/p:1" proposed="true">subsection (b)(1)</cato:entity-ref> for any use other than a use permitted under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="National Security Act of 1947/s:1104/ss:c/p:1" proposed="true">subsection (c)(1)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
              </paragraph>
            </subsection> 
<subsection id="HFA8A4ADC87554CD68DF13ED3238AEC67">
              <enum>(h)</enum>
              <header>Definitions</header>
              <text>In this section:</text> 
<paragraph id="HAE677A32584945F6843D479317C71F23">
                <enum>(1)</enum>
                <header>Availability</header>
                <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>availability</quote> means ensuring timely and reliable access to and use of information.</text>
              </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H36B333AA412542648062D4520D80BDAA">
                <enum>(2)</enum>
                <header>Certified entity</header>
                <text>The term <term>certified entity</term> means a protected entity, self-protected entity, or cybersecurity provider that—</text> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H742B81C488464A7D869EFE1FADCF0008">
                  <enum>(A)</enum>
                  <text>possesses or is eligible to obtain a security clearance, as determined by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body">Director of National Intelligence</cato:entity-ref>; and</text>
                </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6F68977EA3DE4CA7990652C735762A0B">
                  <enum>(B)</enum>
                  <text>is able to demonstrate to the Director of National Intelligence that such provider or such entity can appropriately protect classified cyber threat intelligence.</text>
                </subparagraph>
              </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9FFF14E8E7DC41E381E1BDD5091DDE09">
                <enum>(3)</enum>
                <header>Confidentiality</header>
                <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>confidentiality</quote> means preserving authorized restrictions on access and disclosure, including means for protecting personal privacy and proprietary information.</text>
              </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1744313037464B48A39FA5ECD82F4C1F">
                <enum>(4)</enum>
                <header>Cyber threat information</header> 
<subparagraph id="HF5EE489F85FC46CD99748CCA4ED3F1E4">
                  <enum>(A)</enum>
                  <header>In General</header>
                  <text>The term <quote>cyber threat information</quote> means information directly pertaining to—</text> 
<clause id="HF004BF7F11B943C38A71151D2BC6E7BA">
                    <enum>(i)</enum>
                    <text>a vulnerability of a system or network of a government or private entity;</text>
                  </clause> 
<clause id="H0E4F8A82EAF949CFB134E5D2764EFB5E">
                    <enum>(ii)</enum>
                    <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a threat to the integrity, confidentiality, or availability of a system or network of a government or private entity or any information stored on, processed on, or transiting such a system or network;</text>
                  </clause> 
<clause id="H3B5F03B3D47447B98C97C7645078C537">
                    <enum>(iii)</enum>
                    <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">efforts to deny access to or degrade, disrupt, or destroy a system or network of a government or private entity; or</text>
                  </clause> 
<clause id="H488C60DEA84C4501BECFBCCC65284920">
                    <enum>(iv)</enum>
                    <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">efforts to gain unauthorized access to a system or network of a government or private entity, including to gain such unauthorized access for the purpose of exfiltrating information stored on, processed on, or transiting a system or network of a government or private entity.</text>
                  </clause>
                </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H60364C3AE2C54A61BCAAB118C1F5F813">
                  <enum>(B)</enum>
                  <header>Exclusion</header>
                  <text> Such term does not include information pertaining to efforts to gain unauthorized access to a system or network of a government or private entity that solely involve violations of consumer terms of service or consumer licensing agreements and do not otherwise constitute unauthorized access.</text>
                </subparagraph>
              </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC73719199E64479DB753E018DF8BA4B1">
                <enum>(5)</enum>
                <header>Cyber threat intelligence</header> 
<subparagraph id="H8E6490D049DC4FF59CBACCC30FD88109">
                  <enum>(A)</enum>
                  <header>In general</header>
                  <text>The term <quote>cyber threat intelligence</quote> means intelligence in the possession of an element of the intelligence community directly pertaining to—</text> 
<clause id="H47D0E94551714F358E1C539479DB52DD">
                    <enum>(i)</enum>
                    <text>a vulnerability of a system or network of a government or private entity;</text>
                  </clause> 
<clause id="H7CF8DB8B52534BBD85EEBE3D1C5AB95E">
                    <enum>(ii)</enum>
                    <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a threat to the integrity, confidentiality, or availability of a system or network of a government or private entity or any information stored on, processed on, or transiting such a system or network;</text>
                  </clause> 
<clause id="HBC51343705584032B60E4D71FB4C39DE">
                    <enum>(iii)</enum>
                    <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">efforts to deny access to or degrade, disrupt, or destroy a system or network of a government or private entity; or</text>
                  </clause> 
<clause id="HFE388B88EABA42E2AAB222DE0E134355">
                    <enum>(iv)</enum>
                    <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">efforts to gain unauthorized access to a system or network of a government or private entity, including to gain such unauthorized access for the purpose of exfiltrating information stored on, processed on, or transiting a system or network of a government or private entity.</text>
                  </clause>
                </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC9B3548D38474767B53FF61E9CBBF5AE" display-inline="no-display-inline">
                  <enum>(B)</enum>
                  <header>Exclusion</header>
                  <text> Such term does not include intelligence pertaining to efforts to gain unauthorized access to a system or network of a government or private entity that solely involve violations of consumer terms of service or consumer licensing agreements and do not otherwise constitute unauthorized access.</text>
                </subparagraph>
              </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6F710ADC45A14970A1FFF4DD53E01DFD">
                <enum>(6)</enum>
                <header>Cybersecurity crime</header>
                <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>cybersecurity crime</quote> means—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HB32455F819CE40DE93EF16D44F0001E9">
                  <enum>(A)</enum>
                  <text>a crime under a Federal or State law that involves—</text> 
<clause id="H711794A636E440A3838F3984A9DC59AF">
                    <enum>(i)</enum>
                    <text>efforts to deny access to or degrade, disrupt, or destroy a system or network;</text>
                  </clause> 
<clause id="H0C37F5C7AFE94BD1B44D1313338C56DF">
                    <enum>(ii)</enum>
                    <text>efforts to gain unauthorized access to a system or network; or</text>
                  </clause> 
<clause id="H3502E1CAD8C04CEE92EF61D7DB1DF911">
                    <enum>(iii)</enum>
                    <text>efforts to exfiltrate information from a system or network without authorization; or</text>
                  </clause>
                </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD0B107B6196C498CBBF1F205740E5867">
                  <enum>(B)</enum>
                  <text>the violation of a provision of Federal law relating to computer crimes, including a violation of any provision of <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc/18">title 18, United States Code</cato:entity-ref>, created or amended by the <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
                      <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Computer Fraud and Abuse Act of 1986">Computer Fraud and Abuse Act of 1986</cato:entity-ref> (<cato:entity-ref entity-type="public-law" value="public-law/99/474">Public Law 99–474</cato:entity-ref>)</cato:entity>.</text>
                </subparagraph>
              </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H46BAB7ED01AB4AEEB14F9E7F8D3DE60B">
                <enum>(7)</enum>
                <header>Cybersecurity provider</header>
                <text>The term <term>cybersecurity provider</term> means a non-governmental entity that provides goods or services intended to be used for cybersecurity purposes.</text>
              </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HAF601F36B77C4C5EBF3ED2577A5CC32A">
                <enum>(8)</enum>
                <header>Cybersecurity purpose</header> 
<subparagraph id="H4DDCCB8F35ED47DB99CAB6B4D6E3AA5E">
                  <enum>(A)</enum>
                  <header>In general</header>
                  <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>cybersecurity purpose</quote> means the purpose of ensuring the integrity, confidentiality, or availability of, or safeguarding, a system or network, including protecting a system or network from—</text> 
<clause id="HFCD8650461D348AABA60C7FC97918BF0">
                    <enum>(i)</enum>
                    <text>a vulnerability of a system or network;</text>
                  </clause> 
<clause id="HA16382694B5D4BCA9CCD614E8E78853C">
                    <enum>(ii)</enum>
                    <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a threat to the integrity, confidentiality, or availability of a system or network or any information stored on, processed on, or transiting such a system or network;</text>
                  </clause> 
<clause id="HEE8331FA1F8D419DB9BED0F9A7D9F842">
                    <enum>(iii)</enum>
                    <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">efforts to deny access to or degrade, disrupt, or destroy a system or network; or</text>
                  </clause> 
<clause id="H99BD8686BF1C405E9146A828624CA317">
                    <enum>(iv)</enum>
                    <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">efforts to gain unauthorized access to a system or network, including to gain such unauthorized access for the purpose of exfiltrating information stored on, processed on, or transiting a system or network.</text>
                  </clause>
                </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HAA64F5DDDA824213922C3EB5B924E1AF">
                  <enum>(B)</enum>
                  <header>Exclusion</header>
                  <text> Such term does not include the purpose of protecting a system or network from efforts to gain unauthorized access to such system or network that solely involve violations of consumer terms of service or consumer licensing agreements and do not otherwise constitute unauthorized access.</text>
                </subparagraph>
              </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H734C8D1173B9455993F1F8E739E66E7C" display-inline="no-display-inline">
                <enum>(9)</enum>
                <header>Cybersecurity system</header> 
<subparagraph id="HFD3A02997ED942F0B1B7BBBCC69F3842">
                  <enum>(A)</enum>
                  <header>In general</header>
                  <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>cybersecurity system</quote> means a system designed or employed to ensure the integrity, confidentiality, or availability of, or safeguard, a system or network, including protecting a system or network from—</text> 
<clause id="HECFC1493D20648AEBC8F2602D7165580">
                    <enum>(i)</enum>
                    <text>a vulnerability of a system or network;</text>
                  </clause> 
<clause id="HAE54FD08CB7D484E84D01AFE50C4E25C">
                    <enum>(ii)</enum>
                    <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a threat to the integrity, confidentiality, or availability of a system or network or any information stored on, processed on, or transiting such a system or network;</text>
                  </clause> 
<clause id="HA101F7F84CAA4C7A8208537DC98457D6">
                    <enum>(iii)</enum>
                    <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">efforts to deny access to or degrade, disrupt, or destroy a system or network; or</text>
                  </clause> 
<clause id="H6167F6F8D64C43CE9B9B1A36DB295F6B">
                    <enum>(iv)</enum>
                    <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">efforts to gain unauthorized access to a system or network, including to gain such unauthorized access for the purpose of exfiltrating information stored on, processed on, or transiting a system or network.</text>
                  </clause>
                </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD903515BCD4247769319AEF5F68A4B3E">
                  <enum>(B)</enum>
                  <header>Exclusion</header>
                  <text> Such term does not include a system designed or employed to protect a system or network from efforts to gain unauthorized access to such system or network that solely involve violations of consumer terms of service or consumer licensing agreements and do not otherwise constitute unauthorized access.</text>
                </subparagraph>
              </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE3BD48B7C1D5460EB01DA8671888EE68">
                <enum>(10)</enum>
                <header>Integrity</header>
                <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>integrity</quote> means guarding against improper information modification or destruction, including ensuring information nonrepudiation and authenticity.</text>
              </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCA3053C38FA9484DBF6E350F41D040FD">
                <enum>(11)</enum>
                <header>Protected entity</header>
                <text>The term <term>protected entity</term> means an entity, other than an individual, that contracts with a cybersecurity provider for goods or services to be used for cybersecurity purposes.</text>
              </paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" id="HD315BFFE5C90465598E674E017421870">
                <enum>(12)</enum>
                <header>Self-protected entity</header>
                <text>The term <term>self-protected entity</term> means an entity, other than an individual, that provides goods or services for cybersecurity purposes to itself.</text>
              </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE0822919E7EC4ACFBEE25B2769416888" display-inline="no-display-inline">
                <enum>(13)</enum>
                <header>Utility</header>
                <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>utility</term> means an entity providing essential services (other than law enforcement or regulatory services), including electricity, natural gas, propane, telecommunications, transportation, water, or wastewater services.</text>
              </paragraph>
            </subsection>
          </section>
          <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
        </quoted-block>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="H0AAA8202678A4ADB9B33A993F306F0DA">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Procedures and guidelines</header>
        <text>The Director of National Intelligence shall—</text> 
<paragraph id="H079CDBE13C814306AE7618B6AD55A6E6">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not later than 60 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, establish procedures under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="National Security Act of 1947/s:1104/ss:a/p:1" proposed="true">paragraph (1) of section 1104(a) of the National Security Act of 1947</cato:entity-ref>, as added by <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="National Security Act of 1947/s:1104/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref> of this section, and issue guidelines under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="National Security Act of 1947/s:1104/ss:a/p:3" proposed="true">paragraph (3) of such section 1104(a)</cato:entity-ref>;</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFAB9C0263C5C462FB186239670F12CC6" display-inline="no-display-inline">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in establishing such procedures and issuing such guidelines, consult with the Secretary of Homeland Security to ensure that such procedures and such guidelines permit the owners and operators of critical infrastructure to receive all appropriate cyber threat intelligence (as defined in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="National Security Act of 1947/s:1104/ss:h/p:3" proposed="true">section 1104(h)(3) of such Act</cato:entity-ref>, as added by <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="National Security Act of 1947/s:1104/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref>) in the possession of the Federal Government; and</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" id="HF3B13A0C40864656A532BBB94301D402">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <text>following the establishment of such procedures and the issuance of such guidelines, expeditiously distribute such procedures and such guidelines to appropriate departments and agencies of the Federal Government, private-sector entities, and utilities (as defined in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="National Security Act of 1947/s:1104/ss:h/p:9" proposed="true">section 1104(h)(9) of such Act</cato:entity-ref>, as added by <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="National Security Act of 1947/s:1104/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref>).</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="HC6D4BECDEDFC4537916F7D31AD3EBAE6">
        <enum>(c)</enum>
        <header>Initial report</header>
        <text>The first report required to be submitted under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="National Security Act of 1947/s:1104/ss:e" proposed="true">subsection (e) of section 1104 of the National Security Act of 1947</cato:entity-ref>, as added by <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="National Security Act of 1947/s:1104/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref> of this section, shall be submitted not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="H7E6F762007454B47A883C4AF77194D41">
        <enum>(d)</enum>
        <header>Table of contents amendment</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of contents in the first <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="National Security Act of 1947/s:1">section of the National Security Act of 1947</cato:entity-ref> is amended by adding at the end the following new item:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE9C78E313F7B42F5A21DBFF8C21E733A" style="traditional"> 
<toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> 
<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 1104. Cyber threat intelligence and information sharing.</toc-entry>
          </toc>
          <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
        </quoted-block>
      </subsection>
    </section> 
<section id="H023713C98927452A9ECFD16DF8BE7071" commented="no">
      <enum>3.</enum>
      <header>Sunset</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Effective on the date that is 5 years after the date of the enactment of this Act—</text> 
<paragraph id="HA48D00CBCE6A429DA428815EC328B51F" commented="no">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text>
          <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="National Security Act of 1947/s:1104" proposed="true">section 1104 of the National Security Act of 1947</cato:entity-ref>, as added by <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="National Security Act of 1947/s:2/ss:a" proposed="true">section 2(a)</cato:entity-ref> of this Act, is repealed; and</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H62B49130AD9A419A9D22B7E702C98C58" commented="no">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text>the table of contents in the first <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="National Security Act of 1947/s:1">section of the National Security Act of 1947</cato:entity-ref>, as amended by <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="National Security Act of 1947/s:2/ss:d" proposed="true">section 2(d)</cato:entity-ref> of this Act, is amended by striking the item relating to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="National Security Act of 1947/s:1104" proposed="true">section 1104</cato:entity-ref>, as added by such <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="National Security Act of 1947/s:2/ss:d" proposed="true">section 2(d)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
      </paragraph>
    </section> 
</legis-body> 
</bill></doc>