<doc>
  <docmeta id="113hr3621ih">
    <bill congress="113" type="hr" number="3621" version="ih"/>
    <revision size="2329" annotations="0" status="complete" id="3" commit-time="2013-12-05T23:17:43Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113hr3621ih/3.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H67897BF650F3459ABE6F83D355E33A4C" public-private="public">
  <metadata>
<dublinCore>
<dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">113 HR 3621 IH: To provide for access to health insurance coverage of life-sustaining treatments furnished by certain providers.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">2013-11-22</dc:date>
<dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
    <congress>113th CONGRESS</congress>
    <session>1st Session</session>
    <legis-num>H. R. 3621</legis-num>
    <current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
    <action>
      <action-date date="20131122">November 22, 2013</action-date>
      <action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="D000614">Mr. Duffy</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>
      </action-desc>
    </action>
    <legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
    <official-title>To provide for access to health insurance coverage of life-sustaining treatments furnished by certain providers.</official-title>
  </form>
  <legis-body id="H1D25337E6E494E058395CADBB92E191E" style="OLC">
    <section id="H2A2E4B191CAE4D56BADB9FF1351469C4" section-type="section-one">
      <enum>1.</enum>
      <header>Providing for access to health insurance coverage of life-sustaining treatments furnished by certain providers</header>
      <subsection id="H3027F4F1067748A995E05EDC80127FF7">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>In general</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, in the case of an individual who resides in a State and who as of December 31 of a year had in effect health insurance coverage that provided benefits for a life-sustaining treatment, with respect to a health condition of such individual, furnished by a provider that before such date furnished one or more services to such individual related to such condition, if—</text>
        <paragraph id="HFAEB1DA36A0C421391CB309CB5B6A53A">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>such coverage for such individual is not continued for the plan year beginning after such date; and</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H3BD9FEEACCBF42E8A12A0FF05AD6C0CA">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>there is no health insurance coverage offered in such State that provides for coverage of such life-saving treatment by such provider;</text>
        </paragraph>
        <continuation-text continuation-text-level="subsection">the individual may enroll in health insurance coverage offered in any other State, which provides for coverage of such operation by such provider, as if such individual were a resident of such other State.</continuation-text>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="H3FE4BFDA3BC84A00982F57016EB5FF80">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Life-Sustaining treatment defined</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="113 HR 3621/s:1/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref>, the term <term>life-sustaining treatment</term> means, with respect to an individual, any medical device or procedure, including a drug, ventilator, surgery, therapy, or artificially provided fluids and nutrients, that, as certified by the health care provider of such individual, is required to increase life expectancy of such individual by restoring or taking over a vital bodily function.</text>
      </subsection>
    </section>
  </legis-body>
</bill>
</doc>