<doc>
  <docmeta id="113hr3994ih">
    <bill congress="113" type="hr" number="3994" version="ih"/>
    <revision size="14262" annotations="0" status="complete" id="4" commit-time="2014-02-07T15:26:15Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113hr3994ih/4.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HAF8C4193852A465082DD7663C6C29167" public-private="public">
  <metadata>
<dublinCore>
<dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">113 HR 3994 IH: Federal Lands Invasive Species Control, Prevention, and Management Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">2014-02-05</dc:date>
<dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
    <congress>113th CONGRESS</congress>
    <session>2d Session</session>
    <legis-num>H. R. 3994</legis-num>
    <current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
    <action>
      <action-date date="20140205">February 5, 2014</action-date>
      <action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="B001250">Mr. Bishop of Utah</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="H001066">Mr. Horsford</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Agriculture</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
    </action>
    <legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
    <official-title>To improve the control and management of invasive species that threaten and harm Federal lands under the jurisdiction of the Secretary of Agriculture and the Secretary of the Interior, and for other purposes.</official-title>
  </form>
  <legis-body id="H066B6A825B78429780E1D8B6DEC7A048" style="OLC">
    <section id="H23695D2854A941A6833CF9D41E7310FE" section-type="section-one">
      <enum>1.</enum>
      <header>Short title; table of contents</header>
      <subsection id="H1D8ABB1ED12C49B3BA5EF43150AF3C96">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Short title</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote>
            <short-title>
              <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Federal Lands Invasive Species Control, Prevention, and Management Act" proposed="true">Federal Lands Invasive Species Control, Prevention, and Management Act</cato:entity-ref>
            </short-title>
          </quote>.</text>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="H4BEC2BB317CD47ECAEFBED36C053CECE">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Table of contents</header>
        <text>The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text>
        <toc container-level="legis-body-container" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded" lowest-level="section" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" regeneration="yes-regeneration">
          <toc-entry idref="H23695D2854A941A6833CF9D41E7310FE" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title; table of contents.</toc-entry>
          <toc-entry idref="HFB3E4EE4C87F4E51A4ACEB6B6833CC34" level="section">Sec. 2. Definitions.</toc-entry>
          <toc-entry idref="H91FD075EDDCA4B7AB0B1184D57FB0E52" level="section">Sec. 3. Federal efforts to control and manage invasive species on Federal lands.</toc-entry>
          <toc-entry idref="H9670256502A1446CAB64F24194A17B7F" level="section">Sec. 4. Program funding allocations.</toc-entry>
          <toc-entry idref="H8F4E297821494EAB8253AA45415490F2" level="section">Sec. 5. Prudent use of funds.</toc-entry>
          <toc-entry idref="H896D35607A5547A3BBD92AF3B92907A7" level="section">Sec. 6. Use of partnerships.</toc-entry>
        </toc>
      </subsection>
    </section>
    <section id="HFB3E4EE4C87F4E51A4ACEB6B6833CC34">
      <enum>2.</enum>
      <header>Definitions</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text>
      <paragraph id="H8955E548940544B4AB3B4E9E680BE9DF">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <header>Alien species</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>alien species</term> means, with respect to a particular ecosystem, any species, including its seeds, eggs, spores, or other biological material capable of propagating that species, that is not native to that ecosystem.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H98BBB9E6CD344383925C171FCE4B9119">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <header>Control</header>
        <text>The term <term>control</term> means the eradication, suppression, or reduction of the population of an invasive species within the area in which the invasive species is present.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H4024036BD0244CE3A78BD3D3D4FEB439">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <header>Ecosystem</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>ecosystem</term> means the complex of a community of organisms and its environment.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H461889A3FF6A450DA8A90605FE4BD9AA">
        <enum>(4)</enum>
        <header>Eligible state</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>eligible State</term> means any of the several States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, American Samoa, Guam, and the United States Virgin Islands.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H5181278BE35043748C44B97DDEAE1897">
        <enum>(5)</enum>
        <header>Invasive species</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>invasive species</term> means an alien species whose introduction does or is likely to cause economic or environmental harm or harm to human health.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H987FD54CF4ED4246B363AA7C55F3E8E9">
        <enum>(6)</enum>
        <header>Manage</header>
        <text>The terms <term>manage</term> and <term>management</term> mean the active implementation of activities—</text>
        <subparagraph id="H9B5B1FEE4BCE4CF5970C9FA83BFFD237">
          <enum>(A)</enum>
          <text>to reduce or stop the spread of an invasive species; and</text>
        </subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="H69996D257E36407B904C5B9B31A3E4FE">
          <enum>(B)</enum>
          <text>to inhibit further infestations or spread of invasive species or harm caused by invasive species, including investigations regarding methods to prevent, control, or manage invasive species.</text>
        </subparagraph>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H279D154E116D48A4B69415AE64F08588">
        <enum>(7)</enum>
        <header>Prevent</header>
        <text>The term <term>prevent</term> means to hinder the introduction of invasive species onto lands or waters or to impede the spread of invasive species within lands or waters by inspecting, intercepting, or confiscating invasive species threats prior to their establishment onto lands or waters of an eligible State.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H206B29C477934094B31E483D3D718DA0">
        <enum>(8)</enum>
        <header>Secretary concerned</header>
        <text>The term <term>Secretary concerned</term> means—</text>
        <subparagraph id="HE42F454E3D92486E9124AF8A93E39DE4">
          <enum>(A)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1400">Secretary of the Interior</cato:entity-ref>, with respect to Federal lands administered by that Secretary through the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1450">Bureau of Indian Affairs</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1422">Bureau of Land Management</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1425">Bureau of Reclamation</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1443">National Park Service</cato:entity-ref>, or the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1448">United States Fish and Wildlife Service</cato:entity-ref>; and</text>
        </subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="H59953BE32B114EB299AF50796831FB7A">
          <enum>(B)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1200">Secretary of Agriculture</cato:entity-ref>, with respect to Federal lands administered by that Secretary through the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="12C2">United States Forest Service</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
        </subparagraph>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HDA0E1E14117548C686B5D6FD732EA2E4">
        <enum>(9)</enum>
        <header>Species</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>species</term> means a group of organisms, all of which have a high degree of physical and genetic similarity, generally interbreed only among themselves, and show persistent differences from members of allied groups of organisms.</text>
      </paragraph>
    </section>
    <section id="H91FD075EDDCA4B7AB0B1184D57FB0E52">
      <enum>3.</enum>
      <header>Federal efforts to control and manage invasive species on Federal lands</header>
      <subsection id="H14B3F392ECE84158B63D2B48DC0D6D24">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Control and management</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary concerned shall plan and carry out activities on lands directly managed by the Secretary concerned to control and manage invasive species to inhibit or reduce their populations and to effectuate restoration or reclamation efforts.</text>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="HB0874AF2F10141A79A953C6B75287AB5">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Strategic plan</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary concerned shall develop a strategic plan for the implementation of the invasive species program of that Secretary to endeavor to achieve an annual five percent net reduction of invasive species populations on lands managed by that Secretary.</text>
      </subsection>
    </section>
    <section id="H9670256502A1446CAB64F24194A17B7F">
      <enum>4.</enum>
      <header>Program funding allocations</header>
      <subsection id="HFFB4C525AD304E209488FB8A3A7F436F">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Control and management activities</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Of the amount appropriated or otherwise made available to the Secretary concerned for a fiscal year for programs that address or include invasive species management, the Secretary concerned shall use not less than 75 percent of the amount for on-the-ground control and management of invasive species, including through—</text>
        <paragraph id="H39B4766F5A5040A081BFD91B0D70D883">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>the purchase of necessary products, equipment, or services to conduct such control and management;</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H185E70B869C949B99CA66D9F602D3C61">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>the use of integrated pest management options, including pesticides authorized for sale, distribution, or use under the <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Federal Insecticide, Fungicide, and Rodenticide Act">Federal Insecticide, Fungicide, and Rodenticide Act</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/136">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/7/136/etseq">7 U.S.C. 136 et seq</cato:entity-ref>.</external-xref>)</cato:entity>;</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HC78FF42064B2471F81079B3574097984">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <text>the use of biological control agents that are proven to be effective to reduce invasive species populations;</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H46C600CA578D4D22A65AA00D45C573B3">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
          <text>the use of re-vegetation or cultural restoration methods designed to improve the diversity and richness of ecosystems; or</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H7370924D0CDF42A3B1D486C53645CC26">
          <enum>(5)</enum>
          <text>the use of other effective mechanical or manual control method.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="H6921B668DA964543B408FFBED8C2D59D">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Investigations, outreach, and public awareness</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Of the amount appropriated or otherwise made available to the Secretary concerned for a fiscal year for programs that address or include invasive species management, the Secretary concerned may use not more than 15 percent of the amount for investigations, development activities, and outreach and public awareness efforts to address invasive species control and management needs.</text>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="H319EDB572418492B9D54F4FAB40DF231">
        <enum>(c)</enum>
        <header>Administrative costs</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Of the amount appropriated or otherwise made available to the Secretary concerned for a fiscal year for programs that address or include invasive species management, not more than 10 percent may be used for administrative costs incurred to carry out such programs, including costs related to oversight and management of such programs, recordkeeping, and implementation of the strategic plan.</text>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="H2133F5C8126E491DAD98055719470DED">
        <enum>(d)</enum>
        <header>Reporting requirements</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 60 days after the end of the second fiscal year beginning after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary concerned shall submit to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> a report—</text>
        <paragraph id="HA2E96D4DFA1945A09E0653D2981059FD">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>describing the use by that Secretary during the preceding two fiscal years of funds for programs that address or include invasive species management; and</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H740F7EFBA1914FF6AB5DAFA0A74E81D3">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>specifying the percentage of funds expended for each of the purposes specified in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Federal Lands Invasive Species Control, Prevention, and Management Act/s:4/ss:a" proposed="true">subsections (a)</cato:entity-ref>, <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Federal Lands Invasive Species Control, Prevention, and Management Act/s:4/ss:b" proposed="true">(b)</cato:entity-ref>, and <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Federal Lands Invasive Species Control, Prevention, and Management Act/s:4/ss:c" proposed="true">(c)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
    </section>
    <section id="H8F4E297821494EAB8253AA45415490F2">
      <enum>5.</enum>
      <header>Prudent use of funds</header>
      <subsection id="H7688406FBA1A4FB7A210BAA186EFA4B3">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Cost-Effective methods</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In selecting the method or methods to be used to control or manage an invasive species as part of a specific control or management project, the Secretary concerned shall require the use of the least costly options based on sound scientific data and other commonly used cost-effective benchmarks in the area to effectively control and manage invasive species.</text>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="H5A0E47B5F9CE4D0F8C12D4D4B7030E42">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Comparative economic assessment</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary concerned shall require a comparative economic assessment of invasive species control and management methods to be conducted to comply with <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Federal Lands Invasive Species Control, Prevention, and Management Act/s:5/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="HAC3878595E384A578FB3116E38A6F9CE">
        <enum>(c)</enum>
        <header>Categorical exclusion</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If an invasive species control or management project or activity to be conducted on lands directly managed by the Secretary concerned will be conducted in a prioritized, high-risk area involving the treatment of land or waterways within 1,000 feet of a water body or waterway, a water project, a utility or telephone infrastructure or right of way, a railroad line, an airport, a port of entry, campground, roadside or highway, heritage site, a national monument, a park, recreation site, school, or other similar and valuable infrastructure, as determined by the Secretary concerned, the project or activity is categorically excluded from the requirement to prepare an environmental assessment or an environmental impact statement under the <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="National Environmental Policy Act of 1969">National Environmental Policy Act of 1969</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4321">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/42/4321/etseq">42 U.S.C. 4321 et seq</cato:entity-ref>.</external-xref>)</cato:entity> so long as the Secretary concerned determines that the project or activity is otherwise conducted consistently with agency procedures, including any land and resource management plan or land use plan applicable to the area covered by the project or activity.</text>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="H288C75AA064D4ABB951047F8B679DF32">
        <enum>(d)</enum>
        <header>Relation to other authority</header>
        <paragraph id="HC99FD87F71224D3299BB7AEA653CAE1C">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>Other invasive species control, prevention, or management authorities</header>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this Act shall be construed to preclude the Secretary concerned from pursuing or supporting, under the authority of any other provision of law, activities regarding the control, prevention, or management of invasive species, including investigations to better control, prevent, or manage invasive species.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HFFE92A0A1F694F47A804AEA1561CD47F">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Public water supply systems</header>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this Act shall be construed to authorize the Secretary concerned to suspend water deliveries or diversions or otherwise prevent the operation of a public water supply system as a measure to control, manage, or prevent the introduction or spread of invasive species.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
    </section>
    <section id="H896D35607A5547A3BBD92AF3B92907A7">
      <enum>6.</enum>
      <header>Use of partnerships</header>
      <subsection id="HF95781B883B84EB5B28D8879B864E91B">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Partnerships authorized</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary concerned may enter into contracts and cooperative agreements with another Federal agency, an eligible State, a political subdivision of an eligible State, or a private entity to partner with the Secretary concerned and assist with the control and management of invasive species.</text>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="H204226C8CBBA48B4977C30966BE9B855">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Memorandum of understanding</header>
        <paragraph id="HD8A9B70AA4484F1E9B75808CB97C563B">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>Required</header>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">As a condition of a contract or cooperative agreement under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Federal Lands Invasive Species Control, Prevention, and Management Act/s:6/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref>, the Secretary concerned and the other Federal agency, eligible State, political subdivision of an eligible State, or private entity involved shall enter into a memorandum of understanding describing the nature of the partnership between the parties and the control and management activities to be conducted.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H731768D342094FEA95B334871C41BD54">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Contents</header>
          <text>The memorandum of understanding shall contain, at a minimum, the following:</text>
          <subparagraph id="H55A30AB60E694E8D89590A49C9366D80">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>A prioritized listing of invasive species to be controlled or managed.</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H8AA21B758B16428AA6E4669622358707">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>An assessment of the total acres or area infested by the invasive species.</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H17A03B03EE8C4E78B0CE3695B585F98B">
            <enum>(C)</enum>
            <text>An estimate of the expected total acres or area infested by the invasive species after control and management of the invasive species is attempted.</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H6ADA9148D9EB4D138FCC4CBC194B62F6">
            <enum>(D)</enum>
            <text>The specific integrated pest management option or options to be used, including a comparative economic assessment to determine the least costly method.</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="HB7B296B9DDE44BC096346AB6702DE2C8">
            <enum>(E)</enum>
            <text>Any maps, boundaries, or Global Positioning System (GPS) coordinates needed to clearly identify the area in which the control and management activities are to be conducted.</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H49DC70C2C4D84B868FF43B25980BDE6C">
            <enum>(F)</enum>
            <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Written assurances that the partner will comply with <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Federal Noxious Weed Act of 1974/s:15">section 15 of the Federal Noxious Weed Act of 1974</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/2814">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/7/2814">7 U.S.C. 2814</cato:entity-ref>
              </external-xref>)</cato:entity>.</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="H0BAF1F65138A40CAA0F45A57520DAEAA">
        <enum>(c)</enum>
        <header>Coordination</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the partner in a contract or cooperative agreement under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Federal Lands Invasive Species Control, Prevention, and Management Act/s:6/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref> is an eligible State, political subdivision of an eligible State, or private entity, the memorandum of understanding shall also contain a description of how the control and management efforts will be coordinated and the expected outcomes of managing and controlling the invasive species.</text>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="HB2FB5F57BE3E4DE2B110C740CEB5CC60">
        <enum>(d)</enum>
        <header>Public outreach and awareness efforts</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a contract or cooperative agreement under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Federal Lands Invasive Species Control, Prevention, and Management Act/s:6/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref> will involve any outreach and public awareness efforts, the memorandum of understanding shall also contain a list of goals and objectives for such outreach and public awareness efforts that have been determined will be efficient to inform national, State, regional, or local audiences regarding invasive species control and management.</text>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="H8770A112FF1C4B3980A7FAA99F063B8E">
        <enum>(e)</enum>
        <header>Investigations</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any invasive species-related investigations undertaken under a contract or cooperative agreement under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Federal Lands Invasive Species Control, Prevention, and Management Act/s:6/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref> shall be undertaken for the purpose of—</text>
        <paragraph id="HCFCAECA3FC9F4B69A3DE643F68D24A97">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">developing solutions and specific recommendations for control and management of invasive species; and</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HFB4C8436F98E496AB4D624991462A4E7">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>specifically providing faster implementation of control and management methods.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
    </section>
  </legis-body>
</bill>
</doc>