<doc>
  <docmeta id="113hr3749ih">
    <bill congress="113" type="hr" number="3749" version="ih"/>
    <revision size="5047" annotations="0" status="complete" id="3" commit-time="2014-01-02T04:02:57Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113hr3749ih/3.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H12EAAF9109694939A716D1A947268D2D" public-private="public">
  <metadata>
<dublinCore>
<dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">113 HR 3749 IH: Medicare Demonstration of Coverage for Low Vision Devices Act of 2013</dc:title>
<dc:publisher xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">2013-12-12</dc:date>
<dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
    <congress>113th CONGRESS</congress>
    <session>1st Session</session>
    <legis-num>H. R. 3749</legis-num>
    <current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
    <action>
      <action-date date="20131212">December 12, 2013</action-date>
      <action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="M000087">Mrs. Carolyn B. Maloney of New York</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="B001257">Mr. Bilirakis</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
    </action>
    <legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
    <official-title>To provide for a Medicare demonstration project to evaluate the fiscal impact of covering low vision devices as durable medical equipment under part B of the Medicare program.</official-title>
  </form>
  <legis-body id="HC05B3AEDA62C4DA3B6F89E3E7AB42A56" style="OLC">
    <section id="H20C93D1E25BD49248AE80E9738493545" section-type="section-one">
      <enum>1.</enum>
      <header>Short title</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote>
          <short-title>Medicare Demonstration of Coverage for Low Vision Devices Act of 2013</short-title>
        </quote>.</text>
    </section>
    <section id="H7A5F35396E224F3CB38EC39C62188B5D">
      <enum>2.</enum>
      <header>Demonstration of Medicare coverage of low vision devices as durable medical equipment</header>
      <subsection id="HCB75588EDE24470CBC8E0AEB2636FE9C">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Establishment of demonstration project</header>
        <paragraph id="H5C0D9A176C594E41A434C30C77258CCF">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>In general</header>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Beginning not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary of Health and Human Services</cato:entity-ref> (in this section referred to as the <quote>Secretary</quote>) shall commence a project (in this section referred to as the <quote>demonstration project</quote>) to demonstrate and evaluate the impact of covering low vision devices (including subsets of such devices) under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Social Security Act/t:XVIII/pt:B">part B of title XVIII of the Social Security Act</cato:entity-ref> in the same or similar manner as coverage is provided for durable medical equipment under such part.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H5C341E386D224EF2B3005234B3D1D00C">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Low vision device defined</header>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <term>low vision device</term> means a device, prescribed by a physician, that magnifies, enhances, or otherwise augments or interprets visual images irrespective of the size, form, or technological features of such device and does not include ordinary eyeglasses or contact lenses or a device that is otherwise available for non-prescription retail sale to the general public at a cost of less than $500. In the previous sentence, the term <term>ordinary eyeglasses or contact lenses</term> means lenses that are intended to fully correct visual acuity or eliminate refractive error.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="HF2C7D9E8FCA04969B09A809DBEDC15D3">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Project details</header>
        <paragraph id="H9BF73C9D35124C6E99A348AB10A69F0E">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>Eligible participants</header>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An individual enrolled under such part is eligible to participate in the demonstration project if an ophthalmologist or optometrist, after a clinical evaluation, has determined and certifies through a prescription that furnishing a low vision device to the individual is medically necessary.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H6B8934CD983E4C7295D01447237902B0">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>National scope and duration</header>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The demonstration project shall be national in scope and shall be conducted for a period of 5 years.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HA454B0E2704545B590EBBB00284AFA4B">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <header>Project design</header>
          <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall design the demonstration project in a manner so as to provide a rich, well-structured, and defined data set from which inferences about the impact of the project can be made using appropriate statistical methods.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HAB49782D35BF4C7E8A8B07A72842F644">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
          <header>Consultation</header>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In conducting the demonstration project the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall consult with organizations of consumers with vision loss and other stakeholder organizations.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="H9D6BFCEC18EC4A62A0186A8B5365956E">
        <enum>(c)</enum>
        <header>Reports</header>
        <paragraph id="HCC9E0D698A1D4F6192A17FC86278074A">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>Interim report</header>
          <text>Not later than 180 days after the last day of the third year of the demonstration project, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall submit to the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="committee" entity-id="SSFI00">Committee on Finance of the Senate</cato:entity-ref> and to the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="committee" entity-id="HWM00">Committees on Ways and Means</cato:entity-ref> and <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="committee" entity-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives</cato:entity-ref> a report that describes the progress and preliminary findings from the demonstration project.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H02FF214E128E4524B929E9EED8CC136D">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Final report</header>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the last day of the demonstration project and after solicitation and consideration of formal written input on the project from organizations representing consumers with vision loss and other stakeholder organizations, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall submit to such Committees a final report on the project. Such report shall include an evaluation of the fiscal impact on the Medicare program of providing coverage of low vision devices and such other findings and recommendations as the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> deems appropriate.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="H289B73DFA998472291462DFD9DB3EBAE">
        <enum>(d)</enum>
        <header>Funding</header>
        <text>
          <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="auth-approp">For fiscal year 2014 and for each of the four succeeding fiscal years, out of any funds in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, <cato:funds-and-year amount="2500000" year="2014,..">$2,500,000</cato:funds-and-year> is appropriated <cato:property name="purpose">to the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> to carry out the demonstration project</cato:property>.</cato:entity>
        </text>
      </subsection>
    </section>
  </legis-body>
</bill>
</doc>