<doc>
  <docmeta id="113hr3294ih">
    <bill congress="113" type="hr" number="3294" version="ih"/>
    <revision size="11906" annotations="0" status="complete" id="3" commit-time="2013-10-18T21:29:56Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113hr3294ih/3.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HDDDA19656C5F4905B0CA1B9E8C7F38EC" public-private="public">
  <metadata>
<dublinCore>
<title>113 HR 3294 IH: State-Run Federal Lands Act</title>
<publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</publisher>
<date>2013-10-15</date>
<format>text/xml</format>
<language>EN</language>
<rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
    <congress>113th CONGRESS</congress>
    <session>1st Session</session>
    <legis-num>H. R. 3294</legis-num>
    <current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
    <action>
      <action-date date="20131015">October 15, 2013</action-date>
      <action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="Y000033">Mr. Young of Alaska</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Agriculture</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
    </action>
    <legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
    <official-title>To establish a streamlined process through which a State may claim authority over and responsibility for management of Federal lands located in the State without claiming ownership of the land, and for other purposes.</official-title>
  </form>
  <legis-body id="HAB09FDE6218D42F99917F50387CD7DF7" style="OLC">
    <section id="H60E28C9A060C4615866CA7BE2BE43680" section-type="section-one">
      <enum>1.</enum>
      <header>Short title</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote>
          <short-title>State-Run Federal Lands Act</short-title>
        </quote>.</text>
    </section>
    <section id="HD7E00FA2182648FABF94243FE384DB0E">
      <enum>2.</enum>
      <header>Definitions</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text>
      <paragraph id="HEC42C7BC1E854519A0A9A4076B1FF4A3">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <header>Qualifying Federal land</header>
        <text>The term <term>qualifying Federal land</term> means Federal land under the jurisdiction of—</text>
        <subparagraph id="H88F655B9A9C54B668C2FD812573C4535">
          <enum>(A)</enum>
          <text>the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1443">National Park Service</cato:entity-ref>, including national monuments and recreation areas;</text>
        </subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="H609B776FE6C742E0ADDA406498463661">
          <enum>(B)</enum>
          <text>the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1422">Bureau of Land Management</cato:entity-ref>;</text>
        </subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="H36D6867F97C9473D9FE7D7AE9CDE4845">
          <enum>(C)</enum>
          <text>the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="12C2">Forest Service</cato:entity-ref>; or</text>
        </subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="H3AF0BD0ACF7A4BAB9717E2C59A278A82">
          <enum>(D)</enum>
          <text>the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1448">United States Fish and Wildlife Service</cato:entity-ref>, including wildlife refuges and preserves.</text>
        </subparagraph>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HAE18F2A940A44CB183D3A2F99707640D">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <header>Secretary concerned</header>
        <text>The term <term>Secretary concerned</term> means—</text>
        <subparagraph id="HBFB98B5992CB42168C7D4569B9C702D3">
          <enum>(A)</enum>
          <text>in the case of land under the jurisdiction of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1443">National Park Service</cato:entity-ref> or the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1448">United States Fish and Wildlife Service</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1400">Secretary of the Interior</cato:entity-ref>; and</text>
        </subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="HD2E627B221E24F8C90341DCA956EF636">
          <enum>(B)</enum>
          <text>in the case of land under the jurisdiction of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="12C2">Forest Service</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1200">Secretary of Agriculture</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
        </subparagraph>
      </paragraph>
    </section>
    <section id="H55F65BE9652B4FFC8FC9631E6DE6A501">
      <enum>3.</enum>
      <header>Petition by states for management of certain qualifying Federal lands</header>
      <subsection id="H52FF02F658ED405BA03480BB9258436F">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Submission of petition by state To manage Federal lands</header>
        <text>Beginning 30 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, a State may submit to the Secretary concerned a petition to enter into a cooperative agreement with the Secretary concerned for purposes of managing certain qualifying Federal lands located in the State.</text>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="H89298272428848CDA1C87CE39895AE92">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Determination</header>
        <text>The Secretary concerned shall approve or deny a petition (including a corrected petition that is resubmitted) submitted under this section not later than 90 days after the date on which the Secretary concerned receives the petition.</text>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="H0E41FDCB7F3C4BCB8A6AD7EBD448C223">
        <enum>(c)</enum>
        <header>Denial of petition</header>
        <text>The Secretary concerned shall approve a petition submitted under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="State-Run Federal Lands Act/s:3/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref> if the Secretary concerned determines that—</text>
        <paragraph id="H7D0505BEAB334BDAACAFB50CD87EA545">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>the State has demonstrated that it has sufficient funds to meet the cost-sharing requirement under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="State-Run Federal Lands Act/s:3/ss:f/p:3" proposed="true">subsection (f)(3)</cato:entity-ref> for the duration of the cooperative agreement;</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H920108D9025548EEB823183CB755A7B1">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>the petition is complete;</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H328CF25A93C74204803A3A2A16003ACE">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <text>the proposed cooperative agreement submitted with the petition contains all of the terms required under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="State-Run Federal Lands Act/s:3/ss:f" proposed="true">subsection (f)</cato:entity-ref>; or</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H3F745C3F24F4448CAAFE8C2CB6DDBCE8">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
          <text>the petition is from a State that had a previous cooperative agreement terminated and the Secretary determines that the reasons for that termination warrant denial of the new (or corrected) petition.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="H1950FD0445D546F480430EA65FDFDBF7">
        <enum>(d)</enum>
        <header>Opportunity To amend petition</header>
        <paragraph id="HE52885C16FA447A3AD38AC8930A8FA15">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>Notice of denial</header>
          <text>If the Secretary concerned denies a petition under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="State-Run Federal Lands Act/s:3/ss:b" proposed="true">subsection (b)</cato:entity-ref>, the Secretary concerned shall provide to the State that submitted such petition written notice of the denial. Such written notice shall include—</text>
          <subparagraph id="HAEE886BCFE214B9AA4041BD322E25C9C">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>a clear and comprehensive statement of the reasons why the petition was denied; and</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H025163DEA928484E90923C49D1E3E880">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>a clear and comprehensive description of any deficiencies in the petition or the related proposed cooperative agreement.</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HD91C40654FD14C31AC886B91D0B9FA68">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Resubmission of corrected petition</header>
          <text>After receiving a notice from the Secretary under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="State-Run Federal Lands Act/s:3/ss:d/p:1" proposed="true">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref>, a State may amend and resubmit the denied petition.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1079061F805842E999D2F93F1A505E53">
        <enum>(e)</enum>
        <header>Petition and cooperative agreement deemed approved</header>
        <text>If the Secretary concerned does not approve or deny a petition submitted under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="State-Run Federal Lands Act/s:3/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref> or <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="State-Run Federal Lands Act/s:3/ss:d/p:2" proposed="true">(d)(2)</cato:entity-ref> within the 90 days after receiving the petition, the petition and the proposed cooperative agreement submitted with the petition shall be deemed approved.</text>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="H8F7AAFE57AA047E9AA4438A53E961EF3">
        <enum>(f)</enum>
        <header>Petition contents</header>
        <text>A petition submitted under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="State-Run Federal Lands Act/s:3/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref> shall include—</text>
        <paragraph id="HEC7C4728976047E7BC6B5AA257702712">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>a letter signed by the Governor of the State submitting such petition addressed to the Secretary concerned that contains a description and a corresponding map of the qualifying Federal lands over which the State seeks to manage;</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HBACA4BF5CA644E4B9949ACBA23B5DA60">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>the proposed cooperative agreement that is the subject of the petition;</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H7B50935B8EC94E9AAAE0C0EE8E88D8C4">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <text>documentation that demonstrates the ability of the State to provide sufficient funds to administer such lands for the duration of the cooperative agreement; and</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HF447EA89145C4ADDB44376C04FF47F87">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
          <text>any other documentation that the Secretary concerned may require.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="H26AEF96BFE394A07B71F318F9067D566">
        <enum>(g)</enum>
        <header>Cooperative Agreement contents</header>
        <text>A cooperative agreement submitted under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="State-Run Federal Lands Act/s:3/ss:e/p:2" proposed="true">subsection (e)(2)</cato:entity-ref> shall contain—</text>
        <paragraph id="HA08D6B41F1F7470980D0E93DBB06AA75">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>a statement that the State shall manage certain qualifying Federal lands located in that State after the effective date of the transfer of management to the State for a specified term of years;</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HE71AB412D67B4ABF8225F0D216E37CDE">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>a cost-sharing requirement stating that the State shall provide a certain amount (equal to not less than 50 percent), in cash or in-kind, of the total amount required for the management of the qualifying Federal lands concerned;</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HB9862CCB98DB4ABCACCFF434BB2A9D15">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <text>the amount to be contributed by the State shall be determined by the Governor of the State and the Secretary concerned, only after the Secretary concerned submits to the State a categorical assessment of all costs, in the recent past and anticipated during the duration of the cooperative agreement, of managing the qualifying Federal lands concerned, including employee salary data;</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph commented="no" id="H2A972C67568946EE9FEC7913C2C38A76">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
          <text>in the event of a natural disaster, as categorized by the Federal Emergency Management Agency, the State shall assume authority over recovery initiatives (nullifying any existing established Federal response protocol) so that—</text>
          <subparagraph commented="no" id="H65C176188CCD44E5846F41876E011238">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>the cost of damages to any structure on the qualifying Federal lands concerned be shared by both State and Federal entities at a ratio in accordance to the cost-sharing agreement; and</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph commented="no" id="H817DB9244D5B4F5090A4A7E5E16C3FF5">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>the cost and administration of repair of damages resulting from natural disasters, not including structures referred to in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="State-Run Federal Lands Act/s:3/ss:g/p:4/sp:A" proposed="true">subparagraph (A)</cato:entity-ref>, shall be assumed by the State rather than the Federal Government;</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HF083BAC28A1345CEA80D8E43D4C34953">
          <enum>(5)</enum>
          <text>all revenue accrued from fees, royalties, and other revenues related to the qualifying Federal lands concerned shall be distributed to the State and Federal entities in accordance to the percentages dictated by the cost-sharing agreement and shall be used so that the percentage of funds designated to the Federal entity shall be made available to the Secretary concerned for use at the sole discretion of the Secretary concerned;</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H35FF13C3EEFC45CDBAAF981B1C7E9AEC">
          <enum>(6)</enum>
          <text>the procedures to be followed for purposes of the transition from Federal to State management of the qualifying Federal lands concerned, including—</text>
          <subparagraph id="H44C4EA04AEDA40BE80B81C49F4422551">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>a guarantee that all Federal employees managing the qualifying Federal lands concerned may remain employed without infringement upon their existing conditions of employment;</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H26FDBB0B80184E458079774F9072E8CF">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a guarantee that the State may use its percentage of the amounts required for the management of the qualifying Federal lands concerned to hire additional staff whose terms of employment shall be decided by the petitioning State; and</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H873582519BE94EA1A159EBEFFD800F31">
            <enum>(C)</enum>
            <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">authority over the qualifying Federal lands concerned shall be directed by the State that submitted the petition and a State-appointed manager, but the implementation of its directives may include the existing Federal superintendent concerned and performed in conjunction with State employees;</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HBB9477A0953F4493995255E1119C221F">
          <enum>(7)</enum>
          <text>the transfer of any special use permits issued to the Secretary concerned with respect to the qualifying Federal lands concerned to the State;</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HE25683B85C794592BCDF835B499FFC4B">
          <enum>(8)</enum>
          <text>a provision stating that lands currently open to mineral entry under the Act of May 10, 1872 (commonly referred to as the <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
              <term>
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="General Mining Act of 1872">General Mining Act of 1872</cato:entity-ref>
              </term> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/22">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/30/22/etseq">30 U.S.C. 22 et seq.</cato:entity-ref>
              </external-xref>)</cato:entity>), shall remain open to mineral entry under State law unless subsequently changed by a State mineral closing order; and</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H5B036024D4E041C9A68BAF0A32B79620">
          <enum>(9)</enum>
          <text>if the qualifying Federal lands concerned cross State lines, all States involved shall submit a joint petition or the States must agree to divide the park by State lines to enable State authority in accordance to the cost-sharing agreement.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="HF92F5CEF15B3435ABB7A777949CC52B4">
        <enum>(h)</enum>
        <header>Applicability of state law on qualifying federal lands under cooperative agreement</header>
        <text>State environmental, wildlife, and land management laws shall supercede Federal environmental, wildlife, and land management laws on the qualifying Federal lands administered by a State under a cooperative agreement in place under this section to the extent that such laws are more restrictive than the corresponding Federal laws.</text>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="HE458D9B65A69493B992DF7F87119B916">
        <enum>(i)</enum>
        <header>Ownership</header>
        <text>Notwithstanding a State management of qualified Federal lands under a cooperative agreement entered into under this section, the United States shall retain all right, title, and interest in and to such lands.</text>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="H80BB68C79D10488AADB974DE56462C09">
        <enum>(j)</enum>
        <header>Termination of cooperative agreement</header>
        <text>A cooperative agreement applicable under this section shall terminate, at the discretion of the Secretary concerned, under the following circumstances:</text>
        <paragraph id="HC3FD23A2498049D589A0BD9F92B80825">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>The State concerned defaults on a payment, thereby requiring Federal entities to assume responsibility for the financial liabilities.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HFA62BDDEF1834CEDA87B1EEB4DD089BB">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The State concerned is in substantial breach of the cooperative agreement as determined by the Secretary concerned.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HAA0C054507E546929B89433B67780540">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The cooperative agreement terminates under a term contained in that agreement.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="HC3FDFF79890B4FF19163253E1FF783F2">
        <enum>(k)</enum>
        <header>Intentional termination of cooperative agreement</header>
        <paragraph id="HF90AB5A2CBC44FC09F525806660EA99B">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>If the State no longer finds that the cooperative agreement is beneficial or in the best interest of the State, the State must submit a petition to the Secretary concerned exhibiting credible purpose and reason for such intent.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HE1D8199BFED44FD78E92816B21F4AD2A">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>Not later than 90 days after receiving a petition under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="State-Run Federal Lands Act/s:3/ss:k/p:1" proposed="true">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref>, the Secretary concerned shall determine whether to approve or deny the petition.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
    </section>
  </legis-body>
</bill>
</doc>