<doc>
  <docmeta id="113hr5611ih">
    <bill congress="113" type="hr" number="5611" version="ih"/>
    <revision size="16312" annotations="0" status="complete" id="4" commit-time="2014-10-20T20:19:59Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113hr5611ih/4.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H503BC16B4F9647AB832534565232BEAA" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata>
<dublinCore>
<dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">113 HR 5611 IH: Public School Emergency Relief Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">2014-09-18</dc:date>
<dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>113th CONGRESS</congress>
<session>2d Session</session>
<legis-num>H. R. 5611</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20140918">September 18, 2014</action-date> 
<action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="I000057">Mr. Israel</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="K000210">Mr. King of New York</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and the Workforce</committee-name>
      </action-desc>
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To provide for temporary emergency impact aid for local educational agencies.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H6F63849FF6574670AC29E57BB5F3CA54" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H3549B2E4ECD64E7580D6B815F01ABB85" section-type="section-one">
      <enum>1.</enum>
      <header>Short title</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote>
          <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Public School Emergency Relief Act" proposed="true">
            <short-title>Public School Emergency Relief Act</short-title>
          </cato:entity-ref>
        </quote>. </text>
    </section> 
<section id="HA9DD1FAC5EC04F85A27A57D87BEC7213">
      <enum>2.</enum>
      <header>Findings</header> <text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Congress finds the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H8854392785A84641BC9CA007AA5DCDA7">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text>In 2014, the United States experienced an unprecedented influx in arrivals of unaccompanied alien children.</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8A355EBD1254482490FABEC6A7F0022A">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text>Between January 1, 2014, and July 31, 2014, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Office of Refugee Resettlement" entity-parent-id="7500">Department of Health and Human Services Office of Refugee Resettlement</cato:entity-ref> released 37,477 unaccompanied alien children to sponsors nationwide.</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H72A39EB33CC54CF0AD1C098BEAC1D43F">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <text>Federal law, as upheld by the Supreme Court decision Plyer v. Doe, permits all children residing in the United States access to a public elementary and secondary education regardless of their immigration status.</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCDB09A1F1E9C444C9F4CC1BD6BC7FD9D">
        <enum>(4)</enum>
        <text>An unprecedented influx of unaccompanied alien children has resulted in a strain on the Nation’s public school system.</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7678BF8641F046FDB75D6F17824B1B92">
        <enum>(5)</enum>
        <text>In response to these conditions, this Act creates an emergency grant for the 2014–2015 school year tailored to the needs of local educational agencies affected by enrollment increases attributable to unaccompanied alien children.</text>
      </paragraph>
    </section> 
<section id="H23D6748031EA48F79A7F3D456128C93F">
      <enum>3.</enum>
      <header>Temporary emergency impact aid for immigrant students</header> 
<subsection id="H91C8098252A3406BB58A171694F0D1C8">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Temporary emergency impact aid authorized</header> 
<paragraph id="H1D8B2AB3B9FB46689F2EBD66F294E636">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>Aid to State educational agencies</header>
          <text>From amounts appropriated to carry out this Act, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="9100" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of Education</cato:entity-ref> shall provide emergency impact aid to State educational agencies to enable the State educational agencies to make emergency impact aid payments to eligible local educational agencies and eligible BIA-funded schools to enable such eligible local educational agencies and schools to provide for the instruction of students served by such agencies and schools.</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3ACADDC3492D456A840CA4C85F4DBA6E">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Aid to local educational agencies and BIA-funded schools</header>
          <text>A State educational agency shall make emergency impact aid payments to eligible local educational agencies and eligible BIA-funded schools in accordance with subsection (c).</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6707048633A34EEB9DE11DE9E0F121BD">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <header>Notice of funds availability</header>
          <text>Not later than 14 calendar days after the date of enactment of this Act, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="9100" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of Education</cato:entity-ref> shall publish in the Federal Register a notice of the availability of funds under this section.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="H9E929687F1A740EDB96C6C759849633F">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Application</header> 
<paragraph id="HB5FAB2DFB64643399BE34ABECC51CB1E">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>State educational agency</header>
          <text>A State educational agency that desires to receive emergency impact aid under this section shall submit an application to the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="9100" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of Education</cato:entity-ref>, not later than 7 calendar days after the date by which an application under paragraph (2) must be submitted, in such manner, and accompanied by such information as the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="9100" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of Education</cato:entity-ref> may reasonably require, including information on the total immigrant student child count of the State provided by eligible local educational agencies in the State and eligible BIA-funded schools in the State under paragraph (2).</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9141FBA2C9FE4A9599CD15AB9E142527">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Local educational agencies and BIA-funded schools</header>
          <text>An eligible local educational agency or eligible BIA-funded school that desires an emergency impact aid payment under this section shall submit an application to the State educational agency, not later than 14 calendar days after the date of the publication of the notice described in subsection (a)(3), in such manner, and accompanied by such information as the State educational agency may reasonably require, including documentation submitted quarterly for the 2014–2015 school year that indicates the following:</text> 
<subparagraph id="H2BCACA603054415E85211DCE60B272EB">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>In the case of an eligible local educational agency, the number of immigrant students enrolled in the elementary schools and secondary schools (including charter schools) served by such agency for such quarter.</text>
          </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H490A1FC6EB934FC7A5E5D68091FDD540">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>In the case of an eligible BIA-funded school, the number of immigrant students enrolled in such school for such quarter.</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4B8243CA46FE4B8D878585CC18F5D69F">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <header>Determination of number of immigrant students</header>
          <text>In determining the number of immigrant students for a quarter under paragraph (2), an eligible local educational agency or eligible BIA-funded school shall include the number of immigrant students served—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H11A031A37D9A4782AA22A38195AC2EE9">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>in the case of a determination for the first quarterly installment, during the quarter prior to the date of enactment of this Act; and</text>
          </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H0FC12FB8A53E4EBB993C6AB91785F025">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>in the case of a determination for each subsequent quarterly installment, during the quarter immediately preceding the quarter for which the installment is provided.</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="HC1029446653E49C5AF4322EEFF8B3920">
        <enum>(c)</enum>
        <header>Amount of emergency impact aid</header> 
<paragraph id="H63A03A0E11F84FAAA896799AE688311F">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>Aid to State educational agencies</header> 
<subparagraph id="H4B0D48E9F36B41D7BFC8AB167FC19A44">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <header>In general</header>
            <text>The amount of emergency impact aid received by a State educational agency for the 2014–2015 school year shall equal the product of—</text> 
<clause id="H96C3606258A0440B98D1E6D097317FC7">
              <enum>(i)</enum>
              <text>the increase (if any) in the number of immigrant students—</text> 
<subclause id="HB8E212B692044496A54A025A1B1DD585">
                <enum>(I)</enum>
                <text>as determined by the eligible local educational agencies and eligible BIA-funded schools in the State under subsection (b)(2); over</text>
              </subclause> 
<subclause id="H9095BCA00C9345AEBD06337445EA27D4">
                <enum>(II)</enum>
                <text>the number of such students enrolled during the corresponding quarter of the 2012–2013 school year; and</text>
              </subclause>
            </clause> 
<clause id="HFEC9B20F417E4D4DAAFF5878C4E6709D">
              <enum>(ii)</enum>
              <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">$12,000.</text>
            </clause>
          </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HAC286D5097F94CFA94C7F9343F36AB5E">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <header>Insufficient funds</header>
            <text>If the amount available under this section to provide emergency impact aid under this subsection is insufficient to pay the full amount that a State educational agency is eligible to receive under this section, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="9100" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of Education</cato:entity-ref> shall ratably reduce the amount of such emergency impact aid.</text>
          </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6EB8868A72C9497A8B229AD25DBCB867">
            <enum>(C)</enum>
            <header>Retention of State share</header>
            <text>In the case of a State educational agency that has made a payment prior to the date of enactment of this Act to a local educational agency for the purpose of covering additional costs incurred as a result of enrolling an immigrant student in a school served by the local educational agency, the State educational agency may retain a portion of the payment described in paragraph (2)(A)(ii) that bears the same relation to the total amount of the payment under such paragraph as the sum of such prior payments bears to the total cost of attendance for all students in that local educational agency for whom the State educational agency made such prior payments.</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE65D31B1B3654DCD8E56F810A4F19F7A">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Aid to eligible local educational agencies and eligible BIA-funded schools</header> 
<subparagraph id="H8D4BD210D68E48AC84723F7021276789">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <header>Quarterly installments</header> 
<clause id="H27DC759CDA124EEF8A7E26792C2FF134">
              <enum>(i)</enum>
              <header>In general</header>
              <text>A State educational agency shall provide emergency impact aid payments under this section on a quarterly basis for the 2014–2015 school year by such dates as determined by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="9100" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of Education</cato:entity-ref>. Such quarterly installment payments shall be based on the number of immigrant students reported under subsection (b)(2).</text>
            </clause> 
<clause id="HE508D3A7409C40A5BAF5155EEF519141">
              <enum>(ii)</enum>
              <header>Payment amount</header>
              <text>Subject to paragraph (1)(B), each quarterly installment payment under clause (i) shall equal 25 percent of the amount determined under paragraph (1)(A).</text>
            </clause> 
<clause id="H7AC3CEA6C2F14376B02E90B283A12FE1">
              <enum>(iii)</enum>
              <header>Timeline</header>
              <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="9100" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of Education</cato:entity-ref> shall establish a timeline for quarterly reporting on the number of immigrant students in order to make the appropriate disbursements in a timely manner.</text>
            </clause> 
<clause id="H0DB6C2511B934FBBBB0BE22E3A999870">
              <enum>(iv)</enum>
              <header>Insufficient funds</header>
              <text>If, for any quarter, the amount available under this section to make payments under this subsection is insufficient to pay the full amount that an eligible local educational agency or eligible BIA-funded school is eligible to receive under this section, the State educational agency shall ratably reduce the amount of such payments.</text>
            </clause>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD6A419D277F54AA79FDBA24A3EF1F2F5">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <header>Immigrant students</header>
          <text>Subject to the subsection (d), an eligible local educational agency or eligible BIA-funded school receiving emergency impact aid payments under this section shall use the payments to provide services and assistance to elementary schools and secondary schools (including charter schools) served by such agency, or to such BIA-funded school, that enrolled an immigrant student.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="H117B470CED474A179CAFECB9A90C82C3">
        <enum>(d)</enum>
        <header>Use of funds</header> 
<paragraph id="H4484EB496D2B46FE89FB73E41881B3DC">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>Authorized uses</header>
          <text>The authorized uses of funds are the following:</text> 
<subparagraph id="HB01459E978724B49A163D1396C3C1C1F">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>Paying the compensation of personnel, including teacher aides, in schools enrolling immigrant students.</text>
          </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H46F193B3A29E4D1386087CC37BD50856">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>Identifying and acquiring curricular material, including the costs of providing additional classroom supplies, and mobile educational units and leasing sites or spaces.</text>
          </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE146D9FACB5C43369E391D6B0FC91CDC">
            <enum>(C)</enum>
            <text>Basic instructional services for such students, including tutoring, mentoring, or academic counseling.</text>
          </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF5F92B455D8848EEA92E8D31A3F1E58E">
            <enum>(D)</enum>
            <text>Reasonable transportation costs.</text>
          </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H8C256F58D8EE439FB45288F4932E40B4">
            <enum>(E)</enum>
            <text>Health and counseling services.</text>
          </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD58B8E8480224DE78F323AD5E1018E8A">
            <enum>(F)</enum>
            <text>Education and support services.</text>
          </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H784E03C8C32349199CDE2FF67F08E33A">
            <enum>(G)</enum>
            <text>Other uses as allowed under <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965/t:III">title III of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/6801">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/20/6801/etseq">20 U.S.C. 6801 et seq.</cato:entity-ref>
              </external-xref>)</cato:entity>.</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA541C07020B0496984B97F3AAB9B6607">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Provision of special education and related services</header> 
<subparagraph id="HCCDBDCAA03CA4550B3E8CC1BCF9AE81B">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <header>In general</header>
            <text>In the case of an immigrant student who is a child with a disability, any payment made on behalf of such student to an eligible local educational agency shall be used to pay for special education and related services consistent with the <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Individuals with Disabilities Education Act">Individuals with Disabilities Education Act</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1400">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/20/1400/etseq">20 U.S.C. 1400 et seq.</cato:entity-ref>
              </external-xref>)</cato:entity>.</text>
          </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H71986500025A4A1B915EE4A8A092FAC8">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <header>Definitions</header>
            <text>In subparagraph (A), the terms <quote>child with a disability</quote>, <quote>special education</quote>, and <quote>related services</quote> have the meaning given such terms in <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Individuals with Disabilities Education Act/s:602">section 602 of the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1401">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/20/1401">20 U.S.C. 1401</cato:entity-ref>
              </external-xref>)</cato:entity>.</text> </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="HD28CDAD4A3F041428423922CBD34D87A">
        <enum>(e)</enum>
        <header>Return of aid</header> 
<paragraph id="H577872C1B66D4A5488F18144DA385AC6">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>Eligible local educational agency or eligible bia-funded school</header>
          <text>An eligible local educational agency or eligible BIA-funded school that receives an emergency impact aid payment under this section shall return to the State educational agency any payment provided to the eligible local educational agency or school under this section that the eligible local educational agency or school has not obligated by the end of the 2014–2015 school year in accordance with this section.</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFDB612830BED44E69A9B68D4F2CD298F">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>State educational agency</header>
          <text>A State educational agency that receives emergency impact aid under this section, shall return to the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="9100" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of Education</cato:entity-ref>—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H414D81C2BE0E4F32AD53B61AEE293125">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>any aid provided to the agency under this section that the agency has not obligated by the end of the 2014–2015 school year in accordance with this section; and</text>
          </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H0FE2E37A54F04B6CA99517134F379F13">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>any payment funds returned to the State educational agency under paragraph (1).</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="HA03A0FC702BD4AB0B65C2244C77DAB41">
        <enum>(f)</enum>
        <header>Limitation on use of aid and payments</header>
        <text>Aid and payments provided under this section shall only be used for expenses incurred during the 2014–2015 school year.</text>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="HBE7F0BBBC4BB448ABF0CC9D58366DE02">
        <enum>(g)</enum>
        <header>Administrative expenses</header>
        <text>A State educational agency that receives emergency impact aid under this section may use not more than 1 percent of such aid for administrative expenses. An eligible local educational agency or eligible BIA-funded school that receives emergency impact aid payments under this section may use not more than 2 percent of such payments for administrative expenses.</text>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="HCB8A6C1D5F0A4A59805A9B32C536E28E">
        <enum>(h)</enum>
        <header>Special funding rule</header>
        <text>In calculating funding under <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965/s:8003">section 8003 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7703">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/20/7703">20 U.S.C. 7703</cato:entity-ref>
          </external-xref>)</cato:entity> for an eligible local educational agency that receives an emergency impact aid payment under this section, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="9100" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of Education</cato:entity-ref> shall not count immigrant students served by such agency for whom an emergency impact aid payment is received under this section, nor shall such students be counted for the purpose of calculating the total number of children in average daily attendance at the schools served by such agency as provided in <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965/s:8003/ss:b/p:3/sp:B/cl:i">section 8003(b)(3)(B)(i) of such Act</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7703">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/20/7703/b/3/B/i">20 U.S.C. 7703(b)(3)(B)(i)</cato:entity-ref>
          </external-xref>)</cato:entity>.</text>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="H4F22961EF4E9489B96514A1081C54FEE">
        <enum>(i)</enum>
        <header>Nondiscrimination</header> 
<paragraph id="H881E5E7768B94C5886A9EEF00AABF2C3">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>In general</header>
          <text>Nothing in this Act may be construed to alter or modify the provisions of the <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Individuals with Disabilities Education Act">Individuals with Disabilities Education Act</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1400">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/20/1400/etseq">20 U.S.C. 1400 et seq.</cato:entity-ref>
            </external-xref>)</cato:entity>, <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Civil Rights Act of 1964/t:VI">title VI of the Civil Rights Act of 1964</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000d">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/42/2000d/etseq">42 U.S.C. 2000d et seq.</cato:entity-ref>
            </external-xref>)</cato:entity>, <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Education Amendments of 1972/t:IX">title IX of the Education Amendments of 1972</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1681">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/20/1681/etseq">20 U.S.C. 1681 et seq.</cato:entity-ref>
            </external-xref>)</cato:entity>, and the <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Rehabilitation Act of 1973">Rehabilitation Act of 1973</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/701">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/29/701/etseq">29 U.S.C. 701 et seq.</cato:entity-ref>
            </external-xref>)</cato:entity>.</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCB0B0070C34F4BE984B4EFFBFFE3141E">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Prohibition</header>
          <text>A school that enrolls an immigrant student under this section shall not discriminate against students on the basis of race, color, national origin, religion, disability, or sex.</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC0A1F7E08D494212948BE7C7B3BD46A6">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <header>Rule of construction</header>
          <text>The amount of any payment (or other form of support provided on behalf of an immigrant student) under this section shall not be treated as income of a parent or guardian of the student for purposes of Federal tax laws or for determining eligibility for any other Federal program.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="HE1FF415DBCE6483391DE81AEDCEB86F4">
        <enum>(j)</enum>
        <header>Treatment of State aid</header>
        <text>A State shall not take into consideration emergency impact aid payments received under this section by a local educational agency in the State in determining the eligibility of such local educational agency for State aid, or the amount of State aid, with respect to free public education of children.</text>
      </subsection> </section> 
<section id="HB3CA3A6C9D0246D68045C5B78DBE5C49" display-inline="no-display-inline">
      <enum>4.</enum>
      <header>Definitions</header> 
<subsection id="H97D326E715CB41739B241A58847E61BB">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>In general</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Unless otherwise specified, the terms used in this Act have the meanings given the terms in <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965/s:9101">section 9101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7801">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/20/7801">20 U.S.C. 7801</cato:entity-ref>
          </external-xref>)</cato:entity>.</text>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="H1E88D9B68CC54740B804C8F1CC693D5D">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Specific definitions</header>
        <text>In this Act:</text> 
<paragraph id="H5B5A27BC740141229EF17CE9E07A0914">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>Eligible local educational agency</header>
          <text>The term <quote>eligible local educational agency</quote> means a local educational agency that serves an elementary school or secondary school (including a charter school) in which there is enrolled an immigrant student.</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2B93E2ACEB0341FEB2AFC939F8C7F332">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Eligible BIA-funded school</header>
          <text>The term <quote>eligible BIA-funded school</quote> means a school funded by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1450" entity-type="federal-body">Bureau of Indian Affairs</cato:entity-ref> in which there is enrolled an immigrant student.</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD38C9B2485544804A3393BDAD841B559">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <header>Immigrant student</header>
          <text>The term <quote>immigrant student</quote> has the meaning given the term <quote>immigrant children and youth</quote> in <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965/s:3301">section 3301 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7011">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/20/7011">20 U.S.C. 7011</cato:entity-ref>
            </external-xref>)</cato:entity>.</text>
        </paragraph> </subsection>
    </section> 
</legis-body> 
</bill>
</doc>