<doc>
  <docmeta id="113hr1944ih">
    <bill congress="113" type="hr" number="1944" version="ih"/>
    <revision size="22835" annotations="0" status="complete" id="3" commit-time="2013-07-05T15:08:29Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113hr1944ih/3.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H2568B31C605843868EF9383B75101FB8" public-private="public">
	<metadata>
<dublinCore>
<title>113 HR 1944 IH: Private Property Rights Protection Act of 2013</title>
<publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</publisher>
<date>2013-05-09</date>
<format>text/xml</format>
<language>EN</language>
<rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>113th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 1944</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20130509">May 9, 2013</action-date>
			<action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="S000244">Mr. Sensenbrenner</sponsor>
			 introduced the following bill; which was referred to the
			 <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the
			 Judiciary</committee-name>
      </action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To protect private property rights.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H91EDD7D062974D968E864A8C7E0083D1" style="OLC">
		<section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9780E9D8CB5646F5B73883775A7843E6" section-type="section-one">
      <enum>1.</enum>
      <header>Short title</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the
			 <quote>
          <short-title>Private Property Rights Protection Act
			 of 2013</short-title>
        </quote>.</text>
		</section>
    <section id="HE748DBD1848149FB9C3AEF9647BE403B">
      <enum>2.</enum>
      <header>Prohibition on
			 eminent domain abuse by States</header>
			<subsection id="H583354EE8FF642FF94025E47AFF8E518">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>In
			 General</header>
        <text>No State or political subdivision of a State shall
			 exercise its power of eminent domain, or allow the exercise of such power by
			 any person or entity to which such power has been delegated, over property to
			 be used for economic development or over property that is used for economic
			 development within 7 years after that exercise, if that State or political
			 subdivision receives Federal economic development funds during any fiscal year
			 in which the property is so used or intended to be used.</text>
			</subsection>
      <subsection id="H36A7AF6AA20A45558C252FB20E27BA08">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Ineligibility
			 for Federal Funds</header>
        <text>A violation of <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Private Property Rights Protection Act of 2013/s:2/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref> by a State or
			 political subdivision shall render such State or political subdivision
			 ineligible for any Federal economic development funds for a period of 2 fiscal
			 years following a final judgment on the merits by a court of competent
			 jurisdiction that such subsection has been violated, and any Federal agency
			 charged with distributing those funds shall withhold them for such 2-year
			 period, and any such funds distributed to such State or political subdivision
			 shall be returned or reimbursed by such State or political subdivision to the
			 appropriate Federal agency or authority of the Federal Government, or component
			 thereof.</text>
			</subsection>
      <subsection id="H5D66B9FB64E0415AAF546E0BE4FD7EAB">
        <enum>(c)</enum>
        <header>Opportunity To
			 Cure Violation</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A State or
			 political subdivision shall not be ineligible for any Federal economic
			 development funds under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Private Property Rights Protection Act of 2013/s:2/ss:b" proposed="true">subsection (b)</cato:entity-ref> if such State or political subdivision
			 returns all real property the taking of which was found by a court of competent
			 jurisdiction to have constituted a violation of <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Private Property Rights Protection Act of 2013/s:2/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref> and replaces any
			 other property destroyed and repairs any other property damaged as a result of
			 such violation. In addition, the State or political subdivision must pay any
			 applicable penalties and interest to reattain eligibility.</text>
			</subsection>
    </section>
    <section id="HC7ED33F722FB44C0BDF0EDC8F0824C0E">
      <enum>3.</enum>
      <header>Prohibition on
			 eminent domain abuse by the Federal Government</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Federal Government or any authority of
			 the Federal Government shall not exercise its power of eminent domain to be
			 used for economic development.</text>
		</section>
    <section id="H89D0EB6117534AB39FEB8E96EE7EF6B1">
      <enum>4.</enum>
      <header>Private right of
			 action</header>
			<subsection id="HF717A9B752014E298F34EA4E41F1D3DA">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Cause of
			 Action</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any (1) owner of
			 private property whose property is subject to eminent domain who suffers injury
			 as a result of a violation of any provision of this Act with respect to that
			 property, or (2) any tenant of property that is subject to eminent domain who
			 suffers injury as a result of a violation of any provision of this Act with
			 respect to that property, may bring an action to enforce any provision of this
			 Act in the appropriate Federal or State court. A State shall not be immune
			 under the 11th Amendment to the Constitution of the United States from any such
			 action in a Federal or State court of competent jurisdiction. In such action,
			 the defendant has the burden to show by clear and convincing evidence that the
			 taking is not for economic development. Any such property owner or tenant may
			 also seek an appropriate relief through a preliminary injunction or a temporary
			 restraining order.</text>
			</subsection>
      <subsection id="H28F084C9745B44338D7C9BCF4803CEF3">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Limitation on
			 Bringing Action</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An action
			 brought by a property owner or tenant under this Act may be brought if the
			 property is used for economic development following the conclusion of any
			 condemnation proceedings condemning the property of such property owner or
			 tenant, but shall not be brought later than seven years following the
			 conclusion of any such proceedings.</text>
			</subsection>
      <subsection id="HFB96F7884F54403C93C686BEAFA81B1B">
        <enum>(c)</enum>
        <header>Attorneys’ Fee
			 and Other Costs</header>
        <text>In any action or proceeding under this Act, the
			 court shall allow a prevailing plaintiff a reasonable attorneys’ fee as part of
			 the costs, and include expert fees as part of the attorneys’ fee.</text>
			</subsection>
    </section>
    <section id="H54F1762786DE495BBFB72A56D314445F">
      <enum>5.</enum>
      <header>Reporting of
			 violations to Attorney General</header>
			<subsection id="H7302F65E1CD941EAA1C4C93C4803CC0B">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Submission of
			 report to attorney general</header>
        <text>Any (1) owner of private property
			 whose property is subject to eminent domain who suffers injury as a result of a
			 violation of any provision of this Act with respect to that property, or (2)
			 any tenant of property that is subject to eminent domain who suffers injury as
			 a result of a violation of any provision of this Act with respect to that
			 property, may report a violation by the Federal Government, any authority of
			 the Federal Government, State, or political subdivision of a State to the
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1500">Attorney General</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
			</subsection>
      <subsection id="HD344D657A7174C9780E2F14D078BFC5F">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Investigation by
			 attorney general</header>
        <text>Upon receiving a report of an alleged violation,
			 the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1500">Attorney General</cato:entity-ref> shall conduct an investigation to determine whether a
			 violation exists.</text>
			</subsection>
      <subsection id="H0E9DA5798E524F339F98FC133E6B55A9">
        <enum>(c)</enum>
        <header>Notification of
			 violation</header>
        <text>If the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1500">Attorney General</cato:entity-ref> concludes that a violation does
			 exist, then the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1500">Attorney General</cato:entity-ref> shall notify the Federal Government, authority
			 of the Federal Government, State, or political subdivision of a State that the
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1500">Attorney General</cato:entity-ref> has determined that it is in violation of the Act. The
			 notification shall further provide that the Federal Government, State, or
			 political subdivision of a State has 90 days from the date of the notification
			 to demonstrate to the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1500">Attorney General</cato:entity-ref> either that (1) it is not in violation
			 of the Act or (2) that it has cured its violation by returning all real
			 property the taking of which the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1500">Attorney General</cato:entity-ref> finds to have constituted a
			 violation of the Act and replacing any other property destroyed and repairing
			 any other property damaged as a result of such violation.</text>
			</subsection>
      <subsection id="HEB80DFFF45F64970A905997DAC4D4C52">
        <enum>(d)</enum>
        <header>Attorney
			 general’s bringing of action To enforce act</header>
        <text>If, at the end of the
			 90-day period described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Private Property Rights Protection Act of 2013/s:5/ss:c" proposed="true">subsection (c)</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1500">Attorney General</cato:entity-ref> determines that
			 the Federal Government, authority of the Federal Government, State, or
			 political subdivision of a State is still violating the Act or has not cured
			 its violation as described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Private Property Rights Protection Act of 2013/s:5/ss:c" proposed="true">subsection (c)</cato:entity-ref>, then the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1500">Attorney General</cato:entity-ref> will
			 bring an action to enforce the Act unless the property owner or tenant who
			 reported the violation has already brought an action to enforce the Act. In
			 such a case, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1500">Attorney General</cato:entity-ref> shall intervene if it determines that
			 intervention is necessary in order to enforce the Act. The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1500">Attorney General</cato:entity-ref> may
			 file its lawsuit to enforce the Act in the appropriate Federal or State court.
			 A State shall not be immune under the 11th Amendment to the Constitution of the
			 United States from any such action in a Federal or State court of competent
			 jurisdiction. In such action, the defendant has the burden to show by clear and
			 convincing evidence that the taking is not for economic development. The
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1500">Attorney General</cato:entity-ref> may seek any appropriate relief through a preliminary
			 injunction or a temporary restraining order.</text>
			</subsection>
      <subsection id="H079429A079804FA28AFF480FBDCE8D6A">
        <enum>(e)</enum>
        <header>Limitation on
			 bringing action</header>
        <text>An action brought by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1500">Attorney General</cato:entity-ref> under
			 this Act may be brought if the property is used for economic development
			 following the conclusion of any condemnation proceedings condemning the
			 property of an owner or tenant who reports a violation of the Act to the
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1500">Attorney General</cato:entity-ref>, but shall not be brought later than seven years following the
			 conclusion of any such proceedings.</text>
			</subsection>
      <subsection id="HA1621DBB5A2748A389FE706E3DD2E0A5">
        <enum>(f)</enum>
        <header>Attorneys’ fee
			 and other costs</header>
        <text>In any action or proceeding under this Act
			 brought by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1500">Attorney General</cato:entity-ref>, the court shall, if the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1500">Attorney General</cato:entity-ref> is a
			 prevailing plaintiff, award the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1500">Attorney General</cato:entity-ref> a reasonable attorneys’ fee as
			 part of the costs, and include expert fees as part of the attorneys’
			 fee.</text>
			</subsection>
    </section>
    <section id="H29266963E73548478E50C879A9F72BAD">
      <enum>6.</enum>
      <header>Notification by
			 Attorney General</header>
			<subsection id="H918309E9D0954DA18FF0AD9714B00835">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Notification to
			 States and Political Subdivisions</header>
				<paragraph id="H1C650D4B918640FFA39640F46523F4ED">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>Not later than 30
			 days after the enactment of this Act, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1500">Attorney General</cato:entity-ref> shall provide to the
			 chief executive officer of each State the text of this Act and a description of
			 the rights of property owners and tenants under this Act.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H1C43895A6EEA484991C253EC0F9668F4">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>Not later than 120
			 days after the enactment of this Act, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1500">Attorney General</cato:entity-ref> shall compile a list
			 of the Federal laws under which Federal economic development funds are
			 distributed. The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1500">Attorney General</cato:entity-ref> shall compile annual revisions of such list
			 as necessary. Such list and any successive revisions of such list shall be
			 communicated by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1500">Attorney General</cato:entity-ref> to the chief executive officer of each
			 State and also made available on the Internet website maintained by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1500">United
			 States Department of Justice</cato:entity-ref> for use by the public and by the authorities in
			 each State and political subdivisions of each State empowered to take private
			 property and convert it to public use subject to just compensation for the
			 taking.</text>
				</paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="HCB845EF9D26D4AA197A4381754C36232">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Notification to
			 Property Owners and tenants</header>
        <text>Not later than 30 days after the
			 enactment of this Act, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1500">Attorney General</cato:entity-ref> shall publish in the Federal
			 Register and make available on the Internet website maintained by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1500">United
			 States Department of Justice</cato:entity-ref> a notice containing the text of this Act and a
			 description of the rights of property owners and tenants under this Act.</text>
			</subsection>
    </section>
    <section id="H5D38AECB2D324A968A6B7C5E53C5A2AC">
      <enum>7.</enum>
      <header>Reports</header>
			<subsection id="HFF74F51AACC94A8DA28655FD6D5163D0">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>By Attorney
			 General</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year
			 after the date of enactment of this Act, and every subsequent year thereafter,
			 the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1500">Attorney General</cato:entity-ref> shall transmit a report identifying States or political
			 subdivisions that have used eminent domain in violation of this Act to the
			 Chairman and Ranking Member of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="committee" entity-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary of the House of
			 Representatives</cato:entity-ref> and to the Chairman and Ranking Member of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="committee" entity-id="SSJU00">Committee on the
			 Judiciary of the Senate</cato:entity-ref>. The report shall—</text>
				<paragraph id="H5C03783D92754917A85198A9C9770B1E">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>identify all
			 private rights of action brought as a result of a State’s or political
			 subdivision’s violation of this Act;</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H914DDB148A5A4CF9B3067B1B5C92497A">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>identify all
			 violations reported by property owners and tenants under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Private Property Rights Protection Act of 2013/s:5/ss:c" proposed="true">section 5(c) of this
			 Act</cato:entity-ref>;</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HD4BB857EA6F04E5B8A4F47EC97B37806">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <text>identify the
			 percentage of minority residents compared to the surrounding nonminority
			 residents and the median incomes of those impacted by a violation of this
			 Act;</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H62579028118549A2BFC28DB219C364F2">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
          <text>identify all
			 lawsuits brought by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1500">Attorney General</cato:entity-ref> under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Private Property Rights Protection Act of 2013/s:5/ss:d" proposed="true">section 5(d) of this Act</cato:entity-ref>;</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HB5C6F35C301D42898DC0B2D8957F3CE2">
          <enum>(5)</enum>
          <text>identify all
			 States or political subdivisions that have lost Federal economic development
			 funds as a result of a violation of this Act, as well as describe the type and
			 amount of Federal economic development funds lost in each State or political
			 subdivision and the Agency that is responsible for withholding such funds;
			 and</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H67AEED706935462D9A4C96C7E49A909B">
          <enum>(6)</enum>
          <text>discuss all
			 instances in which a State or political subdivision has cured a violation as
			 described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Private Property Rights Protection Act of 2013/s:2/ss:c" proposed="true">section 2(c) of this Act</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
				</paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="HA430D0C5BEB2409AA181350BE6D642E5">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Duty of
			 States</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each State and local
			 authority that is subject to a private right of action under this Act shall
			 have the duty to report to the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1500">Attorney General</cato:entity-ref> such information with respect
			 to such State and local authorities as the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1500">Attorney General</cato:entity-ref> needs to make the
			 report required under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Private Property Rights Protection Act of 2013/s:7/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
			</subsection>
    </section>
    <section id="HBABD4329A7AA4909BD50FC9BE2DEBBCE">
      <enum>8.</enum>
      <header>Sense of Congress
			 regarding rural America</header>
			<subsection id="HD856A0DC80484A57B3F17E9FD2F82AE7">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Findings</header>
        <text>The
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> finds the following:</text>
				<paragraph id="HBD42FC94B87F4F8F9B4C250FDF53075C">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>The founders
			 realized the fundamental importance of property rights when they codified the
			 Takings Clause of the Fifth Amendment to the Constitution, which requires that
			 private property shall not be taken <quote>for public use, without just
			 compensation</quote>.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H26CC55B7AF23447F890299D8EAB9B330">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>Rural lands are
			 unique in that they are not traditionally considered high tax
			 revenue-generating properties for State and local governments. In addition,
			 farmland and forest land owners need to have long-term certainty regarding
			 their property rights in order to make the investment decisions to commit land
			 to these uses.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HAFF32BEC05A542E49B8C3203C58AB577">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <text>Ownership rights
			 in rural land are fundamental building blocks for our Nation’s agriculture
			 industry, which continues to be one of the most important economic sectors of
			 our economy.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HFDE11DEE4CA644F9AED3DF9A2EDE5435">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
          <text>In the wake of the
			 Supreme Court’s decision in Kelo v. City of New London, abuse of eminent domain
			 is a threat to the property rights of all private property owners, including
			 rural land owners.</text>
				</paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="H126C28AB635B4C329D345E0BA081AC99">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Sense of
			 Congress</header>
        <text>It is the sense of <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> that the use of eminent
			 domain for the purpose of economic development is a threat to agricultural and
			 other property in rural America and that the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> should protect the
			 property rights of Americans, including those who reside in rural areas.
			 Property rights are central to liberty in this country and to our economy. The
			 use of eminent domain to take farmland and other rural property for economic
			 development threatens liberty, rural economies, and the economy of the United
			 States. The taking of farmland and rural property will have a direct impact on
			 existing irrigation and reclamation projects. Furthermore, the use of eminent
			 domain to take rural private property for private commercial uses will force
			 increasing numbers of activities from private property onto this Nation’s
			 public lands, including its National forests, National parks and wildlife
			 refuges. This increase can overburden the infrastructure of these lands,
			 reducing the enjoyment of such lands for all citizens. Americans should not
			 have to fear the government’s taking their homes, farms, or businesses to give
			 to other persons. Governments should not abuse the power of eminent domain to
			 force rural property owners from their land in order to develop rural land into
			 industrial and commercial property. <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> has a duty to protect the property
			 rights of rural Americans in the face of eminent domain abuse.</text>
			</subsection>
    </section>
    <section id="H09977AFF122648F0A38CFFED372B22EF">
      <enum>9.</enum>
      <header>Sense of
			 Congress</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the policy of
			 the United States to encourage, support, and promote the private ownership of
			 property and to ensure that the constitutional and other legal rights of
			 private property owners are protected by the Federal Government.</text>
		</section>
    <section id="H6EB9E77037F947048A053BCF659ECD7A">
      <enum>10.</enum>
      <header>Religious and
			 nonprofit organizations</header>
			<subsection id="H1E7FA97273D242038C1395931B893EB3">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Prohibition on
			 States</header>
        <text>No State or political subdivision of a State shall
			 exercise its power of eminent domain, or allow the exercise of such power by
			 any person or entity to which such power has been delegated, over property of a
			 religious or other nonprofit organization by reason of the nonprofit or
			 tax-exempt status of such organization, or any quality related thereto if that
			 State or political subdivision receives Federal economic development funds
			 during any fiscal year in which it does so.</text>
			</subsection>
      <subsection id="HEED9BFEC52F24C8E90814D79882AA110">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Ineligibility
			 for Federal Funds</header>
        <text>A violation of <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Private Property Rights Protection Act of 2013/s:10/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref> by a State or
			 political subdivision shall render such State or political subdivision
			 ineligible for any Federal economic development funds for a period of 2 fiscal
			 years following a final judgment on the merits by a court of competent
			 jurisdiction that such subsection has been violated, and any Federal agency
			 charged with distributing those funds shall withhold them for such 2-year
			 period, and any such funds distributed to such State or political subdivision
			 shall be returned or reimbursed by such State or political subdivision to the
			 appropriate Federal agency or authority of the Federal Government, or component
			 thereof.</text>
			</subsection>
      <subsection id="H8822E58D7C8D445C855A4DF07409D91D">
        <enum>(c)</enum>
        <header>Prohibition on
			 Federal Government</header>
        <text>The Federal Government or any authority of the
			 Federal Government shall not exercise its power of eminent domain over property
			 of a religious or other nonprofit organization by reason of the nonprofit or
			 tax-exempt status of such organization, or any quality related thereto.</text>
			</subsection>
    </section>
    <section id="H2D0A6A23CBDF4D0B8BB4D2E7CB2E48FB">
      <enum>11.</enum>
      <header>Report by
			 Federal agencies on regulations and procedures relating to eminent
			 domain</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 180 days
			 after the date of the enactment of this Act, the head of each Executive
			 department and agency shall review all rules, regulations, and procedures and
			 report to the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1500">Attorney General</cato:entity-ref> on the activities of that department or agency
			 to bring its rules, regulations and procedures into compliance with this
			 Act.</text>
		</section>
    <section id="HCF1D23BFD88040BD86D839DDF639C437">
      <enum>12.</enum>
      <header>Sense of
			 Congress</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> that any and all precautions shall be taken by the government to avoid
			 the unfair or unreasonable taking of property away from survivors of Hurricane
			 Katrina who own, were bequeathed, or assigned such property, for economic
			 development purposes or for the private use of others.</text>
		</section>
    <section id="H3DB35757C24F4A93BE81DFE35185294B">
      <enum>13.</enum>
      <header>Disproportionate
			 impact</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">If the court determines
			 that a violation of this Act has occurred, and that the violation has a
			 disproportionately high impact on the poor or minorities, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1500">Attorney General</cato:entity-ref>
			 shall use reasonable efforts to locate former owners and tenants and inform
			 them of the violation and any remedies they may have.</text>
		</section>
    <section id="HC848C78AE7114D5A8B6B3CC5F269E04D">
      <enum>14.</enum>
      <header>Definitions</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act the following definitions
			 apply:</text>
			<paragraph id="HEEE8A7E6D58D47DA8A9C59425D64B31E">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <header>Economic
			 development</header>
        <text>The term <term>economic development</term> means
			 taking private property, without the consent of the owner, and conveying or
			 leasing such property from one private person or entity to another private
			 person or entity for commercial enterprise carried on for profit, or to
			 increase tax revenue, tax base, employment, or general economic health, except
			 that such term shall not include—</text>
				<subparagraph id="HF936A68BFA7A4606B22C3EBE2C32C8E1">
          <enum>(A)</enum>
          <text>conveying private
			 property—</text>
					<clause id="H031037740E8645AEA4B56E31405B6425">
            <enum>(i)</enum>
            <text>to
			 public ownership, such as for a road, hospital, airport, or military
			 base;</text>
					</clause>
          <clause id="H6DE7A3C22D554C679727225A8C89AD27">
            <enum>(ii)</enum>
            <text>to
			 an entity, such as a common carrier, that makes the property available to the
			 general public as of right, such as a railroad or public facility;</text>
					</clause>
          <clause id="H0B796F22ADFE414F8A174FC9E3A5678F">
            <enum>(iii)</enum>
            <text>for use as a
			 road or other right of way or means, open to the public for transportation,
			 whether free or by toll; and</text>
					</clause>
          <clause id="HCA580648C2B24B239B70FBAD38202573">
            <enum>(iv)</enum>
            <text>for
			 use as an aqueduct, flood control facility, pipeline, or similar use;</text>
					</clause>
        </subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="H4ADEFE4FC61242389A9C66734E171D8B">
          <enum>(B)</enum>
          <text>removing harmful
			 uses of land provided such uses constitute an immediate threat to public health
			 and safety;</text>
				</subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="H20B05C535AC54B96AFEA9DEA06E1DA00">
          <enum>(C)</enum>
          <text>leasing property
			 to a private person or entity that occupies an incidental part of public
			 property or a public facility, such as a retail establishment on the ground
			 floor of a public building;</text>
				</subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="H80EDB3A63CB14CD3931BE65DB4976821">
          <enum>(D)</enum>
          <text>acquiring
			 abandoned property;</text>
				</subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="HECE268F87A694218BFC93BFB6F458068">
          <enum>(E)</enum>
          <text>clearing defective
			 chains of title;</text>
				</subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="H669C4456BF344685BBD390234A075FC7">
          <enum>(F)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">taking private property for use by a
			 utility providing electric, natural gas, telecommunication, water, wastewater,
			 or other utility services either directly to the public or indirectly through
			 provision of such services at the wholesale level for resale to the public;
			 and</text>
				</subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="H61BEB7FD1E16456C88160B1AD0C31FCA">
          <enum>(G)</enum>
          <text>redeveloping of a
			 brownfield site as defined in the <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Small Business Liability Relief and Brownfields Revitalization Act">Small Business Liability Relief and
			 Brownfields Revitalization Act</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/9601">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/42/9601//39">42 U.S.C. 9601(39)</cato:entity-ref>
              </external-xref>)</cato:entity>.</text>
				</subparagraph>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HB409C9FE9243416A85AA7061C2C215A3">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <header>Federal economic
			 development funds</header>
        <text>The term <term>Federal economic development
			 funds</term> means any Federal funds distributed to or through States or
			 political subdivisions of States under Federal laws designed to improve or
			 increase the size of the economies of States or political subdivisions of
			 States.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H83B9303E9A414CF9AD1F30B0DC856968">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <header>State</header>
        <text>The
			 term <term>State</term> means each of the several States, the District of
			 Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, or any other territory or possession
			 of the United States.</text>
			</paragraph>
    </section>
    <section id="HA468113D5A5646E084116570E744C1FB">
      <enum>15.</enum>
      <header>Limitation on
			 statutory construction</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing
			 in this Act may be construed to supersede, limit, or otherwise affect any
			 provision of the <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
          <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Uniform Relocation Assistance and Real Property Acquisition Policies Act of 1970">Uniform Relocation Assistance and Real Property Acquisition
			 Policies Act of 1970</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4601">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/42/4601/etseq">42 U.S.C. 4601 et seq.</cato:entity-ref>
          </external-xref>)</cato:entity>.</text>
		</section>
    <section id="H418780F21E974803953AF6F4AB2C23F2">
      <enum>16.</enum>
      <header>Broad
			 construction</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act shall be
			 construed in favor of a broad protection of private property rights, to the
			 maximum extent permitted by the terms of this Act and the Constitution.</text>
		</section>
    <section id="H81F1BBD7B9DE4521A8461C66783B028B">
      <enum>17.</enum>
      <header>Severability and
			 effective date</header>
			<subsection id="H8524F5958D92477BA2BB4E3FC733A2CD">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Severability</header>
        <text>The
			 provisions of this Act are severable. If any provision of this Act, or any
			 application thereof, is found unconstitutional, that finding shall not affect
			 any provision or application of the Act not so adjudicated.</text>
			</subsection>
      <subsection id="HA7E8B0B480EB43558488346FCC9DF561">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Effective
			 Date</header>
        <text>This Act shall take effect upon the first day of the first
			 fiscal year that begins after the date of the enactment of this Act, but shall
			 not apply to any project for which condemnation proceedings have been initiated
			 prior to the date of enactment.</text>
			</subsection>
    </section>
  </legis-body>
</bill>
</doc>