<doc>
  <docmeta id="113hres612ih">
    <bill congress="113" type="hres" number="612" version="ih"/>
    <revision size="2429" annotations="0" status="complete" id="4" commit-time="2014-06-16T21:16:21Z" committer="zwilliams" doc="113hres612ih/4.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <resolution xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" dms-id="HAC8F2E504F70415B9FE6C1D5EAA852E0" key="H" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print">
	<metadata>
<dublinCore>
<dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">113 HRES 612 IH: Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives that the Government of Mexico should forthwith repatriate Sgt. Andrew Paul Tahmooressi from Mexican prison(s) and expressing the sense of the House of Representatives that the President of the United States should take actions to impose sanctions on Mexico until such time as Sgt. Tahmooressi is released.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">2014-06-09</dc:date>
<dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">113th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session display="yes">2d Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. RES. 612</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20140609">June 9, 2014</action-date>
			<action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="S000937">Mr. Stockman</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name>
      </action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives that the Government of Mexico should forthwith
			 repatriate Sgt. Andrew Paul Tahmooressi from Mexican prison(s) and
			 expressing the sense of the House of Representatives that the President of
			 the United States should take actions to impose sanctions on Mexico until
			 such time as Sgt. Tahmooressi is released.</official-title>
	</form>
	<preamble>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas Sgt. Tahmooressi served with the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1727">U.S. Marine Corps</cato:entity-ref> for two tours of duty in Afghanistan
			 earning a rare combat field promotion to Sergeant;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas Sgt. Tahmooressi was driving near the U.S.-Mexican border on March 31, 2014, when he took a
			 wrong turn and unintentionally drove into Mexico.  He was stopped by
			 police in Mexico and arrested for possessing three firearms which were
			 fully legal in Texas and were registered to him; and</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas Sgt. Tahmooressi has a distinguished record in the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1727">U.S. Marine Corps</cato:entity-ref> and there is no
			 indication that Sgt. Tahmooressi was in violation of other laws in Mexico,
			 except possession of his own firearms: Now, therefore, be it</text>
    </whereas>
  </preamble>
  <resolution-body id="HED2CC605808045EBBB0AE91924A5095E" style="traditional">
		<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HEC15D10EECC145298EB652AA28357057" section-type="undesignated-section">
      <enum/>
      <text>That it is the sense of the <cato:entity-ref entity-id="0050" entity-type="federal-body">House of Representatives</cato:entity-ref> that—</text>
			<paragraph id="id75C5CE696D4C4A28A0A4922CE3795D51">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text>the Government of Mexico should expeditiously release and repatriate Sgt. Tahmooressi and all
			 possessions that have been seized;  and</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id17D90D363EA54D9BBD980466AC6A2028">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text>the <cato:entity-ref entity-id="1101" entity-type="federal-body">President of the United States</cato:entity-ref> should communicate with the Government of Mexico that he will
			 impose increasingly harsh sanctions on Mexico until such time as Sgt.
			 Tahmooressi is released.</text>
      </paragraph>
    </section>
  </resolution-body>
</resolution>
</doc>