<doc>
  <docmeta id="113hr3655ih">
    <bill congress="113" type="hr" number="3655" version="ih"/>
    <revision size="6374" annotations="0" status="complete" id="4" commit-time="2013-12-10T18:52:37Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113hr3655ih/4.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H685CF2B514074944A402DFEA9A9FE686" public-private="public">
  <metadata>
<dublinCore>
<dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">113 HR 3655 IH: To award a Congressional Gold Medal to Simeon Booker in recognition of his achievements in the field of journalism, including reporting during the Civil Rights movement, as well as social and political commentary.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">2013-12-04</dc:date>
<dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
    <congress>113th CONGRESS</congress>
    <session>1st Session</session>
    <legis-num>H. R. 3655</legis-num>
    <current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
    <action>
      <action-date date="20131204">December 4, 2013</action-date>
      <action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="R000577">Mr. Ryan of Ohio</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="J000295">Mr. Joyce</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name>
      </action-desc>
    </action>
    <legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
    <official-title>To award a Congressional Gold Medal to Simeon Booker in recognition of his achievements in the field of journalism, including reporting during the Civil Rights movement, as well as social and political commentary.</official-title>
  </form>
  <legis-body id="HC6D3088092A94E5293FDB6713B09954E" style="OLC">
    <section id="HAFF7DBF8DCA942E784EFF02163EE1B03" section-type="section-one">
      <enum>1.</enum>
      <header>Findings</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">
        <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> finds the following:</text>
      <paragraph id="H37306B48229F4EF7BF0EB289333234CE">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text>Simeon Saunders Booker, Jr., was born on August 27, 1918, in Baltimore, Maryland, to Reberta Waring and Simeon Saunders Booker, Sr., a YMCA director and minister.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HE26EA6D8B9454ED78991D74F99E6147F">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text>After his family moved to Youngstown, Ohio, Booker became interested in journalism.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HA85A82899B6543559849A9BA47307F4E">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <text>Booker promoted and wrote about Negro League baseball teams in Youngstown’s local newspaper, The Vindicator.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H6212A2E374364D87AC95AC9E13E4C40A">
        <enum>(4)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In 1945, he moved back to Ohio to work for the Call and Post, where he became the first African-American reporter to win a Newspaper Guild Award for his series on Cleveland, Ohio, slum housing, and a Willkie Award for reporting on racial inequities in the public schools.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H6BF156B0CD1F45B58B90A397BEB5B6E7">
        <enum>(5)</enum>
        <text>In 1950, Booker was the recipient of the Nieman Fellowship from Harvard University to study journalism and develop his talent as a reporter.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H27E5A67F2A8C4DFF83A054848CCA7D3E">
        <enum>(6)</enum>
        <text>After leaving Harvard in 1951, Booker became the first full-time African-American reporter at The Washington Post.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H8F5275C7D40D4C568A43367C34EB5B7A">
        <enum>(7)</enum>
        <text>In 1955, he helped to advance the civil rights movement with his famous coverage of the Emmett Till murder and trial, turning a common occurrence in the Deep South into a national tragedy that united the black community.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H73F383C3E0984A78B355B1C487CB93A2">
        <enum>(8)</enum>
        <text>He remained at the forefront of the civil rights movement, reporting on the 1957 integration of Central High School in Little Rock, Arkansas.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HDAF3EE60BFE84A57B23D378B9F91B84F">
        <enum>(9)</enum>
        <text>In 1961, he rode with the Congress on Racial Equality (CORE) Freedom Riders through the Deep South.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H5CA666B37C82480893AAA46C39DEC21A">
        <enum>(10)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">When the Freedom Riders were firebombed and beaten in Anniston, Alabama, in a Ku Klux Klan ambush, Booker arranged for their rescue by calling U.S. Attorney General Robert F. Kennedy.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H5857D60C283B4D70AC29E669FE8BA556">
        <enum>(11)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In two wartime tours of Vietnam in the 1960's, he interviewed Black troops on the front lines, and took enemy fire in a helicopter with United States Army General William Westmoreland for reports for Jet and Ebony magazines.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HEA09456BE0DD467CB9C51068C3A5598E">
        <enum>(12)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">He has chronicled the most tumultuous period in American history in two highly acclaimed books, Shocking the Conscience: A Reporter’s Account of the Civil Rights Movement (University Press of Mississippi, 2013), and Black Man’s America (Prentice Hall, 1964).</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H5F4E968B0885467FB2FFD525CA6978B1">
        <enum>(13)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Often called the <quote>dean of the black press</quote>, as chief of Ebony and Jet magazines’ Washington bureau, he interviewed presidents, senators and representatives, members of the judiciary, cabinet officers, foreign ambassadors, and other important members of the Washington community. His column, <quote>Ticker Tape U.S.A.</quote>, became a must-read for politicians and government officials.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H9A6299778F9541A281D65FFF3781B8E2">
        <enum>(14)</enum>
        <text>He covered every Presidential election since the Eisenhower Administration in his fifty-three years with Johnson Publishing until he retired in 2007.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HDA353A64B3284D21968FAF1536461C50">
        <enum>(15)</enum>
        <text>In 1982, Booker received one of the most prestigious awards in journalism, the National Press Club’s Fourth Estate Award.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H8CCBBEE2C7904AB2899300E4A180CB37">
        <enum>(16)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">His honors and awards include: Nieman Fellowship, Harvard University 1950; elected president of the Capitol Press Club, 1956; Fourth Estate Award, National Press Club, 1982; inducted into Hall of Fame, Washington Chapter of Sigma Delta Chi, and Hall of Fame of Washington, D.C., 1984; Master Communicators Award, National Black Media Coalition, 1998; Phoenix Award, Congressional Black Caucus Foundation, 2010; inducted into Hall of Fame, National Association of Black Journalists, 2013.</text>
      </paragraph>
    </section>
    <section id="H466754D5164A4A94855EB53B134AE285">
      <enum>2.</enum>
      <header>Congressional Gold Medal</header>
      <subsection id="H6943FF51597246D18EDA5ECAD78ED905">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Presentation authorized</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Speaker of the House of Representatives" entity-parent-id="0050">Speaker of the House of Representatives</cato:entity-ref> and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="President Pro Tempore of the Senate" entity-parent-id="0010">President Pro Tempore of the Senate</cato:entity-ref> shall make appropriate arrangements for the presentation, on behalf of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref>, of a gold medal of appropriate design, to Simeon Saunders Booker, Jr., in recognition of his achievements in the field of journalism, including reporting during the Civil Rights movement, as well as social and political commentary.</text>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="HE75213448414413A902DAB24A7BD3472">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Design and striking</header>
        <text>For purposes of the presentation referred to in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="113 HR 3655/s:2/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary of the Treasury</cato:entity-ref> (referred to in this Act as the <quote>Secretary</quote>) shall strike a gold medal with suitable emblems, devices, and inscriptions to be determined by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
      </subsection>
    </section>
    <section id="H46DB646A896F469CA4400A068BE3513A">
      <enum>3.</enum>
      <header>Duplicate medals</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> may strike and sell duplicates in bronze of the gold medal struck pursuant to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="113 HR 3655/s:2" proposed="true">section 2</cato:entity-ref> under such regulations as the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> may prescribe, at a price sufficient to cover the cost thereof, including labor, materials, dies, use of machinery, and overhead expenses, and the cost of the gold medal.</text>
    </section>
    <section id="H214858DBDD0241AC947E0DB1E105DE65">
      <enum>4.</enum>
      <header>Status of medals</header>
      <subsection id="H3C0B80B58308450591410730D895380D">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>National medals</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The medals struck pursuant to this Act are national medals for purposes of <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc-chapter/31/51">
            <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/31/51">chapter 51</external-xref> of title 31, United States Code</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="H8E2F1D79F7694756915053ECEB7CAFC2">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Numismatic Items</header>
        <text>For purposes of <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc/31/5134">sections <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/31/5134">5134</external-xref>
          </cato:entity-ref> and <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc/31/5136">
            <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/31/5136">5136</external-xref> of title 31, United States Code</cato:entity-ref>, all medals struck under this Act shall be considered to be numismatic items.</text>
      </subsection>
    </section>
  </legis-body>
</bill>
</doc>