<doc>
  <docmeta id="113hr1229ih">
    <bill congress="113" type="hr" number="1229" version="ih"/>
    <revision size="102290" annotations="0" id="14" commit-time="2013-04-18T22:31:23+00:00" committer="favila" doc="113hr1229ih/14.xml" status="complete">
      <description/>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HC8B4A2AF2E4D4ACB9AF2E0043405F308" public-private="public">
	<metadata>
<dublinCore>
<title>113 HR 1229 IH: Security and Financial Empowerment Act</title>
<publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</publisher>
<date>2013-03-15</date>
<format>text/xml</format>
<language>EN</language>
<rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>113th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 1229</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20130315">March 15, 2013</action-date>
			<action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="R000486">Ms. Roybal-Allard</sponsor>
			 introduced the following bill; which was referred to the
			 <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and the
			 Workforce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on
			 <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Financial Services</committee-name>,
			 <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, and
			 <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, for a
			 period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for
			 consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the
			 committee concerned</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">To promote the economic security and safety
		  of victims of domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, or stalking,
		  and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="HAFDBC1CDE6D34B68ACAE3455D95D5D7B" style="OLC">
		<section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8BC96B523E3D42F18072382B5CD5CD94" section-type="section-one">
      <enum>1.</enum>
      <header>Short title; table of
			 contents</header>
			<subsection id="HA9A93DDC79AD4DECBB0CADDB97CA9136">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Short
			 title</header>
        <text>This Act may be cited as the <quote>
            <short-title>Security and Financial Empowerment
			 Act</short-title>
          </quote>.</text>
			</subsection>
      <subsection id="HC5557F6FD1D14DE6A6A8AA7B4F335C59">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Table of
			 contents</header>
        <text>The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text>
				<toc container-level="legis-body-container" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded" lowest-level="section" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" regeneration="yes-regeneration">
					<toc-entry idref="H8BC96B523E3D42F18072382B5CD5CD94" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title; table of contents.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H372885301A334A1AACAFDFE31180B829" level="section">Sec. 2. Findings.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HEFF9463398164434B994F38220348864" level="title">Title I—Reauthorization of National Resource Center
				grants</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HC77C47CFC8D040798D2DD7EB54A20EE5" level="section">Sec. 101. Grant program reauthorization.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H0E5E32229E6E4C80B44F900BEAC05A04" level="title">Title II—Emergency leave for addressing domestic violence, dating
				violence, sexual assault, or stalking</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H9E6F1C8F08F24F5288FF635DF3ABD60E" level="section">Sec. 201. Amendment to VAWA.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HE4AB73A69E624CE284A89F69CD1344BC" level="section">Sec. 202. Conforming amendments.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H70F818D22CCF466AB7534DECD76C1A7C" level="section">Sec. 203. Effective date.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H8C85218AC9FA4048BCD6ECAF037A3033" level="title">Title III—Victims’ employment sustainability</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HFC07A6A2E29340B9BF75B7CE6803D483" level="section">Sec. 301. Amendment to VAWA.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H89EA0A67220140B2AC555E35A9A11BB9" level="section">Sec. 302. Attorney’s fees.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H0D8BCBE4274F4334B026B53E7FAC4691" level="title">Title IV—Entitlement to unemployment compensation for victims of
				domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, or stalking</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H4AFD6FEC7B7F4483807FDBB91A690B8F" level="section">Sec. 401. Unemployment compensation and training
				provisions.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HED52426655DC483986A403A0B90428A0" level="title">Title V—Victims of abuse insurance protection</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H8AC26D74374540C6855660C3C71E17EB" level="section">Sec. 501. Short title.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HF37C22DBAB7B444DA5B6BE093081604B" level="section">Sec. 502. Definitions.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H8081719C777C4318AAD4409714ECADD6" level="section">Sec. 503. Discriminatory acts prohibited.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H744E2FA171BC4BCABA2EED8D995BF204" level="section">Sec. 504. Insurance protocols for subjects of
				abuse.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H99D85FF5FFE54BD38BEC47DD442DA889" level="section">Sec. 505. Reasons for adverse actions.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H174C36C7C0E14BB5A4DAE423BC085938" level="section">Sec. 506. Life insurance.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H4714FB1B14154F1E8AC7F42B6E2777BD" level="section">Sec. 507. Subrogation without consent prohibited.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H83D0EBBB29F24EDF886690BC0DA34845" level="section">Sec. 508. Enforcement.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H451DD231CCC5431899C534A04179E976" level="section">Sec. 509. Effective date.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HB46A690F43234C52B2149B6D2B3F2CA6" level="title">Title VI—Severability</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 601. Severability.</toc-entry>
				</toc>
			</subsection>
    </section>
    <section id="H372885301A334A1AACAFDFE31180B829">
      <enum>2.</enum>
      <header>Findings</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">
        <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> finds the following:</text>
			<paragraph id="H886F5D9C63F7418595890C4EBA874C37">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text>Violence against
			 women has been reported to be the leading cause of physical injury to women.
			 Such violence has a devastating impact on women’s physical and emotional
			 health, financial security, and ability to maintain their jobs, and thus
			 impacts interstate commerce.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H8B9A7F0B63554558B63DCE62BB990B85">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text>Victims of
			 domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, and stalking are
			 particularly vulnerable to changes in employment, pay, and benefits, and as a
			 result of their desperate need for economic stability, are in particular need
			 of legal protection.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HC4DA6EFD6CCF49F5A47CB993B184CCF6">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <text>The Bureau of
			 National Affairs has estimated that domestic violence costs United States
			 employers between $3,000,000,000 and $5,000,000,000 annually in lost time and
			 productivity, while other reports have estimated the cost at between
			 $5,800,000,000 and $13,000,000,000 annually.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H0FC677B85689434B9E02A640556FA701">
        <enum>(4)</enum>
        <text>United States
			 medical costs for domestic violence have been estimated to be $31,000,000,000
			 per year. The medical cost associated with each incident of domestic violence
			 ranges from $387 to $948, including costs of health care and mental health
			 services.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H4A380466705844099A0E100E5AA22C04">
        <enum>(5)</enum>
        <text>Domestic violence
			 crimes account for approximately 15 percent of total crime costs in the United
			 States each year.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H8A5AF5A31FF24C8CA3608CBFC95561DB">
        <enum>(6)</enum>
        <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H17FB9799EA7444E393B979BD6037DAEF">
          <enum>(A)</enum>
          <text>According to the
			 National Institute of Justice, crime costs an estimated $450,000,000,000
			 annually in medical expenses, lost earnings, social service costs, pain,
			 suffering, and reduced quality of life for victims, which harms the Nation's
			 productivity and drains the Nation's resources.</text>
				</subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="H9B8F588F861E44DDAF2981B8908809BA" indent="up1">
          <enum>(B)</enum>
          <text>Violent crime accounts for
			 $426,000,000,000 per year of this amount.</text>
				</subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="HB768B91775244D6DB3D021A3A9238B3B" indent="up1">
          <enum>(C)</enum>
          <text>Rape exacts the highest costs per
			 victim of any criminal offense, and accounts for $127,000,000,000 per year of
			 the amount described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Security and Financial Empowerment Act/s:2/p:6/sp:A" proposed="true">subparagraph (A)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
				</subparagraph>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H5DC31A42BF6F4E5CB5B8CFD5632802D3">
        <enum>(7)</enum>
        <text>Violent crime
			 results in wage losses equivalent to 1 percent of all United States earnings,
			 and causes 3 percent of the Nation's medical spending and 14 percent of the
			 Nation's injury-related medical spending.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H3C788BC2BD8D4D4AAA136F466073D5FC">
        <enum>(8)</enum>
        <text>Homicide is the
			 leading cause of death for women on the job. Husbands, boyfriends, and
			 ex-partners commit 15 percent of workplace homicides against women.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H26DBC6134BAD4C09BC27DD38E1E01D77">
        <enum>(9)</enum>
        <text>According to a
			 recent study by the National Institutes of Health and Centers for Disease
			 Control and Prevention, each year there are 5,300,000 non-fatal violent
			 victimizations committed by intimate partners against women. Female murder
			 victims were substantially more likely than male murder victims to have been
			 killed by an intimate partner. About <fraction>1/3</fraction> of female murder
			 victims, and about 4 percent of male murder victims, were killed by an intimate
			 partner.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H2F28561C7D0144DBBE15DCD7651E28C6">
        <enum>(10)</enum>
        <text>Forty-nine
			 percent of senior executives recently surveyed said domestic violence has a
			 harmful effect on their company's productivity, 47 percent said domestic
			 violence negatively affects attendance, and 44 percent said domestic violence
			 increases health care costs.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H09909436050343A8BF51D3C5E526E846">
        <enum>(11)</enum>
        <text>Seventy-eight
			 percent of human resources professionals consider partner violence a workplace
			 issue. However, more than 70 percent of United States workplaces have no formal
			 program or policy that addresses workplace violence, let alone domestic
			 violence. In fact, only 4 percent of employers provided training on domestic
			 violence.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HEED9356DEDC74B85B21C50DA6E215E8C">
        <enum>(12)</enum>
        <text>Ninety-four
			 percent of corporate security and safety directors at companies nationwide rank
			 domestic violence as a high security concern.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HC728823A4D8244F6834B58F2C2BF2EB1">
        <enum>(13)</enum>
        <text>Women who have
			 experienced domestic violence or dating violence are more likely than other
			 women to be unemployed, to suffer from health problems that can affect
			 employability and job performance, to report lower personal income, and to rely
			 on welfare.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HCBC4D4CFDD844301BA9A0014504F373D">
        <enum>(14)</enum>
        <text>Studies indicate
			 that one of the best predictors of whether a victim will be able to stay away
			 from her abuser is her degree of economic independence. However, domestic
			 violence, dating violence, sexual assault, and stalking often negatively impact
			 a victim's ability to maintain employment.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HAE7EA7C888584AF1A2F8D64E67488B4E">
        <enum>(15)</enum>
        <text>According to a
			 1998 report of the General Accounting Office, between <fraction>1/4</fraction>
			 and <fraction>½</fraction> of domestic violence victims surveyed in 3 studies
			 reported that they lost a job due, at least in part, to domestic
			 violence.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HFCD0FC1955684FBE876C7A8A962074BB">
        <enum>(16)</enum>
        <text>Employees in the
			 United States who have been victims of domestic violence, dating violence,
			 sexual assault, or stalking too often suffer adverse consequences in the
			 workplace as a result of their victimization.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HF3136B29547D4718AEE06189689AA8BC">
        <enum>(17)</enum>
        <text>Domestic violence
			 also affects abusers’ ability to work. A recent study found that 48 percent of
			 abusers reported having difficulty concentrating at work and 42 percent
			 reported being late to work. Seventy-eight percent reported using their own
			 company’s resources in connection with the abusive relationship.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HB8EBFA4C776B41239FDA61F50E505490">
        <enum>(18)</enum>
        <text>Abusers
			 frequently seek to exert financial control over their partners by actively
			 interfering with their ability to work, including preventing their partners
			 from going to work, harassing their partners at work, limiting the access of
			 their partners to cash or transportation, and sabotaging the child care
			 arrangements of their partners.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H730B2B46AD6E42BA8ADF2F73F8DBF2F4">
        <enum>(19)</enum>
        <text>Studies indicate
			 that between 35 and 56 percent of employed battered women surveyed were
			 harassed at work by their abusive partners.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H03D4855C9E67413F896FD637A6EE8872">
        <enum>(20)</enum>
        <text>More than
			 <fraction>½</fraction> of women receiving welfare have been victims of domestic
			 violence as adults and between <fraction>1/4</fraction> and
			 <fraction>1/3</fraction> of women receiving welfare reported being abused in
			 the last year.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H5BCDB981E2D3484DA1882B94D28FAC75">
        <enum>(21)</enum>
        <text>Victims of
			 domestic violence also frequently miss work due to injuries, court dates, and
			 safety concerns requiring legal protections. Victims of intimate partner
			 violence lose 8,000,000 days of paid work each year, the equivalent of over
			 32,000 full-time jobs and 5,600,000 days of household productivity.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H7734D2BFF0254F619A06AE3089803272">
        <enum>(22)</enum>
        <text>Approximately
			 10,200,000 people have been stalked at some time in their lives. Four out of
			 every 5 stalking victims are women. Stalkers harass and terrorize their victims
			 by spying on the victims, standing outside their places of work or homes,
			 making unwanted phone calls, sending or leaving unwanted letters or items, or
			 vandalizing property.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HC74A8EA2A87741179F8883A63C8C1079">
        <enum>(23)</enum>
        <text>More than 35
			 percent of stalking victims report losing time from work due to the stalking
			 and 7 percent never return to work.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H727A90BD5A91410FB4E17B9814AA023B">
        <enum>(24)</enum>
        <text>The prevalence of
			 sexual assault and other violence against women at work is also dramatic. About
			 36,500 individuals, 80 percent of whom are women, were raped or sexually
			 assaulted in the workplace each year from 1993 through 1999. Half of all female
			 victims of violent workplace crimes know their attackers. Nearly one out of 10
			 violent workplace incidents are committed by partners or spouses. Women who
			 work for State and local governments suffer a higher incidence of workplace
			 assaults, including rapes, than women who work in the private sector.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HB626C723B6CC419DAEDFBFC00F1517CF">
        <enum>(25)</enum>
        <text>According to
			 recent Government estimates, approximately 987,400 rapes occur annually in the
			 United States, with 89 percent of the rapes perpetrated against female victims.
			 Since 2001, rapes have actually increased by 4 percent.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HABB274A234194BD6B11AEFE2F5405A62">
        <enum>(26)</enum>
        <text>Sexual assault,
			 whether occurring in or out of the workplace, can impair an employee's work
			 performance, require time away from work, and undermine the employee's ability
			 to maintain a job. Almost 50 percent of sexual assault survivors lose their
			 jobs or are forced to quit in the aftermath of the assaults. An estimated 24 to
			 30 percent of abused working women lose their jobs due to their abuse.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H730BD5B8AC714EF8951E341CFE4108E3">
        <enum>(27)</enum>
        <text>Domestic and
			 sexual violence victims have been subjected to discrimination by private and
			 State employers, including discrimination motivated by sex and stereotypic
			 notions about women.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H93A9E657E9674AD39B43F99628615A21">
        <enum>(28)</enum>
        <text>Domestic violence
			 victims and third parties who help them have been subjected to discriminatory
			 practices by life, disability, and property and casualty insurers and employers
			 who self-insure employee benefits, who have denied or canceled coverage,
			 rejected claims, and raised rates based on domestic violence. Although some
			 State legislatures have tried to address those practices, the scope of
			 protection afforded by the laws adopted varies from State to State, with many
			 failing to address the problem involved comprehensively. Moreover, Federal law
			 prevents States from protecting the almost 40 percent of employees whose
			 employers self-insure employee benefits.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HC5A5FF48AFFD4B4191D7F5DB45F4EEE0">
        <enum>(29)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Only the States of Hawaii, Illinois, New
			 York, and Oregon prohibit employment discrimination against all victims of
			 domestic violence, sexual assault, or stalking.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H45015E819BC04BF4BDDDB00CD693238C">
        <enum>(30)</enum>
        <text>Employees,
			 including individuals participating in welfare-to-work programs, may need to
			 take time during business hours to—</text>
				<subparagraph id="H477BEC26CB96463B8BC100F20C4786FC">
          <enum>(A)</enum>
          <text>obtain orders of
			 protection;</text>
				</subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="HD83D11681E464BB98F61ABC97E2FE4A9">
          <enum>(B)</enum>
          <text>seek medical or
			 legal assistance, counseling, or other services; or</text>
				</subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="HEFCCE282B6364BA38DCE7F679F022E3C">
          <enum>(C)</enum>
          <text>look for housing
			 in order to escape from domestic violence.</text>
				</subparagraph>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H4C9B0B1728F14AED8D7EE47B16DDB0D5">
        <enum>(31)</enum>
        <text>Only 11 States
			 provide domestic violence victims with leave from work to go to court, to go to
			 the doctor, or to take other steps to address the domestic violence in their
			 lives.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HAAC3F149552449329614F75760D2D288">
        <enum>(32)</enum>
        <text>Only 36 States
			 and the District of Columbia have laws that explicitly provide unemployment
			 insurance to domestic violence victims in certain circumstances, and none of
			 the laws explicitly cover victims of sexual assault or stalking.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HB43D01CB04684390B11084E39A6513DF">
        <enum>(33)</enum>
        <text>Existing Federal
			 law does not explicitly—</text>
				<subparagraph id="H096A0A8FF7414E34AA6D4DF021BF2465">
          <enum>(A)</enum>
          <text>authorize victims
			 of domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, or stalking to take
			 leave from work to seek legal assistance and redress, counseling, or assistance
			 with safety planning activities;</text>
				</subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="H6E89B1F49A514B849789674A17463DB5">
          <enum>(B)</enum>
          <text>address the
			 eligibility of victims of domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault,
			 or stalking for unemployment compensation;</text>
				</subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="H9D2959A8EC35434EB2580321EA0ADF49">
          <enum>(C)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide job protection to actual or
			 perceived victims of domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, or
			 stalking; or</text>
				</subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="HF034E20AC5794D48874BE4FF08D505AB">
          <enum>(D)</enum>
          <clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HF91300E481E444068AA34334585FADDF">
            <enum>(i)</enum>
            <text>prohibit insurers and
			 employers who self-insure employee benefits from discriminating against
			 domestic violence victims and those who help them in determining eligibility,
			 rates charged, and standards for payment of claims; or</text>
					</clause>
          <clause id="HBCDFD9B0DD68414CA6A7AB7553681A48" indent="up1">
            <enum>(ii)</enum>
            <text>prohibit insurers from disclosing
			 information about abuse and the location of the victims through insurance
			 databases and other means.</text>
					</clause>
        </subparagraph>
      </paragraph>
    </section>
    <title id="HEFF9463398164434B994F38220348864">
      <enum>I</enum>
      <header>Reauthorization of
			 National Resource Center grants</header>
			<section id="HC77C47CFC8D040798D2DD7EB54A20EE5">
        <enum>101.</enum>
        <header>Grant program
			 reauthorization</header>
				<subsection id="H6EEF566974E54C5A887A3A8555CB48D6">
          <enum>(a)</enum>
          <header>Information and
			 assistance to victims’ service providers and community
			 organizations</header>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">
            <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Violence Against Women Act/s:41501/ss:a">Section
			 41501(a) of the Violence Against Women Act</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/14043f">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/42/14043f/a">42 U.S.C. 14043f(a)</cato:entity-ref>
              </external-xref>)</cato:entity> is amended by
			 striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>, and to victim service
			 organizations (as defined in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Violence Against Women Act/s:41701">section 41701</cato:entity-ref>), including community based
			 organizations, and tribal, State and territorial domestic violence or sexual
			 assault coalitions to enable them to provide resource materials or other
			 assistance to employers, labor organizations, or employees.</quote>.</text>
				</subsection>
        <subsection id="H6C2AD5EFF07A4ED394687151ED980A78">
          <enum>(b)</enum>
          <header>Authorization of
			 Appropriations</header>
          <text>
            <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Violence Against Women Act/s:41501/ss:e">Section 41501(e) of such Act</cato:entity-ref> is amended by
			 striking <quote>2007 through 2011</quote> and inserting <quote>2014 through
			 2018</quote>.</text>
				</subsection>
        <subsection id="HA51AFC6007E44ECDB0C2A664F74DDEBE">
          <enum>(c)</enum>
          <header>Administrative
			 provisions</header>
          <text>
            <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Violence Against Women Act/s:41501">Section 41501 of such Act</cato:entity-ref> is further amended by adding
			 at the end the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDDA104195D3142EAA9E3389A42B3C48A" style="OLC">
						<subsection id="HA42FD7AA88D341F9AFF7018F933B0574">
              <enum>(g)</enum>
              <header>Administrative
				Costs</header>
							<paragraph id="HD22BCA610AB24DEA869D7B29D5FB9DA6">
                <enum>(1)</enum>
                <header>In
				general</header>
                <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">From the amount
				appropriated under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Violence Against Women Act/s:41501/ss:e">subsection (e)</cato:entity-ref> for each fiscal year, the Attorney General
				shall not use more than 2.5 percent for the administration and monitoring of
				grants made available under this section.</text>
							</paragraph>
              <paragraph id="HD43D392869B447E7A4E3FBD9CA17E8FD">
                <enum>(2)</enum>
                <header>Evaluations</header>
                <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">From the amount appropriated under
				<cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Violence Against Women Act/s:41501/ss:e">subsection (e)</cato:entity-ref> for each fiscal year, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Office on Violence Against Women" entity-parent-id="1500">Director</cato:entity-ref> shall not use more than 5
				percent to award contracts or cooperative agreements to entities with
				demonstrated expertise in program evaluation, to evaluate programs under this
				section.</text>
							</paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
          </quoted-block>
				</subsection>
      </section>
    </title>
    <title id="H0E5E32229E6E4C80B44F900BEAC05A04">
      <enum>II</enum>
      <header>Emergency leave
			 for addressing domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, or
			 stalking</header>
			<section id="H9E6F1C8F08F24F5288FF635DF3ABD60E">
        <enum>201.</enum>
        <header>Amendment to
			 VAWA</header>
        <text display-inline="no-display-inline">The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Violence Against Women Act">Violence Against
			 Women Act</cato:entity-ref> is amended by adding at the end the following new subtitle:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H59F71A97C8E2463B810778D0BE64F40C" style="OLC">
					<subtitle id="HBAC1A7D309294F01B4490DED442346B1">
            <enum>Q</enum>
            <header>Entitlement to
				emergency leave for addressing domestic violence, dating violence, sexual
				assault, or stalking</header>
						<section id="HC6A76AD43F964768B1E54519D9C92592">
              <enum>41701.</enum>
              <header>Definitions</header>
              <text display-inline="no-display-inline">As used in this subtitle, the following
				definitions apply:</text>
							<paragraph id="H7008D53266B24E79A82A6A20FB8448F1">
                <enum>(1)</enum>
                <header>Employ;
				State</header>
                <text>The terms <term>employ</term> and <term>State</term> have
				the meanings given the terms in <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
                    <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938/s:3">section 3 of the Fair Labor Standards Act of
				1938</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/203">29 U.S.C. 203</external-xref>)</cato:entity>.</text>
							</paragraph>
              <paragraph id="H92D63112E72646E7923010F3961984BB">
                <enum>(2)</enum>
                <header>Employee</header>
								<subparagraph id="H7060C4984E064AFFABA9BDD8180D8349">
                  <enum>(A)</enum>
                  <header>In
				general</header>
                  <text>The term <term>employee</term> means any person employed
				by an employer. In the case of an individual employed by a public agency, such
				term means an individual employed as described in <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
                      <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938/s:3/ss:e/p:2">section 3(e)(2) of the Fair
				Labor Standards Act of 1938</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/203">
                        <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/29/203/e/2">29 U.S.C. 203(e)(2)</cato:entity-ref>
                      </external-xref>)</cato:entity>.</text>
								</subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="H1D167434B1E24B6D9DD4070A70BF81EA">
                  <enum>(B)</enum>
                  <header>Basis</header>
                  <text>The
				term includes a person employed as described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Violence Against Women Act/s:41701/p:2/sp:A" proposed="true">subparagraph (A)</cato:entity-ref> on a full- or
				part-time basis, for a fixed time period, on a temporary basis, pursuant to a
				detail, or as a participant in a work assignment as a condition of receipt of
				Federal or State income-based public assistance.</text>
								</subparagraph>
              </paragraph>
              <paragraph id="HAF22CB4060BF4F4A94D3F4494DC3D581">
                <enum>(3)</enum>
                <header>Employer</header>
                <text>The
				term <term>employer</term>—</text>
								<subparagraph id="HFC141BCD2F094B3C8EC93338703C99AA">
                  <enum>(A)</enum>
                  <text>means any person
				engaged in commerce or in any industry or activity affecting commerce who
				employs fifteen or more individuals; and</text>
								</subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="H98A60322FC354EFB899D3FA18FEF1E8B">
                  <enum>(B)</enum>
                  <text>includes any
				person acting directly or indirectly in the interest of an employer in relation
				to an employee, and includes a public agency that employs individuals as
				described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938/s:3/ss:e/p:2">section 3(e)(2) of the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938</cato:entity-ref>, but does
				not include any labor organization (other than when acting as an employer) or
				anyone acting in the capacity of officer or agent of such labor
				organization.</text>
								</subparagraph>
              </paragraph>
              <paragraph id="HC8673444FFD741789BEB32EB3690BA6F">
                <enum>(4)</enum>
                <header>Employment
				benefits</header>
                <text>The term <term>employment benefits</term> means all
				benefits provided or made available to employees by an employer, including
				group life insurance, health insurance, disability insurance, sick leave,
				annual leave, educational benefits, and pensions, regardless of whether such
				benefits are provided by a practice or written policy of an employer or through
				an <quote>employee benefit plan</quote>, as defined in <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
                    <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974/s:3/p:3">section 3(3) of the
				<act-name parsable-cite="ERISA">Employee Retirement Income Security Act of
				1974</act-name>
                    </cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/1002">
                      <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/29/1002//3">29 U.S.C. 1002(3)</cato:entity-ref>
                    </external-xref>)</cato:entity>.</text>
							</paragraph>
              <paragraph id="HA5521AAD47334F54AC2C9B27BDC6764F">
                <enum>(5)</enum>
                <header>Family or
				household member</header>
                <text>The term <term>family or household
				member</term>, used with respect to a person, means a nonabusive individual who
				is a spouse, former spouse, parent, son or daughter, or person residing or
				formerly residing in the same dwelling unit as the person.</text>
							</paragraph>
              <paragraph id="H5FAD3EE7D30D4526B9A8C6968F15C6D1">
                <enum>(6)</enum>
                <header>Parent; son or
				daughter</header>
                <text>The terms <term>parent</term> and <term>son or
				daughter</term> have the meanings given the terms in <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
                    <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Family and Medical Leave Act of 1993/s:101">section 101 of the
				<act-name>Family and Medical Leave Act of 1993</act-name>
                    </cato:entity-ref> (<cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/29/2611">29 U.S.C.
				2611</cato:entity-ref>)</cato:entity>.</text>
							</paragraph>
              <paragraph id="HA559344B0B8E417FB6854FE64DA323F3">
                <enum>(7)</enum>
                <header>Person</header>
                <text>The
				term <term>person</term> has the meaning given the term in <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
                    <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938/s:3">section 3 of the
				<act-name>Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938</act-name>
                    </cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/203">29 U.S.C. 203</external-xref>)</cato:entity>.</text>
							</paragraph>
              <paragraph id="H3744A909B35646D28B822A12B3340E42">
                <enum>(8)</enum>
                <header>Public
				agency</header>
                <text>The term <term>public agency</term> has the meaning given
				the term in <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
                    <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938/s:3">section 3 of the <act-name>Fair Labor Standards Act of
				1938</act-name>
                    </cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/203">29 U.S.C. 203</external-xref>)</cato:entity>.</text>
							</paragraph>
              <paragraph id="H1301DD84C6B74125B09B18351B27E4E2">
                <enum>(9)</enum>
                <header>Public
				assistance</header>
                <text>The term <term>public assistance</term> includes cash,
				food stamps, medical assistance, housing assistance, and other benefits
				provided on the basis of income by a public agency.</text>
							</paragraph>
              <paragraph id="HA2CE5D79F5E94CD7A657E917A4951EF0">
                <enum>(10)</enum>
                <header>Reduced leave
				schedule</header>
                <text>The term <term>reduced leave schedule</term> means a
				leave schedule that reduces the usual number of hours per workweek, or hours
				per workday, of an employee.</text>
							</paragraph>
              <paragraph id="HF03D256BD7C94E50A6EBFEEFDFAACA56">
                <enum>(11)</enum>
                <header>Secretary</header>
                <text>The
				term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Labor.</text>
							</paragraph>
              <paragraph commented="no" id="H6260B543AD154937BB039CCC0504F06B">
                <enum>(12)</enum>
                <header>Victim of
				domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, or
				stalking</header>
                <text>The term <term>victim of domestic violence, dating
				violence, sexual assault, or stalking</term> includes a person who has been a
				victim of domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, or stalking and a
				person whose family or household member has been a victim of domestic violence,
				dating violence, sexual assault, or stalking.</text>
							</paragraph>
              <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5F3130A792C541DF8B2D27D422A3656E">
                <enum>(13)</enum>
                <header>Victim services
				organization</header>
                <text>The term <term>victim services organization</term>
				means a nonprofit, nongovernmental organization that provides assistance to
				victims of domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, or stalking, or
				to advocates for such victims, including a rape crisis center, an organization
				carrying out a domestic violence program, an organization operating a shelter
				or providing counseling services, or an organization providing assistance
				through the legal process.</text>
							</paragraph>
            </section>
            <section id="H79D4F4E731244095A0A23A01E4957E04">
              <enum>41702.</enum>
              <header>Entitlement
				to emergency leave for addressing domestic violence, dating violence, sexual
				assault, or stalking</header>
							<subsection id="HCBE41854CB354399AE38DDA80D8DA8E0">
                <enum>(a)</enum>
                <header>Entitlement to
				leave</header>
								<paragraph id="HE4368B368F2E40018ECA2ECEEE3AAC9F">
                  <enum>(1)</enum>
                  <header>Basis</header>
                  <text>An
				employee who is a victim of domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault,
				or stalking may take leave from work to address domestic violence, dating
				violence, sexual assault, or stalking, by—</text>
									<subparagraph id="H5710AE11105042A9809414C86D991AD6">
                    <enum>(A)</enum>
                    <text>seeking medical
				attention for, or recovering from, physical or psychological injuries caused by
				domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, or stalking to the employee
				or the employee’s family or household member;</text>
									</subparagraph>
                  <subparagraph id="H02FA0D01EA0F4ADCB35F9167F64218FA">
                    <enum>(B)</enum>
                    <text>obtaining services
				from a victim services organization for the employee or the employee’s family
				or household member;</text>
									</subparagraph>
                  <subparagraph id="H2ACD6364DB21499784902E9D135BBB65">
                    <enum>(C)</enum>
                    <text>obtaining
				psychological or other counseling for the employee or the employee’s family or
				household member;</text>
									</subparagraph>
                  <subparagraph id="H9B2F17131E4A487B93F184CCEAB09BD0">
                    <enum>(D)</enum>
                    <text>participating in
				safety planning, temporarily or permanently relocating, or taking other actions
				to increase the safety of the employee or the employee’s family or household
				member from future domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, or
				stalking or ensure economic security; or</text>
									</subparagraph>
                  <subparagraph id="H00F02614F7E441EAB4AF3B01FB0AC43D">
                    <enum>(E)</enum>
                    <text>seeking legal
				assistance or remedies to ensure the health and safety of the employee or the
				employee’s family or household member, including preparing for or participating
				in any civil or criminal legal proceeding related to or derived from domestic
				violence, dating violence, sexual assault, or stalking.</text>
									</subparagraph>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="H3001203E591245418EE3FDFBA1AD2C61">
                  <enum>(2)</enum>
                  <header>Period</header>
                  <text>An
				employee may take not more than 30 days of leave, as described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Violence Against Women Act/s:41702/ss:a/p:1" proposed="true">paragraph
				(1)</cato:entity-ref>, in any 12-month period.</text>
								</paragraph>
                <paragraph id="H124776B1F0D348AD8BE88845173C5D78">
                  <enum>(3)</enum>
                  <header>Schedule</header>
                  <text>Leave
				described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Violence Against Women Act/s:41702/ss:a/p:1" proposed="true">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref> may be taken intermittently or on a reduced leave
				schedule.</text>
								</paragraph>
              </subsection>
              <subsection id="H9C31DB153B424278ABA780DFC83743FA">
                <enum>(b)</enum>
                <header>Notice</header>
                <text>The
				employee shall provide the employer with reasonable notice of the employee’s
				intention to take the leave, unless providing such notice is not
				practicable.</text>
							</subsection>
              <subsection id="H1D0269216D804899BDBEBAEB48A56951">
                <enum>(c)</enum>
                <header>Certification</header>
								<paragraph id="H0223A3FFAE6B439A934449730B23D4B3">
                  <enum>(1)</enum>
                  <header>In
				general</header>
                  <text>The employer may require the employee to provide
				certification to the employer, within a reasonable period after the employer
				requests the certification, that—</text>
									<subparagraph id="HF68C8F384EBB48549F6684FE741416CB">
                    <enum>(A)</enum>
                    <text>the employee or
				the employee’s family or household member is a victim of domestic violence,
				dating violence, sexual assault, or stalking; and</text>
									</subparagraph>
                  <subparagraph id="HFB1D0435264F415E87B124FD2F86DB44">
                    <enum>(B)</enum>
                    <text>the leave is for
				one of the purposes enumerated in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Violence Against Women Act/s:41702/ss:a/p:1" proposed="true">subsection (a)(1)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
									</subparagraph>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="H34E6B3CBC8F54CA19EBE2695EBBE446A">
                  <enum>(2)</enum>
                  <header>Contents</header>
                  <text>An
				employee may satisfy the certification requirement of <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Violence Against Women Act/s:41702/ss:c/p:1" proposed="true">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref> by
				providing to the employer—</text>
									<subparagraph id="H7E3D276D76494CB39E8272F36E1B0E75">
                    <enum>(A)</enum>
                    <text>a sworn statement
				of the employee;</text>
									</subparagraph>
                  <subparagraph id="H1CFAF68D68E048D48C3B8E6FCCB15F48">
                    <enum>(B)</enum>
                    <text>documentation from
				an employee, agent, or volunteer of a victim services organization, an
				attorney, a member of the clergy, or a medical or other professional, from whom
				the employee or the employee’s family or household member has sought assistance
				in addressing domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, or stalking
				and the effects of domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, or
				stalking;</text>
									</subparagraph>
                  <subparagraph id="H11B99D498E284B50832EAA5609B4C865">
                    <enum>(C)</enum>
                    <text>a police or court
				record; or</text>
									</subparagraph>
                  <subparagraph id="HEE1C0B79D64143FFBDD6546B705CADCB">
                    <enum>(D)</enum>
                    <text>other
				corroborating evidence.</text>
									</subparagraph>
                </paragraph>
              </subsection>
              <subsection id="H8E9C50958FD547FE8A8FFDE0E1B73FDB">
                <enum>(d)</enum>
                <header>Confidentiality</header>
                <text>All
				information provided to the employer pursuant to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Violence Against Women Act/s:41702/ss:b" proposed="true">subsection (b)</cato:entity-ref> or <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Violence Against Women Act/s:41702/ss:c" proposed="true">(c)</cato:entity-ref>,
				including a statement of the employee or any other documentation, record, or
				corroborating evidence, and the fact that the employee has requested or
				obtained leave pursuant to this section, shall be retained in the strictest
				confidence by the employer, except to the extent that disclosure is—</text>
								<paragraph id="H73EE2DAD906C479992408A001EFD9917">
                  <enum>(1)</enum>
                  <text>requested or
				consented to by the employee in writing; or</text>
								</paragraph>
                <paragraph id="HDFA3CD5D142D4A7B941E19588608169F">
                  <enum>(2)</enum>
                  <text>otherwise required
				by applicable Federal or State law.</text>
								</paragraph>
              </subsection>
              <subsection id="H3B37291327954A0EACB6684EB20D2807">
                <enum>(e)</enum>
                <header>Employment and
				benefits</header>
								<paragraph id="HD8B9EA71F2864FF8A8C075AEBE2700D8">
                  <enum>(1)</enum>
                  <header>Restoration to
				position</header>
									<subparagraph id="H052E9BC37C7F477297B428021336C8DC">
                    <enum>(A)</enum>
                    <header>In
				general</header>
                    <text>Except as provided in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Violence Against Women Act/s:41702/ss:e/p:2" proposed="true">paragraph (2)</cato:entity-ref>, any employee who
				takes leave under this section for the intended purpose of the leave shall be
				entitled, on return from such leave—</text>
										<clause id="HF0D4203259F148B18046F69417E4B88B">
                      <enum>(i)</enum>
                      <text>to
				be restored by the employer to the position of employment held by the employee
				when the leave commenced; or</text>
										</clause>
                    <clause id="HB4494AE45B854470B238CFDE5CCB1AC3">
                      <enum>(ii)</enum>
                      <text>to be restored to
				an equivalent position with equivalent employment benefits, pay, and other
				terms and conditions of employment.</text>
										</clause>
                  </subparagraph>
                  <subparagraph id="HA59CA42F99A14ED1BAD2E1E4FA5D525C">
                    <enum>(B)</enum>
                    <header>Loss of
				benefits</header>
                    <text>The taking of leave under this section shall not result
				in the loss of any employment benefit accrued prior to the date on which the
				leave commenced.</text>
									</subparagraph>
                  <subparagraph id="H5F1BA09FAB72413493F1C891E2C0595C">
                    <enum>(C)</enum>
                    <header>Limitations</header>
                    <text>Nothing
				in this subsection shall be construed to entitle any restored employee
				to—</text>
										<clause id="H0A72C724F3F04F4BB9F6F27943C5A529">
                      <enum>(i)</enum>
                      <text>the accrual of any
				seniority or employment benefits during any period of leave; or</text>
										</clause>
                    <clause id="HFFB519D93FFC491DAB8E19DEBD0C605E">
                      <enum>(ii)</enum>
                      <text>any right,
				benefit, or position of employment other than any right, benefit, or position
				to which the employee would have been entitled had the employee not taken the
				leave.</text>
										</clause>
                  </subparagraph>
                  <subparagraph id="HBD3FAF33104D463C833636179F63B565">
                    <enum>(D)</enum>
                    <header>Construction</header>
                    <text>Nothing
				in this paragraph shall be construed to prohibit an employer from requiring an
				employee on leave under this section to report periodically to the employer on
				the status and intention of the employee to return to work.</text>
									</subparagraph>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="H4648C1AEC29E469FBA0895ABDC0E8C34">
                  <enum>(2)</enum>
                  <header>Exemption
				concerning certain highly compensated employees</header>
									<subparagraph id="H72C7E4D9215141D18492A13093E97DE2">
                    <enum>(A)</enum>
                    <header>Denial of
				restoration</header>
                    <text>An employer may deny restoration under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Violence Against Women Act/s:41702/ss:e/p:1" proposed="true">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref>
				to any employee described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Violence Against Women Act/s:41702/ss:e/p:2/sp:B" proposed="true">subparagraph (B)</cato:entity-ref> if—</text>
										<clause id="H33C891D4BDC44CFDA710716AE62C9752">
                      <enum>(i)</enum>
                      <text>such denial is
				necessary to prevent substantial and grievous economic injury to the operations
				of the employer;</text>
										</clause>
                    <clause id="HD960CB91B2E2422E9BD01AFE4B394BD0">
                      <enum>(ii)</enum>
                      <text>the employer
				notifies the employee of the intent of the employer to deny restoration on such
				basis at the time the employer determines that such injury would occur;
				and</text>
										</clause>
                    <clause id="H1914DFF884A54E5AAB7F2CE8D7405C06">
                      <enum>(iii)</enum>
                      <text>in any case in
				which the leave has commenced, the employee elects not to return to employment
				after receiving such notice.</text>
										</clause>
                  </subparagraph>
                  <subparagraph id="H6A52687FB7F34100AE3191450AB1C27C">
                    <enum>(B)</enum>
                    <header>Affected
				employees</header>
                    <text>An employee referred to in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Violence Against Women Act/s:41702/ss:e/p:2/sp:A" proposed="true">subparagraph (A)</cato:entity-ref> is a
				salaried employee who is among the highest paid 10 percent of the employees
				employed by the employer within 75 miles of the facility at which the employee
				is employed.</text>
									</subparagraph>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="H06AB373DC5D948BBA518913CE8D29CBF">
                  <enum>(3)</enum>
                  <header>Maintenance of
				health benefits</header>
									<subparagraph id="H1CD9B1145DAE45F48B83129B7711E5E2">
                    <enum>(A)</enum>
                    <header>Coverage</header>
                    <text>Except
				as provided in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Violence Against Women Act/s:41702/ss:e/p:2/sp:B" proposed="true">subparagraph (B)</cato:entity-ref>, during any period that an employee takes leave
				under this section, the employer shall maintain coverage under any group health
				plan (as defined in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:5000/ss:b/p:1">
                        <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/5000">section 5000(b)(1)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986</cato:entity-ref>)
				for the duration of such leave at the level and under the conditions coverage
				would have been provided if the employee had continued in employment
				continuously for the duration of such leave.</text>
									</subparagraph>
                  <subparagraph id="HE2810EFF821A42FBA297391BA78B32F4">
                    <enum>(B)</enum>
                    <header>Failure to
				return from leave</header>
                    <text>The employer may recover the premium that the
				employer paid for maintaining coverage for the employee under such group health
				plan during any period of leave under this section if—</text>
										<clause id="HF4BEF7F5425D4F8E9FD083A10A71AB10">
                      <enum>(i)</enum>
                      <text>the employee fails
				to return from leave under this section after the period of leave to which the
				employee is entitled has expired; and</text>
										</clause>
                    <clause id="H58C4CAEDAA534A5A902576910A33A4BA">
                      <enum>(ii)</enum>
                      <text>the employee
				fails to return to work for a reason other than—</text>
											<subclause id="HC295BAF52DEB42EE99ABC0F70E487BFF">
                        <enum>(I)</enum>
                        <text>the continuation
				of, recurrence of, or onset of an episode of domestic violence, dating
				violence, sexual assault, or stalking, that entitles the employee to leave
				pursuant to this section; or</text>
											</subclause>
                      <subclause id="HE1DA6E204BC2403B85238BFF83130FE4">
                        <enum>(II)</enum>
                        <text>other
				circumstances beyond the control of the employee.</text>
											</subclause>
                    </clause>
                  </subparagraph>
                  <subparagraph id="HD8671D8D11C44B20B1ECE15AAF8302CF">
                    <enum>(C)</enum>
                    <header>Certification</header>
										<clause id="H7966619BD91344D08F417B28C80B517B">
                      <enum>(i)</enum>
                      <header>Issuance</header>
                      <text>An
				employer may require an employee who claims that the employee is unable to
				return to work because of a reason described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Violence Against Women Act/s:41702/ss:e/p:3/sp:B/cl:ii/scl:I" proposed="true">subclause (I)</cato:entity-ref> or <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Violence Against Women Act/s:41702/ss:e/p:3/sp:B/cl:ii/scl:II" proposed="true">(II) of
				subparagraph (B)(ii)</cato:entity-ref> to provide, within a reasonable period after making the
				claim, certification to the employer that the employee is unable to return to
				work because of that reason.</text>
										</clause>
                    <clause id="HEE3B340B68F54BBFB1FE1EDE8F9C93AD">
                      <enum>(ii)</enum>
                      <header>Contents</header>
                      <text>An
				employee may satisfy the certification requirement of <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Violence Against Women Act/s:41702/ss:e/p:3/sp:C/cl:i" proposed="true">clause (i)</cato:entity-ref> by providing
				to the employer—</text>
											<subclause id="H5C0AC70E85A64EA195EFEC56C8E4EC17">
                        <enum>(I)</enum>
                        <text>a sworn statement
				of the employee;</text>
											</subclause>
                      <subclause id="HBCFF6F25809442EEA97F139503EBED9F">
                        <enum>(II)</enum>
                        <text>documentation
				from an employee, agent, or volunteer of a victim services organization, an
				attorney, a member of the clergy, or a medical or other professional, from whom
				the employee or the employee's family or household member has sought assistance
				in addressing domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, or stalking
				and the effects of domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, or
				stalking;</text>
											</subclause>
                      <subclause id="HE219A212835F41ADA208B996671D2DBB">
                        <enum>(III)</enum>
                        <text>a police or
				court record; or</text>
											</subclause>
                      <subclause id="H4595347185EC42F78CCB46A98B7ABC5A">
                        <enum>(IV)</enum>
                        <text>other
				corroborating evidence.</text>
											</subclause>
                    </clause>
                  </subparagraph>
                  <subparagraph id="H5F408DB850304632BC216B9E595227BE">
                    <enum>(D)</enum>
                    <header>Confidentiality</header>
                    <text>All
				information provided to the employer pursuant to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Violence Against Women Act/s:41702/ss:e/p:3/sp:C" proposed="true">subparagraph (C)</cato:entity-ref>, including a
				statement of the employee or any other documentation, record, or corroborating
				evidence, and the fact that the employee is not returning to work because of a
				reason described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Violence Against Women Act/s:41702/ss:e/p:3/sp:B/cl:ii/scl:I" proposed="true">subclause (I)</cato:entity-ref> or <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Violence Against Women Act/s:41702/ss:e/p:3/sp:B/cl:ii/scl:II" proposed="true">(II) of subparagraph (B)(ii)</cato:entity-ref>, shall be
				retained in the strictest confidence by the employer, except to the extent that
				disclosure is—</text>
										<clause id="H4CD4F80FE4DA4A24896C2D82BD965DBF">
                      <enum>(i)</enum>
                      <text>requested or
				consented to by the employee; or</text>
										</clause>
                    <clause id="H4CBCB2F91F774F6F96B8F8E4597349FF">
                      <enum>(ii)</enum>
                      <text>otherwise
				required by applicable Federal or State law.</text>
										</clause>
                  </subparagraph>
                </paragraph>
              </subsection>
              <subsection id="H73CA4C01427C41C9BF7E70F06064C6C6">
                <enum>(f)</enum>
                <header>Prohibited
				acts</header>
								<paragraph id="HFC2352DE5E7D4B90B5ED583D96354E16">
                  <enum>(1)</enum>
                  <header>Interference
				with rights</header>
									<subparagraph id="HC3DD0362ED804CED92AC8CF9E418D138">
                    <enum>(A)</enum>
                    <header>Exercise of
				rights</header>
                    <text>It shall be unlawful for any employer to interfere with,
				restrain, or deny the exercise of or the attempt to exercise, any right
				provided under this section.</text>
									</subparagraph>
                  <subparagraph id="H6A63F94B57B54AA789A54FDFDFE36EE2">
                    <enum>(B)</enum>
                    <header>Employer
				discrimination</header>
                    <text>It shall be unlawful for any employer to discharge
				or harass any individual, or otherwise discriminate against any individual with
				respect to compensation, terms, conditions, or privileges of employment of the
				individual (including retaliation in any form or manner) because the
				individual—</text>
										<clause id="H57FA3657624E4441AB3CEB2406D781EC">
                      <enum>(i)</enum>
                      <text>exercised any
				right provided under this section; or</text>
										</clause>
                    <clause id="H3CC0EBF33A594CF29C51DFC9820EEF12">
                      <enum>(ii)</enum>
                      <text>opposed any
				practice made unlawful by this section.</text>
										</clause>
                  </subparagraph>
                  <subparagraph id="H231BAFA1E9894AD1B24656427D2D4486">
                    <enum>(C)</enum>
                    <header>Public agency
				sanctions</header>
                    <text>It shall be unlawful for any public agency to deny,
				reduce, or terminate the benefits of, otherwise sanction, or harass any
				individual, or otherwise discriminate against any individual (including
				retaliation in any form or manner) with respect to the amount, terms, or
				conditions of public assistance of the individual because the
				individual—</text>
										<clause id="H615BE13D0548418AB1D0D2CEDF5FD974">
                      <enum>(i)</enum>
                      <text>exercised any
				right provided under this section; or</text>
										</clause>
                    <clause id="HA5A0BE760A554A04BF9EBC4F7116FD52">
                      <enum>(ii)</enum>
                      <text>opposed any
				practice made unlawful by this section.</text>
										</clause>
                  </subparagraph>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="HAF748D3EA0414DF685032172F7705220">
                  <enum>(2)</enum>
                  <header>Interference
				with proceedings or inquiries</header>
                  <text>It shall be unlawful for any person
				to discharge or in any other manner discriminate (as described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Violence Against Women Act/s:41702/ss:f/p:1/sp:B" proposed="true">subparagraph
				(B)</cato:entity-ref> or <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Violence Against Women Act/s:41702/ss:f/p:1/sp:C" proposed="true">(C) of paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref>) against any individual because such
				individual—</text>
									<subparagraph id="H2566F2F5BF1D43269E48558653ACD7DB">
                    <enum>(A)</enum>
                    <text>has filed any
				charge, or has instituted or caused to be instituted any proceeding, under or
				related to this section;</text>
									</subparagraph>
                  <subparagraph id="H400D39D26E26493EA01BF10F31C97900">
                    <enum>(B)</enum>
                    <text>has given, or is
				about to give, any information in connection with any inquiry or proceeding
				relating to any right provided under this section; or</text>
									</subparagraph>
                  <subparagraph id="HE848820B5C0647BEA527A19688413ADA">
                    <enum>(C)</enum>
                    <text>has testified, or
				is about to testify, in any inquiry or proceeding relating to any right
				provided under this section.</text>
									</subparagraph>
                </paragraph>
              </subsection>
              <subsection id="H1EF1BA19E3D84A9B9476EBE58A46B8A2">
                <enum>(g)</enum>
                <header>Enforcement</header>
								<paragraph id="H437B8DF3F35E4464A337E9E853D78C36">
                  <enum>(1)</enum>
                  <header>Civil action by
				affected individuals</header>
									<subparagraph id="HA571571821B94365951ECD46112170C8">
                    <enum>(A)</enum>
                    <header>Liability</header>
                    <text>Any
				employer that violates <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Violence Against Women Act/s:41702/ss:f" proposed="true">subsection (f)</cato:entity-ref> shall be liable to any individual
				affected—</text>
										<clause id="HF8717A74233642F0AFD9F6C6DA4AE07F">
                      <enum>(i)</enum>
                      <text>for damages equal
				to—</text>
											<subclause id="HDAB539D1E9E84AFB90D6BAB4F75B7613">
                        <enum>(I)</enum>
                        <text>the amount
				of—</text>
												<item id="H84E900B829AD4FC9B69C0A553A764129">
                          <enum>(aa)</enum>
                          <text>any
				wages, salary, employment benefits, or other compensation denied or lost to
				such individual by reason of the violation; or</text>
												</item>
                        <item id="H9E9F44304A8344D2BC2D63D06526E44B">
                          <enum>(bb)</enum>
                          <text>in
				a case in which wages, salary, employment benefits, or other compensation has
				not been denied or lost to the individual, any actual monetary losses sustained
				by the individual as a direct result of the violation;</text>
												</item>
                      </subclause>
                      <subclause id="HBCA93A160EE94C9A8B370A7D07F5D19E">
                        <enum>(II)</enum>
                        <text>the interest on
				the amount described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Violence Against Women Act/s:41702/ss:g/p:1/sp:A/cl:i/scl:I" proposed="true">subclause (I)</cato:entity-ref> calculated at the prevailing rate;
				and</text>
											</subclause>
                      <subclause id="HE31B8463D73F4CDC931F9B433410C323">
                        <enum>(III)</enum>
                        <text>an additional
				amount as liquidated damages equal to the sum of the amount described in
				<cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Violence Against Women Act/s:41702/ss:g/p:1/sp:A/cl:i/scl:I" proposed="true">subclause (I)</cato:entity-ref> and the interest described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Violence Against Women Act/s:41702/ss:g/p:1/sp:A/cl:i/scl:II" proposed="true">subclause (II)</cato:entity-ref>, except that if an
				employer that has violated <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Violence Against Women Act/s:41702/ss:f" proposed="true">subsection (f)</cato:entity-ref> proves to the satisfaction of the
				court that the act or omission that violated <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Violence Against Women Act/s:41702/ss:f" proposed="true">subsection (f)</cato:entity-ref> was in good faith
				and that the employer had reasonable grounds for believing that the act or
				omission was not a violation of <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Violence Against Women Act/s:41702/ss:f" proposed="true">subsection (f)</cato:entity-ref>, such court may, in the
				discretion of the court, reduce the amount of the liability to the amount and
				interest determined under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Violence Against Women Act/s:41702/ss:g/p:1/sp:A/cl:i/scl:I" proposed="true">subclauses (I)</cato:entity-ref> and <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Violence Against Women Act/s:41702/ss:g/p:1/sp:A/cl:i/scl:II" proposed="true">(II)</cato:entity-ref>, respectively; and</text>
											</subclause>
                    </clause>
                    <clause id="H21CF102BED07442DA39ECF554690D59D">
                      <enum>(ii)</enum>
                      <text>for such
				equitable relief as may be appropriate, including employment, reinstatement,
				and promotion.</text>
										</clause>
                  </subparagraph>
                  <subparagraph id="H43CC07FE9AA44B59AB7A4F910D7A54F0">
                    <enum>(B)</enum>
                    <header>Right of
				action</header>
                    <text>An action to recover the damages or equitable relief
				prescribed in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Violence Against Women Act/s:41702/ss:g/p:1/sp:A" proposed="true">subparagraph (A)</cato:entity-ref> may be maintained against any employer in any
				Federal or State court of competent jurisdiction by any one or more affected
				individuals for and on behalf of—</text>
										<clause id="H9294126753DE43C98463E40CCACE0A31">
                      <enum>(i)</enum>
                      <text>the individuals;
				or</text>
										</clause>
                    <clause id="H2CE99D3BE1A54974BAADC2DB7478D9DE">
                      <enum>(ii)</enum>
                      <text>the individuals
				and other individuals similarly situated.</text>
										</clause>
                  </subparagraph>
                  <subparagraph id="H142FA61A19234E5295C0F3E601D733B7">
                    <enum>(C)</enum>
                    <header>Fees and
				costs</header>
                    <text>The court in such an action shall, in addition to any
				judgment awarded to the plaintiff, allow a reasonable attorney’s fee,
				reasonable expert witness fees, and other costs of the action to be paid by the
				defendant.</text>
									</subparagraph>
                  <subparagraph id="H68A09B7F37974A11803C8B13346F9D6E">
                    <enum>(D)</enum>
                    <header>Limitations</header>
                    <text>The
				right provided by <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Violence Against Women Act/s:41702/ss:g/p:1/sp:B" proposed="true">subparagraph (B)</cato:entity-ref> to bring an action by or on behalf of any
				affected individual shall terminate—</text>
										<clause id="HBABA8952068E486F9978FF17A231D0BB">
                      <enum>(i)</enum>
                      <text>on
				the filing of a complaint by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> in an action under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Violence Against Women Act/s:41702/ss:g/p:4" proposed="true">paragraph (4)</cato:entity-ref> in
				which restraint is sought of any further delay in the payment of the amount
				described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Violence Against Women Act/s:41702/ss:g/p:1/sp:A/cl:i" proposed="true">subparagraph (A)(i)</cato:entity-ref> to such individual by an employer responsible
				under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Violence Against Women Act/s:41702/ss:g/p:1/sp:A" proposed="true">subparagraph (A)</cato:entity-ref> for the payment; or</text>
										</clause>
                    <clause id="H568EDB1F8DE542DB81A24E540F4F16DF">
                      <enum>(ii)</enum>
                      <text>on the filing of
				a complaint by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> in an action under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Violence Against Women Act/s:41702/ss:g/p:2" proposed="true">paragraph (2)</cato:entity-ref> in which a
				recovery is sought of the damages described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Violence Against Women Act/s:41702/ss:g/p:1/sp:A/cl:i" proposed="true">subparagraph (A)(i)</cato:entity-ref> owing to an
				affected individual by an employer liable under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Violence Against Women Act/s:41702/ss:g/p:1/sp:A" proposed="true">subparagraph (A)</cato:entity-ref>,</text>
										</clause>
                    <continuation-text continuation-text-level="subparagraph">unless
				the action described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Violence Against Women Act/s:41702/ss:g/p:1/sp:C/cl:i" proposed="true">clause (i)</cato:entity-ref> or <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Violence Against Women Act/s:41702/ss:g/p:1/sp:C/cl:ii" proposed="true">(ii)</cato:entity-ref> is dismissed without prejudice on
				motion of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref>.</continuation-text>
                  </subparagraph>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="H68F84F32478741BFB1164E3635D19F05">
                  <enum>(2)</enum>
                  <header>Action by the
				Secretary</header>
									<subparagraph id="HEAEB15859CF04313BE50BE5ECEBD85C4">
                    <enum>(A)</enum>
                    <header>Administrative
				action</header>
                    <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall receive, investigate, and attempt to
				resolve complaints of violations of <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Violence Against Women Act/s:41702/ss:f" proposed="true">subsection (f)</cato:entity-ref> in the same manner as the
				<cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> receives, investigates, and attempts to resolve complaints of
				violations of <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938/s:6">sections 6</cato:entity-ref> and <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938/s:7">7 of the <act-name>Fair Labor Standards Act of
				1938</act-name>
                      </cato:entity-ref> (<cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc/29/206">29 U.S.C. 206</cato:entity-ref> and <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc/29/207">207</cato:entity-ref>).</text>
									</subparagraph>
                  <subparagraph id="H906578212EAC4206AB751FD28BF8D037">
                    <enum>(B)</enum>
                    <header>Civil
				action</header>
                    <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> may bring an action in any court of
				competent jurisdiction to recover the damages described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Violence Against Women Act/s:41702/ss:g/p:1/sp:A/cl:i" proposed="true">paragraph
				(1)(A)(i)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
									</subparagraph>
                  <subparagraph id="H72DC9EAC02544D24A3CAB81BF8C1DD79">
                    <enum>(C)</enum>
                    <header>Sums
				recovered</header>
                    <text>Any sums recovered by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> pursuant to
				<cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Violence Against Women Act/s:41702/ss:g/p:2/sp:B" proposed="true">subparagraph (B)</cato:entity-ref> shall be held in a special deposit account and shall be paid,
				on order of the Secretary, directly to each individual affected. Any such sums
				not paid to such an individual because of inability to do so within a period of
				3 years shall be deposited into the Treasury of the United States as
				miscellaneous receipts.</text>
									</subparagraph>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="H4A936EB2B069475F939C3B746EDE7FC3">
                  <enum>(3)</enum>
                  <header>Limitation</header>
									<subparagraph id="HF257015DB6884DF6B418181E2F7D1072">
                    <enum>(A)</enum>
                    <header>In
				general</header>
                    <text>Except as provided in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Violence Against Women Act/s:41702/ss:g/p:2/sp:B" proposed="true">subparagraph (B)</cato:entity-ref>, an action may be
				brought under this subsection not later than 2 years after the date of the last
				event constituting the alleged violation for which the action is
				brought.</text>
									</subparagraph>
                  <subparagraph id="H17668C393F2E4F58B8FA051DB9FC2830">
                    <enum>(B)</enum>
                    <header>Willful
				violation</header>
                    <text>In the case of such action brought for a willful
				violation of <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Violence Against Women Act/s:41702/ss:f" proposed="true">subsection (f)</cato:entity-ref>, such action may be brought within 3 years after
				the date of the last event constituting the alleged violation for which such
				action is brought.</text>
									</subparagraph>
                  <subparagraph id="H2D7F21221904499F8EF38E585A7FCDDC">
                    <enum>(C)</enum>
                    <header>Commencement</header>
                    <text>In
				determining when an action is commenced by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> under this subsection
				for the purposes of this paragraph, it shall be considered to be commenced on
				the date when the complaint is filed.</text>
									</subparagraph>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="H39A52382F09E46F6A3328954AC1081C9">
                  <enum>(4)</enum>
                  <header>Action for
				injunction by Secretary</header>
                  <text>The district courts of the United States
				shall have jurisdiction, for cause shown, in an action brought by the
				<cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref>—</text>
									<subparagraph id="HEC99B639B02D46E885EA91CFB00D13DE">
                    <enum>(A)</enum>
                    <text>to restrain
				violations of <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Violence Against Women Act/s:41702/ss:f" proposed="true">subsection (f)</cato:entity-ref>, including the restraint of any withholding of
				payment of wages, salary, employment benefits, or other compensation, plus
				interest, found by the court to be due to affected individuals; or</text>
									</subparagraph>
                  <subparagraph id="HAF32A4A1F72540678D236729A1FEC7E2">
                    <enum>(B)</enum>
                    <text>to award such
				other equitable relief as may be appropriate, including employment,
				reinstatement, and promotion.</text>
									</subparagraph>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="H97EAEC4ABB9E46969FCB1DB8A65748D1">
                  <enum>(5)</enum>
                  <header>Solicitor of
				Labor</header>
                  <text>The Solicitor of Labor may appear for and represent the
				<cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> on any litigation brought under this subsection.</text>
								</paragraph>
                <paragraph id="HA0719BD3ABA34D31A1EC1A7566DF878C">
                  <enum>(6)</enum>
                  <header>Employer
				liability under other laws</header>
                  <text>Nothing in this section shall be
				construed to limit the liability of an employer or public agency to an
				individual, for harm suffered relating to the individual’s experience of
				domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, or stalking, pursuant to
				any other Federal or State law, including a law providing for a legal
				remedy.</text>
								</paragraph>
                <paragraph commented="no" id="H253B755FCD044D629B13D9F851C56AB9">
                  <enum>(7)</enum>
                  <header>Library of
				Congress</header>
                  <text>Notwithstanding any other provision of this subsection,
				in the case of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0300">Library of Congress</cato:entity-ref>, the authority of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> under
				this subsection shall be exercised by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0300">Librarian of Congress</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
								</paragraph>
                <paragraph commented="no" id="H15461248372F4A078962673277D5ABA6">
                  <enum>(8)</enum>
                  <header>Certain public
				agency employers</header>
									<subparagraph commented="no" id="H8C5BC6404E874F4FBDE8929BB5FE4805">
                    <enum>(A)</enum>
                    <header>Agencies</header>
                    <text>Notwithstanding
				any other provision of this subsection, in the case of a public agency that
				employs individuals as described in <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
                        <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938/s:3/ss:e/p:2/sp:A">subparagraph (A)</cato:entity-ref> or <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938/s:3/ss:e/p:2/sp:B">(B) of section 3(e)(2)
				of the <act-name>Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938</act-name>
                        </cato:entity-ref> (<cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/29/203/e/2">29 U.S.C.
				203(e)(2)</cato:entity-ref>)</cato:entity> (other than an entity of the legislative branch of the Federal
				Government), <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Violence Against Women Act/s:41702/ss:g/p:8/sp:B" proposed="true">subparagraph (B)</cato:entity-ref> shall apply.</text>
									</subparagraph>
                  <subparagraph commented="no" id="H897BF6642BB941148A65EEDE55AF35C5">
                    <enum>(B)</enum>
                    <header>Authority</header>
                    <text>In
				the case described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Violence Against Women Act/s:41702/ss:g/p:8/sp:A" proposed="true">subparagraph (A)</cato:entity-ref>, the powers, remedies, and procedures
				provided in the case of a violation of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/63">chapter 63</external-xref> of title 5, United States
				Code, in that title to an employing agency, in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc-chapter/5/12">chapter 12 of that title</cato:entity-ref> to the
				Merit Systems Protection Board, or in that title to any person alleging a
				violation of <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc-chapter/5/63">chapter 63 of that title</cato:entity-ref>, shall be the powers, remedies, and
				procedures this subsection provides in the case of a violation of <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Violence Against Women Act/s:41702/ss:f" proposed="true">subsection
				(f)</cato:entity-ref> to that agency, that Board, or any person alleging a violation of
				<cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Violence Against Women Act/s:41702/ss:f" proposed="true">subsection (f)</cato:entity-ref>, respectively, against an employee who is such an
				individual.</text>
									</subparagraph>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph commented="no" id="H21C00B7359774212ABE7ADC686343840">
                  <enum>(9)</enum>
                  <header>Public agencies
				providing public assistance</header>
                  <text>Consistent with regulations
				prescribed under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Violence Against Women Act/s:106/ss:d">section 106(d)</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> shall ensure that any public
				agency that violates <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Violence Against Women Act/s:41702/ss:f/p:1/sp:C" proposed="true">subsection (f)(1)(C)</cato:entity-ref>, or <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Violence Against Women Act/s:41702/ss:f/p:2" proposed="true">subsection (f)(2)</cato:entity-ref> by
				discriminating as described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Violence Against Women Act/s:41702/ss:f/p:1/sp:C" proposed="true">subsection (f)(1)(C)</cato:entity-ref>, shall provide to any
				individual who receives a less favorable amount, term, or condition of public
				assistance as a result of the violation—</text>
									<subparagraph commented="no" id="H8ED4DAF1118F4EE8808B4BAF0A01D77A">
                    <enum>(A)</enum>
                    <clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HD7889F5FAE08412B8BA6B5B3ED9AE90A">
                      <enum>(i)</enum>
                      <text>the amount of any public
				assistance denied or lost to such individual by reason of the violation;
				and</text>
										</clause>
                    <clause commented="no" id="HD25914E636914AB9A22A401427D60A67" indent="up1">
                      <enum>(ii)</enum>
                      <text>the interest on the amount
				described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Violence Against Women Act/s:41702/ss:g/p:8/sp:A/cl:i" proposed="true">clause (i)</cato:entity-ref>; and</text>
										</clause>
                  </subparagraph>
                  <subparagraph commented="no" id="H73FEFA518F4F43AEA3342ADE220D2227">
                    <enum>(B)</enum>
                    <text>such equitable
				relief as may be appropriate.</text>
									</subparagraph>
                </paragraph>
              </subsection>
            </section>
            <section id="H6D27483FB0014BC39152AE5DD29C8C49">
              <enum>41703.</enum>
              <header>Existing
				leave usable for addressing domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault,
				or stalking</header>
              <text display-inline="no-display-inline">An employee who is
				entitled to take paid or unpaid leave (including family, medical, sick, annual,
				personal, or similar leave) from employment, pursuant to State or local law, a
				collective bargaining agreement, or an employment benefits program or plan, may
				elect to substitute any period of such leave for an equivalent period of leave
				provided under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Violence Against Women Act/s:41702" proposed="true">section 41702</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
						</section>
            <section id="HEAC50F2EB00D4A8CBD99057B638D2B97">
              <enum>41704.</enum>
              <header>Emergency
				benefits</header>
							<subsection id="H26E1F6D2F30D402FA42215FF0B44A169">
                <enum>(a)</enum>
                <header>In
				general</header>
                <text>A State may use funds provided to the State under <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
                    <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Social Security Act/t:IV/pt:A">part A
				of title IV of the <act-name parsable-cite="SSA">Social Security Act</act-name>
                    </cato:entity-ref>
				(<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/601">
                      <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/42/601/etseq">42 U.S.C. 601 et seq.</cato:entity-ref>
                    </external-xref>)</cato:entity> to provide nonrecurrent short-term emergency benefits
				to an individual for any period of leave the individual takes pursuant to
				<cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Violence Against Women Act/s:41702" proposed="true">section 41702</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
							</subsection>
              <subsection id="H46212A3013BB47B5BD3B4139C7134F4B">
                <enum>(b)</enum>
                <header>Eligibility</header>
                <text>In
				calculating the eligibility of an individual for such emergency benefits, the
				State shall count only the cash available or accessible to the
				individual.</text>
							</subsection>
              <subsection id="HFE208C5DC9264CAD8FB30357DD86A83F">
                <enum>(c)</enum>
                <header>Timing</header>
								<paragraph id="HD6C1D198525447EBA05C5230ACB5797E">
                  <enum>(1)</enum>
                  <header>Applications</header>
                  <text>An
				individual seeking emergency benefits under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Violence Against Women Act/s:41704/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref> from a State shall
				submit an application to the State.</text>
								</paragraph>
                <paragraph id="H8AB1FF02A8D749258CDD96D3BC195874">
                  <enum>(2)</enum>
                  <header>Benefits</header>
                  <text>The
				State shall provide benefits to an eligible applicant under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Violence Against Women Act/s:41704/ss:c/p:1" proposed="true">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref> on an
				expedited basis, and not later than 7 days after the applicant submits an
				application under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Violence Against Women Act/s:41704/ss:c/p:1" proposed="true">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
								</paragraph>
              </subsection>
            </section>
            <section id="HBD2FA83B25164939A29BB5493D844C12">
              <enum>41705.</enum>
              <header>Effect on
				other laws and employment benefits</header>
							<subsection id="H8AF15DA904CD4F0F89AF972CFDD1530C">
                <enum>(a)</enum>
                <header>More protective
				laws, agreements, programs, and plans</header>
                <text>Nothing in this title shall
				be construed to supersede any provision of any Federal, State, or local law,
				collective bargaining agreement, or employment benefits program or plan that
				provides—</text>
								<paragraph id="HB651E2AB826242D6B9439C764BD596A4">
                  <enum>(1)</enum>
                  <text>greater leave
				benefits for victims of domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, or
				stalking than the rights established under this title; or</text>
								</paragraph>
                <paragraph id="H74239421930B4555A547A5D7B49F3386">
                  <enum>(2)</enum>
                  <text>leave benefits for
				a larger population of victims of domestic violence, dating violence, sexual
				assault, or stalking (as defined in such law, agreement, program, or plan) than
				the victims of domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, or stalking
				covered under this title.</text>
								</paragraph>
              </subsection>
              <subsection id="H1C6E7BD644CA49F09F056E7E0E6FF7AF">
                <enum>(b)</enum>
                <header>Less protective
				laws, agreements, programs, and plans</header>
                <text>The rights established for
				victims of domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, or stalking
				under this title shall not be diminished by any State or local law, collective
				bargaining agreement, or employment benefits program or plan.</text>
							</subsection>
            </section>
            <section commented="no" id="HD3B9E49B65254281940A40BA85B2DD67">
              <enum>41706.</enum>
              <header>Regulations</header>
							<subsection commented="no" id="HE9B9247C0D6444D499EBD36855D1AFCD">
                <enum>(a)</enum>
                <header>In
				general</header>
								<paragraph commented="no" id="H4D8FBA36D9C243DF86903A09D5369EAD">
                  <enum>(1)</enum>
                  <header>Authority to
				issue regulations</header>
                  <text>Except as provided in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Violence Against Women Act/s:41706/ss:b" proposed="true">subsections (b)</cato:entity-ref>, <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Violence Against Women Act/s:41706/ss:c" proposed="true">(c)</cato:entity-ref>, and
				<cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Violence Against Women Act/s:41706/ss:d" proposed="true">(d)</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall issue regulations to carry out this title.</text>
								</paragraph>
                <paragraph commented="no" id="HEAC2AD1EAF3A467499EF5AAFA3E21F01">
                  <enum>(2)</enum>
                  <header>Regulations
				regarding notices</header>
                  <text>The regulations described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Violence Against Women Act/s:41706/ss:a/p:1" proposed="true">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref>
				shall include regulations requiring every employer to post and keep posted, in
				conspicuous places on the premises of the employer where notices to employees
				are customarily placed, a notice, to be prepared or approved by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref>,
				summarizing the provisions of this title and providing information on
				procedures for filing complaints. The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall develop such a notice and
				provide copies to employers upon request without charge.</text>
								</paragraph>
              </subsection>
              <subsection commented="no" id="H4622DAD3D93A4327B4AC3AF6B44FA36A">
                <enum>(b)</enum>
                <header>Library of
				Congress</header>
                <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0300">Librarian of Congress</cato:entity-ref> shall prescribe the
				regulations described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Violence Against Women Act/s:41706/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref> with respect to employees of the
				<cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0300">Library of Congress</cato:entity-ref>. The regulations prescribed under this subsection shall, to
				the extent appropriate, be consistent with the regulations prescribed by the
				<cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Violence Against Women Act/s:41706/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
							</subsection>
              <subsection commented="no" id="HA7A069949A544ABBAF1B17C77C53B47E">
                <enum>(c)</enum>
                <header>Certain public
				agency employers</header>
                <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2400">Office of Personnel Management</cato:entity-ref> shall
				prescribe the regulations described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Violence Against Women Act/s:41706/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref> with respect to
				individuals described in <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
                    <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938/s:3/ss:e/p:2/sp:A">subparagraph (A)</cato:entity-ref> or <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938/s:3/ss:e/p:2/sp:B">(B) of section 3(e)(2) of the
				<act-name>Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938</act-name>
                    </cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/203">
                      <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/29/203/e/2">29 U.S.C. 203(e)(2)</cato:entity-ref>
                    </external-xref>)</cato:entity>
				(other than an individual employed by an entity of the legislative branch of
				the Federal Government). The regulations prescribed under this subsection
				shall, to the extent appropriate, be consistent with the regulations prescribed
				by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Violence Against Women Act/s:41706/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
							</subsection>
              <subsection commented="no" id="H53A46B3737B645DCB290F8891B5E1C91">
                <enum>(d)</enum>
                <header>Public agencies
				providing public assistance</header>
                <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> shall prescribe the
				regulations described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Violence Against Women Act/s:41706/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref> with respect to applicants for and
				recipients of public assistance, in the case of violations of <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Violence Against Women Act/s:41702/ss:f/p:1/sp:C">section
				41702(f)(1)(C)</cato:entity-ref>, or <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Violence Against Women Act/s:41702/ss:f/p:2">section 41702(f)(2)</cato:entity-ref> due to discrimination described in
				<cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Violence Against Women Act/s:41702/ss:f/p:1/sp:C">section 41702(f)(1)(C)</cato:entity-ref>. The regulations prescribed under this subsection shall,
				to the extent appropriate, be consistent with the regulations prescribed by the
				<cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Violence Against Women Act/s:41706/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection
				(a)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
							</subsection>
            </section>
          </subtitle>
          <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
        </quoted-block>
			</section>
      <section id="HE4AB73A69E624CE284A89F69CD1344BC">
        <enum>202.</enum>
        <header>Conforming
			 amendments</header>
				<subsection id="H296A38E1DA1A47DDB32E02788DD920C4">
          <enum>(a)</enum>
          <header>Social Security
			 Act</header>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">
            <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Social Security Act/s:404">Section 404 of the
			 <act-name parsable-cite="SSA">Social Security Act</act-name>
              </cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/604">42 U.S.C. 604</external-xref>)</cato:entity> is
			 amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
					<quoted-block act-name="Social Security Act" id="HCA73129115D44F63A66E3B8BCF085E70">
						<subsection id="H5717CAE8F4124067AACE58EDE20185BD">
              <enum>(l)</enum>
              <header>Authority To
				provide emergency benefits</header>
              <text>A State that receives a grant under
				<cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Social Security Act/s:403">section 403</cato:entity-ref> may use the grant to provide nonrecurrent short-term emergency
				benefits, in accordance with <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Violence Against Women Act/s:41704">section 41704 of the Violence Against Women Act</cato:entity-ref>,
				to individuals who take leave pursuant to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Violence Against Women Act/s:41702">section 41702 of that Act</cato:entity-ref>, without
				regard to whether the individuals receive assistance under the State program
				funded under this
				part.</text>
						</subsection>
            <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
          </quoted-block>
				</subsection>
        <subsection id="HC173CA727F4F4F72A113C16D2266CECA">
          <enum>(b)</enum>
          <header>Rehabilitation
			 Act</header>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">
            <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Rehabilitation Act Amendments of 1986/s:1003/ss:a/p:1">Section 1003(a)(1) of the
			 Rehabilitation Act Amendments of 1986</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000d-7">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/42/2000d–7/a/1">42 U.S.C. 2000d–7(a)(1)</cato:entity-ref>
              </external-xref>)</cato:entity> is amended by
			 inserting <quote>section 41702 of the Violence Against Women Act,</quote> after
			 <quote>
              <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Civil Rights Act of 1964">Civil Rights Act of 1964</cato:entity-ref>,</quote>.</text>
				</subsection>
      </section>
      <section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H70F818D22CCF466AB7534DECD76C1A7C" section-type="subsequent-section">
        <enum>203.</enum>
        <header>Effective
			 date</header>
        <text display-inline="no-display-inline">The amendments made by
			 this title take effect 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act.</text>
			</section>
    </title>
    <title id="H8C85218AC9FA4048BCD6ECAF037A3033">
      <enum>III</enum>
      <header>Victims’
			 employment sustainability</header>
			<section id="HFC07A6A2E29340B9BF75B7CE6803D483">
        <enum>301.</enum>
        <header>Amendment to
			 VAWA</header>
        <text display-inline="no-display-inline">The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Violence Against Women Act">Violence Against
			 Women Act</cato:entity-ref>, as amended by <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Security and Financial Empowerment Act/s:101" proposed="true">section 101</cato:entity-ref>, is further amended by adding at the end
			 the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEE20B0B0BD5244B69CBEF616AA818DCF" style="OLC">
					<subtitle id="HD31AA5CDD66D4E0AB2F769ECE85CE7CB">
            <enum>R</enum>
            <header>Victims’
				employment sustainability</header>
						<section id="HB982B5B8AC324BFFBDC886A70F85A372">
              <enum>41801.</enum>
              <header>Short
				title</header>
              <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This subtitle may be
				cited as the <quote>
                  <short-title>Victims’ Employment
				Sustainability Act</short-title>
                </quote>.</text>
						</section>
            <section id="H02225AD141CC4D00BBC957FE762A750A">
              <enum>41802.</enum>
              <header>Prohibited
				discriminatory acts</header>
							<subsection id="HD43DFD7225E44BB1AE3E8D56C2E869F6">
                <enum>(a)</enum>
                <header>In
				general</header>
                <text>An employer shall not fail to hire, refuse to hire,
				discharge, or harass any individual, or otherwise discriminate against any
				individual with respect to the compensation, terms, conditions, or privileges
				of employment of the individual (including retaliation in any form or manner),
				and a public agency shall not deny, reduce, or terminate the benefits of,
				otherwise sanction, or harass any individual, or otherwise discriminate against
				any individual with respect to the amount, terms, or conditions of public
				assistance of the individual (including retaliation in any form or manner),
				because—</text>
								<paragraph id="H3B915D79810845958A7ED8CF9DB727A5">
                  <enum>(1)</enum>
                  <text>the individual
				involved is or the employer or public agency involved perceives that individual
				to be a victim of domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, or
				stalking;</text>
								</paragraph>
                <paragraph id="HCAF21E8DDEBA4798AA973DB4143F410F">
                  <enum>(2)</enum>
                  <text>that individual
				attended, participated in, prepared for, or requested leave to attend,
				participate in, or prepare for, a criminal or civil court proceeding relating
				to an incident of domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, or
				stalking of which the individual, or the family or household member of the
				individual, was a victim;</text>
								</paragraph>
                <paragraph id="HB42517FBDD2F4BACA2454455BA626093">
                  <enum>(3)</enum>
                  <text>that individual,
				in response to actual or threatened domestic violence, dating violence, sexual
				assault, or stalking, requested that the employer or public agency implement a
				reasonable safety procedure or a job-related modification to enhance the
				security of that individual or safeguard the workplace involved; or</text>
								</paragraph>
                <paragraph id="HAF70B876C20A46949EAD78D9E9A13656">
                  <enum>(4)</enum>
                  <text>the workplace is
				disrupted or threatened by the action of a person whom that individual states
				has committed or threatened to commit domestic violence, dating violence,
				sexual assault, or stalking against that individual, or that individual’s
				family or household member.</text>
								</paragraph>
              </subsection>
              <subsection id="H12E91E8DB8AC4FB9B8D32DB6A2A52600">
                <enum>(b)</enum>
                <header>Definitions</header>
                <text>In
				this section:</text>
								<paragraph id="H5DD6B7B9A8AE497DB1EC0451879B6F28">
                  <enum>(1)</enum>
                  <header>Discriminate</header>
                  <text>The
				term <term>discriminate</term>, used with respect to the terms, conditions, or
				privileges of employment or with respect to the terms or conditions of public
				assistance, includes failing to implement, on request from an individual, in
				response to actual or threatened domestic violence, dating violence, sexual
				assault, or stalking, a reasonable safety procedure or a job-related
				modification to enhance the security of that individual or safeguard the
				workplace (such as installation of a lock, change of a telephone number or
				seating assignment, provision of a transfer, provision of leave, modification
				of a schedule, or adjustment of a work requirement), unless the employer or
				public agency can demonstrate that granting the request would impose an undue
				hardship on the operation of the employer or public agency.</text>
								</paragraph>
                <paragraph id="H2B9456F424154454AE009259EBC8276B">
                  <enum>(2)</enum>
                  <header>Undue
				hardship</header>
                  <text>The term <term>undue hardship</term> means an action
				requiring significant difficulty or expense.</text>
								</paragraph>
              </subsection>
            </section>
            <section id="H02EF3716F65E4D62B3B57FFD9DF0EF4C">
              <enum>41803.</enum>
              <header>Enforcement</header>
							<subsection id="HAAA298EFA4B84611A6EF4ED1DD6D0C40">
                <enum>(a)</enum>
                <header>Civil action by
				individuals</header>
								<paragraph id="H21A813F511E5415DB78DB2FFE6FF4B8E">
                  <enum>(1)</enum>
                  <header>Liability</header>
                  <text>Any
				employer that violates <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Violence Against Women Act/s:41802" proposed="true">section 41802</cato:entity-ref> shall be liable to any individual affected
				for—</text>
									<subparagraph id="HF314815E27F94368AE86873608D9ECE5">
                    <enum>(A)</enum>
                    <text>damages equal to
				the amount of wages, salary, employment benefits, or other compensation denied
				or lost to such individual by reason of the violation, and the interest on that
				amount calculated at the prevailing rate;</text>
									</subparagraph>
                  <subparagraph id="HA4D66D8DDC004287AAFEB673316C09CE">
                    <enum>(B)</enum>
                    <text>compensatory
				damages, including damages for future pecuniary losses, emotional pain,
				suffering, inconvenience, mental anguish, loss of enjoyment or life, and other
				nonpecuniary losses;</text>
									</subparagraph>
                  <subparagraph id="H9F6C83C0696A475D9E2697E5BA66AA22">
                    <enum>(C)</enum>
                    <text>such punitive
				damages, up to 3 times the amount of actual damages sustained, as the court
				described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Violence Against Women Act/s:41803/ss:a/p:2" proposed="true">paragraph (2)</cato:entity-ref> shall determine to be appropriate; and</text>
									</subparagraph>
                  <subparagraph id="HC48487ECD4B5494FBB1BACB5E42238E2">
                    <enum>(D)</enum>
                    <text>such equitable
				relief as may be appropriate, including employment, reinstatement, and
				promotion.</text>
									</subparagraph>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="HB4A1AFC49EB146CEA152C35D35435B1E">
                  <enum>(2)</enum>
                  <header>Right of
				action</header>
                  <text>An action to recover the damages or equitable relief
				prescribed in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Violence Against Women Act/s:41803/ss:a/p:1" proposed="true">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref> may be maintained against any employer in any
				Federal or State court of competent jurisdiction by any one or more individuals
				described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Violence Against Women Act/s:41802" proposed="true">section 41802</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
								</paragraph>
              </subsection>
              <subsection id="H8E4336760A8C4A4BBDB53131625B66A7">
                <enum>(b)</enum>
                <header>Action by
				department of justice</header>
                <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1500">Attorney General</cato:entity-ref> may bring a civil
				action in any Federal or State court of competent jurisdiction to recover the
				damages or equitable relief described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Violence Against Women Act/s:41803/ss:a/p:1" proposed="true">subsection (a)(1)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
							</subsection>
              <subsection commented="no" id="HE8CFE63959714470B1DF82F009EA3C13">
                <enum>(c)</enum>
                <header>Library of
				Congress</header>
                <text>Notwithstanding any other provision of this section, in
				the case of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0300">Library of Congress</cato:entity-ref>, the authority of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> under this
				section shall be exercised by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0300">Librarian of Congress</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
							</subsection>
              <subsection commented="no" id="H7C30B656BE46401DA596BDA6C8BFF264">
                <enum>(d)</enum>
                <header>Certain public
				agency employers</header>
								<paragraph commented="no" id="H8300817F6AB940588B9EE947A87D0F52">
                  <enum>(1)</enum>
                  <header>Agencies</header>
                  <text>Notwithstanding
				any other provision of this subsection, in the case of a public agency that
				employs individuals as described in <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
                      <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938/s:3/ss:e/p:2/sp:A">subparagraph (A)</cato:entity-ref> or <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938/s:3/ss:e/p:2/sp:B">(B) of section 3(e)(2)
				of the <act-name>Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938</act-name>
                      </cato:entity-ref> (<cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/29/203/e/2">29 U.S.C.
				203(e)(2)</cato:entity-ref>)</cato:entity> (other than an entity of the legislative branch of the Federal
				Government), <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Violence Against Women Act/s:41803/ss:d/p:2" proposed="true">paragraph (2)</cato:entity-ref> shall apply.</text>
								</paragraph>
                <paragraph commented="no" id="H1CF4076918FC4B23BC21BBED9AA744E2">
                  <enum>(2)</enum>
                  <header>Authority</header>
                  <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case described in subparagraph (A),
				the powers, remedies, and procedures provided (in the case of a violation of
				<cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc/5/2302/b/1/A">
                      <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/5/2302">section 2302(b)(1)(A)</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code</cato:entity-ref>) in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc/5">title 5, United States
				Code</cato:entity-ref>, to an employing agency, the Office of Special Counsel, the Merit Systems
				Protection Board, or any person alleging a violation of such <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc/5/2302/b/1/A">section
				2302(b)(1)(A)</cato:entity-ref>, shall be the powers, remedies, and procedures this section
				provides in the case of a violation of <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Violence Against Women Act/s:41802">section 41802</cato:entity-ref> to that agency, that
				Office, that Board, or any person alleging a violation of <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Violence Against Women Act/s:41802">section 41802</cato:entity-ref>,
				respectively, against an employee who is such an individual.</text>
								</paragraph>
              </subsection>
              <subsection commented="no" id="HB6C2C50EFAFD4D10A3CC996B1828BF3C">
                <enum>(e)</enum>
                <header>Public agencies
				providing public assistance</header>
                <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Consistent with regulations prescribed
				under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Violence Against Women Act/s:41805/ss:d">section 41805(d)</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> shall ensure that any public agency that
				violates <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Violence Against Women Act/s:41802/ss:a">section 41802(a)</cato:entity-ref> by taking an action prohibited under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Violence Against Women Act/s:41802/ss:a">section 41802(a)</cato:entity-ref>
				against any individual with respect to the amount, terms, or conditions of
				public assistance, shall provide to any individual who receives a less
				favorable amount, term, or condition of public assistance as a result of the
				violation—</text>
								<paragraph commented="no" id="H46499BE3074D47CDA274AE81257B29EC">
                  <enum>(1)</enum>
                  <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HDFAAB910A5DF407C8CD05689D905B1AE">
                    <enum>(A)</enum>
                    <text>the amount of any public
				assistance denied or lost to such individual by reason of the violation;
				and</text>
									</subparagraph>
                  <subparagraph commented="no" id="H8218FA1D7F144F01B587058082E7AB75" indent="up1">
                    <enum>(B)</enum>
                    <text>the interest on the amount described
				in clause (i) calculated at the prevailing rate; and</text>
									</subparagraph>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA40DAFDB3B56446ABE0D2B2BB2DED140">
                  <enum>(2)</enum>
                  <text>such equitable
				relief as may be appropriate.</text>
								</paragraph>
              </subsection>
            </section>
            <section commented="no" id="HFE74ED408809405E8F89CAB8F7743BBC">
              <enum>41804.</enum>
              <header>Regulations</header>
							<subsection commented="no" id="H4B6372C6FE30413AAA77B4B3B14CE706">
                <enum>(a)</enum>
                <header>In
				general</header>
                <text>Except as provided in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Violence Against Women Act/s:41804/ss:b" proposed="true">subsections (b)</cato:entity-ref>, <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Violence Against Women Act/s:41804/ss:c" proposed="true">(c)</cato:entity-ref>, and <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Violence Against Women Act/s:41804/ss:d" proposed="true">(d)</cato:entity-ref>, the
				<cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall issue regulations to carry out this title.</text>
							</subsection>
              <subsection commented="no" id="H5B6A224A49104158954C9E33DF88DB81">
                <enum>(b)</enum>
                <header>Library of
				Congress</header>
                <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0300">Librarian of Congress</cato:entity-ref> shall prescribe the
				regulations described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Violence Against Women Act/s:41804/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref> with respect to employees of the
				<cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0300">Library of Congress</cato:entity-ref>. The regulations prescribed under this subsection shall, to
				the extent appropriate, be consistent with the regulations prescribed by the
				<cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Violence Against Women Act/s:41804/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
							</subsection>
              <subsection commented="no" id="H7993EEDC054D46A5886D7BC5155B9DEC">
                <enum>(c)</enum>
                <header>Certain public
				agency employers</header>
                <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2400">Office of Personnel Management</cato:entity-ref>, after
				consultation under the Office of Special Counsel and the Merit Systems
				Protection Board, shall prescribe the regulations described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Violence Against Women Act/s:41804/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref>
				with respect to individuals described in <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
                    <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938/s:3/ss:e/p:2/p:A">subparagraph (A)</cato:entity-ref> or <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938/s:3/ss:e/p:2/p:B">(B) of section
				3(e)(2) of the <act-name>Fair Labor Standards Act</act-name> of 1938</cato:entity-ref> (<cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/29/203/e/2">29 U.S.C.
				203(e)(2)</cato:entity-ref>)</cato:entity> (other than an individual employed by an entity of the legislative
				branch of the Federal Government). The regulations prescribed under this
				subsection shall, to the extent appropriate, be consistent with the regulations
				prescribed by the Secretary under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Violence Against Women Act/s:41804/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
							</subsection>
              <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE297CC383BF44BA6807BF6FA15FC6442">
                <enum>(d)</enum>
                <header>Public agencies
				providing public assistance</header>
                <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> shall prescribe the
				regulations described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Violence Against Women Act/s:41804/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref> with respect to public agencies
				providing public assistance as described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Violence Against Women Act/s:41803/ss:e" proposed="true">section 41803(e)</cato:entity-ref>, including
				violations of <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Violence Against Women Act/s:41802/ss:a" proposed="true">section 41802(a)</cato:entity-ref> by such agencies. The regulations prescribed
				under this subsection shall, to the extent appropriate, be consistent with the
				regulations prescribed by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Violence Against Women Act/s:41804/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection
				(a)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
							</subsection>
            </section>
          </subtitle>
          <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
        </quoted-block>
			</section>
      <section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H89EA0A67220140B2AC555E35A9A11BB9" section-type="subsequent-section">
        <enum>302.</enum>
        <header>Attorney’s
			 fees</header>
        <text display-inline="no-display-inline">
          <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Revised Statutes/s:722/ss:b">Section 722(b) of the
			 Revised Statutes</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1988">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/42/1988/b">42 U.S.C. 1988(b)</cato:entity-ref>
            </external-xref>)</cato:entity> is amended by inserting <quote>the
			 <act-name>Victims’ Employment Sustainability Act</act-name>,</quote> after
			 <quote>
            <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Civil Rights Act of 1964/t:VI">title VI of the <act-name parsable-cite="CRA64">Civil Rights Act of
			 1964</act-name>
            </cato:entity-ref>,</quote>.</text>
			</section>
    </title>
    <title id="H0D8BCBE4274F4334B026B53E7FAC4691">
      <enum>IV</enum>
      <header>Entitlement to
			 unemployment compensation for victims of domestic violence, dating violence,
			 sexual assault, or stalking</header>
			<section id="H4AFD6FEC7B7F4483807FDBB91A690B8F">
        <enum>401.</enum>
        <header>Unemployment
			 compensation and training provisions</header>
				<subsection id="HB056E4D8F8DB47DAB85AEBA6D79B24C2">
          <enum>(a)</enum>
          <header>Unemployment
			 compensation</header>
          <text>
            <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:3304">
              <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/3304">Section 3304</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986</cato:entity-ref>
			 (relating to approval of State unemployment compensation laws) is
			 amended—</text>
					<paragraph id="HDCA9025A2D404C0DAC9EFDF476D91C4B">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <text>in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:3304/ss:a">subsection
			 (a)</cato:entity-ref>—</text>
						<subparagraph id="HD8FDB057E6A1466A9D91AD408AB1353A">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:3304/ss:a/p:18">paragraph (18)</cato:entity-ref>,
			 by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text>
						</subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="HE0451C7A304749D4A15206A171020D25">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>by redesignating
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:3304/ss:a/p:19">paragraph (19)</cato:entity-ref> as <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:3304/ss:a/p:20" proposed="true">paragraph (20)</cato:entity-ref>; and</text>
						</subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H44485BAEA7254AF28131020DE5BD50E1">
              <enum>(C)</enum>
              <text>by inserting after
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:3304/ss:a/p:18">paragraph (18)</cato:entity-ref> the following new paragraph:</text>
							<quoted-block id="HCD4D1910568242869CEAC81A709F84C1">
								<paragraph id="H03335876B70C4072B6A109B20FFE8101">
                  <enum>(19)</enum>
                  <text>compensation
				shall not be denied where an individual is separated from employment due to
				circumstances resulting from the individual’s experience of domestic violence,
				dating violence, sexual assault, or stalking, nor shall States impose
				additional conditions that restrict the individual’s eligibility for or receipt
				of benefits beyond those required of other individuals who are forced to leave
				their jobs or are deemed to have good cause for voluntarily separating from a
				job in the State; and</text>
								</paragraph>
                <after-quoted-block>;
				and</after-quoted-block>
              </quoted-block>
						</subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H256D8CF31DC24108BC07A31C6CD90734">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <text>by adding at the
			 end the following new subsection:</text>
						<quoted-block id="HAE2982DF0CE4471FAD7DD0CAA1A2184C">
							<subsection id="H56D602C707EC47F0BF2B506F9835E031">
                <enum>(g)</enum>
                <header>Construction</header>
                <text>For
				purposes of <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:3304/ss:a/p:19">subsection (a)(19)</cato:entity-ref>—</text>
								<paragraph id="HC4FF703464CF4A8EB9D0629D3D858BB2">
                  <enum>(1)</enum>
                  <header>Documentation</header>
                  <text>In
				determining eligibility for compensation due to circumstances resulting from an
				individual’s experience of domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault,
				or stalking—</text>
									<subparagraph id="H3C0E09B2518B44ECB272157A94910840">
                    <enum>(A)</enum>
                    <text>States shall
				adopt, or have adopted, by statute, regulation, or policy a list of forms of
				documentation that may be presented to demonstrate eligibility; and</text>
									</subparagraph>
                  <subparagraph id="H2146B73351C9472C83DB1B64FCB41AE3">
                    <enum>(B)</enum>
                    <text>presentation of
				any one of such forms of documentation shall be sufficient to demonstrate
				eligibility, except that a State may require the presentation of a form of
				identification in addition to the written statement of claimant described in
				<cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:3304/ss:g/p:2/sp:G" proposed="true">paragraph (2)(G)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
									</subparagraph>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="H5A233EB2763B4499A10E3052C00333BF">
                  <enum>(2)</enum>
                  <header>List of forms of
				documentation</header>
                  <text>The list referred to in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:3304/ss:g/p:1/sp:A" proposed="true">paragraph (1)(A)</cato:entity-ref> shall
				include not less than three of the following forms of documentation:</text>
									<subparagraph id="H6945EACE33154B60B763224E863510A0">
                    <enum>(A)</enum>
                    <text>An order of
				protection or other documentation issued by a court.</text>
									</subparagraph>
                  <subparagraph id="H7D5C598FDC74425F9B147B9591F6EB8E">
                    <enum>(B)</enum>
                    <text>A police report or
				criminal charges documenting the domestic violence, dating violence, sexual
				assault, or stalking.</text>
									</subparagraph>
                  <subparagraph id="HF2BC542957794D88B1E2CDCD88E6D558">
                    <enum>(C)</enum>
                    <text>Documentation that
				the perpetrator has been convicted of the offense of domestic violence, dating
				violence, sexual assault, or stalking.</text>
									</subparagraph>
                  <subparagraph id="H58CB9E046E7B43F291C6CA62A7EF50DD">
                    <enum>(D)</enum>
                    <text>Medical
				documentation of the domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, or
				stalking.</text>
									</subparagraph>
                  <subparagraph id="H07C042FFCB0447068788B84B1D43CF01">
                    <enum>(E)</enum>
                    <text>Evidence of
				domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, or stalking from a
				counselor, social worker, health worker, or domestic violence shelter
				worker.</text>
									</subparagraph>
                  <subparagraph id="H5EF65C94877A4A71A589BA211DE48DBD">
                    <enum>(F)</enum>
                    <text>A written
				statement that the applicant or the applicant’s minor child is a victim of
				domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, or stalking, provided by a
				social worker, member of the clergy, shelter worker, attorney at law, or other
				professional who has assisted the applicant in dealing with the domestic
				violence, dating violence, sexual assault, or stalking.</text>
									</subparagraph>
                  <subparagraph id="H72C78316EA6E48CF9FE7B4C5C0BDC938">
                    <enum>(G)</enum>
                    <text>A written
				statement of the claimant.</text>
									</subparagraph>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="H382B2504F45A419DB62C3CD63D14F00C">
                  <enum>(3)</enum>
                  <header>Domestic
				violence, dating violence, sexual assault, and stalking defined</header>
                  <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The terms <term>domestic violence</term>,
				<term>dating violence</term>, <term>sexual assault</term>, and
				<term>stalking</term> have the meanings given such terms in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Violence Against Women Act/s:40002">section 40002 of
				the <act-name>Violence Against Women
				Act</act-name>
                    </cato:entity-ref>.</text>
								</paragraph>
              </subsection>
              <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
            </quoted-block>
					</paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="H3E42D31F1BD5450CA9A4DA324F33FE9A">
          <enum>(b)</enum>
          <header>Unemployment
			 compensation personnel training</header>
          <text>
            <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Social Security Act/s:303/ss:a">Section 303(a) of the
			 <act-name parsable-cite="SSA">Social Security Act</act-name>
              </cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/503">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/42/503/a">42 U.S.C. 503(a)</cato:entity-ref>
              </external-xref>)</cato:entity>
			 is amended—</text>
					<paragraph id="HBA8B6D9A26594A7499AAF0FA18149408">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <text>by redesignating
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Social Security Act/s:303/ss:a/p:4..12">paragraphs (4) through (12)</cato:entity-ref> as <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Social Security Act/s:303/ss:a/p:5..13" proposed="true">paragraphs (5) through (13)</cato:entity-ref>, respectively;
			 and</text>
					</paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H2240191FF18F4923B8F739C6F8F0A7E7">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <text>by inserting after
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Social Security Act/s:303/ss:a/p:3">paragraph (3)</cato:entity-ref> the following new paragraph:</text>
						<quoted-block id="HD011A565677F4DFC95FDECC3589D1A9B">
							<paragraph id="H8099D8FE376748258A9B447ED38A9F8D">
                <enum>(4)</enum>
                <text>Such methods of
				administration as will ensure that—</text>
								<subparagraph id="H2CCE562D9A784C95B7E96C088EB2B614">
                  <enum>(A)</enum>
                  <text>applicants for
				unemployment compensation and individuals inquiring about such compensation are
				adequately notified of the provisions of <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:3304/ss:a/p:19">subsections (a)(19)</cato:entity-ref> and <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:3304/ss:g">(g) of section
				3304 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986</cato:entity-ref> (relating to the availability of
				unemployment compensation for victims of domestic violence, dating violence,
				sexual assault, or stalking); and</text>
								</subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="HBDCC563BC0084FB896FE7B23FE0FE7F9">
                  <enum>(B)</enum>
                  <text>claims reviewers
				and hearing personnel are adequately trained in—</text>
									<clause id="H0B5D78EBF0564F69B6F3C3CCA2B39F70">
                    <enum>(i)</enum>
                    <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the nature and dynamics of domestic
				violence, dating violence, sexual assault, or stalking (as such terms are
				defined in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Violence Against Women Act/s:40002">section 40002 of the <act-name>Violence Against Women
				Act</act-name>
                      </cato:entity-ref>); and</text>
									</clause>
                  <clause id="HF5A441AB850E44D682C6660AFC2C6B32">
                    <enum>(ii)</enum>
                    <text>methods of
				ascertaining and keeping confidential information about possible experiences of
				domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, or stalking (as so defined)
				to ensure that—</text>
										<subclause id="H7EF6919E18F44E6A9817FD76C7D4480E">
                      <enum>(I)</enum>
                      <text>requests for
				unemployment compensation based on separations stemming from domestic violence,
				dating violence, sexual assault, or stalking (as so defined) are reliably
				screened, identified, and adjudicated; and</text>
										</subclause>
                    <subclause id="H3DB435DAFB774848A491D0DD29553340">
                      <enum>(II)</enum>
                      <text>full
				confidentiality is provided for the individual’s claim and submitted evidence;
				and</text>
										</subclause>
                  </clause>
                </subparagraph>
              </paragraph>
              <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
            </quoted-block>
					</paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="H8CF94A19EF49470E9EC243F26122FE2B">
          <enum>(c)</enum>
          <header>TANF personnel
			 training</header>
          <text>
            <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Social Security Act/s:402/ss:a">Section 402(a) of the <act-name parsable-cite="SSA">Social Security Act</act-name>
              </cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/602">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/42/602/a">42 U.S.C. 602(a)</cato:entity-ref>
              </external-xref>)</cato:entity> is
			 amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text>
					<quoted-block act-name="Social Security Act" id="HE41A0065A04940DA9799C8466E3392C5">
						<paragraph id="H6627789C6FD94A21995B1F6B3330622A">
              <enum>(8)</enum>
              <header>Certification
				that the State will provide information to victims of domestic violence, dating
				violence, sexual assault, or stalking</header>
              <text>A certification by the
				chief officer of the State that the State has established and is enforcing
				standards and procedures to—</text>
							<subparagraph id="H58A0178D9E604B088865C2BD76FADAE3">
                <enum>(A)</enum>
                <text>ensure that
				applicants for assistance under the program and individuals inquiring about
				such assistance are adequately notified of—</text>
								<clause id="HA9BB1C5B5AFE4BDB95D5A827AF656675">
                  <enum>(i)</enum>
                  <text>the provisions of
				<cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:3304/ss:a/p:19">subsections (a)(19)</cato:entity-ref> and <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:3304/ss:g">(g) of section 3304 of the Internal Revenue Code of
				1986</cato:entity-ref> (relating to the availability of unemployment compensation for victims of
				domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, or stalking); and</text>
								</clause>
                <clause id="H4AD7DDE1EF9D484F9F4AE7D3BC8F620B">
                  <enum>(ii)</enum>
                  <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">assistance made available by the State to
				victims of domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, or stalking (as
				such terms are defined in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Violence Against Women Act/s:40002">section 40002 of the <act-name>Violence Against Women
				Act</act-name>
                    </cato:entity-ref>);</text>
								</clause>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="H28BFE9356A1B448C881EDD8F1F5E1B95">
                <enum>(B)</enum>
                <text>ensure that case
				workers and other agency personnel responsible for administering the State
				program funded under this part are adequately trained in—</text>
								<clause id="HC4899FABA6714843A428D348D2A95183">
                  <enum>(i)</enum>
                  <text>the nature and
				dynamics of domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, or stalking (as
				so defined);</text>
								</clause>
                <clause id="H7F4A4F5A8C244EAB97F571627C20C275">
                  <enum>(ii)</enum>
                  <text>State standards
				and procedures relating to the prevention of, and assistance for individuals
				who experience, domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, or stalking
				(as so defined); and</text>
								</clause>
                <clause id="HE2B3A58CBDA74B86838A425036F2DDD5">
                  <enum>(iii)</enum>
                  <text>methods of
				ascertaining and keeping confidential information about possible experiences of
				domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, or stalking (as so
				defined);</text>
								</clause>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="HDA43C4B15FB247269F9D3415E0F43B29">
                <enum>(C)</enum>
                <text>if a State has
				elected to establish and enforce standards and procedures regarding the
				screening for and identification of domestic violence pursuant to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Social Security Act/s:402/ss:a/p:7">paragraph
				(7)</cato:entity-ref>, ensure that—</text>
								<clause id="HC50BD6F2178A4297B21678D58509B05B">
                  <enum>(i)</enum>
                  <text>applicants for
				assistance under the program and individuals inquiring about such assistance
				are adequately notified of options available under such standards and
				procedures; and</text>
								</clause>
                <clause id="H5878724FE8D34261AD0996EAD740326F">
                  <enum>(ii)</enum>
                  <text>case workers and
				other agency personnel responsible for administering the State program funded
				under this part are provided with adequate training regarding such standards
				and procedures and options available under such standards and procedures;
				and</text>
								</clause>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="H759FCA11135C4B2DADC20A4C2E2A9FE5">
                <enum>(D)</enum>
                <text>ensure that the
				training required under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Social Security Act/s:402/ss:a/p:8/sp:B" proposed="true">subparagraphs (B)</cato:entity-ref> and, if applicable, <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Social Security Act/s:402/ss:a/p:8/sp:C/cl:ii" proposed="true">(C)(ii)</cato:entity-ref> is
				provided through a training program operated by an eligible entity (as defined
				in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Security and Financial Empowerment Act/s:401/ss:d/p:2">section 401(d)(2) of the <act-name>Security and Financial Empowerment
				Act</act-name>
                  </cato:entity-ref>).</text>
							</subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
          </quoted-block>
				</subsection>
        <subsection id="H043719A9B6F0497984641F22526500D2">
          <enum>(d)</enum>
          <header>Domestic
			 violence, dating violence, sexual assault, or stalking training grant
			 program</header>
					<paragraph id="H46DECCE8E0C941DB8702E7800AD948CD">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <header>Grants
			 authorized</header>
            <text>The Secretary of Health and Human Services (in this
			 subsection referred to as the <term>Secretary</term>) is authorized to
			 award—</text>
						<subparagraph id="H96229185C87E4CFB94B230677C34452F">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>a grant to a
			 national victim services organization in order for such organization to—</text>
							<clause id="HB3A1E2F8E03A4B98AA40B954A97A0E47">
                <enum>(i)</enum>
                <text>develop and
			 disseminate a model training program (and related materials) for the training
			 required under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Social Security Act/s:303/ss:a/p:4/sp:B">section 303(a)(4)(B) of the <act-name parsable-cite="SSA">Social
			 Security Act</act-name>
                  </cato:entity-ref>, as added by <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Security and Financial Empowerment Act/s:401/ss:b" proposed="true">subsection (b)</cato:entity-ref>, and under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Social Security Act/s:402/ss:a/p:8/sp:B">subparagraphs
			 (B)</cato:entity-ref> and, if applicable, <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Social Security Act/s:402/ss:a/p:8/sp:C/cl:ii">(C)(ii) of section 402(a)(8) of such Act</cato:entity-ref>, as added by
			 subsection (c); and</text>
							</clause>
              <clause id="HDC69C57785AF4E228C968B613753F5BD">
                <enum>(ii)</enum>
                <text>provide technical
			 assistance with respect to such model training program; and</text>
							</clause>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="HE9D88970833945C7B475C35AA8AE725B">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>grants to State,
			 tribal, or local agencies in order for such agencies to contract with eligible
			 entities to provide State, tribal, or local case workers and other State,
			 tribal, or local agency personnel responsible for administering the temporary
			 assistance to needy families program established under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Social Security Act/t:IV/pt:A">part A of title IV of
			 the <act-name parsable-cite="SSA">Social Security Act</act-name>
                </cato:entity-ref> in a State or
			 Indian reservation with the training required under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Social Security Act/s:402/ss:a/p:8/sp:B">subparagraphs (B)</cato:entity-ref> and, if
			 applicable, <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Social Security Act/s:402/ss:a/p:8/sp:C/cl:ii">(C)(ii) of such section 402(a)(8)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
						</subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H9A71BA920BE44A5D9EEB53EBA982E97E">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <header>Eligible entity
			 defined</header>
            <text>For purposes of <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Security and Financial Empowerment Act/s:401/ss:d/p:1/sp:B" proposed="true">paragraph (1)(B)</cato:entity-ref>, the term <term>eligible
			 entity</term> means an entity—</text>
						<subparagraph id="HEE946FBE897A466D982A9F2FEDE525D6">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>that is—</text>
							<clause id="HB6F08B3088E34242A731675995CDE680">
                <enum>(i)</enum>
                <text>a
			 State or tribal domestic violence coalition or sexual assault coalition;</text>
							</clause>
              <clause id="HB280BFBD185D49D0A142A65A947835EA">
                <enum>(ii)</enum>
                <text>a
			 State or local victim services organization with recognized expertise in the
			 dynamics of domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, or stalking
			 whose primary mission is to provide services to victims of domestic violence,
			 dating violence, sexual assault, or stalking, such as a rape crisis center or
			 domestic violence program; or</text>
							</clause>
              <clause id="HDE639BE593F2400B817A78471B9122B1">
                <enum>(iii)</enum>
                <text>an
			 organization with demonstrated expertise in State or county welfare laws and
			 implementation of such laws and experience with disseminating information on
			 such laws and implementation, but only if such organization will provide the
			 required training in partnership with an entity described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Security and Financial Empowerment Act/s:401/ss:d/p:2/sp:A/cl:i" proposed="true">clause (i)</cato:entity-ref> or
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Security and Financial Empowerment Act/s:401/ss:d/p:2/sp:A/cl:ii" proposed="true">(ii)</cato:entity-ref>; and</text>
							</clause>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="HE64CFB9DEFEA4A74A71A026438914191">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>that—</text>
							<clause id="H40670B6954754D62AB8847D20A772BFE">
                <enum>(i)</enum>
                <text>has
			 demonstrated expertise in the dynamics of both domestic violence and sexual
			 assault, such as a joint domestic violence and sexual assault coalition;
			 or</text>
							</clause>
              <clause id="H7118A539367149F194BAE242923DF16F">
                <enum>(ii)</enum>
                <text>will provide the
			 required training in partnership with an entity described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Security and Financial Empowerment Act/s:401/ss:d/p:2/sp:A/cl:i" proposed="true">clause (i)</cato:entity-ref> or <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Security and Financial Empowerment Act/s:401/ss:d/p:2/sp:A/cl:ii" proposed="true">(ii)
			 of subparagraph (A)</cato:entity-ref> in order to comply with the dual domestic violence and
			 sexual assault expertise requirement under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Security and Financial Empowerment Act/s:401/ss:d/p:2/sp:B/cl:i" proposed="true">clause (i)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
							</clause>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H1DAAD55C0833422E9F005B974B68163C">
            <enum>(3)</enum>
            <header>Application</header>
            <text>An
			 entity seeking a grant under this subsection shall submit an application to the
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> at such time, in such form and manner, and containing such
			 information as the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> specifies.</text>
					</paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H46B8D170E9B74B06ABD62E4243E0D8BC">
            <enum>(4)</enum>
            <header>Reports</header>
						<subparagraph id="HD75007A465824C00942619153A296181">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <header>Reports to
			 Congress</header>
              <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall annually submit a report to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref>
			 on the grant program established under this subsection.</text>
						</subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H18AEDB415CB44592BE8F5732D7166E7C">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <header>Reports
			 available to public</header>
              <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall establish procedures for
			 the dissemination to the public of each report submitted under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Security and Financial Empowerment Act/s:401/ss:d/p:4/sp:A" proposed="true">subparagraph
			 (A)</cato:entity-ref>. Such procedures shall include the use of the Internet to disseminate such
			 reports.</text>
						</subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="HF1EFD955A9F4474695836874844FC917">
            <enum>(5)</enum>
            <header>Authorization of
			 appropriations</header>
						<subparagraph id="H19FB3AC2654242AA8FBD7D30F726F028">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <header>Authorization</header>
              <text>There
			 are authorized to be appropriated—</text>
							<clause id="H038D41C79BF046FE9A901D2ACE432773">
                <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="auth-auth-approp">
                  <enum>(i)</enum>
                <text>
                    <cato:funds-and-year amount="1000000" year="2014">$1,000,000 for
			 fiscal year 2014</cato:funds-and-year> <cato:property name="purpose">to carry out the provisions of <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Security and Financial Empowerment Act/s:401/ss:d/p:1/sp:A" proposed="true">paragraph (1)(A)</cato:entity-ref>
                    </cato:property>; and</text>
                </cato:entity>
							</clause>
              <clause id="HCF03B4724EF946838559089F40E3DD1A">
                <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="auth-auth-approp">
                  <enum>(ii)</enum>
                <text>
                    <cato:funds-and-year amount="12000000" year="2015, 2016, 2017, 2018">$12,000,000 for
			 each of fiscal years 2015 through 2018</cato:funds-and-year> <cato:property name="purpose">to carry out the provisions of <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Security and Financial Empowerment Act/s:401/ss:d/p:1/sp:B" proposed="true">paragraph
			 (1)(B)</cato:entity-ref>
                    </cato:property>.</text>
                </cato:entity>
							</clause>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H73701D8A66344C49BE6FF5E204CEB0AD">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <header>Three-year
			 availability of grant funds</header>
              <text>Each recipient of a grant under this
			 subsection shall return to the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> any unused portion of such grant not
			 later than 3 years after the date the grant was awarded, together with any
			 earnings on such unused portion.</text>
						</subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H1FD50FC3767F4E609CA7CA5613A6B708">
              <enum>(C)</enum>
              <header>Amounts
			 returned</header>
              <text>Any amounts returned pursuant to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Security and Financial Empowerment Act/s:401/ss:d/p:5/sp:B" proposed="true">subparagraph (B)</cato:entity-ref> shall
			 be available without further appropriation to the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> for the purpose of
			 carrying out the provisions of <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Security and Financial Empowerment Act/s:401/ss:d/p:1/sp:B" proposed="true">paragraph (1)(B)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
						</subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="HE26E44423D28409A803785DEF2BB1986">
          <enum>(e)</enum>
          <header>Effect on
			 existing laws, etc</header>
					<paragraph id="HF4043C9EDEF04BF5A7DE75B18C885D62">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <header>More protective
			 laws, agreements, programs, and plans</header>
            <text>Nothing in this title shall
			 be construed to supersede any provision of any Federal, State, or local law,
			 collective bargaining agreement, or employment benefits program or plan that
			 provides greater unemployment insurance benefits for victims of domestic
			 violence, dating violence, sexual assault, or stalking than the rights
			 established under this title.</text>
					</paragraph>
          <paragraph id="HF086E5137EE34F2F9F1F58BFDDA0E1C5">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <header>Less protective
			 laws, agreements, programs, and plans</header>
            <text>The rights established for
			 victims of domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, or stalking
			 under this title shall not be diminished by any more restrictive State or local
			 law, collective bargaining agreement, or employment benefits program or
			 plan.</text>
					</paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="H7FA6A406A00F4631803967E6D6584E40">
          <enum>(f)</enum>
          <header>Effective
			 date</header>
					<paragraph id="HD16EC7545FA34646BB41FD5C7F59A403">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <header>Unemployment
			 amendments</header>
						<subparagraph id="H2AF862A48D26400F8B405C451A99141A">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <header>In
			 general</header>
              <text>Except as provided in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Security and Financial Empowerment Act/s:401/ss:f/p:1/sp:B" proposed="true">subparagraph (B)</cato:entity-ref> and <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Security and Financial Empowerment Act/s:401/ss:f/p:2" proposed="true">paragraph (2)</cato:entity-ref>,
			 the amendments made by this section shall apply in the case of compensation
			 paid for weeks beginning on or after the expiration of 180 days from the date
			 of enactment of this Act.</text>
						</subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="HD85C5F5718A34FE782720FCF7F4FE2E2">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <header>Extension of
			 effective date for State law amendment</header>
							<clause id="H9A459E9D9E2F4E34A4E46AEEC11BACF7">
                <enum>(i)</enum>
                <header>In
			 general</header>
                <text>If the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1600">Secretary of Labor</cato:entity-ref> identifies a State as requiring
			 a change to its statutes, regulations, or policies in order to comply with the
			 amendments made by this section (excluding the amendment made by <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Security and Financial Empowerment Act/s:401/ss:c" proposed="true">subsection
			 (c)</cato:entity-ref>), such amendments shall apply in the case of compensation paid for weeks
			 beginning after the earlier of—</text>
								<subclause id="HBBD4561A665A481D926939A317CD04B4">
                  <enum>(I)</enum>
                  <text>the date the State
			 changes its statutes, regulations, or policies in order to comply with such
			 amendments; or</text>
								</subclause>
                <subclause id="H42D80BCED6B743F39F2CF066837C18DC">
                  <enum>(II)</enum>
                  <text>the end of the
			 first session of the State legislature which begins after the date of enactment
			 of this Act or which began prior to such date and remained in session for at
			 least 25 calendar days after such date;</text>
								</subclause>
                <continuation-text continuation-text-level="clause">except that in
			 no case shall such amendments apply before the date that is 180 days after the
			 date of enactment of this Act.</continuation-text>
              </clause>
              <clause id="H2DB0934902044C4D917BB3301AE30E11">
                <enum>(ii)</enum>
                <header>Session
			 defined</header>
                <text>In this subparagraph, the term <term>session</term> means
			 a regular, special, budget, or other session of a State legislature.</text>
							</clause>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H17B6CBA933D1467C925C46F37E6A9E5C">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <header>TANF
			 amendment</header>
						<subparagraph id="H59F6294D27284E00BD94723DF37329C2">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <header>In
			 general</header>
              <text>Except as provided in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Security and Financial Empowerment Act/s:401/ss:f/p:2/sp:B" proposed="true">subparagraph (B)</cato:entity-ref>, the amendment
			 made by <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Security and Financial Empowerment Act/s:401/ss:c" proposed="true">subsection (c)</cato:entity-ref> shall take effect on the date of enactment of this
			 Act.</text>
						</subparagraph>
            <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9319C799C4564AA99458ECC9FED3E8AA">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <header>Extension of
			 effective date for State law amendment</header>
              <text>In the case of a State
			 plan under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Social Security Act/t:IV/pt:A">part A of title IV of the <act-name parsable-cite="SSA">Social
			 Security Act</act-name>
                </cato:entity-ref> which the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary of Health and Human Services</cato:entity-ref>
			 determines requires State action (including legislation, regulation, or other
			 administrative action) in order for the plan to meet the additional
			 requirements imposed by the amendment made by <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Security and Financial Empowerment Act/s:401/ss:c" proposed="true">subsection (c)</cato:entity-ref>, the State plan
			 shall not be regarded as failing to comply with the requirements of such
			 amendment on the basis of its failure to meet these additional requirements
			 before the first day of the first calendar quarter beginning after the close of
			 the first regular session of the State legislature that begins after the date
			 of enactment of this Act. For purposes of the previous sentence, in the case of
			 a State that has a 2-year legislative session, each year of the session is
			 considered to be a separate regular session of the State legislature.</text>
						</subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </title>
    <title id="HED52426655DC483986A403A0B90428A0">
      <enum>V</enum>
      <header>Victims of abuse
			 insurance protection</header>
			<section id="H8AC26D74374540C6855660C3C71E17EB">
        <enum>501.</enum>
        <header>Short
			 title</header>
        <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This title may be cited
			 as the <quote>
            <short-title>Victims of Abuse Insurance
			 Protection Act</short-title>
          </quote>.</text>
			</section>
      <section id="HF37C22DBAB7B444DA5B6BE093081604B">
        <enum>502.</enum>
        <header>Definitions</header>
        <text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this title, the following definitions
			 apply:</text>
				<paragraph id="HEF5D7BA6672A453FA0AD39AF7503A2CA">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>Abuse</header>
          <text>The
			 term <term>abuse</term> means the occurrence of one or more of the following
			 acts by a current or former household or family member, intimate partner, or
			 caretaker:</text>
					<subparagraph id="H280B6C396D58476391D8A855E9DEDE8B">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>Attempting to
			 cause or causing another person bodily injury, physical harm, substantial
			 emotional distress, or psychological trauma.</text>
					</subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="HE3066D8A37F84A988079D96A4093170F">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>Attempting to
			 engage in or engaging in rape, sexual assault, or involuntary sexual
			 intercourse.</text>
					</subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H4C2D745F0E814F2E8FCAE82AD6B698CE">
            <enum>(C)</enum>
            <text>Engaging in a
			 course of conduct or repeatedly committing acts toward another person,
			 including following the person without proper authority and under circumstances
			 that place the person in reasonable fear of bodily injury or physical
			 harm.</text>
					</subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="HC0699BA9B8B64C969181732381EB4D98">
            <enum>(D)</enum>
            <text>Subjecting another
			 person to false imprisonment or kidnaping.</text>
					</subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H1018A014AE774D75914D21E7950817DD">
            <enum>(E)</enum>
            <text>Attempting to
			 cause or causing damage to property so as to intimidate or attempt to control
			 the behavior of another person.</text>
					</subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H9D4F261522DA4AD28AB6D688083A92FF">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Health
			 carrier</header>
          <text>The term <term>health carrier</term> means a person that
			 contracts or offers to contract on a risk-assuming basis to provide, deliver,
			 arrange for, pay for, or reimburse any of the cost of health care services,
			 including a sickness and accident insurance company, a health maintenance
			 organization, a nonprofit hospital and health service corporation, or any other
			 entity providing a plan of health insurance, health benefits, or health
			 services.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HAD0727D8B84B4CFE8D57E2DAA24FC9B2">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <header>Insured</header>
          <text>The
			 term <term>insured</term> means a party named on a policy, certificate, or
			 health benefit plan, including an individual, corporation, partnership,
			 association, unincorporated organization, or any similar entity, as the person
			 with legal rights to the benefits provided by the policy, certificate, or
			 health benefit plan. For group insurance, the term includes a person who is a
			 beneficiary covered by a group policy, certificate, or health benefit plan. For
			 life insurance, the term refers to the person whose life is covered under an
			 insurance policy.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H2F6B574A7AF64DEB875A52AC33D6FEB8">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
          <header>Insurer</header>
          <text>The
			 term <term>insurer</term> means any person, reciprocal exchange, inter insurer,
			 Lloyds insurer, fraternal benefit society, or other legal entity engaged in the
			 business of insurance, including agents, brokers, adjusters, and third-party
			 administrators. The term includes employers who provide or make available
			 employment benefits through an employee benefit plan, as defined in <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974/s:3/p:3">section
			 3(3) of the <act-name parsable-cite="ERISA">Employee Retirement Income Security
			 Act of 1974</act-name>
              </cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/102">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/29/102//3">29 U.S.C. 102(3)</cato:entity-ref>
              </external-xref>)</cato:entity>. The term also includes health
			 carriers, health benefit plans, and life, disability, and property and casualty
			 insurers.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HB2C8A2E819F249B292C8C9CDD1A0957D">
          <enum>(5)</enum>
          <header>Policy</header>
          <text>The
			 term <term>policy</term> means a contract of insurance, certificate, indemnity,
			 suretyship, or annuity issued, proposed for issuance, or intended for issuance
			 by an insurer, including endorsements or riders to an insurance policy or
			 contract.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H6E43F0526578427AA78398BE2E5BD31D">
          <enum>(6)</enum>
          <header>Subject of
			 abuse</header>
          <text>The term <term>subject of abuse</term> means—</text>
					<subparagraph id="HB7E36AE27F8B4543807D4796B94329AA">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>a person against
			 whom an act of abuse has been directed;</text>
					</subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="HE4FE7FA01E4E4F3C9F8710F22010FAC3">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>a person who has
			 prior or current injuries, illnesses, or disorders that resulted from abuse;
			 or</text>
					</subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H178FF7C2E6424937A54995E1C6004EA3">
            <enum>(C)</enum>
            <text>a person who
			 seeks, may have sought, or had reason to seek medical or psychological
			 treatment for abuse, protection, court-ordered protection, or shelter from
			 abuse.</text>
					</subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
      </section>
      <section id="H8081719C777C4318AAD4409714ECADD6">
        <enum>503.</enum>
        <header>Discriminatory
			 acts prohibited</header>
				<subsection id="H21E0499E7114415C8B29DF9879FC6741">
          <enum>(a)</enum>
          <header>In
			 general</header>
          <text>No insurer may, directly or indirectly, engage in any of
			 the following acts or practices on the basis that the applicant or insured, or
			 any person employed by the applicant or insured or with whom the applicant or
			 insured is known to have a relationship or association, is, has been, or may be
			 the subject of abuse or has incurred or may incur abuse-related claims:</text>
					<paragraph id="HD62ADC8C13CB49A49FE0073489607BE6">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <text>Denying, refusing
			 to issue, renew, or reissue, or canceling or otherwise terminating an insurance
			 policy or health benefit plan.</text>
					</paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H5AAC865F31EF42CFB6745D595766B54A">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <text>Restricting,
			 excluding, or limiting insurance coverage for losses or denying a claim, except
			 as otherwise permitted or required by State laws relating to life insurance
			 beneficiaries.</text>
					</paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H1BED2369AD724C8F81CD5A7BAF3C9D9E">
            <enum>(3)</enum>
            <text>Adding a premium
			 differential to any insurance policy or health benefit plan.</text>
					</paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="HD28A214AB1394466B35BFAB954B630FB">
          <enum>(b)</enum>
          <header>Prohibition on
			 limitation of claims</header>
          <text>No insurer may, directly or indirectly, deny
			 or limit payment to an insured who is a subject of abuse if the claim for
			 payment is a result of the abuse.</text>
				</subsection>
        <subsection id="HD18DDDD5FA7E45159AF1F8C0858CF4C3">
          <enum>(c)</enum>
          <header>Prohibition on
			 termination</header>
					<paragraph id="H24A2F70C5ECE4D488380AEABD2127FE7">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <header>In
			 general</header>
            <text>No insurer or health carrier may terminate health
			 coverage for a subject of abuse because coverage was originally issued in the
			 name of the abuser and the abuser has divorced, separated from, or lost custody
			 of the subject of abuse or the abuser’s coverage has terminated voluntarily or
			 involuntarily and the subject of abuse does not qualify for an extension of
			 coverage under <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974/t:I/st:B/pt:6">part 6 of subtitle B of title I of the
			 <act-name parsable-cite="ERISA">Employee Retirement Income Security Act of
			 1974</act-name>
                </cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/1161">
                  <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/29/1161/etseq">29 U.S.C. 1161 et seq.</cato:entity-ref>
                </external-xref>)</cato:entity> or <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:4980B">section 4980B of the Internal
			 Revenue Code of 1986</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
					</paragraph>
          <paragraph id="HFA965384F6004075854FD20ED0975C89">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <header>Payment of
			 premiums</header>
            <text>Nothing in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Security and Financial Empowerment Act/s:503/ss:c/p:1" proposed="true">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref> shall be construed to prohibit
			 the insurer from requiring that the subject of abuse pay the full premium for
			 the subject’s coverage under the health plan if the requirements are applied to
			 all insured of the health carrier.</text>
					</paragraph>
          <paragraph id="HC34E62B6FEA241E796F9E4B0B4148A15">
            <enum>(3)</enum>
            <header>Exception</header>
            <text>An
			 insurer may terminate group coverage to which this subsection applies after the
			 continuation coverage period required by this subsection has been in force for
			 18 months if it offers conversion to an equivalent individual plan.</text>
					</paragraph>
          <paragraph id="HF2AFB1D53C9B4B6EB1C07367EA8C2A37">
            <enum>(4)</enum>
            <header>Continuation
			 coverage</header>
            <text>The continuation of health coverage required by this
			 subsection shall be satisfied by any extension of coverage under <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974/t:I/st:B/pt:6">part 6 of
			 subtitle B of title I of the <act-name parsable-cite="ERISA">Employee
			 Retirement Income Security Act of 1974</act-name>
                </cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/1161">
                  <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/29/1161/etseq">29 U.S.C. 1161 et seq.</cato:entity-ref>
                </external-xref>)</cato:entity> or
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:4980B">
                <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/4980B">section 4980B</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986</cato:entity-ref> provided to a subject of
			 abuse and is not intended to be in addition to any extension of coverage
			 otherwise provided for under such <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974/t:I/st:B/pt:6">part 6</cato:entity-ref> or <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:4980B">section 4980B</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
					</paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="H9DC02FB5036B48C2A27499D14553A95F">
          <enum>(d)</enum>
          <header>Use of
			 information</header>
					<paragraph id="H14856766B94C4363A01FC5A6DD955F35">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <header>Limitation</header>
						<subparagraph id="H51B6E68F48B249079D2FF042028FB74D">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <header>In
			 general</header>
              <text>In order to protect the safety and privacy of subjects of
			 abuse, no person employed by or contracting with an insurer or health benefit
			 plan may (without the consent of the subject)—</text>
							<clause id="H3DE23A4BAD3349F2A8DCF8A3E26C3BA6">
                <enum>(i)</enum>
                <text>use,
			 disclose, or transfer information relating to abuse status, acts of abuse,
			 abuse-related medical conditions, or the applicant’s or insured’s status as a
			 family member, employer, associate, or person in a relationship with a subject
			 of abuse for any purpose unrelated to the direct provision of health care
			 services unless such use, disclosure, or transfer is required by an order of an
			 entity with authority to regulate insurance or an order of a court of competent
			 jurisdiction; or</text>
							</clause>
              <clause id="HDA28D295C6DB49438C93FBAD5466A809">
                <enum>(ii)</enum>
                <text>disclose or
			 transfer information relating to an applicant’s or insured’s mailing address or
			 telephone number or the mailing address and telephone number of a shelter for
			 subjects of abuse, unless such disclosure or transfer—</text>
								<subclause id="H71D4300B093F4AE9ADD8AB981BBF79F8">
                  <enum>(I)</enum>
                  <text>is required in
			 order to provide insurance coverage; and</text>
								</subclause>
                <subclause id="H0D4D30DBA7084D71AB70B624522147F6">
                  <enum>(II)</enum>
                  <text>does not have the
			 potential to endanger the safety of a subject of abuse.</text>
								</subclause>
              </clause>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H1CADE62F0178450C9B91FAB6D53AA595">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <header>Rule of
			 construction</header>
              <text>Nothing in this paragraph may be construed to limit
			 or preclude a subject of abuse from obtaining the subject’s own insurance
			 records from an insurer.</text>
						</subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="HD3C0C75566734580BD68BFFF841374D3">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <header>Authority of
			 subject of abuse</header>
            <text>A subject of abuse, at the absolute discretion
			 of the subject of abuse, may provide evidence of abuse to an insurer for the
			 limited purpose of facilitating treatment of an abuse-related condition or
			 demonstrating that a condition is abuse-related. Nothing in this paragraph
			 shall be construed as authorizing an insurer or health carrier to disregard
			 such provided evidence.</text>
					</paragraph>
        </subsection>
      </section>
      <section id="H744E2FA171BC4BCABA2EED8D995BF204">
        <enum>504.</enum>
        <header>Insurance
			 protocols for subjects of abuse</header>
        <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Insurers shall develop and adhere to written
			 policies specifying procedures to be followed by employees, contractors,
			 producers, agents, and brokers for the purpose of protecting the safety and
			 privacy of a subject of abuse and otherwise implementing this title when taking
			 an application, investigating a claim, or taking any other action relating to a
			 policy or claim involving a subject of abuse.</text>
			</section>
      <section id="H99D85FF5FFE54BD38BEC47DD442DA889">
        <enum>505.</enum>
        <header>Reasons for
			 adverse actions</header>
        <text display-inline="no-display-inline">An insurer
			 that takes an action that adversely affects a subject of abuse, shall advise
			 the applicant or insured who is the subject of abuse of the specific reasons
			 for the action in writing. For purposes of this section, reference to general
			 underwriting practices or guidelines shall not constitute a specific
			 reason.</text>
			</section>
      <section id="H174C36C7C0E14BB5A4DAE423BC085938">
        <enum>506.</enum>
        <header>Life
			 insurance</header>
        <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this
			 title shall be construed to prohibit a life insurer from declining to issue a
			 life insurance policy if the applicant or prospective owner of the policy is or
			 would be designated as a beneficiary of the policy, and if—</text>
				<paragraph id="H0C7C048409DB48378C6489A4037E02AA">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>the applicant or
			 prospective owner of the policy lacks an insurable interest in the insured;
			 or</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HCD1B3A367D3D4E9F89A40DEE43C7A68A">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>the applicant or
			 prospective owner of the policy is known, on the basis of police or court
			 records, to have committed an act of abuse against the proposed insured.</text>
				</paragraph>
      </section>
      <section id="H4714FB1B14154F1E8AC7F42B6E2777BD">
        <enum>507.</enum>
        <header>Subrogation
			 without consent prohibited</header>
        <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Subrogation of claims resulting from abuse
			 is prohibited without the informed consent of the subject of abuse.</text>
			</section>
      <section id="H83D0EBBB29F24EDF886690BC0DA34845">
        <enum>508.</enum>
        <header>Enforcement</header>
				<subsection id="H4E3056F9492946D3B25A76246F85CA78">
          <enum>(a)</enum>
          <header>Federal Trade
			 Commission</header>
          <text>Any act or practice prohibited by this title shall be
			 treated as an unfair and deceptive act or practice pursuant to <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Federal Trade Commission Act/s:5">section 5 of the
			 <act-name>Federal Trade Commission Act</act-name>
              </cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/45">15 U.S.C. 45</external-xref>)</cato:entity> and the
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2900">Federal Trade Commission</cato:entity-ref> shall enforce this title in the same manner, by the
			 same means, and with the same jurisdiction, powers, and duties as though all
			 applicable terms and provisions of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Federal Trade Commission Act">Federal Trade Commission Act</cato:entity-ref> were
			 incorporated into and made a part of this title, including issuing a cease and
			 desist order granting any individual relief warranted under the circumstances,
			 including temporary, preliminary, and permanent injunctive relief and
			 compensatory damages.</text>
				</subsection>
        <subsection id="H42A987DD945F4D679E1978AF4BA39BE6">
          <enum>(b)</enum>
          <header>Private cause of
			 action</header>
					<paragraph id="H9B1FA41A49EC48068DB3217DEF97236A">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <header>In
			 general</header>
            <text>An applicant or insured who believes that the applicant
			 or insured has been adversely affected by an act or practice of an insurer in
			 violation of this title may maintain an action against the insurer in a Federal
			 or State court of original jurisdiction.</text>
					</paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H2B3C6A7CF552474D93E9455424C8B4A2">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <header>Relief</header>
            <text>Upon
			 proof of such conduct by a preponderance of the evidence in an action described
			 in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Security and Financial Empowerment Act/s:508/ss:b/p:1" proposed="true">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref>, the court may award appropriate relief, including temporary,
			 preliminary, and permanent injunctive relief and compensatory and punitive
			 damages, as well as the costs of suit and reasonable fees for the aggrieved
			 individual’s attorneys and expert witnesses.</text>
					</paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H556F18D7231846E59D7BF039017C6F9C">
            <enum>(3)</enum>
            <header>Statutory
			 damages</header>
            <text>With respect to compensatory damages in an action
			 described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Security and Financial Empowerment Act/s:508/ss:b/p:1" proposed="true">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref>, the aggrieved individual may elect, at any time
			 prior to the rendering of final judgment, to recover in lieu of actual damages,
			 an award of statutory damages in the amount of $5,000 for each
			 violation.</text>
					</paragraph>
        </subsection>
      </section>
      <section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H451DD231CCC5431899C534A04179E976" section-type="subsequent-section">
        <enum>509.</enum>
        <header>Effective
			 date</header>
        <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This title shall apply
			 with respect to any action taken after the date of enactment of this
			 Act.</text>
			</section>
    </title>
    <title id="HB46A690F43234C52B2149B6D2B3F2CA6">
      <enum>VI</enum>
      <header>Severability</header>
			<section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H487379B9F8924D3AB5EF7B1B7122333D" section-type="subsequent-section">
        <enum>601.</enum>
        <header>Severability</header>
        <text display-inline="no-display-inline">If any provision of this Act, any amendment
			 made by this Act, or the application of such provision or amendment to any
			 person or circumstance is held to be unconstitutional, the remainder of the
			 provisions of this Act, the amendments made by this Act, and the application of
			 such provisions or amendments to any person or circumstance shall not be
			 affected.</text>
			</section>
    </title>
  </legis-body>
</bill>
</doc>