<doc>
  <docmeta id="113hr3212rs">
    <bill congress="113" type="hr" number="3212" version="rs"/>
    <revision size="119013" annotations="0" status="complete" id="6" commit-time="2014-07-14T20:43:31Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113hr3212rs/6.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <bill bill-stage="Reported-in-Senate" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H883F0D06596A44FEA3BE8D8B052FCD5B" public-private="public" stage-count="1">
  <metadata>
<dublinCore>
<dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">113 HR 3212 RS: Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2013</dc:title>
<dc:publisher xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">2013-12-17</dc:date>
<dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
    <calendar>Calendar No. 450</calendar>
    <congress>113th CONGRESS</congress>
    <session>2d Session</session>
    <legis-num>H. R. 3212</legis-num>
    <associated-doc role="report">[Report No. 113–204]</associated-doc>
    <current-chamber display="yes">IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
    <action>
      <action-date date="20131212" legis-day="20131211">December 12 (legislative day, December 11), 2013</action-date>
      <action-desc>Received</action-desc>
    </action>
    <action>
      <action-date date="20131217">December 17, 2013</action-date>
      <action-desc>Read twice and referred to the <committee-name added-display-style="italic" committee-id="SSFR00" deleted-display-style="strikethrough">Committee on Foreign Relations</committee-name>
      </action-desc>
    </action>
    <action stage="Reported-in-Senate">
      <action-date>June 26, 2014</action-date>
      <action-desc>Reported by <sponsor name-id="S306">Mr. Menendez</sponsor>, with an amendment</action-desc>
      <action-instruction>Strike out all after the enacting clause and insert the part printed in italic</action-instruction>
    </action>
    <legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type>
    <official-title display="yes">To ensure compliance with the 1980 Hague Convention on the Civil Aspects of International Child
			 Abduction by countries with which the United States enjoys reciprocal
			 obligations, to establish procedures for the prompt return of children
			 abducted to other countries, and for other purposes.</official-title>
  </form>
  <legis-body id="H993EEB13EBD042108D182722D511893A" style="OLC">
    <section changed="deleted" committee-id="SSFR00" id="HE72D462468904AD4BE78F3FD7D9346B5" reported-display-style="strikethrough" section-type="section-one">
      <enum>1.</enum>
      <header>Short title and table of contents</header>
      <subsection id="HA5148D894C6B43A1AB1EB55AA2B5C9BF">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Short title</header>
        <text>This Act may be cited as the <quote>
            <short-title>
              Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2013
            </short-title>
          </quote>.</text>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="H534D57D116ED468A9F419A5070919E9E">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Table of contents</header>
        <text>The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text>
        <toc changed="deleted" committee-id="SSFR00" container-level="legis-body-container" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded" lowest-level="section" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" regeneration="yes-regeneration" reported-display-style="strikethrough">
          <toc-entry idref="HE72D462468904AD4BE78F3FD7D9346B5" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title and table of contents.</toc-entry>
          <toc-entry idref="H3072466932D04C1CAF3D3A3C7B047D70" level="section">Sec. 2. Findings; sense of Congress; purposes.</toc-entry>
          <toc-entry idref="H58AF3C0168E2470E96B7FE61C03D361F" level="section">Sec. 3. Definitions.</toc-entry>
          <toc-entry idref="HBD1310EA24124B0698AB80A61A08F0AE" level="title">Title I—Department of State Actions</toc-entry>
          <toc-entry idref="H20E247A528AF4A2D831953A8D1197CCA" level="section">Sec. 101. Annual report.</toc-entry>
          <toc-entry idref="H9DCE5FF6F5B24E4D8FCF401833728BB3" level="section">Sec. 102. Standards and assistance.</toc-entry>
          <toc-entry idref="H9A0C6542324E44A7AC386B1E78D7EAE2" level="section">Sec. 103. Memorandum of understanding.</toc-entry>
          <toc-entry idref="H566CB1E271094287833A4A18CDFBC174" level="section">Sec. 104. Notification of congressional representatives.</toc-entry>
          <toc-entry idref="HDFBCFDBF572F48D48C72C8052182CC54" level="title">Title II—Presidential Actions</toc-entry>
          <toc-entry idref="H5AC567E29CC34585AA9015B8EF9FD1EF" level="section">Sec. 201. Presidential actions in response to unresolved cases.</toc-entry>
          <toc-entry idref="HB02DBD03717244459C91DA48C79DEBAE" level="section">Sec. 202. Presidential actions in response to patterns of noncooperation in cases of international
			 child abductions.</toc-entry>
          <toc-entry idref="H736055E091D34FE799A9D3087BDB1DB6" level="section">Sec. 203. Consultations with foreign governments.</toc-entry>
          <toc-entry idref="H4E6C8EAA5B52459CBA89C38BF83A5762" level="section">Sec. 204. Report to Congress.</toc-entry>
          <toc-entry idref="H6A892B19D7294BEFAD364D1A17D73CCF" level="section">Sec. 205. Presidential actions.</toc-entry>
          <toc-entry idref="HF02C073DFCE44C1281FFD2FBF8ABCBF4" level="section">Sec. 206. Presidential waiver.</toc-entry>
          <toc-entry idref="H8770BA92A55B419782978AC57883FE86" level="section">Sec. 207. Publication in Federal Register.</toc-entry>
          <toc-entry idref="HBB8FAB486465416EADC771518756F84C" level="section">Sec. 208. Termination of Presidential actions.</toc-entry>
        </toc>
      </subsection>
    </section>
    <section changed="deleted" committee-id="SSFR00" id="H3072466932D04C1CAF3D3A3C7B047D70" reported-display-style="strikethrough">
      <enum>2.</enum>
      <header>Findings; sense of Congress; purposes</header>
      <subsection id="H449E4355E0EE41469FDCA748EBF6CBC4">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Findings</header>
        <text>Congress finds the following:</text>
        <paragraph id="H5E00EDF5E85443ADB860CAB15F2320D9">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>Sean Goldman, a United States citizen and resident of New Jersey, was abducted from the United
			 States in 2004 and separated from his father, David Goldman, who spent
			 nearly six years battling for the return of his son from Brazil before
			 Sean was finally returned to Mr. Goldman’s custody on December 24, 2009.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HBA4B984C84664C439198D4CD2C8C3B71">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>The Department of State’s Office of Children’s Issues, which serves as the Central Authority of the
			 United States for the purposes of the 1980 Hague Convention on the Civil
			 Aspects of International Child Abduction, has received thousands of
			 requests since 2007 for assistance in the return to the United States of
			 children who have been abducted by a parent or other legal guardian to
			 another country. For a variety of reasons reflecting the significant
			 obstacles to the recovery of abducted children, as well as the legal and
			 factual complexity involving such cases, not all cases are reported to the
			 Central Authority of the United States.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HE474831239FE46088B057BF83C3491E7">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <text>More than one thousand outgoing international child abductions are reported to the Central
			 Authority of the United States every year.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H439C85F319ED4988819DEE70AB676C66">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
          <text>Only about half of the children abducted from the United States to countries with which the United
			 States enjoys reciprocal obligations under the Hague Abduction Convention
			 are returned to the United States.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H6380B13B61ED448AAA40C25E246C3D60">
          <enum>(5)</enum>
          <text>The United States and Convention countries have expressed their desire, through the Hague Abduction
			 Convention, <quote>
              <short-title>to protect children internationally from the harmful effects of their wrongful removal or retention
			 and to establish procedures to ensure their prompt return to the State of
			 their habitual residence, as well as to secure protection for rights of
			 access.</short-title>
            </quote>.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H81B65B18E5EC43829E7F1845FA750A41">
          <enum>(6)</enum>
          <text>Compliance by the United States and Convention countries depends on the actions of their designated
			 central authorities, the performance of their judiciaries as reflected in
			 the legal process and decisions rendered to enforce or effectuate the
			 Hague Abduction Convention, and the ability and willingness of their law
			 enforcement to insure the swift enforcement of orders rendered pursuant to
			 the Hague Abduction Convention.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HB75917D02EAE4AF1BD4025CCEBBEDA0A">
          <enum>(7)</enum>
          <text>According to data compiled by the Central Authority of the United States, approximately 40 percent
			 of abduction cases and access cases involve children taken from the United
			 States to countries with which the United States does not have Hague
			 Abduction Convention obligations or other agreements relating to the
			 resolution of abduction cases and access cases.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H52D4C4A59E4D480B918C73857E8AAA07">
          <enum>(8)</enum>
          <text>According to the Department of State’s April 2010 Report on Compliance with the Hague Convention on
			 the Civil Aspects of International Child Abduction, <quote>
              <short-title>parental child abduction jeopardizes the child and has substantial long-term consequences for both
			 the child and the left-behind parent.</short-title>
            </quote>.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H342F2AD18DE34F8290588E148B8B3C97">
          <enum>(9)</enum>
          <text>Abducted children are at risk of serious emotional and psychological problems and have been found
			 to experience anxiety, eating problems, nightmares, mood swings, sleep
			 disturbances, aggressive behavior, resentment, guilt and fearfulness, and
			 as adults may struggle with identity issues, personal relationships, and
			 parenting.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HD46C0244B4CC4E6AB762957869BFEF3A">
          <enum>(10)</enum>
          <text>Left-behind parents may encounter substantial psychological and emotional problems, and few have
			 the extraordinary financial resources necessary to pursue individual civil
			 or criminal remedies in both the United States and a foreign country, even
			 where available, or to engage in repeated foreign travel to attempt to
			 procure the return of their children by evoking diplomatic and
			 humanitarian remedies.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H7174E5B541674649AA91C9B6BA86ACF6">
          <enum>(11)</enum>
          <text>Left-behind parents who are military parents may be unable to leave their military duties to pursue
			 multinational litigation or take leave to attend multiple court
			 proceedings, and foreign authorities may not schedule proceedings to
			 accommodate such duties.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="H575092E8F9454D8EBA4E6B1754F4BF00">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Sense of Congress</header>
        <text>It is the sense of Congress that the United States should set a strong example for Convention
			 countries in the timely location and return of abducted children in the
			 United States whose habitual residence is not the United States.</text>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="HEEF24BA5E4CE497582B171D7DC836681">
        <enum>(c)</enum>
        <header>Purposes</header>
        <text>The purposes of this Act are to—</text>
        <paragraph id="H7C9A40B6A82E4F13A4E54E1915493FC9">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>protect children whose habitual residence is the United States from the harmful effects of
			 abduction and to assist left-behind parents to have access to their
			 abducted child in a safe and predictable manner, wherever the child is
			 located, while an abduction case is pending;</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HEDFE29CF801347C6A9376574E8B505E9">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>provide left-behind parents, including military parents, their advocates, and judges the
			 information they need to enhance the resolution of abduction cases and
			 access cases through established legal procedures, risk assessment tools,
			 and the practical means for overcoming obstacles to recovering an abducted
			 child;</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H29562780049D4BDD90777FD87BED2D8E">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <text>establish measured, effective, and predictable actions to be undertaken by the President on behalf
			 of abducted children whose habitual residence is the United States at the
			 time of the abduction;</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HB992D82AE4874C1193D1D53D2468D646">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
          <text>promote an international consensus that it is in the interest of children to have any issues
			 related to their care and custody determined in the country of their
			 habitual residence;</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H12CDD100ADEB4CFAA79925E7BAC30E68">
          <enum>(5)</enum>
          <text>provide the necessary training for officials of the United States Armed Forces and the Department
			 of Defense to establish policies and provide services to military parents
			 that address the unique circumstances of abductions and violations of
			 rights of access that may occur with regard to military dependent
			 children; and</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H172AD122C8DD4B92B1160A7A8D92F1EE">
          <enum>(6)</enum>
          <text>encourage the effective implementation of international mechanisms, particularly those established
			 pursuant to the Hague Abduction Convention, to achieve reciprocity in the
			 resolution of abductions and to protect children from the harmful effects
			 of an abduction.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
    </section>
    <section changed="deleted" committee-id="SSFR00" id="H58AF3C0168E2470E96B7FE61C03D361F" reported-display-style="strikethrough">
      <enum>3.</enum>
      <header>Definitions</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text>
      <paragraph id="H97260637B2C94C889ED18633E210CA5C">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <header>Abducted child</header>
        <text>The term <term>abducted child</term> means a child who is the victim of an abduction.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HEA25E6C7BB5C40978AD420634794F173">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <header>Abduction</header>
        <text>The term <term>abduction</term> means—</text>
        <subparagraph id="HDE1293F7C03E4E6F8F511FEA79C20BD4">
          <enum>(A)</enum>
          <text>the alleged wrongful removal of a child from the child’s country of habitual residence;</text>
        </subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="H761C8332AB414E7A8443738BDED83671">
          <enum>(B)</enum>
          <text>the alleged wrongful retention of a child outside the child’s country of habitual residence; or</text>
        </subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="HFABDD218B98C4AA7B808A87AD8E3002F">
          <enum>(C)</enum>
          <text>the alleged wrongful removal or retention of a military dependent child from the exercise of rights
			 of custody of a military parent.</text>
        </subparagraph>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H959BB73A621146EBB0FE17614F60EA72">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <header>Abduction case</header>
        <text>The term <term>abduction case</term> means a case involving an application filed with the Central Authority of the United States by a
			 left-behind parent for the resolution of an abduction.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HA8E91C288E71441EB4A2E9AEE54DDD2D">
        <enum>(4)</enum>
        <header>Access case</header>
        <text>The term <term>access case</term> means a case involving an application filed with the Central Authority of the United States by a
			 left-behind parent for the establishment of rights of access.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HD7DD4A68B108403997485B4D7430B537">
        <enum>(5)</enum>
        <header>Annual report</header>
        <text>The term <term>Annual Report</term> means the Annual Report on International Child Abduction required under section 101.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HDF3FD99BE98A4E4DAB2DBFA1201C755E">
        <enum>(6)</enum>
        <header>Application</header>
        <text>The term <term>application</term> means—</text>
        <subparagraph id="HA0127C98AD9B4211BAEC90B0F4B8BCD4">
          <enum>(A)</enum>
          <text>in the case of a Convention country, the application required pursuant to article 8 of the Hague
			 Abduction Convention;</text>
        </subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="H34B8AD61210E4AEFA9880355687731F1">
          <enum>(B)</enum>
          <text>in the case of an MOU country, the formal document required pursuant to the provisions of the
			 applicable MOU to request the return of an abducted child or to request
			 rights of access, as applicable; and</text>
        </subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="H29B8161D890843479BB362FD90814A01">
          <enum>(C)</enum>
          <text>in the case of a nonparty country, the formal request by the Central Authority of the United States
			 to the Central Authority of such country requesting the return of an
			 abducted child or for rights of access to an abducted child.</text>
        </subparagraph>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HF0F7EF42FE054842960AC998CBA1A651">
        <enum>(7)</enum>
        <header>Appropriate congressional committees</header>
        <text>The term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Committee on
			 Foreign Relations of the Senate.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H18B1A42C7AE44515812BF2DEEA9F4607">
        <enum>(8)</enum>
        <header>Central authority</header>
        <text>The term <term>Central Authority</term> means—</text>
        <subparagraph id="H7519E9AFFA7F4B10BAE56B98A2E8555E">
          <enum>(A)</enum>
          <text>in the case of a Convention country, the meaning given such term in article 6 of the Hague
			 Abduction Convention;</text>
        </subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="H2C3770DDC8774CA7B123BF3BA97DDB50">
          <enum>(B)</enum>
          <text>in the case of an MOU country, the official entity designated by the government of the MOU country
			 within the applicable MOU pursuant to section 103(b)(1) to discharge the
			 duties imposed on the entity in such MOU; and</text>
        </subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="H671333B9E05E4131BB52114EC88B7857">
          <enum>(C)</enum>
          <text>in the case of a nonparty country, the foreign ministry of such country.</text>
        </subparagraph>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H405FEC1FA73D420D9F8A11EA98EA044A">
        <enum>(9)</enum>
        <header>Child</header>
        <text>The term <term>child</term> means an individual who has not attained the age of 16.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HCE36E83EA5224219AC76C5DE14ECA059">
        <enum>(10)</enum>
        <header>Convention country</header>
        <text>The term <term>Convention country</term> means a country other than the United States that has ratified, acceded, or succeeded to the Hague
			 Abduction Convention and with respect to which the United States has
			 entered into a reciprocal agreement pursuant to the Hague Abduction
			 Convention.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H4A584633DC134CDDA1C2FCB32E40CFE4">
        <enum>(11)</enum>
        <header>Hague abduction convention</header>
        <text>The term <term>Hague Abduction Convention</term> means the Convention on the Civil Aspects of International Child Abduction, done at The Hague on
			 October 25, 1980.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H22E379126F2A4A8796325B00BC6408C1">
        <enum>(12)</enum>
        <header>Left-behind parent</header>
        <text>The term <term>left-behind parent</term> means an individual or entity, either individually or jointly, who alleges that an abduction has
			 occurred that is in breach of rights of custody—</text>
        <subparagraph id="HE3F59AF621A940C9A12D9EABC2C90C4B">
          <enum>(A)</enum>
          <text>attributed to such individual or entity, as applicable; and</text>
        </subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="HC3F91DEC08A244949361A9B1EEE5BD5E">
          <enum>(B)</enum>
          <text>exercised at the time of the abduction or that would have been exercised but for the abduction.</text>
        </subparagraph>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HCBDC098577E1491B9C73E9730CBA3D04">
        <enum>(13)</enum>
        <header>Legal residence</header>
        <text>The term <term>legal residence</term> means the congressional district and State in which an individual either is residing, or if an
			 individual is residing temporarily outside the United States, the
			 congressional district and State to which the individual intends to
			 return.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H82B5910195E04ACEA76F1EF85E023475">
        <enum>(14)</enum>
        <header>Military dependent child</header>
        <text>The term <term>military dependent child</term> means a child whose habitual residence is the United States according to United States law even
			 though the child is residing outside the United States with a military
			 parent.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HE75EB54D97FD46CB8131751C099FC9B4">
        <enum>(15)</enum>
        <header>Military parent</header>
        <text>The term <term>military parent</term> means an individual who has rights of custody over a child and who is serving outside the United
			 States as a member of the United States Armed Forces.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HE2920F9A5773446D848A655D341964ED">
        <enum>(16)</enum>
        <header>MOU</header>
        <text>The term <term>MOU</term> means a memorandum of understanding between the United States and a country that is not a
			 Convention country to resolve abduction cases and access cases.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H51B2632C9C704E3FB6139CE2E6298E05">
        <enum>(17)</enum>
        <header>MOU country</header>
        <text>The term <term>MOU country</term> means a country with respect to which the United States has entered into an MOU.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HCDE6EA216AAE4F148D1E0C1B3EF9FC1F">
        <enum>(18)</enum>
        <header>Nonparty country</header>
        <text>The term <term>nonparty country</term> means a country that is neither a Convention country nor an MOU country.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H6E78E52BA5DA4D9898B87EE32BE0E029">
        <enum>(19)</enum>
        <header>Pattern of noncooperation</header>
        <subparagraph id="H5259B04240894631A485FBC003B57400">
          <enum>(A)</enum>
          <header>In general</header>
          <text>The term <term>pattern of noncooperation</term> means the persistent failure—</text>
          <clause id="H88D897F2D4AA4B4EA32661E39A2806F9">
            <enum>(i)</enum>
            <text>of a Convention country to implement and abide by the provisions of the Hague Abduction Convention;
			 and</text>
          </clause>
          <clause id="H4BFAD7AF15D34457BAEF5C4D3CF690A9">
            <enum>(ii)</enum>
            <text>of an MOU country to implement and abide by the provisions of the applicable MOU.</text>
          </clause>
        </subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="H14AACEFD6E1A4C25B5BA734EC1F428DF">
          <enum>(B)</enum>
          <header>Criteria</header>
          <text>Such persistent failure may be evidenced by one or more of the following criteria:</text>
          <clause id="H0CAF8CCE9F4B483EADCD53E166322014">
            <enum>(i)</enum>
            <text>The existence of 10 or more unresolved abduction cases.</text>
          </clause>
          <clause id="H6C490DFDB199408AB6525EAEFAEF135F">
            <enum>(ii)</enum>
            <text>The failure of the Central Authority of the country to fulfill its responsibilities pursuant to the
			 Hague Abduction Convention or the MOU, as applicable.</text>
          </clause>
          <clause id="H1559B8BF9B1A4C7EBB6BEC8C3F87D390">
            <enum>(iii)</enum>
            <text>The failure of the judicial or administrative branch, as applicable, of the national government of
			 the country to implement and comply with the provisions of the Hague
			 Abduction Convention or the MOU, as applicable.</text>
          </clause>
          <clause id="H1E228C005F5E4CFDB1FBD9C6142DE3F9">
            <enum>(iv)</enum>
            <text>The failure of law enforcement to locate abducted children or to enforce return orders or
			 determinations of rights of access rendered by the judicial or
			 administrative authorities of the national government of the country in
			 abduction cases or access cases.</text>
          </clause>
        </subparagraph>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H1803D30948BE4847A9DC47578BD18F14">
        <enum>(20)</enum>
        <header>Rights of access</header>
        <text>The term <term>rights of access</term> means the rights of contact between a child and a left-behind parent provided as a provisional
			 measure while an abduction case is pending, by operation of law or by
			 reason of judicial or administrative determination or by agreement having
			 legal effect, under the law of the country in which the child is located.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HA64F072F9351403D995CB3385333DE15">
        <enum>(21)</enum>
        <header>Rights of custody</header>
        <text>The term <term>rights of custody</term> means rights of care and custody of an abducted child, including the right to determine the place
			 of residence of an abducted child—</text>
        <subparagraph id="HFC005F3A1F514870A7A75979658AC6E2">
          <enum>(A)</enum>
          <text>attributed to an individual or entity, either individually or jointly, and</text>
        </subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="H325B021B2B18455D968B9C7E2BD6870F">
          <enum>(B)</enum>
          <text>arising by operation of law or by reason of a judicial or administrative decision, or by reason of
			 an agreement having legal effect,</text>
        </subparagraph>
        <continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph">under the law of the country in which the child was an habitual resident immediately before the
			 abduction.</continuation-text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H0DAA95A15706416089F1C265678B0ED3">
        <enum>(22)</enum>
        <header>Unresolved abduction case</header>
        <subparagraph id="H27F1B16F18B344209003B5F8A57916C8">
          <enum>(A)</enum>
          <header>In general</header>
          <text>Subject to subparagraph (B), the term <term>unresolved abduction case</term> means an abduction case that remains unresolved for a period that exceeds 180 days after the date
			 on which the completed application for return of the child is submitted
			 for determination to the judicial or administrative authority, as
			 applicable, in the country in which the child is located.</text>
        </subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="H67721313BDB940C3AD7E76CAA4D5E575">
          <enum>(B)</enum>
          <header>Resolution of case</header>
          <text>An abduction case shall be considered to be resolved if—</text>
          <clause id="H1D9418D6E8DB41A7979BE8B32BE0E0C8">
            <enum>(i)</enum>
            <text>the child is returned to the country of habitual residence, pursuant to the Hague Abduction
			 Convention or MOU, if applicable;</text>
          </clause>
          <clause id="H68E94C263EEF4C2E85196E95E6C3ED79">
            <enum>(ii)</enum>
            <text>the judicial or administrative branch, as applicable, of the national government of the country in
			 which the child is located has implemented and is complying with the
			 provisions of the Hague Abduction Convention or the MOU, as applicable,
			 and a final determination is made by such judicial or administrative
			 branch that the child will not be returned to the country of habitual
			 residence; or</text>
          </clause>
          <clause id="H0D4D9E5009D247488D28404711F0F9DF">
            <enum>(iii)</enum>
            <text>the child attains the age of 16.</text>
          </clause>
        </subparagraph>
      </paragraph>
    </section>
    <title changed="deleted" committee-id="SSFR00" id="HBD1310EA24124B0698AB80A61A08F0AE" reported-display-style="strikethrough">
      <enum>I</enum>
      <header>Department of State Actions</header>
      <section id="H20E247A528AF4A2D831953A8D1197CCA">
        <enum>101.</enum>
        <header>Annual report</header>
        <subsection id="HE51DD4DFFF5749BDB480696021006876">
          <enum>(a)</enum>
          <header>In general</header>
          <text>Not later than March 31 of each year, the Secretary of State shall submit to the appropriate
			 congressional committees an Annual Report on International Child
			 Abduction.</text>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="H16AE36286739486BB782CEF6CCC35123">
          <enum>(b)</enum>
          <header>Contents</header>
          <text>Each Annual Report shall include the following:</text>
          <paragraph id="H6332A49470F749DFAE21D8919F32A9A9">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A list of all countries with respect to which there were one or more abduction cases during the
			 preceding year that identifies whether each such country is a Convention
			 country, an MOU country, or a nonparty country.</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H33586BB1049F4A78928F8085C32E99E3">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <text>For each country with respect to which there were 5 or more abduction cases during the preceding
			 year:</text>
            <subparagraph id="HF6EE1AFDD58249C692F176C8F43FFFC3">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>The number of abduction cases and the number of access cases, respectively, reported during the
			 preceding year.</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H6E7F43C2A1504DF69B072F77F0713C54">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>The number of abduction cases and the number of access cases, respectively, that are pending as of
			 March 1 of the year in which such Annual Report is submitted.</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H62D684B87D7D499A9B9D4C3EF28E6083">
              <enum>(C)</enum>
              <clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H9B4EC29BE0104F89A8441ED17CB9A194">
                <enum>(i)</enum>
                <text>For Convention and MOU countries, the number of abduction cases and the number of access cases,
			 respectively, that were pending at any point for more than 180 days after
			 the date on which the Central Authority of the United States transmitted
			 the complete application for each such case to the Central Authority of
			 such country, and were not submitted by the Central Authority to the
			 judicial or administrative authority, as applicable, of such country
			 within the 180-day period.</text>
              </clause>
              <clause changed="deleted" committee-id="SSFR00" id="HB42324CA990942D1B688F957E66A26E7" indent="up1" reported-display-style="strikethrough">
                <enum>(ii)</enum>
                <text>The reason for the delay in submission of each case identified in clause (i) by the Central
			 Authority of such country to the judicial or administrative authority.</text>
              </clause>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H432B0B0BECF44865B0F99A078C211E0E">
              <enum>(D)</enum>
              <text>The number of unresolved abduction cases, and the length of time each case has been pending.</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="HBBEF961F01DD4AA2A1E11CC0752FFA91">
              <enum>(E)</enum>
              <text>The number of unresolved abduction cases in which a completed application has been filed and law
			 enforcement has failed to locate the abducted child or to enforce a return
			 order rendered by the judicial or administrative authorities of such
			 country.</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H83132CA099BA472A959F74122ADC3DA3">
              <enum>(F)</enum>
              <text>The median time required for resolution of abduction cases during the preceding year, to be
			 measured from the date on which the application with respect to the
			 abduction case is transmitted by the Central Authority of the United
			 States to the Central Authority of such country to the date on which the
			 abduction case is resolved.</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H87A969E385024701AA9B7A04700A6A0D">
              <enum>(G)</enum>
              <text>The total number and the percentage of the total number of abduction cases and access cases,
			 respectively, resolved during the preceding year.</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="HBEC60D41F2114DA6B95F4FB7DB48AC3A">
              <enum>(H)</enum>
              <text>Detailed information about each unresolved abduction case described in subparagraph (E) and on
			 actions taken by the Department of State to resolve such case, including
			 the specific actions taken by the United States chief of mission in such
			 country.</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H07EDB71534F14215A6BD5106E61B38BA">
              <enum>(I)</enum>
              <text>Recommendations to improve resolution of abduction cases and access cases.</text>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="HAA9BC3B40C8747A19F24420C31CF26CD">
            <enum>(3)</enum>
            <text>The number of abducted children from the United States who were returned to the United States from
			 Convention countries, MOU countries, and nonparty countries, respectively.</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="HB3C7CE3B51E0493591C224794F07F294">
            <enum>(4)</enum>
            <text>A list of Convention countries and MOU countries that have failed to comply with any of their
			 obligations under the Hague Abduction Convention or the MOU, as
			 applicable, with respect to the resolution of abduction cases and access
			 cases.</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H4E6B06C2C3A64DE683028CAF5F17D6BA">
            <enum>(5)</enum>
            <text>A list of countries demonstrating a pattern of noncooperation, and a summary of the criteria on
			 which the determination of a pattern of noncooperation for each country is
			 based.</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="HA15A8E2E95A74370B1F74BAE8F78B829">
            <enum>(6)</enum>
            <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H02B1833D924F466FA8BAF3805BA386F5">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>Information on efforts by the Secretary of State to encourage other countries to become signatories
			 to the Hague Abduction Convention or to enter into an MOU.</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph changed="deleted" committee-id="SSFR00" id="HA05B5BD8232144CEA9E6AD6524393D4A" indent="up1" reported-display-style="strikethrough">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>The efforts referred to in subparagraph (A) shall include efforts to address pending abduction
			 cases and access cases in such countries.</text>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="HCE0695E0C17E45469CFE54A9089F0AB5">
            <enum>(7)</enum>
            <text>A description of the efforts of the Secretary of State to encourage Convention countries and MOU
			 countries to facilitate the work of nongovernmental organizations within
			 their respective countries that assist left-behind parents.</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H8EEEC49080A74B6F8651C986B249F3E0">
            <enum>(8)</enum>
            <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The number of cases which were successfully resolved without abducted children being returned to
			 the United States from Convention countries, MOU countries, and nonparty
			 countries, respectively.</text>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="HEE7330F1494C46188DD704DCEAE681ED">
          <enum>(c)</enum>
          <header>Exception</header>
          <text>The Annual Report shall not include—</text>
          <paragraph id="H97B483BB8BC34A33AEF8006491336F54">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <text>the names of left-behind parents or children involved in abduction cases or access cases; or</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H63D79BD7B53642859E605935B1DBD472">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <text>information that may identify a party involved in an abduction case or access case unless the party
			 stipulates in writing to the Central Authority of the United States that
			 such information may be included in the Annual Report.</text>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="H26E3A80989BF47B38A1DED13E431DBEF">
          <enum>(d)</enum>
          <header>Additional thematic sections</header>
          <text>Each Annual Report shall also include—</text>
          <paragraph id="HB2F878416F4A4849AB3CF482E54AB3F7">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <text>information on the number of unresolved abduction cases affecting left-behind parents who are
			 military parents and a summary of assistance offered to such left-behind
			 parents;</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H021C0CE1BAC5443A9D5485063A91382E">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <text>information on the use of airlines in abductions, voluntary airline practices to prevent
			 abductions, and recommendations for best airline practices to prevent
			 abductions;</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H3AF2BC7A29E34D0A8AB312703A68F091">
            <enum>(3)</enum>
            <text>information on actions taken by the Central Authority of the United States to train domestic judges
			 in application of the Hague Abduction Convention; and</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H2866842C9DA849B0A3B1A633DABCB2B6">
            <enum>(4)</enum>
            <text>information on actions taken by the Central Authority of the United States to train United States
			 Armed Forces legal assistance personnel, military chaplains, and military
			 family support center personnel about abductions, the risk of loss of
			 access to children, and the legal frameworks available to resolve such
			 cases.</text>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="H9D6F76C652E344B39158A5E85B338711">
          <enum>(e)</enum>
          <header>Repeal of the Hague Convention Compliance Report</header>
          <text>
            Section 2803 of the Foreign Affairs Reform and Restructuring Act of 1998 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/11611">
              42 U.S.C. 11611
            </external-xref>) is repealed.</text>
        </subsection>
      </section>
      <section id="H9DCE5FF6F5B24E4D8FCF401833728BB3">
        <enum>102.</enum>
        <header>Standards and assistance</header>
        <text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary of State shall ensure that United States diplomatic and consular missions abroad—</text>
        <paragraph id="H2B1BE28A63244DF1B2BB1074166F8AA2">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>maintain a consistent reporting standard with respect to abduction cases and access cases involving
			 abducted children in the country in which such mission is located for
			 purposes of the Annual Report;</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H9F0AB0ABE98541C1BB10FD16C7D2076B">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>designate at least one official in each such mission to assist left-behind parents from the United
			 States who are visiting such country to resolve cases involving an
			 abduction or rights of access; and</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H9A8D897BE2F04B459A9AB8774492B641">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <text>monitor developments in cases involving abducted children in the country in which such mission is
			 located.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </section>
      <section id="H9A0C6542324E44A7AC386B1E78D7EAE2">
        <enum>103.</enum>
        <header>Memorandum of understanding</header>
        <subsection id="H505A8AECC4B340C39DE58D7A0724DC02">
          <enum>(a)</enum>
          <header>In general</header>
          <text>The Secretary of State should seek to enter into an MOU with every country that is not a Convention
			 country and is unlikely to become a Convention country in the forseeable
			 future, that includes—</text>
          <paragraph id="H23159743C6D047338AB7038138A218A9">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <text>identification of the Central Authority;</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H8FB665A00A4449629976FFA7037A452E">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <text>a protocol to identify, locate, and effectuate the return of an abducted child identified in an
			 abduction case not later than 6 weeks after the application with respect
			 to the abduction case has been submitted to the judicial or administrative
			 authority, as applicable, of the country in which the abducted child is
			 located;</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H3970F2E541A1481F946455C02551ED70">
            <enum>(3)</enum>
            <text>a protocol for the establishment and protection of the rights of access;</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="HD60737F902D447958B10D8C091379E5F">
            <enum>(4)</enum>
            <text>identification of the judicial or administrative authority that will promptly adjudicate abduction
			 cases and access cases;</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="HAA70BB8CDBDE4D5688E9405475101628">
            <enum>(5)</enum>
            <text>identification of a law enforcement agency and available law enforcement mechanisms and procedures
			 to ensure the immediate enforcement of an order issued by the authority
			 identified pursuant to paragraph (4) to return an abducted child to a
			 left-behind parent, including by—</text>
            <subparagraph id="H050DF1B05AE349A3860E5BAD36C4F507">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>conducting an investigation to ascertain the location of the abducted child;</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H3DA51D1313C744409DE8FF90D57BDD7F">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>providing protection to the abducted child after such child is located; and</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="HD4EDD76BEE164A958930555AB44CC014">
              <enum>(C)</enum>
              <text>retrieving the abducted child and making the appropriate arrangements for such child to be returned
			 to the country of habitual residence;</text>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H466AF3B2554E4B31B47DB497CC38B764">
            <enum>(6)</enum>
            <text>a protocol to establish periodic visits between a United States embassy or consular official and an
			 abducted child to allow the official to ascertain the child’s location and
			 welfare; and</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="HCF245FBB7FCA4AECB16F69925583117C">
            <enum>(7)</enum>
            <text>such other provisions as determined to be appropriate by the Secretary of State.</text>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="H242CC0D7CBED4166A19EEDCB77F89AC2">
          <enum>(b)</enum>
          <header>Rule of construction</header>
          <paragraph id="H5155F98B01CA45E1A88842D97AF09F12">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <header>In general</header>
            <text>Nothing in this Act shall be construed to prohibit the United States from proposing and entering
			 into a memorandum of understanding with a Convention country to further
			 clarify the reciprocal obligations of the United States and the Convention
			 country under the Hague Abduction Convention.</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="HFC49F7A90D78423EA2751A40DE28B083">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <header>Treatment of obligations of convention country</header>
            <text>In those instances in which there is a memorandum of understanding as described in paragraph (1),
			 the obligations of the Convention country under such memorandum shall be
			 considered to be obligations of such country under the Hague Abduction
			 Convention for purposes of this Act.</text>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
      </section>
      <section id="H566CB1E271094287833A4A18CDFBC174">
        <enum>104.</enum>
        <header>Notification of congressional representatives</header>
        <subsection id="H9C73FE9B0B0B4D32BE33DC90CB60A281">
          <enum>(a)</enum>
          <header>Notification</header>
          <text>Except as provided in subsection (b), the Secretary of State shall notify in writing the Member of
			 Congress and Senators representing the legal residence of a left-behind
			 parent when such parent reports an abduction to the Central Authority of
			 the United States.</text>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="H2BC0AE6F098A4DB298A3D34D92087147">
          <enum>(b)</enum>
          <header>Exception</header>
          <text>The notification requirement under subsection (a) shall not apply if the left-behind parent does
			 not consent to the notification described in such subsection.</text>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="H142B0396DA4A4FBFB655555AB9BAC3CD">
          <enum>(c)</enum>
          <header>Timing</header>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">At the request of any person who is a left-behind parent, including a left-behind parent who
			 previously reported an abduction to the Central Authority of the United
			 States before the date of the enactment of this Act, notification of a
			 Member of Congress, in accordance with subsections (a) and (b), shall be
			 provided as soon as is practicable.</text>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="HF6DD4DFCD1EB40ECB2E604B129067ABB">
          <enum>(d)</enum>
          <header>Member of congress defined</header>
          <text>In this section, the term <term>Member of Congress</term> means a Representative in, or Delegate or Resident Commissioner to, the Congress.</text>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </title>
    <title changed="deleted" committee-id="SSFR00" id="HDFBCFDBF572F48D48C72C8052182CC54" reported-display-style="strikethrough">
      <enum>II</enum>
      <header>Presidential Actions</header>
      <section id="H5AC567E29CC34585AA9015B8EF9FD1EF">
        <enum>201.</enum>
        <header>Presidential actions in response to unresolved cases</header>
        <subsection id="H402017D245904A27A1107605AF09030D">
          <enum>(a)</enum>
          <header>Response to international child abductions</header>
          <paragraph id="HB3361908C93E4B219DF851E596FCAB97">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <header>United states policy</header>
            <text>It shall be the policy of the United States to—</text>
            <subparagraph id="HAB55D28DB5014044B23E4FD77447E2B5">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>promote the best interest of children abducted from the United States by establishing legal rights
			 and procedures for their prompt return and by promoting such rights and
			 procedures through actions that ensure the enforcement of reciprocal
			 international obligations; and</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H56D89909243543BFBF2F7ADDA8A3BC35">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>recognize the international character of the Hague Abduction Convention, and the need for
			 reciprocity pursuant to and the uniform international interpretation of
			 the Hague Abduction Convention, by promoting the timely resolution of
			 abduction cases through one or more of the actions described in section
			 205.</text>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H14D452C529E24BFCB1B58D4B84393647">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <header>Requirement of presidential action</header>
            <text>Whenever the President determines that the government of a foreign country has failed to resolve an
			 unresolved abduction case, the President shall oppose such failure through
			 one or more of the actions described in subsection (b).</text>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="H631A5D68C36146A898CAD3A7B006286A">
          <enum>(b)</enum>
          <header>Presidential actions</header>
          <paragraph id="H973011AE509040F29E9D9E327905B24A">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <header>In general</header>
            <text>Subject to paragraphs (2) and (3), the President, in consultation with the Secretary of State,
			 shall, as expeditiously as practicable in response to the failure
			 described in subsection (a) by the government of a foreign country, take
			 one or more of the actions described in paragraphs (1) through (13) of
			 section 205(a) (or commensurate action as provided in section 205(b)) with
			 respect to such country.</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H0D3FDB8E0A16438BA1AAD4490DA08AC5">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <header>Deadline for actions</header>
            <subparagraph id="HFA631730D7CE45028546A4C942E0858E">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <header>In general</header>
              <text>Except as provided in subparagraph (B), not later than March 31 of each year, the President shall
			 take one or more of the actions described in paragraphs (1) through (13)
			 of section 205(a) (or commensurate action as provided in section 205(b))
			 with respect to each foreign country the government of which has failed to
			 resolve an unresolved abduction case that is pending as of such date.</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="HA6B3F2EF620049D89AAF258E61DBC48F">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <header>Exception</header>
              <text>In the case of an action under any of paragraphs (10) through (13) of section 205(a) (or
			 commensurate action as provided in section 205(b))—</text>
              <clause id="HA382411AE0414BBBB6079713B94F884F">
                <enum>(i)</enum>
                <text>the action may only be taken after the requirements of sections 203 and 204 have been satisfied;
			 and</text>
              </clause>
              <clause id="H47C698AB347A4FEC9EAEEC6DF162699C">
                <enum>(ii)</enum>
                <text>the March 31 deadline to take the action shall not apply.</text>
              </clause>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H7C51A44845984A4FA2C8D686628A13AC">
            <enum>(3)</enum>
            <header>Authority for delay of presidential actions</header>
            <text>The President may delay action described in any of the paragraphs (10) through (13) of section
			 205(a) (or commensurate action as provided in section 205(b)), as required
			 under paragraph (2), if the President determines and certifies to the
			 appropriate congressional committees that an additional, specified period
			 of time is necessary for a continuation of negotiations that have been
			 commenced with the country to resolve the unresolved case.</text>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="H1D81EF2789E84E6783AFB3FD1C17D2BE">
          <enum>(c)</enum>
          <header>Implementation</header>
          <paragraph id="H7FA2BDFDD12E41B78BD59264C7873C34">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <header>In general</header>
            <text>In carrying out subsection (b), the President shall—</text>
            <subparagraph id="H7F4347737FDC475E904AABF5138534F3">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>take one or more actions that most appropriately respond to the nature and severity of the failure
			 to resolve the unresolved abduction cases; and</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H063B2A39732A406FBA11988ECAD1FC82">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>seek to the fullest extent possible to target action as narrowly as practicable with respect to the
			 agencies or instrumentalities of the foreign government that are
			 responsible for such failures, in ways that respect the separation of
			 powers and independence of the judiciary in foreign countries.</text>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H7A8ACDDA6C424E159513A3A9883DC618">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <header>Guidelines for presidential actions</header>
            <text>In addition to the guidelines under paragraph (1), the President, in determining whether to take
			 one or more actions under paragraphs (10) through (13) of section 205(a)
			 (or commensurate action as provided in section 205(b)), shall seek to
			 minimize any adverse impact on—</text>
            <subparagraph id="HC364DBE92CBF49B6847D55943B3B3238">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>the population of the country whose government is targeted by the action or actions; and</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="HFB67359DA7C34CB2AFBA4348977FBD6F">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>the humanitarian activities of United States and foreign nongovernmental organizations in the
			 country.</text>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
      </section>
      <section id="HB02DBD03717244459C91DA48C79DEBAE">
        <enum>202.</enum>
        <header>Presidential actions in response to patterns of noncooperation in cases of international child
			 abductions</header>
        <subsection id="H9BEEEFF303634263A3725EC2B5252E55">
          <enum>(a)</enum>
          <header>Response to a pattern of noncooperation</header>
          <paragraph id="HB3585652FA0143BC9B3B97FAF66D3DA6">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <header>United states policy</header>
            <text>It shall be the policy of the United States to—</text>
            <subparagraph id="H7A25D5DF43264417B5D7C452C2F3266E">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>oppose institutional or other systemic failures of foreign governments to fulfill their obligations
			 pursuant to the Hague Abduction Convention or MOU, as applicable, to
			 resolve abduction cases and access cases; and</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H150058514FFA4CB2AD0FE14152A3BEB8">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>promote reciprocity pursuant to and compliance with the Hague Abduction Convention by Convention
			 countries and compliance with the applicable MOU by MOU countries.</text>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H825BD91B9CDA45729EAECD5895ACDCA4">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <header>Requirement of presidential action</header>
            <text>Whenever the President determines that the government of a foreign country has engaged in a pattern
			 of noncooperation, the President shall promote the resolution of the
			 unresolved abduction cases through one or more of the actions described in
			 subsection (c).</text>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="H7CBD639FB83C481A90A1D7B5620F968A">
          <enum>(b)</enum>
          <header>Designations of countries with patterns of noncooperation in cases of international child abduction</header>
          <paragraph id="HB148BD0FF4B348319760A69F4FAAA8C9">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <header>Annual review</header>
            <subparagraph id="HD1E9D81838274AD08079981AA299EA7F">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <header>In general</header>
              <text>Not later than March 31 of each year, the President shall review the status of abduction cases and
			 access cases in each foreign country to determine whether the government
			 of such country has engaged in a pattern of noncooperation during the
			 preceding 12 months or since the date of the last review of such country
			 under this subparagraph, whichever period is longer. The President shall
			 designate each country the government of which has engaged in a pattern of
			 noncooperation as a Country With a Pattern of Noncooperation.</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H2E5EEB3755C541AC9A1E988307065493">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <header>Basis of review</header>
              <text>Each review conducted under subparagraph (A) shall be based upon information contained in the
			 latest Annual Report and on any other evidence available.</text>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="HF65FA4D82A5145349DA59E773E1502EA">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <header>Determinations of responsible parties</header>
            <text>For the government of each country designated as a Country With a Pattern of Noncooperation under
			 paragraph (1)(A), the President shall seek to determine the agencies or
			 instrumentalities of such government that are responsible for the pattern
			 of noncooperation by such government in order to appropriately target
			 actions under this section in response.</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H1977229144704FEA8DA484E9FED09715">
            <enum>(3)</enum>
            <header>Congressional notification</header>
            <text>Whenever the President designates a country as a Country With a Pattern of Noncooperation under
			 paragraph (1)(A), the President shall, as soon as practicable after such
			 designation is made, transmit to the appropriate congressional committees—</text>
            <subparagraph id="HAA28529CEB0543F8A4030914FBD23B96">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>the designation of the country, signed by the President; and</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="HEBB2211D59654CE8ABA71C90EB69F113">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>the identification, if any, of responsible agencies or instrumentalities determined under paragraph
			 (2).</text>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="HE5ABFDB8739D46109D5DAC7CD9A4EE49">
          <enum>(c)</enum>
          <header>Presidential actions with respect to a country with a pattern of noncooperation</header>
          <paragraph id="H3074053DCA5B450DA1B35F6C2B462566">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <header>In general</header>
            <text>Subject to paragraphs (2) and (3) with respect to each Country With a Pattern of Noncooperation
			 designated under subsection (b)(1)(A), the President shall, after the
			 requirements of sections 203 and 204 have been satisfied, but not later
			 than 90 days (or 180 days in case of a delay under paragraph (2)) after
			 the date of such designation of the country under such subsection, take
			 one or more of the actions under paragraphs (10) through (13) of section
			 205(a) (or commensurate action as provided in section 205(b)).</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H9AF578D89CF240B597F700B435AC919A">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <header>Authority for delay of presidential actions</header>
            <text>If, on or before the date that the President is required to take action under paragraph (1), the
			 President determines and certifies to the appropriate congressional
			 committees that a single, additional period of time not to exceed 90 days
			 is necessary—</text>
            <subparagraph id="H1139F8A764AD4C6A872BF78359F4858B">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>for a continuation of negotiations that have been commenced with the government of a country
			 described in such paragraph to bring about a cessation of the pattern of
			 noncooperation by such country, or</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="HDF13493794FE4342848829D8047F9AF0">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>for a review of corrective action taken by such country after designation of such country as a
			 Country With a Pattern of Noncooperation under subsection (b)(1)(A) or in
			 anticipation that corrective action will be taken by such country during
			 such 90-day period,</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph">the President shall not be required to take such action until the expiration of such period of
			 time.</continuation-text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H1E16265AE3D34EA08EAD923260DA383C">
            <enum>(3)</enum>
            <header>Exception for ongoing presidential action</header>
            <subparagraph id="HC87D1F4988464F7EB433D605869D95A8">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <header>In general</header>
              <text>The President shall not be required to take action under paragraph (1) with respect to a Country
			 With a Pattern of Noncooperation if—</text>
              <clause id="H7B919F6CBEBB4623B964EBED40EBD70B">
                <enum>(i)</enum>
                <text>the President has taken action pursuant to paragraph (1) with respect to such country in a
			 preceding year, such action is in effect at the time such country is
			 designated as a Country with a Pattern of Noncooperation under subsection
			 (b)(1)(A), and the President submits to the appropriate congressional
			 committees the information described in section 204 regarding the actions
			 in effect with respect to such country; or</text>
              </clause>
              <clause id="H2DC47FC50CA14CC5BAFA569C6FDCC021">
                <enum>(ii)</enum>
                <text>subject to subparagraph (B), the President determines that such country is subject to multiple,
			 broad-based sanctions imposed in significant part in response to human
			 rights abuses and that such sanctions also satisfy the requirements of
			 this subsection.</text>
              </clause>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H539AA86E0C484CC2A3B34771283E64B2">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <header>Additional requirements</header>
              <text>If the President makes a determination under subparagraph (A)(ii)—</text>
              <clause id="H7124EA476A234009B262C9F0BDA10966">
                <enum>(i)</enum>
                <text>the report under section 204 and, as applicable, the publication in the Federal Register under
			 section 208, shall specify the specific sanction or sanctions that the
			 President has determined satisfy the requirements of this subsection; and</text>
              </clause>
              <clause id="HCA9805046F9D41D6B09EB1CE61F474AA">
                <enum>(ii)</enum>
                <text>such sanctions shall remain in effect subject to section 209.</text>
              </clause>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="HD92E4B644CD54F09B992ED2DCF8DD864">
          <enum>(d)</enum>
          <header>Rule of construction</header>
          <text>A determination under this section that a foreign country has engaged in a pattern of
			 noncooperation shall not be construed to require the termination of
			 assistance or other activities with respect to such country under any
			 other provision of law, including section 116 or 502B of the Foreign
			 Assistance Act of 1961 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2151">
              22 U.S.C. 2151(n)
            </external-xref> or 2304).</text>
        </subsection>
      </section>
      <section id="H736055E091D34FE799A9D3087BDB1DB6">
        <enum>203.</enum>
        <header>Consultations with foreign governments</header>
        <text display-inline="no-display-inline">As soon as practicable after the President makes a determination under section 201 in response to
			 failures to resolve unresolved abduction cases and the President decides
			 to take action under paragraphs (10) through (13) of section 205(a) (or
			 commensurate action as provided in section 205(b)) with respect to that
			 country, or not later than 90 days after the President designates a
			 country as a country with a pattern of noncooperation pursuant to section
			 202(b)(1)(a), the President shall—</text>
        <paragraph id="HE12F921A394B4980A5AA674E2EF89FA0">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>request consultation with the government of such country regarding the failures giving rise to
			 designation of that country as a Country With a Pattern of Noncooperation
			 regarding the pattern of noncooperation or to action under section 201;
			 and</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H1545031B36A54B1D889EB71023065AF0">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>if agreed to, enter into such consultations with such country, privately or publicly.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </section>
      <section id="H4E6C8EAA5B52459CBA89C38BF83A5762">
        <enum>204.</enum>
        <header>Report to Congress</header>
        <subsection id="H871CCEB258C045C4A7D402EFAF819D4B">
          <enum>(a)</enum>
          <header>In general</header>
          <text>Subject to subsection (b), not later than 90 days after the President makes a determination under
			 section 201 in response to failures to resolve unresolved abduction cases
			 and the President decides to take action under paragraphs (10) through
			 (13) of section 205(a) (or commensurate action as provided in section
			 205(b)) with respect to that country, or not later than 90 days after the
			 President designates a country as a Country With a Pattern of
			 Noncooperation pursuant to section 202(b)(1)(A), the President shall
			 transmit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on the
			 following:</text>
          <paragraph id="HDCCE1914688E4547B22690E5E0FD36BE">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <header>Identification of presidential actions</header>
            <text>An identification of the action or actions described in section 205(a) (or commensurate action as
			 provided in section 205(b)) to be taken with respect to such country.</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H2DE45FECBC0342B5ACF2078F9093BB3C">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <header>Description of violations</header>
            <text>A description of the failure to resolve an unresolved case or the pattern of noncooperation, as
			 applicable, giving rise to the action or actions to be taken by the
			 President.</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H23A064C59E514CA2B8B508BD2D21CAFF">
            <enum>(3)</enum>
            <header>Purpose of presidential actions</header>
            <text>A description of the purpose of the action or actions.</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H0C052E75EA194739B500BD7D0441A0B1">
            <enum>(4)</enum>
            <header>Evaluation</header>
            <subparagraph id="HC81643D234184D45836E42C5EF4BC173">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <header>Description</header>
              <text>An evaluation, in consultation with the Secretary of State, the parties described in section
			 203(b), and other parties the President determines appropriate, of the
			 anticipated impact of the Presidential action upon—</text>
              <clause id="HEAADB5A0A3264D4B93FC7419A975A6FA">
                <enum>(i)</enum>
                <text>pending abduction cases in such country;</text>
              </clause>
              <clause id="HE3B8DA21D4624E21820287843967A641">
                <enum>(ii)</enum>
                <text>the government of such country;</text>
              </clause>
              <clause id="HC83469EC10664E3DB2DA9801B873B3E8">
                <enum>(iii)</enum>
                <text>the population of such country;</text>
              </clause>
              <clause id="H5683333CEA6B42368D8FAEE4D16B9C79">
                <enum>(iv)</enum>
                <text>the United States economy;</text>
              </clause>
              <clause id="H4FE5B9345FD240AEA4FBFB1E4F3DB469">
                <enum>(v)</enum>
                <text>other interested parties; and</text>
              </clause>
              <clause id="H24190E540E9A49D6A12CD221B891B627">
                <enum>(vi)</enum>
                <text>if such country is a Convention country or an MOU country, the reciprocal fulfillment of
			 obligations pursuant to such Convention or applicable MOU, as applicable.</text>
              </clause>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="HF1EFE88B8DDA48EEA379BDFDFD5A423A">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <header>Form</header>
              <text>The evaluation under subparagraph (A) shall be transmitted in unclassified form, but may contain a
			 classified annex if necessary.</text>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H53D58CBC7F604D7F8BDD5099F25CF3CB">
            <enum>(5)</enum>
            <header>Statement of policy options</header>
            <text>A statement that noneconomic policy options designed to resolve the unresolved case or bring about
			 the cessation of the pattern of noncooperation have reasonably been
			 exhausted, including the consultations required in section 203.</text>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="H7D0407F6B71D412FB5E0AFE848DA166B">
          <enum>(b)</enum>
          <header>Delay in transmittal of report</header>
          <text>If, on or before the date that the President is required to submit a report under subsection (a) to
			 the appropriate congressional committees, the President determines and
			 certifies to such committees that a single, additional period of time not
			 to exceed 90 days is necessary pursuant to section 202(c)(2), the
			 President shall not be required to submit the report to such committees
			 until the expiration of such period of time.</text>
        </subsection>
      </section>
      <section id="H6A892B19D7294BEFAD364D1A17D73CCF">
        <enum>205.</enum>
        <header>Presidential actions</header>
        <subsection id="HB2B3D19B8D8743F991DBFF61B95D6EA1">
          <enum>(a)</enum>
          <header>Description of presidential actions</header>
          <text>Except as provided in subsection (c), the Presidential actions referred to in this subsection are
			 the following:</text>
          <paragraph id="HFA55845DAF3B44C1A0D03A500EEED471">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <text>A private demarche.</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H2A99434AD5524CBF843AF83F62340D5A">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <text>An official public demarche.</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H0F8B81433A9846A98F61818171B00BCA">
            <enum>(3)</enum>
            <text>A public condemnation.</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="HAE34A11864DF4207B088B020964B0A17">
            <enum>(4)</enum>
            <text>A public condemnation within one or more multilateral fora.</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H8BCA00867D184CB8ABD11CE63201C54F">
            <enum>(5)</enum>
            <text>The delay or cancellation of one or more scientific exchanges.</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H879D5A224A004A6F9430EBE9117AB0AC">
            <enum>(6)</enum>
            <text>The delay or cancellation of one or more cultural exchanges.</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H54BA47A9BEEC4CD1BC3CF799632529E1">
            <enum>(7)</enum>
            <text>The denial of one or more working, official, or state visits.</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="HB318C675AF154FA1A74E0F5CC5073F92">
            <enum>(8)</enum>
            <text>The delay or cancellation of one or more working, official, or state visits.</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H6A6B4E092E244310A96C9069F08749CB">
            <enum>(9)</enum>
            <text>A formal request to the foreign country concerned to extradite an individual who is engaged in
			 abduction and who has been formally accused of, charged with, or convicted
			 of an extraditable offense.</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="HF3E7E1A633F8440C81E7EE188D452AB4">
            <enum>(10)</enum>
            <text>The withdrawal, limitation, or suspension of United States development assistance in accordance
			 with section 116 of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2151n">
                22 U.S.C. 2151n
              </external-xref>).</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H320DB88DD2DE4768906A23C0CBEC3451">
            <enum>(11)</enum>
            <text>The withdrawal, limitation, or suspension of United States security assistance in accordance with
			 section 502B of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2304">
                22 U.S.C. 2304
              </external-xref>).</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H234F11D196A842E7BB39FC8E6CDEB1F0">
            <enum>(12)</enum>
            <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The withdrawal, limitation, or suspension of assistance to the central government of a country
			 pursuant to chapter 4 of part II of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2346">
                22 U.S.C. 2346 et seq.
              </external-xref>; relating to the Economic Support Fund).</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="HB482965DD19A41A4BA7F3210B287941A">
            <enum>(13)</enum>
            <text>Ordering the heads of the appropriate United States agencies not to issue any (or a specified
			 number of) specific licenses, and not to grant any other specific
			 authority (or a specified number of authorities), to export any goods or
			 technology to such government or to the agency or instrumentality of such
			 government determined by the President to be responsible for such
			 unresolved case or pattern of noncooperation, as applicable, under—</text>
            <subparagraph id="H042CF3666A5D4BEA8C725B14850BCDFF">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>the Export Administration Act of 1979 (as continued in effect under the International Emergency
			 Economic Powers Act);</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H1669116EBB0346428703F1472E81DC2C">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>the Arms Export Control Act;</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="HB0D4079F634B4A9F88FC60E91A833F1A">
              <enum>(C)</enum>
              <text>the Atomic Energy Act of 1954; or</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H3BCA4AFC76C64CE1A8A10BAF6AAC93E5">
              <enum>(D)</enum>
              <text>any other statute that requires the prior review and approval of the United States Government as a
			 condition for the export or re-export of goods or services.</text>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="HE1D1E0E4F9E649209D2327EC8B129F46">
          <enum>(b)</enum>
          <header>Commensurate action</header>
          <text>Except as provided in subsection (c), the President may substitute any other action authorized by
			 law for any action described in subsection (a) if such action is
			 commensurate in effect to the action substituted and if such action would
			 further the purposes of this Act as specified in section 2(c). The
			 President shall seek to take all appropriate and feasible actions
			 authorized by law to resolve the unresolved case or to obtain the
			 cessation of such pattern of noncooperation, as applicable. If
			 commensurate action is taken under this subsection, the President shall
			 transmit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on such
			 action, together with an explanation for taking such action.</text>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="HE47AA7C72E8D4738B31ED7375F35D9C0">
          <enum>(c)</enum>
          <header>Exceptions</header>
          <paragraph id="H23CF8F5224C042EC879F6EFE18A62982">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <header>Humanitarian exception</header>
            <text>Any action taken pursuant to subsection (a) or (b) may not prohibit or restrict the provision of
			 medicine, medical equipment or supplies, food, or other life-saving
			 humanitarian assistance.</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H5B4DD8D84EF348BDAD9CCB2DBA01E8CD">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <header>Defense and national security exception</header>
            <text>The President shall not be required to apply or maintain any action under section 205—</text>
            <subparagraph id="HDF7AB88E0C484BF3851F79D33C6734A3">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>in the case of procurement of defense articles or defense services—</text>
              <clause id="HAC7C97B152D248B5BA352905832E00A8">
                <enum>(i)</enum>
                <text>under existing contracts or subcontracts, including the exercise of options for production
			 quantities, to satisfy requirements essential to the national security of
			 the United States;</text>
              </clause>
              <clause id="H40AB9A047EDD49BC9B44C1202E7EE2BD">
                <enum>(ii)</enum>
                <text>if the President determines in writing and transmits to the appropriate congressional committees a
			 report that the government or the agency or instrumentality of such
			 government to which such action would otherwise be applied is a sole
			 source supplier of such defense articles or services, that such defense
			 articles or services are essential, and that alternative sources are not
			 readily or reasonably available; or</text>
              </clause>
              <clause id="HC4CF7B76357549F38789613174675259">
                <enum>(iii)</enum>
                <text>if the President determines in writing and transmits to the appropriate congressional committees a
			 report that such defense articles or services are essential to the
			 national security of the United States under defense co-production
			 agreements; or</text>
              </clause>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H00D372667D004CE0B52F4FB54EB032CD">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>to products or services provided under contracts entered into before the date on which the
			 President publishes in the Federal Register notice of such action in
			 accordance with section 208.</text>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
      </section>
      <section id="HF02C073DFCE44C1281FFD2FBF8ABCBF4">
        <enum>206.</enum>
        <header>Presidential waiver</header>
        <subsection id="H40FF4A30937B465FB8D93C3E6299287F">
          <enum>(a)</enum>
          <header>In general</header>
          <text>Subject to subsection (b), the President may waive the application of any of the actions described
			 in paragraphs (10) through (13) of section 205(a) (or commensurate action
			 as provided in section 205(b)) with respect to a country, if the President
			 determines and so reports to the appropriate congressional committees
			 that—</text>
          <paragraph id="H8B7427063A774B0EB223FF1E7FCA65C5">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <text>the government of such country has satisfactorily resolved any abduction case giving rise to the
			 application of any of such actions and—</text>
            <subparagraph id="H83B0AFADB7084256B311E126D56FBE54">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>if such country is a Convention country, such country has taken measures to ensure future
			 compliance with the provisions of the Hague Abduction Convention;</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H81A5F8560F64419CABAA506C83DFC16A">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>if such country is an MOU country, such country has taken measures to ensure future compliance with
			 the provisions of the MOU at issue; or</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="HEF171C2715DC4A3D93EF2F71AB4577AC">
              <enum>(C)</enum>
              <text>if such country was a nonparty country at the time the abductions or denials of rights of access
			 resulting in the abduction cases or access cases occurred, such country
			 has become a Convention country or an MOU country;</text>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H8B8FEFF820D84868B32CDC96F8066BD7">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <text>the exercise of such waiver authority would further the purposes of this Act; or</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H6D54A08874DD4C8DB64A8229B8630AD2">
            <enum>(3)</enum>
            <text>the important national interest of the United States requires the exercise of such waiver
			 authority.</text>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="H642A0A7F55544DE28AB76E2247454838">
          <enum>(b)</enum>
          <header>Congressional notification</header>
          <text>Not later than the date of the exercise of a waiver under subsection (a), the President shall
			 notify the appropriate congressional committees of such waiver or the
			 intention to exercise such waiver, together with a detailed justification
			 thereof.</text>
        </subsection>
      </section>
      <section id="H8770BA92A55B419782978AC57883FE86">
        <enum>207.</enum>
        <header>Publication in Federal Register</header>
        <subsection id="H404211E50101463981595ACAADC37234">
          <enum>(a)</enum>
          <header>In general</header>
          <text>Subject to subsection (b), the President shall ensure publication in the Federal Register of the
			 following:</text>
          <paragraph id="H111D4453490E4729B1F5A53276CFF678">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <header>Determinations of governments, agencies, instrumentalities of countries with patterns of
			 noncooperation</header>
            <text>Any designation of a country that the President has designated as a Country With a Pattern of
			 Noncooperation under section 202(b)(1)(A), together with, when applicable
			 and to the extent practicable, the identities of agencies or
			 instrumentalities determined to be responsible for such pattern of
			 noncooperation.</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="HB16508C66B19468AA46100FA57C3A511">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <header>Presidential actions</header>
            <text>A description of any action under paragraphs (10) through (13) of section 205(a) (or commensurate
			 action as provided in section 205(b)) and the effective date of such
			 action.</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="HB279D13E5C074247BEB058E59D3809CC">
            <enum>(3)</enum>
            <header>Delays in transmittal of presidential action reports</header>
            <text>Any delay in transmittal of a report required under section 204.</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="HF777FE1ABF714D52B1BBD372E448F259">
            <enum>(4)</enum>
            <header>Waivers</header>
            <text>Any waiver issued under section 206.</text>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="H44B801CDBE844B389AEF031BE73B9A2C">
          <enum>(b)</enum>
          <header>Limited disclosure of information</header>
          <text>The President may limit publication of information under this section in the same manner and to the
			 same extent as the President may limit the publication of findings and
			 determinations described in section 654(c) of the Foreign Assistance Act
			 of 1961 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2414">
              22 U.S.C. 2414(c)
            </external-xref>), if the President determines that the publication of such information—</text>
          <paragraph id="H603256EBA23F4F7B8A50EEA332C4C41A">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <text>would be harmful to the national security of the United States; or</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H229C02A3EDC54F4BA55748CAE78DA76D">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <text>would not further the purposes of this Act.</text>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
      </section>
      <section id="HBB8FAB486465416EADC771518756F84C">
        <enum>208.</enum>
        <header>Termination of Presidential actions</header>
        <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Any action taken under this Act or any amendment made by this Act with respect to a foreign country
			 shall terminate on the earlier of the following two dates:</text>
        <paragraph id="HFCAE9D0FF5A348218CDA6ED740A3C1DA">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>Not later than two years after the effective date of such action unless expressly reauthorized by
			 law.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HBDDC6132D7D84D15960827D1ED98FD5D">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>The date on which the President transmits to Congress a certification containing a determination of
			 the President that the government of such country has resolved any
			 unresolved abduction case or has taken substantial and verifiable steps to
			 correct the pattern of noncooperation at issue, as applicable, that gave
			 rise to such action.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </section>
    </title>
  </legis-body>
  <legis-body display-enacting-clause="no-display-enacting-clause">
    <section changed="added" committee-id="SSFR00" id="id5bfca26a-56dc-4886-b0cd-3b81f3f73c63" reported-display-style="italic" section-type="section-one">
      <enum>1.</enum>
      <header>Short title and table of contents</header>
      <subsection id="ideffc5380-7f7b-4996-b28e-c8322db27330">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Short title</header>
        <text>This Act may be cited as the <quote>
            <short-title>
              <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2014" proposed="true">Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2014</cato:entity-ref>
            </short-title>
          </quote>.</text>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="id49435146-664a-46a5-a6a2-dd2b1f9d95bd">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Table of contents</header>
        <text>The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text>
        <toc changed="added" committee-id="SSFR00" reported-display-style="italic">
          <toc-entry idref="HE72D462468904AD4BE78F3FD7D9346B5" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title and table of contents.</toc-entry>
          <toc-entry idref="H3072466932D04C1CAF3D3A3C7B047D70" level="section">Sec. 2. Findings; sense of Congress; purposes.</toc-entry>
          <toc-entry idref="H58AF3C0168E2470E96B7FE61C03D361F" level="section">Sec. 3. Definitions.</toc-entry>
          <toc-entry idref="HBD1310EA24124B0698AB80A61A08F0AE" level="title">TITLE I—Department of State actions</toc-entry>
          <toc-entry idref="H20E247A528AF4A2D831953A8D1197CCA" level="section">Sec. 101. Annual report.</toc-entry>
          <toc-entry idref="H9DCE5FF6F5B24E4D8FCF401833728BB3" level="section">Sec. 102. Standards and assistance.</toc-entry>
          <toc-entry idref="H9A0C6542324E44A7AC386B1E78D7EAE2" level="section">Sec. 103. Bilateral procedures, including memoranda of understanding.</toc-entry>
          <toc-entry idref="H566CB1E271094287833A4A18CDFBC174" level="section">Sec. 104. Report to congressional representatives.</toc-entry>
          <toc-entry idref="HDFBCFDBF572F48D48C72C8052182CC54" level="title">TITLE II—Actions by the Secretary of State</toc-entry>
          <toc-entry idref="H5AC567E29CC34585AA9015B8EF9FD1EF" level="section">Sec. 201. Response to international child abductions.</toc-entry>
          <toc-entry idref="HB02DBD03717244459C91DA48C79DEBAE" level="section">Sec. 202. Actions by the Secretary of State in response to patterns of noncompliance in cases of
			 international child abductions.</toc-entry>
          <toc-entry idref="H736055E091D34FE799A9D3087BDB1DB6" level="section">Sec. 203. Consultations with foreign governments.</toc-entry>
          <toc-entry idref="HF02C073DFCE44C1281FFD2FBF8ABCBF4" level="section">Sec. 204. Waiver by the Secretary of State.</toc-entry>
          <toc-entry idref="HBB8FAB486465416EADC771518756F84C" level="section">Sec. 205. Termination of actions by the Secretary of State.</toc-entry>
          <toc-entry idref="id329525DA96B44308BD84ED026FC8A6E3" level="title">TITLE III—Prevention of International Child Abduction</toc-entry>
          <toc-entry idref="id511C2CB3AEFC4A06B8054B2BE921EDC9" level="section">Sec. 301. Preventing children from leaving the United States in violation of a court order.</toc-entry>
          <toc-entry idref="id0025fe9b6bbd41b2a8776152e689b317" level="section">Sec. 302. Authorization for judicial training on international parental child abduction.</toc-entry>
        </toc>
      </subsection>
    </section>
    <section changed="added" committee-id="SSFR00" id="id5fc5da88-c783-4a00-8318-03bcd2ed9fc7" reported-display-style="italic">
      <enum>2.</enum>
      <header>Findings; sense of Congress; purposes</header>
      <subsection id="id807f3471-a67d-4107-b2f9-5399f10a6acb">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Findings</header>
        <text>Congress finds the following:</text>
        <paragraph id="id198502d9-3f53-4b97-8c38-2390b34c4db2">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>Sean Goldman, a United States citizen and resident of New Jersey, was abducted from the United
			 States in 2004 and separated from his father, David Goldman, who spent
			 nearly 6 years battling for the return of his son from Brazil before
			 Sean was finally returned to Mr. Goldman’s custody on December 24, 2009.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="idee03336b-970f-4b56-95e3-9687f9735267">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1900" entity-type="federal-body">Department of State</cato:entity-ref>’s Office of Children’s Issues, which serves as the Central Authority of the
			 United States for the purposes of the 1980 Hague Convention on the Civil
			 Aspects of International Child Abduction (referred to in this Act as the <quote>Hague Abduction Convention</quote>), has received thousands of
			 requests since 2007 for assistance in the return to the United States of
			 children who have been wrongfully abducted by a parent or other legal
			 guardian to
			 another country.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="id9DB4ACB92DA94902BBFB2810ECB899D7">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <text>For a variety of reasons reflecting the significant
			 obstacles to the recovery of abducted children, as well as the legal and
			 factual complexity involving such cases, not all cases are reported to the
			 Central Authority of the United States.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="id83cf0c0d-ca22-4576-9a08-8e382773336a">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
          <text>More than 1,000 outgoing international child abductions are reported every year to the Central
			 Authority of the United States, which depends solely on proactive
			 reporting of abduction cases.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="idc908d1b4-54dc-43a7-ac89-3e441fd9bda1">
          <enum>(5)</enum>
          <text>Only about one-half of the children abducted from the United States to countries with which the
			 United
			 States enjoys reciprocal obligations under the Hague Abduction Convention
			 are returned to the United States.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="id9b137f50-a540-47e1-af5f-ba0db8b8e2d7">
          <enum>(6)</enum>
          <text>The United States and other Convention countries have expressed their desire, through the Hague
			 Abduction
			 Convention, <quote>to protect children internationally from the harmful effects of their wrongful removal or retention
			 and to establish procedures to ensure their prompt return to the State of
			 their habitual residence, as well as to secure protection for rights of
			 access.</quote>
          </text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="id94d9d4c4-45b4-44d4-9428-2b26a9c87193">
          <enum>(7)</enum>
          <text>Compliance by the United States and other Convention countries depends on the actions of their
			 designated
			 central authorities, the performance of their judicial systems as
			 reflected in
			 the legal process and decisions rendered to enforce or effectuate the
			 Hague Abduction Convention, and the ability and willingness of their law
			 enforcement authorities to ensure the swift enforcement of orders rendered
			 pursuant to
			 the Hague Abduction Convention.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="idb1b2e30b-ed02-4c8e-84dc-0b09fdb4e91c">
          <enum>(8)</enum>
          <text>According to data from the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1900" entity-type="federal-body">Department of State</cato:entity-ref>, approximately 40 percent
			 of abduction cases involve children taken from the United
			 States to countries with which the United States does not have reciprocal
			 obligations under the Hague
			 Abduction Convention or other arrangements relating to the
			 resolution of abduction cases.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="id41484d64-a9b6-4f15-9d17-718ec0e7639c">
          <enum>(9)</enum>
          <text>According to the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1900" entity-type="federal-body">Department of State</cato:entity-ref>’s April 2010 Report on Compliance with the Hague Convention on
			 the Civil Aspects of International Child Abduction, <quote>parental child abduction jeopardizes the child and has substantial long-term consequences for both
			 the child and the left-behind parent.</quote>
          </text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="id53533ad8-60f6-46a5-bc72-1b71f2a5995d">
          <enum>(10)</enum>
          <text>Few left-behind parents have
			 the extraordinary financial resources necessary—</text>
          <subparagraph id="id31F2C1963C4D47379EE0063FF171AA5C">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>to pursue individual civil
			 or criminal remedies in both the United States and a foreign country, even
			 if such remedies are available; or</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="id7F3CB8799B094F8BA09C463B88D424E9">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>to engage in repeated foreign travel to attempt to
			 obtain the return of their children through diplomatic or
			 other channels.</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="idd6af422e-8c37-400d-a3df-ca4ee712ad33">
          <enum>(11)</enum>
          <text>Military parents often face additional complications in resolving abduction
			 cases because of the challenges presented by their military obligations.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="idf00140cd75f14569ab25985324a19a48">
          <enum>(12)</enum>
          <text>In addition to using the Hague Abduction Convention to achieve the return of abducted children, the
			 United States has an array of Federal, State, and local law enforcement,
			 criminal justice, and judicial tools at its disposal to prevent
			 international abductions.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="id8de7fbf2c38e4ed98c81a991bee80d43">
          <enum>(13)</enum>
          <text>Federal agencies tasked with preventing international abductions have indicated that the most
			 effective way to stop international child abductions is while they are in
			 progress, rather than after the child has been removed to a foreign
			 destination.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="id6749973f4f854cbfba153c4682715840">
          <enum>(14)</enum>
          <text>Parental awareness of abductions in progress, rapid response by relevant law enforcement, and
			 effective coordination among Federal, State, local, and international
			 stakeholders are critical in preventing such abductions.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="id477445221942486eb6e70d3f6a104316">
          <enum>(15)</enum>
          <text>A more robust application of domestic tools, in cooperation with international law enforcement
			 entities and appropriate application of the Hague Abduction Convention
			 could—</text>
          <subparagraph id="id32BDC4F65D4D4AFCBFAA7D061910FB9C">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>discourage some parents from attempting abductions;</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="id2D7D4546E0664A73B372DBB332AA135C">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>block attempted abductions at ports of exit; and</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="id338FFC804AE6414BA14E6E60DAA10347">
            <enum>(C)</enum>
            <text>help achieve the return of more abducted children.</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="id11f1ef23-c26e-47c7-95f7-0fc5b920b62f">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Sense of Congress</header>
        <text>It is the sense of Congress that the United States should set a strong example for other Convention
			 countries in the timely location and prompt resolution of cases involving
			 children abducted abroad and brought to the
			 United States.</text>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="id55ced1bd-c904-474d-bf3d-22019b2af880">
        <enum>(c)</enum>
        <header>Purposes</header>
        <text>The purposes of this Act are—</text>
        <paragraph id="id50986b94-2f71-4b81-a937-62830b14fd86">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>to protect children whose habitual residence is the United States from wrongful
			 abduction;</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="idAFED81D4729646E9AC53EE926382EC7F">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>to assist left-behind parents in quickly resolving cases and maintaining safe and predictable
			 contact with their
			 child while an abduction case is pending;</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="idb37b46ea-92b7-40a4-bdfe-21907c6f122a">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <text>to protect the custodial rights of parents, including military parents, by providing the parents,
			 the judicial  system, and law enforcement authorities with the
			 information they need to prevent unlawful abduction before it occurs;</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="id720885DD6B3D4F7EAFEA3CCBC6705DA2">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
          <text>to enhance
			 the prompt resolution of abduction and access cases;</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="id7ab3532c-5bef-450f-aed4-fed54f839ae4">
          <enum>(5)</enum>
          <text>to detail an appropriate set of actions to be undertaken by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1900" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref>
			 to address persistent problems in the resolution of abduction cases;</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="id6c19241aa6b544f8bf9b5e4583f819b1">
          <enum>(6)</enum>
          <text>to establish a program to prevent wrongful abductions; and</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="id53FCF4909A184E69AF664DB095F4AF60">
          <enum>(7)</enum>
          <text>to increase interagency coordination in preventing international child abduction by convening a
			 working group composed of presidentially appointed and <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="0010" entity-type="federal-body">Senate</cato:entity-ref> confirmed
			 officials from the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1900" entity-type="federal-body">Department of State</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="7000" entity-type="federal-body">Department of Homeland
			 Security</cato:entity-ref>, and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1500" entity-type="federal-body">Department of Justice</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
    </section>
    <section changed="added" committee-id="SSFR00" id="ide7ac587c-dd8d-48ba-b55c-2f9bd116e580" reported-display-style="italic">
      <enum>3.</enum>
      <header>Definitions</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text>
      <paragraph id="idfa1e1650-ae6b-46a6-a402-53c2d4697388">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <header>Abducted child</header>
        <text>The term <term>abducted child</term> means a child who is the victim of international child abduction.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="idcdb7b576-3a07-41a6-89e7-cc2be117e554">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <header>Abduction</header>
        <text>The term <term>abduction</term> means the alleged wrongful removal of a child from the child’s country of habitual residence, or
			 the wrongful retention of a child outside such country, in
			 violation of a left-behind parent’s custodial rights, including the rights
			 of a military parent.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="idab4bd7a2-ef5a-4d8c-aac8-e08e1565f1b0">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <header>Abduction case</header>
        <text>The term <term>abduction case</term> means a case that—</text>
        <subparagraph id="idDDAAB79FEA3E451FA9E47C5386F1A3B5">
          <enum>(A)</enum>
          <text>has been reported to the Central Authority of the United States by a
			 left-behind parent for the resolution of an abduction; and</text>
        </subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="idDDAE6ABD4A9140C08845E4614B2A377C">
          <enum>(B)</enum>
          <text>meets the criteria for an international child abduction under the Hague Abduction
			 Convention, regardless of whether the country at issue is a Convention
			 country.</text>
        </subparagraph>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id4e6e956d-3795-4ec4-8853-01fa8e8fc758">
        <enum>(4)</enum>
        <header>Access case</header>
        <text>The term <term>access case</term> means a case involving an application filed with the Central Authority of the United States by a
			 parent seeking rights of access.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="idb7f6db0c-bd77-4b2e-a051-15cc80bd7f69">
        <enum>(5)</enum>
        <header>Annual report</header>
        <text>The term <term>Annual Report</term> means the Annual Report on International Child Abduction required under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2014/s:101" proposed="true">section 101</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id40da2a5f-36bc-484a-bd03-f1ecf3948568">
        <enum>(6)</enum>
        <header>Application</header>
        <text>The term <term>application</term> means—</text>
        <subparagraph id="id1631ecbf-52fa-4577-a443-bfd2be56257c">
          <enum>(A)</enum>
          <text>in the case of a Convention country, the application required pursuant to article 8 of the Hague
			 Abduction Convention;</text>
        </subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="id29c97789-9ce9-460c-bfb2-00249f870103">
          <enum>(B)</enum>
          <text>in the case of a bilateral procedures country, the formal document required, pursuant to the
			 provisions of the
			 applicable arrangement, to request the return of an abducted child or to
			 request
			 rights of access, as applicable; and</text>
        </subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="idb3df3aa5-a802-4991-aef5-f067f0c3f203">
          <enum>(C)</enum>
          <text>in the case of a non-Convention country, the formal request by the Central Authority of the United
			 States
			 to the Central Authority of such country requesting the return of an
			 abducted child or for rights of contact with an abducted child.</text>
        </subparagraph>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id235baecd-e80e-42fb-a536-4d4418bb1b6b">
        <enum>(7)</enum>
        <header>Appropriate congressional committees</header>
        <text>The term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">
            <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="SSFR00" entity-type="committee">Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate</cato:entity-ref>
          </committee-name> and the <committee-name committee-id="">
            <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="HFA00" entity-type="committee">Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives</cato:entity-ref>
          </committee-name>.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id38DA05F692B74875AD939501FEC02E06">
        <enum>(8)</enum>
        <header>Bilateral procedures</header>
        <text>The term <term>bilateral procedures</term> means any procedures established by, or pursuant to, a bilateral arrangement, including a
			 Memorandum of Understanding  between the United States
			 and another
			 country, to resolve abduction and access cases,
			 including procedures to address interim contact matters.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id3125244c-2f47-4cd5-a4ef-bd1c853f3a1f">
        <enum>(9)</enum>
        <header>Bilateral procedures country</header>
        <text>The term <term>bilateral procedures country</term> means a country with which the United States has entered into bilateral procedures, including
			 Memoranda of Understanding, with respect to child abductions.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id1c9f7756-fc06-4360-8d16-6e04a9dc8535">
        <enum>(10)</enum>
        <header>Central authority</header>
        <text>The term <term>Central Authority</term> means—</text>
        <subparagraph id="id0b50b0dc-ce84-4399-a202-c640dbacf605">
          <enum>(A)</enum>
          <text>in the case of a Convention country, the meaning given such term in article 6 of the Hague
			 Abduction Convention;</text>
        </subparagraph>
        <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idFC0BC784B7084BC493A5A5238819956A">
          <enum>(B)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of a bilateral procedures country, the official entity designated by the government of
			 the bilateral procedures country within the applicable memorandum of
			 understanding pursuant to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2014/s:103/ss:b/p:1" proposed="true">section 103(b)(1)</cato:entity-ref> to discharge the duties
			 imposed on the entity; and</text>
        </subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="id16bc0e20-20c7-412d-9722-99879b5b8aba">
          <enum>(C)</enum>
          <text>in the case of a non-Convention country, the foreign ministry or other appropriate authority of
			 such country.</text>
        </subparagraph>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="idce878ff5-1eab-4dba-a7bf-2ef529dbb81c">
        <enum>(11)</enum>
        <header>Child</header>
        <text>The term <term>child</term> means an individual who has not attained 16 years of age.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id2fe887a8-6367-48cc-a991-7e907160d40f">
        <enum>(12)</enum>
        <header>Convention country</header>
        <text>The term <term>Convention country</term> means a country for which the Hague Abduction Convention has entered into force with respect to
			 the United States.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id12180b7b-7747-4fa2-a0d4-6ce18a192f1a">
        <enum>(13)</enum>
        <header>Hague abduction convention</header>
        <text>The term <term>Hague Abduction Convention</term> means the Convention on the Civil Aspects of International Child Abduction, done at The Hague
			 October 25, 1980.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="idABBBD4FA1BFF40D58710EC3591B7B145">
        <enum>(14)</enum>
        <header>Interim contact</header>
        <text>The term <term>interim contact</term> means the ability of a left-behind parent to communicate with or visit an abducted child during
			 the pendency of an abduction case.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id21e750c2-ba54-4d8b-8f67-8478f37b7047">
        <enum>(15)</enum>
        <header>Left-behind parent</header>
        <text>The term <term>left-behind parent</term> means an individual or legal custodian who alleges that an abduction has
			 occurred that is in breach of rights of custody attributed to such
			 individual.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id8e72c7a6-9008-4664-9f1a-3b0968a3a13f">
        <enum>(16)</enum>
        <header>Non-convention country</header>
        <text>The term <term>non-Convention country</term> means a country in which the Hague Abduction Convention has not entered into force with respect to
			 the United States.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id201E20C9434248F7871961236D1F2530">
        <enum>(17)</enum>
        <header>Overseas military dependent child</header>
        <text>The term <term>overseas military dependent child</term> means a child whose habitual residence is the United States according to United States law even
			 though the child is residing outside the United States with a military
			 parent.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="idd165aeed-278d-4b73-80d2-a060beb2e520">
        <enum>(18)</enum>
        <header>Overseas military parent</header>
        <text>The term <term>overseas military parent</term> means an individual who—</text>
        <subparagraph id="id48F6E0B0FC3F4863A667247441C7BDFF">
          <enum>(A)</enum>
          <text>has custodial rights with respect to a child; and</text>
        </subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="idAB2814CD8F9D496AB2A6DDF1FEA05441">
          <enum>(B)</enum>
          <text>is serving outside the United
			 States as a member of the United States Armed Forces.</text>
        </subparagraph>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id21659669-9d20-4bbc-ae13-afe44c7b5d79">
        <enum>(19)</enum>
        <header>Pattern of noncompliance</header>
        <subparagraph id="idb786a26b-4cf7-4435-8ba8-769811eda891">
          <enum>(A)</enum>
          <header>In general</header>
          <text>The term <term>pattern of noncompliance</term> means the persistent failure—</text>
          <clause id="id62b8b8bd-2a49-4535-a9ef-c8a8ed35771f">
            <enum>(i)</enum>
            <text>of a Convention country to implement and abide by provisions of the Hague Abduction Convention;</text>
          </clause>
          <clause id="ide708ec11-b096-492f-b731-216ec7037054">
            <enum>(ii)</enum>
            <text>of a non-Convention country to abide by bilateral procedures that have been
			 established between the United States and such country; or</text>
          </clause>
          <clause id="idC60A7C53DAE748298A34475C72BDC8E9">
            <enum>(iii)</enum>
            <text>of a non-Convention country to work with the Central Authority of the United States to resolve
			 abduction cases.</text>
          </clause>
        </subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="id65059A2F4792466B9B4E55CC184F88AA">
          <enum>(B)</enum>
          <header>Persistent failure</header>
          <text>Persistent failure under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2014/s:3/p:19/sp:A" proposed="true">subparagraph (A)</cato:entity-ref> may be evidenced in a given country by the presence of 1
			 or more of the following criteria:</text>
          <clause id="id1e59fd6d-6f2c-452a-996c-118dd38f088e">
            <enum>(i)</enum>
            <text>Thirty percent or more of the total abduction cases in such country are unresolved abduction cases.</text>
          </clause>
          <clause id="id64769c96-12ce-48a4-be5a-8a5f467dff89">
            <enum>(ii)</enum>
            <text>The Central Authority regularly fails to fulfill its responsibilities pursuant to—</text>
            <subclause id="id9DC38459C96C4678B284675A5B2CD66B">
              <enum>(I)</enum>
              <text>the
			 Hague Abduction Convention; or</text>
            </subclause>
            <subclause id="id228F7399A4354745BCCD19A77270456E">
              <enum>(II)</enum>
              <text>any bilateral procedures between the United States and such country.</text>
            </subclause>
          </clause>
          <clause id="id103f9bbd-1591-4f1f-936d-23230f8fb70b">
            <enum>(iii)</enum>
            <text>The judicial or administrative branch, as applicable, of the national government of
			 a Convention country or a bilateral procedures country fails to
			 regularly implement and comply with the provisions of the Hague
			 Abduction Convention or bilateral procedures, as applicable.</text>
          </clause>
          <clause id="id5678719b-2dfb-4578-b7fa-d9a3980bc30c">
            <enum>(iv)</enum>
            <text>Law enforcement authorities regularly fail to enforce return orders or
			 determinations of rights of access rendered by the judicial or
			 administrative authorities of the government of the country in
			 abduction cases.</text>
          </clause>
        </subparagraph>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id5cb51fb3-de7f-4046-9a26-e94524538ff0">
        <enum>(20)</enum>
        <header>Rights of access</header>
        <text>The term <term>rights of access</term> means the establishment of rights of contact between a child and a parent seeking access in
			 Convention countries—</text>
        <subparagraph id="id338956528A7645FFB41EFC1E397C4C1D">
          <enum>(A)</enum>
          <text>by operation of law;</text>
        </subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="id0A6641E7A912444A8114A9A7F4552A96">
          <enum>(B)</enum>
          <text>through a judicial or administrative determination; or</text>
        </subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="idAD654D652E75466DB24D453757EACDAF">
          <enum>(C)</enum>
          <text>through a legally enforceable arrangement between the parties.</text>
        </subparagraph>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id2bd4c0d2-715e-45e7-83bd-3112c02f223d">
        <enum>(21)</enum>
        <header>Rights of custody</header>
        <text>The term <term>rights of custody</term> means rights of care and custody of a child, including the right to determine the place
			 of residence of a child, under the laws of the country in which
			 the child is a habitual resident—</text>
        <subparagraph id="id783577fa-84e4-42d7-ae2a-717ff1423631">
          <enum>(A)</enum>
          <text>attributed to an individual or legal custodian; and</text>
        </subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="ideecc2b2d-0bdd-47e7-addf-5d948a1b088d">
          <enum>(B)</enum>
          <text>arising—</text>
          <clause id="id7E9217DA705141A5A27B98897298637E">
            <enum>(i)</enum>
            <text>by operation of law; or</text>
          </clause>
          <clause id="id49C1551F502C4DD480A4A97A325126B2">
            <enum>(ii)</enum>
            <text>through a judicial or administrative decision; or</text>
          </clause>
          <clause id="id4A46EC648F4344EF9E727E9F1930FE32">
            <enum>(iii)</enum>
            <text>through a legally enforceable arrangement between the parties.</text>
          </clause>
        </subparagraph>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="ida1bb89a1a12e4055a068536495927768">
        <enum>(22)</enum>
        <header>Rights of interim contact</header>
        <text>The term <term>rights of interim contact</term> means the rights of contact between a child and a left-behind parent, which has been provided as a
			 provisional measure while an abduction case is pending, under the laws of
			 the country in which the child is located—</text>
        <subparagraph id="id5E4C599E054E4A3482C57042FFDD4A42">
          <enum>(A)</enum>
          <text>by operation of law; or</text>
        </subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="idF68C6851407F4408827A7B8E34759221">
          <enum>(B)</enum>
          <text>through a judicial or administrative determination; or</text>
        </subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="idC36C9B6596FF4C94956F123DD47D196A">
          <enum>(C)</enum>
          <text>through a legally enforceable arrangement between the parties.</text>
        </subparagraph>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="idad88d42f-8e44-4bbf-a5e6-b45a41e4e61c">
        <enum>(23)</enum>
        <header>Unresolved abduction case</header>
        <subparagraph id="idb5e5e330-bf37-4fe6-a264-a978d092f77a">
          <enum>(A)</enum>
          <header>In general</header>
          <text>Subject to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2014/s:3/p:23/sp:B" proposed="true">subparagraph (B)</cato:entity-ref>, the term <term>unresolved abduction case</term> means an abduction case that remains unresolved for a period that exceeds 12 months after the date
			 on which the completed application for return of the child is submitted
			 for determination to the judicial or administrative authority, as
			 applicable, in the country in which the child is located.</text>
        </subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="id4a5884f4-2aa6-4120-b49d-c58a607e119a">
          <enum>(B)</enum>
          <header>Resolution of case</header>
          <text>An abduction case shall be considered to be resolved if—</text>
          <clause id="id1c75a28e-582a-4b0c-af3d-70bee4dbb02e">
            <enum>(i)</enum>
            <text>the child is returned to the country of habitual residence, pursuant to the Hague Abduction
			 Convention or other appropriate bilateral procedures, if applicable;</text>
          </clause>
          <clause id="idb86f87fd-15a9-47e0-9f66-a2a80c28670d">
            <enum>(ii)</enum>
            <text>the judicial or administrative branch, as applicable, of the government of the country in
			 which the child is located has implemented, and is complying with, the
			 provisions of the Hague Abduction Convention or other bilateral
			 procedures, as applicable;</text>
          </clause>
          <clause id="idCEF4C8F989384970ABB31D3A4D237FF4">
            <enum>(iii)</enum>
            <text>the left-behind parent reaches a voluntary arrangement with the other  parent;</text>
          </clause>
          <clause id="id123473afcdba44c5bac754d6a1016258">
            <enum>(iv)</enum>
            <text>the left-behind parent submits a written withdrawal of the application or the request for
			 assistance to the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1900" entity-type="federal-body">Department of State</cato:entity-ref>;</text>
          </clause>
          <clause id="idf5cf78bf172a41aa832d6d61c6b2b362">
            <enum>(v)</enum>
            <text>the left-behind parent cannot be located for 1 year despite the documented efforts of the
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1900" entity-type="federal-body">Department of State</cato:entity-ref> to locate the parent; or</text>
          </clause>
          <clause id="ide3db0dcf81ba4600a2e2149b5628b550">
            <enum>(vi)</enum>
            <text>the child or left-behind parent is deceased.</text>
          </clause>
        </subparagraph>
      </paragraph>
    </section>
    <title changed="added" committee-id="SSFR00" id="id6b98dbdc-11a5-489f-9a39-1dbe065cf6f6" reported-display-style="italic">
      <enum>I</enum>
      <header>Department of State actions</header>
      <section id="id9caf7c49-d3ee-4cef-8e7a-13da758e031f">
        <enum>101.</enum>
        <header>Annual report</header>
        <subsection id="idcaafd1fc-f4fb-489f-9e99-a7e77b02c640">
          <enum>(a)</enum>
          <header>In general</header>
          <text>Not later than April 30 of each year, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1900" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref> shall submit to the appropriate
			 congressional committees an Annual Report on International Child
			 Abduction. The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall post the Annual Report to the publicly
			 accessible website of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1900" entity-type="federal-body">Department of
			 State</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="id064c4001-8a22-405b-8e42-3e62c1af3501">
          <enum>(b)</enum>
          <header>Contents</header>
          <text>Each Annual Report shall include—</text>
          <paragraph id="iddd0863a5-9d9d-4e17-97a1-1c078a88eec6">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a list of all countries in  which there were 1 or more abduction cases, during the
			 preceding calendar year, relating to a child whose habitual residence is
			 the United States, including a description of whether each such country—</text>
            <subparagraph id="id6E848F27AA6F4C2199F87383710D34A6">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is a
			 Convention
			 country;</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="id14FA8A4DD5614BF38DBF5DCBC3C7A4EB">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is a bilateral procedures country;</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="idD308658BC5424427B7F29CC16B148054">
              <enum>(C)</enum>
              <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has other procedures for resolving such abductions; or</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="idA2631DD7445D48A889ED00D07C58347F">
              <enum>(D)</enum>
              <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">adheres to no protocols with respect to child abduction;</text>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="id4380bc78-29de-4dc0-8ebd-881d0a0b961f">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <text>for each country with respect to which there were 5 or more pending abduction cases, during the
			 preceding
			 year,	relating to a child whose habitual residence is the United States—</text>
            <subparagraph id="id6c85573c-780c-4d21-9422-a2f4d3a55e06">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>the number of such new abduction and access cases reported during the
			 preceding year;</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="id4845ccbe-918e-4d36-a779-034f7f690d72">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>for Convention and bilateral procedures countries—</text>
              <clause id="id373F7924EEBA494C97BF3D8221015A5A">
                <enum>(i)</enum>
                <text>the number of abduction and access cases that the Central Authority of the United States
			 transmitted
			 to the Central Authority of
			 such country; and</text>
              </clause>
              <clause id="idD634900D69164897B1E7BA1BEDDD8D07">
                <enum>(ii)</enum>
                <text>the number of abduction and access cases that were not submitted by the Central Authority to the
			 judicial or administrative authority, as applicable, of such country;</text>
              </clause>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="id6CCF67E331234ED29B312A6D28DEF6DA">
              <enum>(C)</enum>
              <text>the reason for the delay in submission of each case identified in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2014/s:101/ss:b/p:2/sp:B/cl:ii" proposed="true">subparagraph	(B)(ii)</cato:entity-ref> by the
			 Central
			 Authority of such country to the judicial or administrative authority of
			 that country;</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="id7527600a-700b-4718-a651-450f658e7f57">
              <enum>(D)</enum>
              <text>the number of unresolved abduction and access cases, and the length of time each case has been
			 pending;</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="id2a842acc-12a6-416b-a0aa-50fd5137bd26">
              <enum>(E)</enum>
              <text>the number and percentage of unresolved abduction cases in which law
			 enforcement authorities have—</text>
              <clause id="id07D1839754934149857D225ADCDF83AC">
                <enum>(i)</enum>
                <text>not located the abducted child;</text>
              </clause>
              <clause id="id023A460B29DA422AB174CF6AABB65799">
                <enum>(ii)</enum>
                <text>failed to undertake serious efforts to locate the abducted child; and</text>
              </clause>
              <clause id="id8ED00FCAE6934D6CB113BB75E3F1BEF0">
                <enum>(iii)</enum>
                <text>failed to enforce a return
			 order rendered by the judicial or administrative authorities of such
			 country;</text>
              </clause>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="iddc273fd3-9d16-4b65-a469-06fca8ff9c3b">
              <enum>(F)</enum>
              <text>the total number and the percentage of the total number of abduction and access cases,
			 respectively, resolved during the preceding year;</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="ida5cd034f-b3f3-4d04-9436-52acc89e9418">
              <enum>(G)</enum>
              <text>recommendations to improve the resolution of abduction and access cases; and</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="idC6746DD2F8D5450488BD476B80985E02">
              <enum>(H)</enum>
              <text>the average time it takes to locate a child;</text>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="id42db6827-0055-4a8b-9ddf-2a2bbe76242f">
            <enum>(3)</enum>
            <text>the number of abducted children whose habitual residence is in the United States and who were
			 returned to the United States from—</text>
            <subparagraph id="id2EC4011363F748D194102B1E1DE784CA">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>Convention countries;</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="id97079DCE2BE248BCBD5B789F131D52C1">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>bilateral procedures countries;</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="id057DA238A37849128612F5B66E0B9994">
              <enum>(C)</enum>
              <text>countries having other procedures for resolving such abductions; or</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="id012AEF9354A24A15A8A90FD9ED5C932B">
              <enum>(D)</enum>
              <text>countries adhering to no protocols with respect to child abduction;</text>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="id4cfaf9d7-79c6-4ee6-9360-8474a1af7e00">
            <enum>(4)</enum>
            <text>a list of Convention countries and bilateral procedures countries that have failed to
			 comply with any of their
			 obligations under the Hague Abduction Convention or bilateral procedures,
			 as
			 applicable, with respect to the resolution of abduction and access
			 cases;</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="id2bb547fa-73a9-497d-8eb0-8561e47d8f5a">
            <enum>(5)</enum>
            <text>a list of countries demonstrating a pattern of noncompliance and a description of the
			 criteria on
			 which the determination of a pattern of noncompliance for each country is
			 based;</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="id80c3e59a-676c-4ecf-b915-dc21b19e8563">
            <enum>(6)</enum>
            <text>information on efforts by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1900" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref> to encourage non-Convention countries—</text>
            <subparagraph id="idDEAD16C9310B4E4A8204754312B3D012">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>to ratify or accede to the Hague Abduction Convention;</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="id22D676DE816F4F2885A48036F3E22103">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>to enter into or implement other bilateral procedures, including memoranda of understanding, with
			 the United States; and</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="idFED757A8A3F943699FC0ED7BFCC68065">
              <enum>(C)</enum>
              <text>to address pending abduction
			 and access cases;</text>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="id990223eb-5483-48c7-9518-7487fb737568">
            <enum>(7)</enum>
            <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number of cases resolved without abducted children being returned to
			 the United States from Convention countries, bilateral
			 procedures countries, or
			 other non-Convention 
			 countries;</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="id57C986D1D14044268E607D389DD16453">
            <enum>(8)</enum>
            <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a list of countries that became Convention countries with respect to the United States during
			 the preceding year; and</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="idA6DDE9FAFAF64C898B1F30CDA30C96B8">
            <enum>(9)</enum>
            <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">information about efforts to seek resolution of abduction cases of children whose habitual
			 residence is in the United States and whose abduction occurred before the
			 Hague Abduction Convention entered into force with respect
			 to the United States.</text>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="idba2af67d-ebb8-4746-b730-b2d19453a422">
          <enum>(c)</enum>
          <header>Exceptions</header>
          <text>Unless a left-behind parent provides written permission to the Central Authority of the United
			 States to include personally identifiable information about the parent or
			 the child in the Annual Report, the
			 Annual Report may not include any personally identifiable information
			 about any such parent, child, or party to an abduction or access case
			 involving such parent or child.</text>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="id90903fec-cbaa-4e1a-86d4-f6f67a9a79f1">
          <enum>(d)</enum>
          <header>Additional sections</header>
          <text>Each Annual Report shall also include—</text>
          <paragraph id="id1258d14e-3b6d-4dcd-a029-2a681bb34b1e">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <text>information on the number of unresolved abduction cases affecting military parents;</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="id591004D05B9C48D093E305769FA304EC">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <text>a description of the assistance offered to such military parents;</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="id762e40c7-c009-43a4-b266-3da9f9d901cf">
            <enum>(3)</enum>
            <text>information on the use of airlines in abductions, voluntary airline practices to prevent
			 abductions, and recommendations for best airline practices to prevent
			 abductions;</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="id778a008f-0ba5-4bf2-989f-f66e4edbfd9d">
            <enum>(4)</enum>
            <text>information on actions taken by the Central Authority of the United States to train domestic judges
			 in the application of the Hague Abduction Convention; and</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="id2fde81e2-1c0c-4869-b6a3-5aa10c93bde4">
            <enum>(5)</enum>
            <text>information on actions taken by the Central Authority of the United States to train United States
			 Armed Forces legal assistance personnel, military chaplains, and military
			 family support center personnel about—</text>
            <subparagraph id="idCE30DB5C5BC14A968C01F39002CD7F91">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>abductions;</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="idD53041044A164225A96662350C291182">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>the risk of loss of
			 contact with children; and</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="id7575E50060EC46BDA9D9CDBB0C04C46F">
              <enum>(C)</enum>
              <text>the legal means available to resolve such
			 cases.</text>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="id66b133d8-625a-44c7-b5ca-af8e2098d3ab">
          <enum>(e)</enum>
          <header>Repeal of the Hague Abduction Convention Compliance Report</header>
          <text>
            <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Foreign Affairs Reform and Restructuring Act of 1998/s:2803">Section 2803 of the Foreign Affairs Reform and Restructuring Act of 1998</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/11611">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/42/11611">42 U.S.C. 11611</cato:entity-ref>
            </external-xref>)</cato:entity> is repealed.</text>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="id60b9c4bba4ce406ab4764cffb28cf942">
          <enum>(f)</enum>
          <header>Notification to Congress on countries in noncompliance</header>
          <paragraph id="id17B49DEE07B448ADA0AB1F99257E631E">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <header>In general</header>
            <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1900" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref> shall include, in a separate section of the
			 Annual
			 Report, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Secretary’s</cato:entity-ref> determination, pursuant to the provisions under
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2014/s:202/ss:b" proposed="true">section 202(b)</cato:entity-ref>, of whether each country listed in
			 the report has engaged in a pattern of
			 noncompliance in cases of child abduction during the preceding 12 months.</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="idEE578B79E239499986603B909A3ACA4E">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <header>Contents</header>
            <text>The section described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2014/s:101/ss:f/p:1" proposed="true">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref>—</text>
            <subparagraph id="id8193BFEFF13D472C85D1091B1E3A2DA2">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>shall identify any action or actions described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2014/s:202/ss:d" proposed="true">section 202(d)</cato:entity-ref> (or commensurate action as
			 provided in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2014/s:202/ss:e" proposed="true">section 202(e)</cato:entity-ref>) that have been taken by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> with
			 respect to each country;</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="id08F08060407D4927886CD45B1E570C97">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>shall describe the basis for the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Secretary’s</cato:entity-ref> determination of the pattern of noncompliance by each
			 country;</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="id145B2EC12FAC485E9920A5F7A159E86F">
              <enum>(C)</enum>
              <text>shall indicate whether noneconomic policy options designed to resolve the pattern of
			 noncompliance
			 have reasonably been
			 exhausted, including the consultations required under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2014/s:203" proposed="true">section 203</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
      </section>
      <section id="id52938abd-b47f-40b1-84c4-830f86e4a5a7">
        <enum>102.</enum>
        <header>Standards and assistance</header>
        <text display-inline="no-display-inline">The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1900" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref> shall—</text>
        <paragraph id="id9821AA02E4974B56BBBC36E78DF4A7BF">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">ensure that United States diplomatic and consular missions abroad—</text>
          <subparagraph id="idCCBE581B26184429BC7E015BAD700E19">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">maintain a consistent reporting standard with respect to abduction and access cases;</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="idD4AEDA1FDBD14F5A8F29827108E08628">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">designate at least 1 senior official in each such mission, at the discretion of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Chief of Mission" entity-parent-id="1900">Chief of
			 Mission</cato:entity-ref>, to assist left-behind parents from the United
			 States who are visiting such country or otherwise seeking to resolve
			 abduction or access cases; and</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="idB5E6BFE53AE3456194D76EC18F43AC62">
            <enum>(C)</enum>
            <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">monitor developments in abduction and access cases; and</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="id9fd19410b2244a48b90b521e61cde31b">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>develop and implement written strategic plans for engagement with any Convention or non-Convention
			 country in which there are 5 or more cases of international child
			 abduction.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </section>
      <section id="id1f1eac1d-c868-4f20-b687-7ae016e2008e">
        <enum>103.</enum>
        <header>Bilateral procedures, including memoranda of understanding</header>
        <subsection id="id7E3581338A06468FB69FB3492FFA98D8">
          <enum>(a)</enum>
          <header>Development</header>
          <paragraph id="id5C6CD5FF804D4CBF93EF5243EFE621A2">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <header>In general</header>
            <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1900" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref> shall
			 initiate a process to develop and enter into appropriate bilateral
			 procedures, including
			 memoranda of understanding, as appropriate, with non-Convention
			 countries that are unlikely to become Convention countries in the
			 foreseeable
			 future, or with Convention countries that have unresolved abduction cases
			 that occurred before the Hague Abduction Convention entered into force
			 with respect to the United States or that country.</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="idFA3D956CA3404FA0B738F66FB7613B55">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <header>Prioritization</header>
            <text>In carrying out <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2014/s:103/ss:a/p:1" proposed="true">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1900" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref> shall give priority to countries with
			 significant abduction cases and related issues.</text>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="id1BA1C2C4419147FEB6143CE18F038C62">
          <enum>(b)</enum>
          <header>Elements</header>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The bilateral procedures described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2014/s:103/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref> should include provisions relating to—</text>
          <paragraph id="id6ff3f61b-458b-4d81-9d91-3fb5b9694018">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <text>the identification of—</text>
            <subparagraph id="id4AF8AEBDB05E451A9CEC7E3ABF5D156F">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>the Central Authority;</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="id9b53c5978b9a4e78b56e1aa81a15d904">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>the judicial or administrative authority that will promptly adjudicate abduction and access cases;</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="idb359da5d3c254ae7bd2f622bb15ae0b1">
              <enum>(C)</enum>
              <text>the law enforcement agencies; and</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="id85080CA5A90D4CD99AC2C255D717ACBB">
              <enum>(D)</enum>
              <text>the implementation of procedures to ensure the
			 immediate enforcement of an order issued by the authority identified
			 pursuant to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2014/s:103/ss:b/p:1/sp:B" proposed="true">subparagraph (B)</cato:entity-ref> to return an abducted child to a left-behind
			 parent, including by—</text>
              <clause id="idffd3801857fe436489d0d745058d9ae3">
                <enum>(i)</enum>
                <text>conducting an investigation to ascertain the location of the abducted child;</text>
              </clause>
              <clause id="ida1c0eeeab0f64230a04fcca01e14e2a3">
                <enum>(ii)</enum>
                <text>providing protection to the abducted child after such child is located; and</text>
              </clause>
              <clause id="id59e190cb038c4c898a9b9a61cec68690">
                <enum>(iii)</enum>
                <text>retrieving the abducted child and making the appropriate arrangements for such child to be returned
			 to the child’s country of habitual residence;</text>
              </clause>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="id0c8a0f23-3987-4694-b1a3-b2f6f4ea35f3">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <text>the implementation of a protocol to effectuate the return of an abducted child identified in an
			 abduction case not later than 6 weeks after the application with respect
			 to the abduction case has been submitted to the judicial or administrative
			 authority, as applicable, of the country in which the abducted child is
			 located;</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="id64944280-9ba7-4f60-80e6-e23a61466f29">
            <enum>(3)</enum>
            <text>the implementation of a protocol for the establishment and protection of the rights of interim
			 contact during pendency of
			 abduction cases; and</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="ide3835e7a-6bae-4daf-bd21-27daf067dbee">
            <enum>(4)</enum>
            <text>the implementation of a protocol to establish periodic visits between a United States embassy or
			 consular official and an
			 abducted child, in order to allow the official to ascertain the child’s
			 location and
			 welfare.</text>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
      </section>
      <section id="id8c958807-b634-41eb-a650-c7ca6655d661">
        <enum>104.</enum>
        <header>Report to congressional representatives</header>
        <subsection id="id1e68d035-b247-4470-84c6-85144c3c6b2d">
          <enum>(a)</enum>
          <header>Notification</header>
          <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1900" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref> shall submit written notification to the Member of
			 Congress and Senators, or Resident Commissioner or Delegate, as
			 appropriate, representing the legal residence of a left-behind
			 parent if such parent—</text>
          <paragraph id="idC40D7B8AB6B9468A864163AAD086CB95">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <text>reports an abduction to the Central Authority of
			 the United States; and</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="id82618D52641648FF9306A48483553271">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <text>consents to such notification.</text>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="idEB0491EC8CB24DFF90CDFAF6C3682682">
          <enum>(b)</enum>
          <header>Timing</header>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">At the request of any person who is a left-behind parent, including a left-behind parent who
			 previously reported an abduction to the Central Authority of the United
			 States before the date of the enactment of this Act, the notification
			 required under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2014/s:104/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref> shall be
			 provided as soon as is practicable.</text>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </title>
    <title changed="added" committee-id="SSFR00" id="idd68b7c16-8016-4846-b845-1bd24c4c6f4d" reported-display-style="italic">
      <enum>II</enum>
      <header>Actions by the Secretary of State</header>
      <section id="id2edbdec5-58c3-4dda-b171-4b64585d9ee8">
        <enum>201.</enum>
        <header>Response to international child abductions</header>
        <subsection id="idef2f1fd6-ee6c-4be6-a4a6-5db522db0eea">
          <enum>(a)</enum>
          <header>United States policy</header>
          <text>It is the policy of the United States—</text>
          <paragraph id="idb077a3a0-f1af-4c92-b5ed-29d565ee6fdf">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <text>to promote the best interest of children wrongfully abducted from the United States by—</text>
            <subparagraph id="idECC232F1C7534A79B50D74A945010B7A">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>establishing legal
			 rights
			 and procedures for their prompt return; and</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="id9D4D667E4B2F47EE953BFA2F9442C592">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>ensuring the enforcement of reciprocal
			 international obligations under the Hague Abduction Convention or
			 arrangements under bilateral procedures;</text>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="id75F1344BE5644BB0A5DBA26710370E1B">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <text>to promote the timely resolution of abduction cases through 1 or more of the actions described in
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2014/s:202" proposed="true">section 202</cato:entity-ref>; and</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="idc9119eec-19e5-4b0a-87bf-c7a6a275e1c2">
            <enum>(3)</enum>
            <text>to ensure appropriate coordination within the Federal Government and between Federal, State, and
			 local agencies involved in abduction prevention, investigation, and
			 resolution.</text>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="id1456869B520F46E7B338DB2BE07D4267">
          <enum>(b)</enum>
          <header>Actions by the Secretary of State in response to unresolved cases</header>
          <paragraph id="id79bac7b8-264a-471e-932f-fbac302f453d">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <header>Determination of action by the secretary of state</header>
            <text>For each abduction or access case relating to a child whose habitual residence is in the United
			 States that remains pending or is otherwise unresolved on the date that is
			 12 months after the date on which the Central Authority of the United
			 States submits such case to a foreign country,  the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1900" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref>
			 shall determine whether the government of such foreign country has failed
			 to take
			 appropriate steps to resolve the case. If the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1900" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref>
			 determines that such failure occurred, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> should, as
			 expeditiously as
			 practicable—</text>
            <subparagraph id="id399A5F94865844AE81793C40FF1042AE">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>take 1 or more of the actions described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2014/s:202/ss:d" proposed="true">subsections (d)</cato:entity-ref> and <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2014/s:202/ss:e" proposed="true">(e) of section 202</cato:entity-ref>; and</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="id0E54AD5AE87B450FACD1DB30D194C68F">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>direct the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Chief of Mission" entity-parent-id="1900">Chief of Mission</cato:entity-ref> in that foreign country to directly address the resolution of the case
			 with senior officials in the foreign government.</text>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="idb5cc1a22-6135-45a4-bd2f-ef627aae1edc">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <header>Authority for delay of action by the secretary of state</header>
            <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1900" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref> may delay any action described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2014/s:201/ss:b/p:1" proposed="true">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref> if the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> determines
			 that an additional period
			 of time, not to exceed 1 year, will substantially assist in resolving the
			 case.</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="idFEB3D932C124472FA769C2F86DD4B403">
            <enum>(3)</enum>
            <header>Report</header>
            <text>If the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1900" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref> delays  any action pursuant to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2014/s:201/ss:b/p:2" proposed="true">paragraph (2)</cato:entity-ref> or decides not to take an
			 action described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2014/s:202/ss:d" proposed="true">subsection (d)</cato:entity-ref> or <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2014/s:202/ss:e" proposed="true">(e) of section 202</cato:entity-ref> after making the
			 determination described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2014/s:201/ss:b/p:1" proposed="true">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Secretary</cato:entity-ref>,  not later than
			 15 days after such delay or decision, shall provide a report to the
			 appropriate
			 congressional committees that details the reasons for delaying action or
			 not taking action, as appropriate.</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="idFCA5845CAAA643C9ACFB8B90371D9017">
            <enum>(4)</enum>
            <header>Congressional briefings</header>
            <text>At the request of the appropriate congressional committees, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1900" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref> shall provide a
			 detailed briefing, including a written report, if requested, on actions
			 taken to resolve a case or the cause for delay.</text>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="idff98af31-2426-4dc3-9db0-d13f0745c2ce">
          <enum>(c)</enum>
          <header>Implementation</header>
          <paragraph id="id8494ef7b-ee7c-4e2a-921b-4de357277498">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <header>In general</header>
            <text>In carrying out <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2014/s:201/ss:b" proposed="true">subsection (b)</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1900" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref> should—</text>
            <subparagraph id="id88843497-63e8-4f8b-ba08-ff1a9640fece">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>take 1 or more actions that most appropriately respond to the nature and severity of the
			 governmental failure
			 to resolve the unresolved abduction case; and</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="ided0d88ed-f883-477b-8a33-49637a24ffd8">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>seek, to the fullest extent possible—</text>
              <clause id="id0FC7A1746E0C47C88EF8B011EBDF21AE">
                <enum>(i)</enum>
                <text>to initially respond by communicating with the
			 Central Authority of the country; and</text>
              </clause>
              <clause id="id20F329A5CDFD447D970D767442649E45">
                <enum>(ii)</enum>
                <text>if <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2014/s:201/ss:c/p:1/sp:B/cl:i" proposed="true">clause (i)</cato:entity-ref> is unsuccessful, to target subsequent actions—</text>
                <subclause id="id026F3C2FD16A4ACFADFD9C695CA2A24D">
                  <enum>(I)</enum>
                  <text>as narrowly as
			 practicable, with respect to the
			 agencies or instrumentalities of the foreign government that are
			 responsible for such failures; and</text>
                </subclause>
                <subclause id="id3C82950440F94483893EE74E23238099">
                  <enum>(II)</enum>
                  <text>in ways that respect the separation of
			 powers and independence of the judiciary of the country, as applicable.</text>
                </subclause>
              </clause>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="id16af8801-b8dd-4970-9467-a3e49c259a3c">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <header>Guidelines for actions by the secretary of state</header>
            <text>In addition to the guidelines under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2014/s:201/ss:c/p:1" proposed="true">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1900" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref>, in determining whether
			 to take
			 1 or more actions under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2014/s:202/ss:d/p:5..7" proposed="true">paragraphs (5) through (7) of section 202(d)</cato:entity-ref> or
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2014/s:202/ss:e" proposed="true">section 202(e)</cato:entity-ref>, shall seek to
			 minimize any adverse impact on—</text>
            <subparagraph id="id46e28f16-db6e-44bc-9b9f-f2a236dc722a">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>the population of the country whose government is targeted by the action or actions;</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="id372f8553-db93-4139-9eea-9aff25064f86">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>the humanitarian activities of United States and nongovernmental organizations in the
			 country; and</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="id0EF37111EA55407F8D18B353AD678E17">
              <enum>(C)</enum>
              <text>the national security interests of the United States.</text>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
      </section>
      <section id="id2a492550-51c6-4f74-8726-d337873b6dcb">
        <enum>202.</enum>
        <header>Actions by the Secretary of State in response to patterns of noncompliance in cases of
			 international child
			 abductions</header>
        <subsection id="idd1b4ff81-f268-4c3f-8ef1-375b7a449f91">
          <enum>(a)</enum>
          <header>Response to a pattern of noncompliance</header>
          <text>It is the policy of the United States—</text>
          <paragraph id="id56b29df1-6e61-4544-8b86-8d056e72c4f9">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <text>to oppose institutional or other systemic failures of foreign governments to fulfill their
			 obligations
			 pursuant to the Hague Abduction Convention or bilateral procedures, as
			 applicable, to
			 resolve abduction and access cases;</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="id40b8a48c-c72c-4235-a757-f47fc0e9aa76">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <text>to promote reciprocity pursuant to, and in compliance with, the Hague Abduction Convention or
			 bilateral procedures, as appropriate; and</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="id3CD7F03970544DD2AC43E191F65954E6">
            <enum>(3)</enum>
            <text>to directly engage with senior foreign government officials to most effectively address patterns of
			 noncompliance.</text>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="id104f017d-1a53-4e1e-9ce9-0a01b8775339">
          <enum>(b)</enum>
          <header>Determination of countries with patterns of noncompliance in cases of international child abduction</header>
          <paragraph id="id12845286-9bcb-48bb-aa01-9345888fb855">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <header>Annual review</header>
            <text>Not later than April 30 of each year, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1900" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref> shall—</text>
            <subparagraph id="idFB4EB4A7303C44969996F4352CA61EA0">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>review the status of abduction
			 and
			 access cases in each foreign country in order to determine whether the
			 government
			 of such country has engaged in a pattern of noncompliance during the
			 preceding 12 months; and</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="id883ADC02E81E4A71922DF9D7E8DB6915">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>report such determination pursuant to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2014/s:101/ss:f" proposed="true">section 101(f)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="id7b9f55b5-838d-448b-906b-cc20ceb0f6c1">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <header>Determinations of responsible parties</header>
            <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1900" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref> shall seek to determine the
			 agencies or
			 instrumentalities of the government of each country determined to have
			 engaged in a pattern of noncompliance under
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2014/s:202/ss:b/p:1/sp:A" proposed="true">paragraph (1)(A)</cato:entity-ref> that are responsible for such pattern
			 of noncompliance—</text>
            <subparagraph id="idB0788865E9504547BE956789DF2DB3BD">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>to appropriately target
			 actions in response to such noncompliance;  and</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="id934510A9C14B4A0FA69DD6AD6EE46B56">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>to engage with senior foreign government officials to effectively address such noncompliance.</text>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="id19a17853-7197-4689-8c8e-8f359e7850e1">
          <enum>(c)</enum>
          <header>Actions by the Secretary of State with respect to a country with a pattern of noncompliance</header>
          <paragraph id="ide3beafe2-1ef9-405d-95cb-39f5dd5f2edd">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <header>In general</header>
            <text>Not later
			 than 90 days (or 180 days in case of a delay under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2014/s:202/ss:c/p:2" proposed="true">paragraph (2)</cato:entity-ref>) after a
			 country is determined to have been engaged in a pattern
			 of noncompliance under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2014/s:202/ss:b/p:1/sp:A" proposed="true">subsection (b)(1)(A)</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1900" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref> shall—</text>
            <subparagraph id="id032564B31EB945959367B92D83B5F298">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>take
			 1 or more of the actions described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2014/s:202/ss:d" proposed="true">subsection
			 (d)</cato:entity-ref>;</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="idD3CEA005734E455AB86F30D723355AD6">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>direct the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Chief of Mission" entity-parent-id="1900">Chief of Mission</cato:entity-ref> in that country to directly address the systemic problems that led to
			 such determination; and</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="id52FAB0ACD99D48A9BC5ED386C368B6A5">
              <enum>(C)</enum>
              <text>inform senior officials in the foreign government of the potential repercussions related to such
			 designation.</text>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="id62b6ba01-1d09-4b54-a183-bc1c8f6eb840">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <header>Authority for delay of actions by the secretary of state</header>
            <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall not be required to take action under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2014/s:202/ss:c/p:1" proposed="true">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref> until the expiration of a
			 single, additional period of up to 90 days if, on or before the date on
			 which the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1900" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref> is required to take such action, the
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> determines and certifies to the appropriate congressional
			 committees that 
			 such additional period is necessary—</text>
            <subparagraph id="iddc49f313-0f5b-42a0-a772-17eb02492258">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>for a continuation of negotiations that have been commenced with the government of a country
			 described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2014/s:202/ss:c/p:1" proposed="true">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref> in order to bring about a cessation of the
			 pattern of
			 noncompliance by such country;</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="id48612bb4-d470-4183-8f83-1b38f5633134">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>for a review of corrective action taken by a country after the designation of such country as being
			 engaged in a
			 pattern of noncompliance under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2014/s:202/ss:b/p:1/sp:A" proposed="true">subsection (b)(1)(A)</cato:entity-ref>; or</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="id5DA9E7C1B2214A1390A0F0E07738C4FD">
              <enum>(C)</enum>
              <text>in
			 anticipation that corrective action will be taken by such country during
			 such 90-day period.</text>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="id56087a08-e3b9-4b5a-a6da-50416d7c79df">
            <enum>(3)</enum>
            <header>Exception for additional action by the secretary of state</header>
            <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1900" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref> shall not be required to take additional action under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2014/s:202/ss:c/p:1" proposed="true">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref> with
			 respect to a
			 country
			 determined to have been engaged in a persistent pattern of noncompliance
			 if the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Secretary</cato:entity-ref>—</text>
            <subparagraph id="id4E713C5B369E4BF1926C1A280348AAEA">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>has taken action pursuant to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2014/s:202/ss:d/p:5" proposed="true">paragraph (5)</cato:entity-ref>, <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2014/s:202/ss:d/p:6" proposed="true">(6)</cato:entity-ref>, or <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2014/s:202/ss:d/p:7" proposed="true">(7) of subsection (d)</cato:entity-ref> with respect to such
			 country in the
			 preceding year and such action continues to be in effect;</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="id771092F317E34F36B4A488ADBAF16DE0">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>exercises the waiver under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2014/s:204" proposed="true">section 204</cato:entity-ref> and briefs the appropriate congressional committees; or</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="idB135A6DC669F49309D43DFD810E54643">
              <enum>(C)</enum>
              <text>submits a report to the appropriate congressional committees that—</text>
              <clause id="id96057B24D03643D5A2B4EF09623B9010">
                <enum>(i)</enum>
                <text>indicates that such country is subject to multiple,
			 broad-based sanctions; and</text>
              </clause>
              <clause id="id8E7BD7670EDD47DC993D70FC266CC84D">
                <enum>(ii)</enum>
                <text>describes how such sanctions satisfy the requirements under this subsection.</text>
              </clause>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="idbb38afc3e5b542f0bf488f3c510b59d7">
            <enum>(4)</enum>
            <header>Report to congress</header>
            <text>Not later than 90 days after the submission of the Annual Report, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall submit a
			 report to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> on the specific actions taken against countries
			 determined to have been engaged in a
			 pattern of noncompliance under this section.</text>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="id8419e01b2e48485dbd26d5b387f4475d">
          <enum>(d)</enum>
          <header>Description of actions by the Secretary of State in Hague Abduction Convention countries</header>
          <text>Except as provided in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2014/s:202/ss:f" proposed="true">subsection (f)</cato:entity-ref>, the actions by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1900" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref> referred to in this
			 subsection are—</text>
          <paragraph id="idd76a3cd4818c4fa58e76bbdbf195e065">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <text>a demarche;</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="ide000034f8815498a9a55fa53adabb2c6">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <text>an official public statement detailing unresolved cases;</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="idf9ebd5f9e1cc4e4a91aee05c413879e2">
            <enum>(3)</enum>
            <text>a public condemnation;</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="id3e422b07f7364f89afc44b6ce9fd515d">
            <enum>(4)</enum>
            <text>a delay or cancellation of 1 or more bilateral working, official, or state visits;</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="id5438cb666bf94cf5898bea45615b8608">
            <enum>(5)</enum>
            <text>the withdrawal, limitation, or suspension of United States development assistance in accordance
			 with <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Foreign Assistance Act of 1961/s:116">section 116 of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2151n">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/22/2151n">22 U.S.C. 2151n</cato:entity-ref>
              </external-xref>)</cato:entity>;</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="idf0869d9e0e734de6af87e0847ba653d6">
            <enum>(6)</enum>
            <text>the withdrawal, limitation, or suspension of United States security assistance in accordance with
			 <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Foreign Assistance Act of 1961/s:502B">section 502B of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2304">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/22/2304">22 U.S.C. 2304</cato:entity-ref>
              </external-xref>)</cato:entity>;</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="id5567b711e1e543178e42a87d0baaa2e8">
            <enum>(7)</enum>
            <text>the withdrawal, limitation, or suspension of assistance to the central government of a country
			 pursuant to <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Foreign Assistance Act of 1961/pt:II/ch:4">chapter 4 of part II of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961</cato:entity-ref> (<cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/22/2346/etseq">22
			 U.S.C. 2346 et seq.</cato:entity-ref>
              </cato:entity>; relating to the Economic Support Fund); and</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="id8d325058be8649cca85761ec74954ddd">
            <enum>(8)</enum>
            <text>a formal request to the foreign country concerned to extradite an individual who is engaged in
			 abduction and who has been formally accused of, charged with, or convicted
			 of an extraditable offense.</text>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="ide770c12de6824312b5134c73b770fa41">
          <enum>(e)</enum>
          <header>Commensurate action</header>
          <paragraph id="idbc98949c982d4ea0b873c5f5fd1625b1">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <header>In general</header>
            <text>Except as provided in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2014/s:202/ss:f" proposed="true">subsection (f)</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1900" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref> may substitute any other action
			 authorized by law for any action described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2014/s:202/ss:d" proposed="true">subsection (d)</cato:entity-ref> if the
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> determines that such
			 action—</text>
            <subparagraph id="id1a0d4d4876684914b71c9722fde0aece">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>is commensurate in effect to the action substituted; and</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="id377937b25f124e1387f32dc46672a29c">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>would substantially further the purposes of this Act.</text>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="ide855581ff4e546679cc356e9ac196e87">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <header>Notification</header>
            <text>If commensurate action is taken pursuant to this subsection, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall submit a report to
			 the appropriate congressional committees that—</text>
            <subparagraph id="id514CF2870D4A466BB482DF3E7776CA0F">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>describes such action;</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="id8C45379C22E34414BDC647C9B7544F31">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>explains the reasons for taking such action; and</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="id8B13F13E98B440A198B2ED09A640359B">
              <enum>(C)</enum>
              <text>specifically describes the basis for the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Secretary’s</cato:entity-ref> determination under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2014/s:202/ss:e/p:1" proposed="true">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref> that such
			 action—</text>
              <clause id="id1A15C90D93604CA18D23925107CA2143">
                <enum>(i)</enum>
                <text>is commensurate with the action substituted; and</text>
              </clause>
              <clause id="id0C4A97D1DD594788BC1784BA54FB287C">
                <enum>(ii)</enum>
                <text>substantially furthers the purposes of this Act.</text>
              </clause>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="id6991d3b9632543fcbc5871c23edae8ea">
          <enum>(f)</enum>
          <header>Resolution</header>
          <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1900" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref> shall seek to take all appropriate actions authorized by law to
			 resolve the unresolved case or to obtain the cessation of such pattern of
			 noncompliance, as applicable.</text>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="id82769dd7d7e7443abac8e6031daccf15">
          <enum>(g)</enum>
          <header>Humanitarian exception</header>
          <text>Any action taken pursuant to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2014/s:202/ss:d" proposed="true">subsection (d)</cato:entity-ref> or <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2014/s:202/ss:e" proposed="true">(e)</cato:entity-ref> may not prohibit or restrict the provision of
			 medicine, medical equipment or supplies, food, or other life-saving
			 humanitarian assistance.</text>
        </subsection>
      </section>
      <section id="idc4395f02-d80e-4d9f-a074-b38105f75490">
        <enum>203.</enum>
        <header>Consultations with foreign governments</header>
        <text display-inline="no-display-inline">As soon as practicable after the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1900" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref> makes a determination under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2014/s:201" proposed="true">section 201</cato:entity-ref> in
			 response to
			 a failure to resolve unresolved abduction cases or the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> takes an
			 action under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2014/s:202/ss:d" proposed="true">subsection (d)</cato:entity-ref> or <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2014/s:202/ss:e" proposed="true">(e) of section 202</cato:entity-ref>, based on a pattern of
			 noncompliance, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Secretary</cato:entity-ref>
			 shall request consultations with the government of such country regarding
			 the situation giving rise to
			 such determination.</text>
      </section>
      <section id="id3244aa3f-472e-4557-b1eb-c1967687d12c">
        <enum>204.</enum>
        <header>Waiver by the Secretary of State</header>
        <subsection id="id0625cc1d-eac5-4401-aac6-5564691b541d">
          <enum>(a)</enum>
          <header>In general</header>
          <text>Subject to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2014/s:204/ss:b" proposed="true">subsection (b)</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1900" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref> may waive the application of any of the actions
			 described
			 in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2014/s:202/ss:d" proposed="true">subsections (d)</cato:entity-ref> and <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2014/s:202/ss:e" proposed="true">(e) of section	202</cato:entity-ref> with respect to a country if
			 the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Secretary</cato:entity-ref>
			 determines and notifies the appropriate congressional committees
			 that—</text>
          <paragraph id="ide4f09764-aa88-40c5-9406-caef83081716">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <text>the government of such country—</text>
            <subparagraph id="idA4022F6BA672421F9C379C251FB7821C">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>has satisfactorily resolved the abduction cases giving
			 rise to the
			 application of any of such actions; or</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="idD5EC71EA112D4BE18F4520687274EE06">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>has ended such country’s pattern of noncompliance; or</text>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="id5794582b-7be7-4431-906f-ad967dc00145">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <text>the national security interest of the United States requires the exercise of such waiver
			 authority.</text>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="id1f3cb7d3-6067-4285-947a-af7bad807692">
          <enum>(b)</enum>
          <header>Congressional notification</header>
          <text>Not later than the date on which the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1900" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref> exercises the waiver
			 authority under
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2014/s:204/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref>,  the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall—</text>
          <paragraph id="id575F49FF5C7A4CC495F2D6868D794A6A">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <text>notify the appropriate congressional committees of such waiver; and</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="id3F8C994EE38F4C329DB8EF271343EBD7">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <text>provide such committees with a detailed justification
			 for such waiver, including an explanation of the steps the noncompliant
			 government has taken—</text>
            <subparagraph id="idECA41FEA55D44D85BDF37EC7D6C3719D">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>to resolve abductions cases; or</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="id3B28B713A8D74A5CBECCF2277D4A8C71">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>to end its pattern of noncompliance.</text>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="id91f529d7-c916-45e9-b243-bba166e3067b">
          <enum>(c)</enum>
          <header>Publication in Federal Register</header>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2014/s:204/ss:d" proposed="true">subsection (d)</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1900" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of  State</cato:entity-ref> shall ensure that each waiver determination
			 under this section—</text>
          <paragraph id="id0B589B42B3604A59BA88634FC56EBDBC">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is published in the Federal Register; or</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="id7552B8CEF7BB44C88DD17EF5C79F7C49">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is posted on the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1900" entity-type="federal-body">Department of State</cato:entity-ref> website.</text>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection commented="no" id="id76c0634660ab45599b86bbaff54d830f">
          <enum>(d)</enum>
          <header>Limited disclosure of information</header>
          <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1900" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref> may limit the publication of information under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2014/s:204/ss:c" proposed="true">subsection (c)</cato:entity-ref> in the
			 same
			 manner and to the same extent as the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> may limit the publication
			 of findings and determinations described in <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Foreign Assistance Act of 1961/s:654/ss:c">section 654(c) of the Foreign
			 Assistance Act of 1961</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2414">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/22/2414/c">22 U.S.C. 2414(c)</cato:entity-ref>
            </external-xref>)</cato:entity>, if the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> determines
			 that the publication of such information would be harmful to the national
			 security of the United States and would not further the purposes of this
			 Act.</text>
        </subsection>
      </section>
      <section id="id669dd411-b3b7-4595-9ee5-dbdb976d2d3c">
        <enum>205.</enum>
        <header>Termination of actions by the Secretary of State</header>
        <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Any specific action taken under this Act or any amendment made by this Act with respect to a
			 foreign country
			 shall terminate on the date on which the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1900" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref> submits a
			 written certification to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> that the
			 government of such country—</text>
        <paragraph id="id9AAF081EBF694633B7EC781153065006">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has resolved any
			 unresolved abduction case that gave rise to such specific action; or</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="id42DA26B00E484CA4A669F5295A4547D8">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has taken substantial and verifiable steps to
			 correct such country’s persistent pattern of noncompliance that gave rise
			 to such specific action, as applicable.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </section>
    </title>
    <title changed="added" committee-id="SSFR00" id="id329525DA96B44308BD84ED026FC8A6E3" reported-display-style="italic" style="OLC">
      <enum>III</enum>
      <header>Prevention of International Child Abduction</header>
      <section id="id511C2CB3AEFC4A06B8054B2BE921EDC9">
        <enum>301.</enum>
        <header>Preventing children from leaving the United States in violation of a court order</header>
        <subsection id="id02886C4722074765A7E765763CC19E6A">
          <enum>(a)</enum>
          <header>In general</header>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">
            <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Homeland Security Act of 2002/t:IV/st:C">Subtitle C of title IV of the Homeland Security Act of 2002</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/231">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/6/231/etseq">6 U.S.C. 231 et seq.</cato:entity-ref>
            </external-xref>)</cato:entity> is amended by
			 adding at the end the following:</text>
          <quoted-block changed="added" committee-id="SSFR00" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idD84C972E83AD4EBAB765858CCABB2A1B" reported-display-style="italic" style="OLC">
            <section id="id1FEEFE93A29D4ABEAA78862281D20357">
              <enum>433.</enum>
              <header>Prevention of international child abduction</header>
              <subsection id="idA478346C69BF4DBFB345EDC7C7E78096">
                <enum>(a)</enum>
                <header>Program established</header>
                <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7000">Secretary</cato:entity-ref>, through the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="7014" entity-type="federal-body">Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection</cato:entity-ref> (referred to in this
			 section as <quote>
                    <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="7014" entity-type="federal-body">CBP</cato:entity-ref>
                  </quote>), in coordination with the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1900" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref>,
			 the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1500" entity-type="federal-body">Attorney General</cato:entity-ref>, and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1549" entity-type="federal-body">Director of the Federal Bureau of
			 Investigation</cato:entity-ref>, shall establish a program that—</text>
                <paragraph id="idD31A32D128694F259880CDA2FEBEC12E">
                  <enum>(1)</enum>
                  <text>seeks to prevent a child
			 (as
			 defined in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc/18/1204/b/1">
                      <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/18/1204">section 1204(b)(1)</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code</cato:entity-ref>) from
			 departing from the territory of the United States if a parent
			 or legal guardian of such child presents a court order from a court of
			 competent jurisdiction prohibiting the removal of such child from the
			 United States to a CBP Officer in sufficient time to prevent such
			 departure for the
			 duration of such court order; and</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="idDF5D2EC436D9456A8B74EF4CB8326037">
                  <enum>(2)</enum>
                  <text>leverages other existing authorities and processes to address the wrongful removal and return of a
			 child.</text>
                </paragraph>
              </subsection>
              <subsection id="id52A7CF635AE14F538D9505462F73AC5C">
                <enum>(b)</enum>
                <header>Interagency coordination</header>
                <paragraph id="id6359AD04BD9145518E9AEC84C04178D1">
                  <enum>(1)</enum>
                  <header>In general</header>
                  <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1900" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref> shall convene and chair an interagency working group to prevent
			 international parental child abduction. The group shall be composed of
			 presidentially appointed, <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="0010" entity-type="federal-body">Senate</cato:entity-ref> confirmed officials from—</text>
                  <subparagraph id="idD5453E6AF6524A758A5A792722B77AEF">
                    <enum>(A)</enum>
                    <text>the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1900" entity-type="federal-body">Department of State</cato:entity-ref>;</text>
                  </subparagraph>
                  <subparagraph id="id1392AF2533934D9BBDEF9D1C44A6E1CF">
                    <enum>(B)</enum>
                    <text>the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="7000" entity-type="federal-body">Department of Homeland Security</cato:entity-ref>, including <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="7014" entity-type="federal-body">U.S. Customs and Border Protection</cato:entity-ref> and <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="7012" entity-type="federal-body">U.S.
			 Immigration and
			 Customs Enforcement</cato:entity-ref>; and</text>
                  </subparagraph>
                  <subparagraph id="id03B2BD13F6334171B77C046D90D6DD3E">
                    <enum>(C)</enum>
                    <text>the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1500" entity-type="federal-body">Department of Justice</cato:entity-ref>, including the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1549" entity-type="federal-body">Federal Bureau of Investigation</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
                  </subparagraph>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="id0CE3B3217BD34D5A82FEAD3DB8761438">
                  <enum>(2)</enum>
                  <header>Department of defense</header>
                  <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="9700" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of Defense</cato:entity-ref> shall designate an official within the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="9700" entity-type="federal-body">Department of Defense</cato:entity-ref>—</text>
                  <subparagraph id="idFCC88F54356B44A7852346ECC361E4CD">
                    <enum>(A)</enum>
                    <text>to coordinate with the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1900" entity-type="federal-body">Department of State</cato:entity-ref> on international child abduction issues; and</text>
                  </subparagraph>
                  <subparagraph id="idF5619B0E666B4310BE42340421F79B4D">
                    <enum>(B)</enum>
                    <text>to oversee activities designed to prevent or resolve international child abduction cases relating
			 to active duty military service members.</text>
                  </subparagraph>
                </paragraph>
              </subsection>
            </section>
            <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
          </quoted-block>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="id0808651AD5EA4FF996DAEB488FD68A2A">
          <enum>(b)</enum>
          <header>Clerical amendment</header>
          <text>The table of contents of the <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Homeland Security Act of 2002">Homeland Security Act of 2002</cato:entity-ref> (<cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/6/101/note">
                <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/101">
              6 U.S.C. 101
            </external-xref> note</cato:entity-ref>)</cato:entity> is amended by adding
			 after the item relating to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Homeland Security Act of 2002/s:432">section 432</cato:entity-ref> the following:</text>
          <quoted-block changed="added" committee-id="SSFR00" id="id41e56dc4-3163-40e6-81c5-3bc97496b600" reported-display-style="italic" style="OLC">
            <toc changed="added" committee-id="SSFR00" reported-display-style="italic">
              <toc-entry idref="id1FEEFE93A29D4ABEAA78862281D20357" level="section">Sec. 433. Prevention of international child abduction.</toc-entry>
            </toc>
            <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
          </quoted-block>
        </subsection>
      </section>
      <section id="id0025fe9b6bbd41b2a8776152e689b317">
        <enum>302.</enum>
        <header>Authorization for judicial training on international parental child abduction</header>
        <subsection id="id57d32a294f954d5d95b08a3e15027a6d">
          <enum>(a)</enum>
          <header>In general</header>
          <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1900" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref>, subject to the availability of appropriations, shall seek to provide
			 training, directly or through another government agency or nongovernmental
			 organizations, on the
			 effective handling of parental abduction cases to the judicial and
			 administrative authorities in countries—</text>
          <paragraph id="id39d88563eea74ec1ae6c3fb8e8a05d03">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <text>in which a significant number of unresolved abduction cases are pending; or</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="id42e2133751af4f8aa5ac60cad05c084b">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <text>that have been designated as having a pattern of noncompliance under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2014/s:202/ss:b" proposed="true">section 202(b)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="idcd6257fd4a374a4d8b132be0a278b175">
          <enum>(b)</enum>
          <header>Strategy requirement</header>
          <text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> shall submit a
			 strategy to carry out the activities described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2014/s:302/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref> to—</text>
          <paragraph id="ida6acbc4ac892478fb4596c35e5db79ef">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <text>the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">
                <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="SSFR00" entity-type="committee">Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate</cato:entity-ref>
              </committee-name>;</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="idF1D1D3797C7E4881B03A7E993A7362DB">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <text>the <committee-name committee-id="">
                <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="HFA00" entity-type="committee">Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives</cato:entity-ref>
              </committee-name>;</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="id807D02EC3DB64EA391605C79D00C3D4D">
            <enum>(3)</enum>
            <text>the <committee-name committee-id="SSAP00">
                <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="SSAP00" entity-type="committee">Committee on Appropriations of the Senate</cato:entity-ref>
              </committee-name>; and</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="id69501b02390d4e7c8e1de5a5412e46d7">
            <enum>(4)</enum>
            <text>the <committee-name committee-id="">
                <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="HAP00" entity-type="committee">Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives</cato:entity-ref>
              </committee-name>.</text>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="id2318800bca6545abba126abb2b699dc2">
          <enum>(c)</enum>
          <header>Authorization of appropriations</header>
          <paragraph id="id87288337DAFF42A88073AD3831C588C6">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <header>In general</header>
            <text>
              <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="auth-auth-approp">There is  authorized to be appropriated to the <cato:entity-ref entity-id="1900" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref> <cato:funds-and-year amount="1000000" year="2015, 2016">$1,000,000 for each of the
			 fiscal years 2015 and 2016</cato:funds-and-year>
			 <cato:property name="purpose">to carry out <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2014/s:302/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref>
                </cato:property>.</cato:entity>
            </text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="idD6F1EA5E16094040B83B29DA879AD2DC">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <header>Use of funds</header>
            <text>Amounts appropriated for the activities set forth in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2014/s:302/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref> shall be used pursuant to the
			 authorization and requirements under this section.</text>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </title>
  </legis-body>
  <endorsement>
    <action-date>June 26, 2014</action-date>
    <action-desc>Reported with an amendment</action-desc>
  </endorsement>
</bill>
</doc>