<doc>
  <docmeta id="113sres154is">
    <bill congress="113" type="sres" number="154" version="is"/>
    <revision size="7410" annotations="0" status="complete" id="5" commit-time="2013-07-16T16:43:50Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113sres154is/5.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <resolution xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print">
	<metadata>
<dublinCore>
<title>113 SRES 154 IS: Supporting political reform in Iran and for other purposes.</title>
<publisher>U.S. Senate</publisher>
<date>2013-05-23</date>
<format>text/xml</format>
<language>EN</language>
<rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">113th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session display="yes">1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. RES. 154</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20130523">May 23, 2013</action-date>
			<action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="S344">Mr. Hoeven</sponsor> (for himself
			 and <cosponsor name-id="S341">Mr. Blumenthal</cosponsor>) submitted the
			 following resolution; which was referred to the
			 <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign
			 Relations</committee-name>
      </action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">Supporting political reform in Iran and for
		  other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<preamble>
		<whereas>
      <text>Whereas democracy, human rights, and civil liberties are
			 universal values and fundamental principles of the foreign policy of the United
			 States;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas an essential element of democratic self-government
			 is for leaders to be chosen and regularly held accountable through elections
			 that are organized and conducted in a manner that is free, fair, inclusive, and
			 consistent with international standards;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas governments in which power does not derive from
			 free and fair elections lack democratic legitimacy;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the Supreme Leader of Iran is unelected, has the
			 power to veto any decision made by the president or parliament of Iran, and
			 controls the foreign and defense policy of Iran;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the current Supreme Leader of Iran has been in
			 power since 1989 and has never been subject to a popular referendum of any
			 kind;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas elections in Iran are marred by the
			 disqualification of candidates based on their political views, the absence of
			 credible international observers, widespread intimidation and repression of
			 candidates, political parties, and citizens, and systemic electoral fraud and
			 manipulation;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas elections in Iran consistently involve severe
			 restrictions on freedom of expression, assembly, and association, including
			 censorship, surveillance, disruptions in telecommunications, and the absence of
			 a free media;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the current president of Iran came to office
			 through an election on June 12, 2009, that was widely condemned in Iran and
			 throughout the world as neither free nor fair and provoked large-scale peaceful
			 protests throughout Iran;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas authorities in Iran continue to hold several
			 candidates from the 2009 election in indefinite detention;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the Government of the Islamic Republic of Iran
			 banned more than 2,200 candidates from participating in the March 2, 2012,
			 parliamentary elections and refused to allow domestic or international election
			 observers to oversee those elections;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the Government of the Islamic Republic of Iran
			 seeks to prevent the people of Iran from accessing news and information by
			 disrupting access to the Internet, including blocking e-mail and social
			 networking sites, limiting access to foreign news and websites, and developing
			 a national Internet that will facilitate government censorship of news and
			 information, and by jamming international broadcasts such as the Voice of
			 America Persian News Network and Radio Farda, a Persian language broadcast of
			 Radio Free Europe/Radio Liberty;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas authorities in Iran have announced that a
			 presidential election will be held on June 14, 2013; and</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the Government of the Islamic Republic of Iran has
			 banned numerous candidates from participating in the June 14, 2013,
			 presidential election: Now, therefore, be it</text>
		</whereas>
  </preamble>
	<resolution-body>
		<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="S1" section-type="undesignated-section">
      <enum/>
      <text>That the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0010">Senate</cato:entity-ref>—</text>
			<paragraph id="idd1eb0a9cf45b4157b1f6fb6ddb57f747">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text>recalls <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="112 SRES 386">Senate
			 Resolution 386, 112th Congress</cato:entity-ref>, agreed to March 5, 2012, which called for free
			 and fair elections in Iran;</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id601002a976814f59996a3925c94f28f9">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text>reaffirms the
			 commitment of the United States to democracy, human rights, civil liberties,
			 and the rule of law, including the universal rights of freedom of assembly,
			 freedom of speech, freedom of the press, and freedom of association;</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id8ae2adc4b5e74aa484750d40b969954e">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <text>expresses support
			 for freedom, human rights, civil liberties, and rule of law in Iran, and for
			 elections that are free and fair;</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id397ca990573c4a4b94ba146fd0e41707">
        <enum>(4)</enum>
        <text>expresses strong
			 support for the people of Iran in their peaceful calls for a representative and
			 responsive democratic government that respects human rights, civil liberties,
			 and the rule of law;</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id2c79889bdfe64534bdb775c34b639f74">
        <enum>(5)</enum>
        <text>condemns the
			 widespread human rights violations of the Government of the Islamic Republic of
			 Iran;</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id7656a1206e1c47c9b3f6f7712a2f336e">
        <enum>(6)</enum>
        <text>calls on the
			 Government of the Islamic Republic of Iran to respect freedom of expression and
			 association in Iran by—</text>
				<subparagraph id="idba5cdc3db5134b70be1756926ae11c6c">
          <enum>(A)</enum>
          <text>holding elections
			 that are free, fair, and responsive to the people of Iran, including by
			 refraining from disqualifying candidates for political reasons;</text>
				</subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="id2d877a28f364469183ca87a9b11cc8ea">
          <enum>(B)</enum>
          <text>making the
			 highest level of executive power in the Government of the Islamic Republic of
			 Iran accountable to the people of Iran through free and fair elections;</text>
				</subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="idc2c0f1562167446b94f60abc75d99bb2">
          <enum>(C)</enum>
          <text>ending arbitrary
			 detention, torture, and other forms of harassment against media professionals,
			 human rights defenders and activists, and opposition figures, and releasing all
			 individuals detained for exercising universally recognized human rights;</text>
				</subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="idd75823418d0345e08427bde164a758c1">
          <enum>(D)</enum>
          <text>lifting
			 legislative restrictions on freedom of assembly, association, and expression;
			 and</text>
				</subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="id7a230543d1794e0ebda87f7650fe5671">
          <enum>(E)</enum>
          <text>allowing the
			 Internet to remain free and open and allowing domestic and international media
			 to operate freely;</text>
				</subparagraph>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id6c9c64b46d60454ca4197d5528dd1cca">
        <enum>(7)</enum>
        <text>calls on the
			 Government of the Islamic Republic of Iran to allow international election
			 monitors to be present for the June 14, 2013, election;</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="idbbdce0a155904b54a044ac70ddd78f00">
        <enum>(8)</enum>
        <text>notes that the
			 legitimacy of the June 14, 2013, election will be further called into question
			 if—</text>
				<subparagraph id="id75C9F114D32F4DF1A2D556F74B9727D2">
          <enum>(A)</enum>
          <text>candidates are
			 disqualified for political reasons;</text>
				</subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="id24C574027BB04F9EA760EE60C78CE58E">
          <enum>(B)</enum>
          <text>international
			 election monitors are not present; and</text>
				</subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="id8523BC4C4D8F48BEBA6088BF8F7C1FDF">
          <enum>(C)</enum>
          <text>following the
			 election, the highest level of executive power in Iran remains unaccountable to
			 the people of Iran; and</text>
				</subparagraph>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id28ebd45d8341416da9571bbdb6e84ab8">
        <enum>(9)</enum>
        <text>urges the
			 <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1101">President of the United States</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref>, and other world
			 leaders—</text>
				<subparagraph id="ideab18dfddf114b1a88bf64f51379f04e">
          <enum>(A)</enum>
          <text>to express
			 support for the universal rights and freedoms of the people of Iran, including
			 to democratic self-government and fully accountable elected leaders;</text>
				</subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="idad1a8a7f59964d72844d7b128493adfa">
          <enum>(B)</enum>
          <text>to engage with
			 the people of Iran and support their efforts to promote human rights and
			 democratic reform, including supporting civil society organizations that
			 promote democracy and governance;</text>
				</subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="idd488d0ff063e44308769f4c37e22b336">
          <enum>(C)</enum>
          <text>to support
			 policies and programs that preserve free and open access to the Internet in
			 Iran; and</text>
				</subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="id06d319f23ae84d768390ac7f01193cb8">
          <enum>(D)</enum>
          <text>to condemn
			 elections that are not free and fair and that do not meet international
			 standards.</text>
				</subparagraph>
      </paragraph>
    </section>
  </resolution-body>
</resolution>
</doc>