<doc>
  <docmeta id="113sres484ats">
    <bill congress="113" type="sres" number="484" version="ats"/>
    <revision size="5421" annotations="0" status="complete" id="6" commit-time="2014-10-27T20:00:05Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113sres484ats/6.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <resolution xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print">
	<metadata>
<dublinCore>
<dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">113 SRES 484 ATS: Recognizing and honoring the 150th anniversary of the establishment of the Yosemite Grant Act.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">2014-06-25</dc:date>
<dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">113th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session display="yes">2d Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. RES. 484</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20140625">June 25, 2014</action-date>
			<action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="S223">Mrs. Boxer</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="S221">Mrs. Feinstein</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was considered and agreed to</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">Recognizing and honoring the 150th anniversary of the establishment of the Yosemite Grant Act.</official-title>
	</form>
	<preamble>
		<whereas>
      <text>Whereas Yosemite National Park is internationally renowned as one of the most extraordinary
			 examples of natural beauty, splendor, and majesty, and is a showcase of
			 spectacular waterfalls, fantastic geologic history, and abundant wildlife
			 that has provided sanctuary, comfort, and inspiration to humans for
			 thousands of years;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas, on June 30, 1864, President Abraham Lincoln signed the Act entitled 
          <quote>
            An Act authorizing a Grant to the State of California of the <quote>Yo-Semite Valley</quote>
and of the Land embracing the <quote>Mariposa Big Tree
Grove</quote>
            
        </quote>, approved June 30, 1864 (commonly known
as the Yosemite Grant) which—</text>
      <paragraph id="id3E3BE92CB5724DC995D8D0D7F4A12604">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text>for one of the first times in United States history set aside land for enjoyment and protection for
			 future generations; and</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id2FAAF0E1AB5F4CA0AEC867C8B8CA7A59">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text>demonstrated—during some of the bloodiest days of the Civil War—the unique vision of the United
			 States to protect what would become one of the most cherished and
			 iconic national parks;</text>
      </paragraph>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas with President Lincoln’s action, this vision was codified and marked Yosemite Valley and
			 Mariposa Grove as the seed of the conservation movement in what is now
			 known as <quote>America’s Best Idea</quote>;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas June 30, 1864, marks the birth of the national park idea, the concept that has inspired
			 over
			 400 National Park units in the United States and hundreds of national
			 parks worldwide;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the land surrounding Yosemite Valley and Mariposa Grove was designated the 3<superscript>rd</superscript> national park on October 1, 1890, and Yosemite Valley and Mariposa Grove were added to Yosemite
			 National Park in
			 1906;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the land preserved within Yosemite National Park is part of the ancestral homeland of
			 several American Indian tribes and groups;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas Yosemite National Park was dedicated a World Heritage Site in 1984 and has fostered sister
			 park relationships with national parks in foreign countries including—</text>
      <paragraph id="id421A04FC359A4F32B71A6B4CAF23E248">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text>Huangshan National Park and Jiuzhaigou National Park in China; and</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id5BC92D90EF8F43D7AAB22F4D4FEA3CF2">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text>Torres del Paine National Park in Chile;</text>
      </paragraph>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas Yosemite National Park, a leader within the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1443">National Park Service</cato:entity-ref>, is—</text>
      <paragraph id="idF8CD67EEBC9A431A83E1217CF9A2FBE5">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text>the first national park to open a museum;</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="idB585930A00774BD48D7C048DC9E1AEC5">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text>the first national park to hire a female law enforcement ranger;</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="idEF10F86AB4854589973CA8880467340B">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <text>the birthplace of rustic style architecture and of big wall rock climbing;</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id0A11E28907C04E2A8C2AC475730BBC90">
        <enum>(4)</enum>
        <text>the first national park to  formally implement park education and interpretation programs; and</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id0DDDE408B12448CA86610E66D45521BC">
        <enum>(5)</enum>
        <text>the first national park to partner with a nonprofit stewardship organization;</text>
      </paragraph>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas Yosemite National Park receives over 4,000,000 visitors each year from around the world;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas Yosemite National Park is home to a variety of natural resource features, containing—</text>
      <paragraph id="idA59BC27D58CB47B8ABE7CABF1C339307">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text>wilderness areas encompassing 94 percent of the park’s acreage;</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="idD235A2A4B70048A1B7417906509A9512">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text>more than 800 miles of trails including the renowned Pacific Crest Trail and John Muir Trail;</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id093B3BB1208649FB822302192D9F59B8">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <text>2 federally designated wild and scenic rivers, the Tuolumne River and the Merced River;</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="idB0F2D5DDA88C44DFB9DD8B7F0509CE1B">
        <enum>(4)</enum>
        <text>the largest intact subalpine meadow complex in the Sierra Nevada; and</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id3C179FBEF7374C7AA32139F1C15A3820">
        <enum>(5)</enum>
        <text>30 properties and districts listed on the National Register of Historic Places and 5 National
			 Historic Landmarks;</text>
      </paragraph>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas Yosemite National Park continues to embody amazing opportunities for recreation and public
			 enjoyment in one of the most amazing natural physical landscapes in the
			 world; and</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the preservation of Yosemite National Park is a testament to the commitment and
			 determination of many dedicated people and institutions over the past 150
			 years: Now, therefore, be it</text>
    </whereas>
  </preamble>
	<resolution-body>
		<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="S1" section-type="undesignated-section">
      <enum/>
      <text>That the <cato:entity-ref entity-id="0010" entity-type="federal-body">Senate</cato:entity-ref>—</text>
			<paragraph id="id9AA3072135BB493BA28C83A5A0CC07A4">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text>recognizes and honors the 150<superscript>th</superscript> anniversary of the establishment of the Act entitled 
            <quote>An Act authorizing a Grant to the State of California of the <quote>Yo-Semite Valley</quote>
and of the Land embracing the <quote>Mariposa Big Tree
Grove</quote>
          </quote>, approved June 30, 1864 (commonly known
as the Yosemite Grant) (referred to in this resolving clause as the <quote>Yosemite Grant Act</quote>) on June 30, 2014; and</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id7CCC6EB7944E4F1392C68ED07447C89D">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text>encourages the people of the United States to observe and honor the 150<superscript>th</superscript> anniversary of the establishment of the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Yosemite Grant Act">Yosemite Grant Act</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
      </paragraph>
    </section>
  </resolution-body>
</resolution>
</doc>