<doc>
  <docmeta id="113s2100is">
    <bill congress="113" type="s" number="2100" version="is"/>
    <revision size="17850" annotations="0" status="complete" id="5" commit-time="2014-03-19T20:10:19Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113s2100is/5.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" public-private="public">
  <metadata>
<dublinCore>
<dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">113 S2100 IS: Clean Cookstoves and Fuels Support Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">2014-03-10</dc:date>
<dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
    <congress>113th CONGRESS</congress>
    <session>2d Session</session>
    <legis-num>S. 2100</legis-num>
    <current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
    <action>
      <action-date date="20140310">March 10, 2014</action-date>
      <action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="S252">Ms. Collins</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="S253">Mr. Durbin</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name added-display-style="italic" committee-id="SSFR00" deleted-display-style="strikethrough">Committee on Foreign Relations</committee-name>
      </action-desc>
    </action>
    <legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
    <official-title>To promote the use of clean cookstoves and fuels to save
		  lives, improve livelihoods, empower women, and protect the environment by
		  creating a thriving global market for clean and efficient household cooking
		  solutions.</official-title>
  </form>
  <legis-body>
    <section id="S1" section-type="section-one">
      <enum>1.</enum>
      <header>Short
			 title</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as
			 the <quote>
          <short-title>
            <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Clean Cookstoves and Fuels Support Act" proposed="true">Clean Cookstoves and Fuels Support Act</cato:entity-ref>
          </short-title>
        </quote>.</text>
    </section>
    <section id="id60894195AA554F2B834749830AE90AC8">
      <enum>2.</enum>
      <header>Findings</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">
        <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> makes the following
			 findings:</text>
      <paragraph id="id62d2596d84424737a5a2ec04a84a99ec">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text>Nearly half the world’s population cooks their food over open fires or inefficient, polluting, and
			 unsafe cookstoves using wood, agricultural waste, dung, coal, or other
			 solid fuels. Smoke from the use of these traditional cookstoves and open
			 fires is associated with a number of chronic and acute diseases and
			 injuries, including respiratory illnesses such as pneumonia, heart
			 disease, and cancer, with women and young children affected
			 disproportionately.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="idcb2406bac67c44f88524d1b09d7df3a2">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text>The Global Burden of Disease Study 2010 doubled the mortality estimates for exposure to smoke from
			 cookstoves, referred to as <term>household air pollution</term>, from 2,000,000 to 4,000,000 deaths annually in the developing world, which the Study indicates 
			 is
			 more than the deaths from malaria, tuberculosis, and  HIV/AIDS combined.
			 The Study attributes 3,500,000 deaths to cookstoves smoke exposures
			 indoors and 500,000 deaths to the contribution of cookstoves to outdoor
			 air pollution.  Millions more are sickened from the toxic smoke and
			 thousands suffer burns annually from open fires or unsafe cookstoves and
			 fuels.  The Study ranks household air pollution  as the fourth worst
			 overall health risk factor in the world and as the second worst health
			 risk factor in the world for women and girls.	Cookstove smoke exposures
			 are particularly prominent in developing regions of Asia and Africa.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id7e9ae64a28ed49eeac31f06d9d80cd5d">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <text>The amount of biomass cooking fuel required each year can reach up to two tons per family. Where
			 demand for local biomass outstrips the natural regrowth of resources,
			 local environmental degradation and loss of biodiversity often result.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id77982442552f4eb799c50c87c5da35f3">
        <enum>(4)</enum>
        <text>Tremendous amounts of time, a burden shouldered disproportionately by women and children, is spent
			 collecting and managing biomass cooking fuel resources. As nearby fuel
			 supplies dwindle, women are forced to go farther to find fuel to cook
			 their families’ meals. In some regions, women and girls risk rape and
			 gender-based violence during the up to 20 hours per week they spend away
			 from their communities gathering firewood.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id4f6bd815162941e2b19471dd1131e8e3">
        <enum>(5)</enum>
        <text>Recent studies show that black carbon created from biomass cookstoves significantly contributes to
			 regional air pollution and climate change. Black carbon emissions from
			 residential cookstoves in developing countries account for an estimated 21
			 percent of total global inventory, and mitigation in this sector
			 represents a large potential public health benefit.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id6b6d654898e64f8fabc43520edc5644f">
        <enum>(6)</enum>
        <text>The Global Alliance for Clean Cookstoves is an innovative public-private partnership  hosted by the
			 United Nations Foundation that was created to enable the adoption of clean
			 and efficient stoves in 100,000,000 homes by 2020. The Alliance works with
			 public, private, and non-profit partners to overcome market barriers that
			 currently impede the production, deployment, and use of clean cookstoves
			 and fuels in the developing world.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="ide453f83e07d7417ab9ebc8de26ecdc2d">
        <enum>(7)</enum>
        <text>The United States Government has committed a total of up to $125,000,000 to the sector, including
			 approximately $60,000,000 in research, $15,000,000 in field implementation
			 activities, and up to $50,000,000 in financing, through the first five
			 years of the Alliance to help spur the adoption of clean cookstoves and
			 fuels in 100,000,000 households by 2020 as follows:</text>
        <subparagraph id="id1c685369dcfb43c6909c9904b90daeeb">
          <enum>(A)</enum>
          <text>The Department of State has committed $1,020,000 through fiscal year 2015 and the United States
			 Agency for International Development has committed $18,400,000 through
			 fiscal year 2015.</text>
        </subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="id34999bb63f1540a190d3f312c9101997">
          <enum>(B)</enum>
          <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="8900">Department of Energy</cato:entity-ref>  has committed $13,200,000 through fiscal year 2016.</text>
        </subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="idd2b3ba4a7bda4ab498aeb7fa4224e8b8">
          <enum>(C)</enum>
          <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Department of Health and Human Services</cato:entity-ref> has committed $31,690,000 through the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7529">National
			 Institutes of Health</cato:entity-ref>  through fiscal year 2016 and $3,900,000 through the
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7523">Centers for Disease Control and Prevention</cato:entity-ref> through fiscal year 2015.</text>
        </subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="idd2f1f549336744559ab4fe466d381be9">
          <enum>(D)</enum>
          <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="6800">Environmental Protection Agency</cato:entity-ref> has committed $9,670,000 through fiscal year 2015.</text>
        </subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="id974fbfa8e06d42bca8bd7a1d47395af2">
          <enum>(E)</enum>
          <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="4900">National Science Foundation</cato:entity-ref> has committed $1,270,000 through fiscal year 2015.</text>
        </subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="id1833ed3e57b148ffaec4871c2b0c7c1c">
          <enum>(F)</enum>
          <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7100">Overseas Private Investment Corporation</cato:entity-ref>  has committed up to $50,000,000 through fiscal year
			 2016 in debt financing or insurance that meet their credit and lending
			 standards to support projects that provide clean, consistent, and
			 affordable access to energy and energy savings through the manufacture,
			 sale, and purchase of cookstoves.</text>
        </subparagraph>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id148a3024f265431381feea59b73c005e">
        <enum>(8)</enum>
        <text>This commitment targets a wide range of work, including expanded research on cookstoves
			 performance, marketing, and adoption; expanded research on the health,
			 climate and air quality benefits of clean cookstoves; and expanded field
			 efforts in Kenya, Haiti, Bangladesh, and Nigeria.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="idd496c4f94b864831b8ed797b573b727d">
        <enum>(9)</enum>
        <text>Additional Federal support is being provided to the Alliance, including by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1200">Department of
			 Agriculture</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1330">National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration</cato:entity-ref>, and the
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1145">Peace Corps</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="idb0b464cbb7f14a5e94ce4cf52ab1dd12">
        <enum>(10)</enum>
        <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="9543">Millennium Challenge Corporation</cato:entity-ref>, in 2010, prior to the launch of the Alliance, committed the
			 largest stoves-related investment to date in Mongolia.  The commitment of
			 $45,300,000 focused on economic growth from energy efficiency and improved
			 air quality.</text>
      </paragraph>
    </section>
    <section id="ID6bb92da01f0c4cb699928a3cf8b7545a">
      <enum>3.</enum>
      <header>Advancement of
			 Global Alliance for Clean Cookstoves goal</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref>, in consultation with the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="6800">Administrator of the Environmental Protection
			 Agency</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="8900">Secretary of Energy</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary of Health and Human
			 Services</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7200">Administrator of the United States Agency for International
			 Development</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="4900">Director of the National Science Foundatio</cato:entity-ref>n, the
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7100">President of the Overseas Private Investment Corporation</cato:entity-ref>, and the heads of
			 other relevant Federal agencies, and in coordination with relevant
			 international nongovernmental organizations and private and governmental
			 entities, shall work to advance the goals and work of the Global Alliance
			 for Clean Cookstoves, including through—</text>
      <paragraph id="idffe78de19994446f813f63f0c2336fbd">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text>applied research and development to improve design, lower costs, promote technology adoption,
			 conduct health research and evaluation, and develop global industry
			 standards and testing protocols for cookstoves and fuels in order to help
			 ensure minimum standards for efficiency and cleanliness are met;</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id265e0b87e0bb40b6b7b44d6bf254c7e3">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text>diplomatic engagement to encourage a commercial market for clean cookstoves and fuels, reduce trade
			 barriers, promote consumer awareness, improve access to large-scale carbon
			 financing, and foster women-owned businesses along the entire business
			 value chain;</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id7323f7fdae90445f9e7982ab8f95b75c">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <text>international development projects to help build commercial businesses to manufacture, market,
			 distribute, sell, and service clean cookstoves and fuels;</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id33880f7fe60d405cbbf6041644ca0234">
        <enum>(4)</enum>
        <text>development efforts related to refugee camps, disaster relief, and long-term humanitarian and
			 empowerment programs aimed at assisting women and girls; and</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="iddb24aa123fe84a2ebb31500c1272c610">
        <enum>(5)</enum>
        <text>financing or insurance to support projects that provide access to clean, affordable energy and
			 energy savings through the manufacture, sale, and purchase of clean
			 cookstoves and fuels.</text>
      </paragraph>
    </section>
    <section commented="no" id="IDbd41896ae84b4ac3a1b488fad5e89c34">
      <enum>4.</enum>
      <header>Authorizations
			 of appropriations</header>
      <subsection commented="no" id="id7e4157a1bfb449f489157e02722a527d">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Department of State and United States Agency for International Development</header>
        <text>
          <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="auth-auth-approp">There are authorized to be appropriated <cato:property name="funds-source">out of funds available to the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Department of State</cato:entity-ref> and the
			 <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7200">United States Agency for International Development</cato:entity-ref>
            </cato:property> <cato:funds-and-year amount="indefinite" year="2014, 2015">such sums as may be
			 necessary  for fiscal years 2014 through 2015</cato:funds-and-year> <cato:property name="purpose">to work with the Global
			 Alliance for Clean Cookstoves and foreign governments</cato:property>
          </cato:entity>, including—</text>
        <paragraph commented="no" id="id32b78a1835184071a885a2edf6880e18">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>to engage in a wide range of diplomatic activities, including with countries across the globe and
			 with United States embassies abroad, to support Alliance activities and
			 the clean cookstoves and fuels sector, and to continue the clean cooking
			 initiative under the
			 Climate and Clean Air Coalition to reduce emissions of short-lived climate
			 pollutants;</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph commented="no" id="iddb878a35f88f4ad5a5c7deb3998b6558">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>to advance programs that support the adoption of affordable cookstoves that require less fuel to
			 meet
			 household energy needs and release fewer pollutants, as a means to improve
			 health, reduce environmental degradation, mitigate climate change, foster
			 economic growth, and empower women; and</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph commented="no" id="id9ac183fe82254991991d2bfc8f2d2c19">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <text>to carry out other activities under this Act.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection commented="no" id="id8e44059f0f2a421b8574b340e84be05f">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Department of Energy</header>
        <text>
          <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="auth-auth-approp">There are authorized to be appropriated to the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="8900">Secretary of Energy</cato:entity-ref> <cato:property name="funds-source">out of funds available to the
			 <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="8900">Department of Energy</cato:entity-ref>
            </cato:property> <cato:funds-and-year amount="indefinite" year="2014, 2015, 2016">such sums as may be necessary for fiscal years 2014
			 through 2016</cato:funds-and-year> <cato:property name="purpose">to work with the Global Alliance for Clean Cookstoves</cato:property>
          </cato:entity>,
			 including—</text>
        <paragraph commented="no" id="id60c1e0480b6240898c8b49ca0d4fd04a">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>to conduct research to spur development of low-cost, low-emission, high-efficiency cookstoves
			 through
			 research in areas such as combustion, heat transfer, and materials
			 development;</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph commented="no" id="idFB58A9EC735F4E25B0CFA12FCC9CE1BB">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>to conduct research to spur development of low-emission, high-efficiency biomass fuels;</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph commented="no" id="id129e8a62a9e8476fa1670dfeb456ec5b">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <text>to support innovative small businesses in the United States that are developing advanced cookstoves
			 and improved cookstove assessment devices; and</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph commented="no" id="idb1891d38d32740cf9ee926625d94b446">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
          <text>to carry out other activities under this Act.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection commented="no" id="id9731fc24eff744b18d8f74e56d6fce06">
        <enum>(c)</enum>
        <header>National Institutes of Health</header>
        <text>
          <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="auth-auth-approp">There are authorized to be appropriated to the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary of Health and Human Services</cato:entity-ref> <cato:property name="funds-source">out of funds
			 available to the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7529">National Institutes of Health</cato:entity-ref>
            </cato:property> <cato:funds-and-year amount="indefinite" year="2014, 2015, 216">such sums as may be
			 necessary for fiscal years 2014 through 2016</cato:funds-and-year> for the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7529">National Institutes
			 of Health</cato:entity-ref> <cato:property name="purpose">to work with the Global Alliance for Clean Cookstoves</cato:property>
          </cato:entity>,
			 including—</text>
        <paragraph commented="no" id="id133e374efd544ce7b46a976532d69549">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>to support health research and training to improve the health and lives of those at risk from
			 household burning of solid fuels, including—</text>
          <subparagraph commented="no" id="idc049c96664c24db1827cb13715ea5df8">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>dedicated resources for research on household air pollution to ensure adoption of life-saving
			 interventions and policy formulation; and</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph commented="no" id="idd8b8416bcf324834b6fe3f1666c3104d">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>regional network research and training hubs in global environmental health and occupational health
			 with a household air pollution focus;
			 and</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph commented="no" id="id7af30677258940e4bcd5dfd63d05ea98">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>to carry out other activities under this Act.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection commented="no" id="idf86bf336c0954df0bec22bdff1711019">
        <enum>(d)</enum>
        <header>Centers for Disease Control and Prevention</header>
        <text>
          <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="auth-auth-approp">There are authorized to be appropriated to the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary of Health and Human Services</cato:entity-ref> <cato:property name="funds-source">out of  funds
			 available to the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7523">Centers for Disease Control and Prevention</cato:entity-ref>
            </cato:property> <cato:funds-and-year amount="indefinite" year="2014, 2015">such sums as
			 may be necessary  for fiscal years 2014 through 2015</cato:funds-and-year> <cato:property name="purpose">for the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7523">Centers for
			 Disease Control and Prevention</cato:entity-ref> to work with the Global Alliance for Clean
			 Cookstoves</cato:property>
          </cato:entity>, including—</text>
        <paragraph commented="no" id="id15659b2d95c347f89ce43a0d286f4850">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>to evaluate cookstove and fuel programs to better understand their public health benefits and key
			 determinants of adoption;</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph commented="no" id="id6b004f2f7fb14e86baf44da0d11d8533">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>to promote a better understanding of the relationship between human exposures and health outcomes
			 from the use of traditional cookstoves and open fires; and</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph commented="no" id="id554a908da26045ad8c80b45a12035733">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <text>to carry out other activities under this Act.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection commented="no" id="idd5e8f026d8084fb88e24382607a2ed87">
        <enum>(e)</enum>
        <header>Environmental Protection Agency</header>
        <text>
          <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="auth-auth-approp">There are authorized to be appropriated to the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="6800">Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency</cato:entity-ref>
			 <cato:property name="funds-source">out of  funds available to the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="6800">Environmental Protection Agency</cato:entity-ref>
            </cato:property> <cato:funds-and-year amount="indefinite" year="2014, 2015">such sums
			 as may be necessary  for fiscal years 2014 through 2015</cato:funds-and-year> for the
			 <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="6800">Environmental Protection Agency</cato:entity-ref> <cato:property name="purpose">to work with the Global Alliance for Clean
			 Cookstoves</cato:property>
          </cato:entity>,
			 including—</text>
        <paragraph commented="no" id="id60b7a97c392b4906be757340a9ec4879">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>to conduct cookstove and fuel testing and evaluation in the lab and field, including evaluation of
			 fuel efficiency and air pollutant emissions that affect human health and
			 the environment, and to develop international standards regarding fuel
			 use, emissions, and safety of cookstoves and fuels;</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph commented="no" id="ide2bb55d227534e33ac5ee39f700b79a7">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>to conduct climate, health, and air quality research, including with United States institutions of
			 higher education, on the air quality and climatic benefits of
			 interventions for cookstoves and residential burning, and to continue the
			 cookstoves initiative under the Climate and Clean Air Coalition to reduce
			 emissions of short-lived climate pollutants; and</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph commented="no" id="id583c98995d654d969ad11caa38ce8eed">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <text>to carry out other activities under this Act.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection commented="no" id="id80a86560ec8b452ca43176c387624eaf">
        <enum>(f)</enum>
        <header>National Science Foundation</header>
        <text>
          <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="auth-auth-approp">There are authorized to be appropriated to the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="4900">Director of the National Science Foundation</cato:entity-ref> <cato:property name="funds-source">out of
			 funds available to the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="4900">National Science Foundation</cato:entity-ref>
            </cato:property>
            <cato:funds-and-year amount="indefinite" year="2014, 2015"> such sums as may be
			 necessary for fiscal years 2014 through 2015</cato:funds-and-year> for the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="4900">National Science
			 Foundation</cato:entity-ref> <cato:property name="purpose">to work with the Global Alliance for Clean Cookstoves</cato:property>
          </cato:entity>,
			 including—</text>
        <paragraph commented="no" id="idec8046a1a3684de1a01f62f93fb47d1c">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>to support research related to the climate, air quality, and health benefits of the adoption of
			 clean cookstoves and fuels; and</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph commented="no" id="idce86e0bb03dc446f8c4add460757e390">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>to carry out other activities under this Act.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection commented="no" id="id15689b0c0006426f8a50e3737d424445">
        <enum>(g)</enum>
        <header>Department of Agriculture</header>
        <text>
          <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="auth-auth-approp">There are authorized to be appropriated to the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1200">Secretary of the Department of Agriculture</cato:entity-ref> <cato:property name="funds-source">out of
			 funds available to the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1200">Department of Agriculture</cato:entity-ref>
            </cato:property> <cato:funds-and-year amount="indefinite" year="2014, 2015">such sums as may be
			 necessary  for fiscal years 2014 through 2015</cato:funds-and-year> for the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1200">Department of
			 Agriculture</cato:entity-ref> <cato:property name="purpose">to work with the Global Alliance for Clean Cookstoves</cato:property>
          </cato:entity>,
			 including—</text>
        <paragraph commented="no" id="idc4193b81d09f4b0aadcd74fea23796ba">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>to provide technical expertise on policy questions facing the cookstoves sector and to help align
			 the Alliance with ongoing international efforts that promote the
			 sustainable production and use of clean burning biomass cooking fuels, to
			 optimize natural resource conservation and agricultural productivity; and</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph commented="no" id="id45e4b71dc1804d9bbf1284af3269edb7">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>to carry out other activities under this Act.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection commented="no" id="id41d89ba91b724a4baa269ba2f7cd1a27">
        <enum>(h)</enum>
        <header>National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration</header>
        <text>
          <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="auth-auth-approp">There are authorized to be appropriated to the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1330">Administrator of the National Oceanic and
			 Atmospheric Administration</cato:entity-ref> (NOAA)  <cato:property name="funds-source">out of  funds available to <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1330">NOAA</cato:entity-ref>
            </cato:property> <cato:funds-and-year amount="indefinite" year="2014, 2015">such
			 sums as may be necessary for fiscal years 2014 through 2015</cato:funds-and-year> for <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1330">NOAA</cato:entity-ref> <cato:property name="purpose">to
			 work with the Global Alliance for Clean Cookstoves</cato:property>
          </cato:entity>, including—</text>
        <paragraph commented="no" id="idcc87088d30a94903ab8ff11f8dabb637">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>to partner with scientists in other countries to monitor global black carbon emissions and assess
			 climate impacts and benefits of switching to clean cookstoves; and</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph commented="no" id="id77b07250cf4f4a31865db08a4944bc8e">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>to carry out other activities under this Act.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection commented="no" id="id65e6f403f41d49d282a1f7b45ab1d697">
        <enum>(i)</enum>
        <header>Peace Corps</header>
        <text>
          <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="auth-auth-approp">There are authorized to be appropriated to the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1145">Director of the Peace Corps</cato:entity-ref> <cato:property name="funds-source">out of funds available
			 to the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1145">Peace Corps</cato:entity-ref>
            </cato:property> <cato:funds-and-year amount="indefinite" year="2014, 2015">such sums as may be necessary for fiscal years 2014
			 through 2015</cato:funds-and-year> for the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1145">Peace Corps</cato:entity-ref> <cato:property name="purpose">to work with the Global Alliance for
			 Clean Cookstoves</cato:property>
          </cato:entity>, including—</text>
        <paragraph commented="no" id="id675d5bb1c4da4ecdae8937acf1cea9c9">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>to train community members to select, construct, and maintain clean cookstoves and fuels, provide
			 ongoing
			 support to sustain their use, and help families, schools, and others
			 access grants to lower the cost; and</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph commented="no" id="idd5bee12747494ce9b017b127d76dadde">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>to carry out other activities under this Act.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="id1e00fcf7389c4696b4fa75a659d22d2c">
        <enum>(j)</enum>
        <header>Future years funding</header>
        <text>It is the sense of <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> that the departments and agencies referenced in this section should be
			 provided sufficient funding in future fiscal years to fund commitments
			 related to work with the Global Alliance for Clean Cookstoves.</text>
      </subsection>
    </section>
  </legis-body>
</bill>
</doc>