<doc>
  <docmeta id="113sres97is">
    <bill congress="113" type="sres" number="97" version="is"/>
    <revision size="2738" annotations="0" id="6" commit-time="2013-04-30T04:16:40+00:00" committer="favila" doc="113sres97is/6.xml" status="complete">
      <description/>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <resolution xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>113 SRES 97 IS: Expressing the sense of the Senate that the Food and Drug Administration should encourage the use of abuse-deterrent formulations of drugs.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2013-04-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">113th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session display="yes">1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. RES. 97</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20130415">April 15, 2013</action-date>
			<action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="S301">Mr. Coburn</sponsor> (for himself,
			 <cosponsor name-id="S270">Mr. Schumer</cosponsor>, and
			 <cosponsor name-id="S174">Mr. McConnell</cosponsor>) submitted the following
			 resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSHR00">Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and
			 Pensions</committee-name>
      </action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">Expressing the sense of the Senate that the
		  Food and Drug Administration should encourage the use of abuse-deterrent
		  formulations of drugs.</official-title>
	</form>
	<preamble>
		<whereas>
      <text>Whereas when abuse-deterrent formulations of a drug have
			 been developed, approved, and recognized as effective by the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7524">Food and Drug
			 Administration,</cato:entity-ref> the approval and marketing of generic versions that do not have
			 abuse-deterrent features are likely to prevent achievement of the public health
			 purposes of the efforts to develop such abuse-deterrent formulations;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1127">Office of National Drug Control Policy</cato:entity-ref> and the
			 <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7524">Food and Drug Administration</cato:entity-ref> have for many years strongly encouraged
			 manufacturers of opioid drug products to develop abuse-deterrent formulations
			 designed to prevent or discourage the abuse or misuse of those products;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas in response, several opioid drug manufacturers
			 have developed abuse-deterrent formulations;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas efforts to reduce the level of abuse of opioid
			 drug products are dependent on the widespread adoption of new technologies and
			 approaches to the safer formulation of these drugs; and</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7524">Commissioner of Food and Drugs</cato:entity-ref> has
			 acknowledged that the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7524">Food and Drug Administration</cato:entity-ref> has the authority under
			 current law to require generic versions of products that have been formulated
			 or reformulated with abuse-deterrent features to have comparable features: Now,
			 therefore, be it</text>
		</whereas>
  </preamble>
	<resolution-body>
		<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="S1" section-type="undesignated-section">
      <enum/>
      <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That it is the sense of the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0010">Senate</cato:entity-ref> that the
			 <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7524">Food and Drug Administration</cato:entity-ref> should exercise its acknowledged authority
			 to—</text>
			<paragraph id="idE5E95E4BC2814673841622753CB8F31E">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text>refuse to approve
			 generic versions of non-abuse-deterrent opioid products that have been replaced
			 in the market with abuse-deterrent formulations recognized by the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7524">Food and Drug
			 Administration</cato:entity-ref> as effective; and</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="idee679e38eb0b45769a14f132be499187">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text>require generic
			 versions of abuse-deterrent opioid products to be formulated with comparable
			 abuse-deterrent features.</text>
			</paragraph>
    </section>
  </resolution-body>
</resolution>
</doc>