<doc>
  <docmeta id="113sres259ats">
    <bill congress="113" type="sres" number="259" version="ats"/>
    <revision size="3586" annotations="0" status="complete" id="3" commit-time="2013-10-10T22:11:42Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113sres259ats/3.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <resolution xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution">
  <metadata>
<dublinCore>
<title>113 SRES 259 ATS: Designating September 2013 as “Campus Fire Safety Month”.</title>
<publisher>U.S. Senate</publisher>
<date>2013-09-25</date>
<format>text/xml</format>
<language>EN</language>
<rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code>
    <congress>113th CONGRESS</congress>
    <session>1st Session</session>
    <legis-num>S. RES. 259</legis-num>
    <current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
    <action>
      <action-date date="20130925" legis-day="20130924">September 25 (legislative day, September 24), 2013</action-date>
      <action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="S252">Ms. Collins</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S229">Mrs. Murray</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S277">Mr. Carper</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was considered and agreed to</action-desc>
    </action>
    <legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
    <official-title>Designating September 2013 as <quote>Campus Fire Safety
		  Month</quote>.</official-title>
  </form>
  <preamble>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas recent campus-related fires at colleges in
			 Massachusetts, Ohio, Minnesota, Wisconsin, New York, Kansas, and other States
			 have tragically cut short the lives of several young people;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas, since January 2000, at least 162 people,
			 including students, parents, and children, have died in campus-related
			 fires;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas approximately 86 percent of those deaths occurred
			 in off-campus residences;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas a majority of college students in the United
			 States live in an off-campus residence;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas many fatal fires have occurred in a building in
			 which the occupants had compromised or disabled the fire safety system;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas automatic fire alarm systems provide the early
			 warning of a fire that is necessary for occupants of a building and the fire
			 department to take appropriate action;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas automatic fire sprinkler systems are a highly
			 effective method of controlling or extinguishing a fire in the early stages,
			 thus protecting the lives of building occupants;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas many college students live in an off-campus
			 residence, fraternity or sorority housing, or a residence hall that is not
			 adequately protected by an automatic fire sprinkler system and an automatic
			 fire alarm system;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas fire safety education is an effective method of
			 reducing the occurrence of fires and the resulting loss of life and property
			 damage;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas college students do not routinely receive
			 effective fire safety education while in college;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas educating young people in the United States about
			 the importance of fire safety is vital to help ensure that young people engage
			 in fire-safe behavior during college and after college; and</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas developing a generation of adults who practice
			 fire safety may significantly reduce future loss of life from fires: Now,
			 therefore, be it</text>
    </whereas>
  </preamble>
  <resolution-body>
    <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="S1" section-type="undesignated-section">
      <enum/>
      <text>That the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0010">Senate</cato:entity-ref>—</text>
      <paragraph id="idA9FFA6D0CE1B49BCA446BD632A104871">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text>designates
			 September 2013 as <quote>Campus Fire Safety Month</quote>; and</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="idF9E9AA59C597464F9C01D9271F961ADE">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text>encourages
			 administrators of institutions of higher education and municipalities across
			 the United States—</text>
        <subparagraph id="id0C8C3537F0A24C04BB8C5513E5FD1EC3">
          <enum>(A)</enum>
          <text>to provide
			 educational programs about fire safety to all college students in September and
			 throughout the school year;</text>
        </subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="idDA5C9854A2BC4F9189B2F1B3E73939BF">
          <enum>(B)</enum>
          <text>to evaluate the
			 level of fire safety being provided in both on-campus and off-campus student
			 housing; and</text>
        </subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="idB75A7480632E415780AB0A3B50B5CD76">
          <enum>(C)</enum>
          <text>to ensure
			 fire-safe living environments through fire safety education, the installation
			 of fire suppression and detection systems, and the development and enforcement
			 of applicable codes relating to fire safety.</text>
        </subparagraph>
      </paragraph>
    </section>
  </resolution-body>
</resolution>
</doc>