<doc>
  <docmeta id="113sres315ats">
    <bill congress="113" type="sres" number="315" version="ats"/>
    <revision size="2167" annotations="0" status="complete" id="3" commit-time="2014-01-15T23:38:49Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113sres315ats/3.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <resolution xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print">
  <metadata>
<dublinCore>
<dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">113 SRES 315 ATS: To authorize the production of records by the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"/>
<dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code>
    <congress display="yes">113th CONGRESS</congress>
    <session display="yes">1st Session</session>
    <legis-num>S. RES. 315</legis-num>
    <current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
    <action display="yes">
      <action-date>December 10, 2013</action-date>
      <action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="S198">Mr. Reid</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S174">Mr. McConnell</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was considered and agreed to</action-desc>
    </action>
    <legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
    <official-title display="yes">To authorize the production of records by the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</official-title>
  </form>
  <preamble>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas, the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="committee" entity-id="SSGA00">Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs</cato:entity-ref> conducted a review of disability claims adjudications made in the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2800">Social Security Administration</cato:entity-ref>'s Huntington, West Virginia Office of Disability Adjudication and Review;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas, the Committee has received a request from a federal agency for access to records of the Committee's review;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas, by the privileges of the Senate of the United States and Rule XI of the Standing Rules of the Senate, no evidence under the control or in the possession of the Senate can, by administrative or judicial process, be taken from such control or possession but by permission of the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0010">Senate</cato:entity-ref>;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas, when it appears that evidence under the control or in the possession of the Senate is needed for the promotion of justice, the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0010">Senate</cato:entity-ref> will take such action as will promote the ends of justice consistent with the privileges of the Senate: Now, therefore, be it</text>
    </whereas>
  </preamble>
  <resolution-body>
    <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="S1" section-type="undesignated-section">
      <enum/>
      <text>That the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="committee" value="Chairman" entity-parent-id="SSGA00">Chairman</cato:entity-ref> and <cato:entity-ref entity-type="committee" value="Ranking Minority Member" entity-parent-id="SSGA00">Ranking Minority Member of the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs</cato:entity-ref>, acting jointly, are authorized to provide to law enforcement officials, regulatory agencies, and other entities or individuals duly authorized by federal or state governments, records of the Committee's review of the disability claims adjudications made in the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2800">Social Security Administration</cato:entity-ref>'s Huntington, West Virginia Office of Disability Adjudication and Review.</text>
    </section>
  </resolution-body>
</resolution>
</doc>