<doc>
  <docmeta id="113sres114ats">
    <bill congress="113" type="sres" number="114" version="ats"/>
    <revision size="2115" annotations="0" status="complete" id="3" commit-time="2013-08-11T16:23:30Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113sres114ats/3.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <resolution xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution">
	<metadata>
<dublinCore>
<title>113 SRES 114 ATS: To authorize testimony, documents, and representation in United States v. Renzi, et al.</title>
<publisher>U.S. Senate</publisher>
<date/>
<format>text/xml</format>
<language>EN</language>
<rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code>
		<congress>113th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. RES. 114</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date>April 24, 2013</action-date>
			<action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="S198">Mr. Reid</sponsor> (for himself
			 and <cosponsor name-id="S174">Mr. McConnell</cosponsor>) submitted the
			 following resolution; which was considered and agreed to</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">To authorize testimony, documents, and
		  representation in United States v. Renzi, et al.</official-title>
	</form>
	<preamble>
		<whereas>
      <text>Whereas, in the case of United States v. Renzi, et al.,
			 Case No. 08–212, pending in Arizona federal district court, the prosecution and
			 defense have requested the production of documents and employee testimony from
			 the offices of Senator John McCain and former Senator Jon Kyl;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas, by the privileges of the Senate of the United
			 States and Rule XI of the Standing Rules of the Senate, no evidence under the
			 control or in the possession of the Senate may, by the judicial or
			 administrative process, be taken from such control or possession but by
			 permission of the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0010">Senate</cato:entity-ref>;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas, when it appears that evidence under the control
			 or in the possession of the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0010">Senate</cato:entity-ref> may promote the administration of justice,
			 the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0010">Senate</cato:entity-ref> will take such action as will promote the ends of justice consistent
			 with the privileges of the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0010">Senate</cato:entity-ref>: Now, therefore, be it</text>
		</whereas>
  </preamble>
	<resolution-body display-resolving-clause="yes-display-resolving-clause" style="traditional">
		<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="S1" section-type="undesignated-section">
      <enum/>
      <text>That the Office of Senator John
			 McCain and the former Office of Senator Jon Kyl are authorized to produce
			 relevant documents and employee testimony in the case of United States v.
			 Renzi, et al., except concerning matters for which a privilege should be
			 asserted.</text>
		</section>
    <section id="id3CFB4E0D4A4A4830AA889993D2AC7ED6">
      <enum>2.</enum>
      <text>The
			 <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" value="Senate Legal Counsel" entity-parent-id="0010">Senate Legal Counsel</cato:entity-ref> is authorized to represent current and former employees of
			 the offices of Senators McCain and Kyl in connection with the production of
			 evidence authorized in section one of this resolution.</text>
		</section>
  </resolution-body>
</resolution>
</doc>