<doc>
  <docmeta id="113sres546is">
    <bill congress="113" type="sres" number="546" version="is"/>
    <revision size="3084" annotations="0" status="complete" id="4" commit-time="2014-10-03T18:14:12Z" committer="mnewby" doc="113sres546is/4.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <resolution xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print">
	<metadata>
<dublinCore>
<dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">113 SRES 546 IS: Congratulating Indonesia's President-elect Joko Widodo on his electoral victory and commending the people of Indonesia on their commitment to democracy and free and fair elections.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">2014-09-16</dc:date>
<dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">113th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session display="yes">2d Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. RES. 546</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20140916">September 16, 2014</action-date>
			<action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="S316">Mr. Whitehouse</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S197">Mr. McCain</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations</committee-name>
      </action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">Congratulating Indonesia's President-elect Joko Widodo on his electoral victory and commending the
			 people of Indonesia on their commitment to democracy and free and fair
			 elections.</official-title>
	</form>
	<preamble>
		<whereas>
      <text>Whereas the United States and Indonesia are the world’s second and third largest democracies,
			 respectively;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the United States and Indonesia share many common values, including respect for human
			 rights and the rule of law;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas in November 2010, the United States and Indonesia launched the U.S.-Indonesia Comprehensive
			 Partnership, which solidified a long-term commitment to cooperation on key
			 bilateral, regional and global issues;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the U.S.-Indonesia Comprehensive Partnership’s Democracy and Civil Society Working Group
			 promotes enhanced cooperation on parliamentary and electoral processes and
			 political empowerment for women;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas Indonesia, a regional and global leader, has undergone a remarkable democratic
			 transformation over the last 2 decades;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas on July 9, 2014, approximately 135,000,000 votes were cast in Indonesia’s Presidential
			 election, which was the largest single day election in the world to date;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas on July 22, 2014, Joko Widodo was declared the winner in Indonesia’s Presidential election;
			 and</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas Indonesia, with its vast geography, large multi-ethnic population, and largest Muslim
			 majority population in the world, is a powerful model for a peaceful,
			 democratic transition of power: Now, therefore, be it</text>
		</whereas>
  </preamble>
	<resolution-body>
		<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="S1" section-type="undesignated-section">
      <enum/>
      <text>That the <cato:entity-ref entity-id="0010" entity-type="federal-body">Senate</cato:entity-ref>—</text>
			<paragraph id="idFB8C1F8AF5484B33A62604A14C9B8787">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text>congratulates Indonesia's President-elect Joko Widodo on his electoral victory;</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id59A7E6B1F5D8418086F3A066A83B8C68">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text>commends the people of Indonesia on their commitment to democracy and free and fair elections;</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="idFA38D9CBDEBE48D8A2E1798D4D84E36C">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <text>affirms the commitment of the United States to strengthening our bilateral relationship with
			 Indonesia;</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id0E5CE0D13AF6479B88BCA3858AF15522">
        <enum>(4)</enum>
        <text>supports the advancement of an inclusive democracy and an active role for civil society in
			 Indonesia; and</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id64DA90A780E44E24ADBFAAD42DB12F04">
        <enum>(5)</enum>
        <text>recognizes Indonesia's 2014 Presidential election as an example of a peaceful, democratic
			 transition of power for other transformational democracies throughout the
			 world to follow.</text>
			</paragraph>
    </section>
  </resolution-body>
</resolution>
</doc>