<doc>
  <docmeta id="113sres316is">
    <bill congress="113" type="sres" number="316" version="is"/>
    <revision size="6092" annotations="0" status="complete" id="4" commit-time="2014-08-11T15:53:56Z" committer="mnewby" doc="113sres316is/4.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <resolution xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print">
  <metadata>
<dublinCore>
<dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">113 SRES 316 IS: Supporting the goals and ideals of American Diabetes Month.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">2013-12-10</dc:date>
<dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code>
    <congress display="yes">113th CONGRESS</congress>
    <session display="yes">1st Session</session>
    <legis-num>S. RES. 316</legis-num>
    <current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
    <action display="yes">
      <action-date date="20131210">December 10, 2013</action-date>
      <action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="S324">Mrs. Shaheen</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="S252">Ms. Collins</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSHR00">Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions</committee-name>
      </action-desc>
    </action>
    <legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
    <official-title display="yes">Supporting the goals and ideals of American Diabetes Month.</official-title>
  </form>
  <preamble>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas according to the <cato:entity-ref entity-id="7523" entity-type="federal-body">Centers for Disease Control and Prevention</cato:entity-ref> (referred to in this preamble as the <quote>
          <cato:entity-ref entity-id="7523" entity-type="federal-body">CDC</cato:entity-ref>
        </quote>), nearly 26,000,000 individuals in the United States have diabetes and an estimated 79,000,000 individuals age 20 years or older in the United States have prediabetes;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas diabetes is a serious chronic condition that affects individuals of every age, race, ethnicity, and income level;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the <cato:entity-ref entity-id="7523" entity-type="federal-body">CDC</cato:entity-ref> reports that Hispanic, African, Asian, and Native Americans are disproportionately affected by diabetes and suffer from the disease at rates that are much higher than the general population of the United States;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas according to the <cato:entity-ref entity-id="7523" entity-type="federal-body">CDC</cato:entity-ref>, an individual age  20 years or older   is diagnosed with diabetes every 17 seconds;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas approximately 5,205 individuals age 20 years and older  in the United States are diagnosed with diabetes each day;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the <cato:entity-ref entity-id="7523" entity-type="federal-body">CDC</cato:entity-ref> estimates that approximately 1,900,000 individuals in the United States age 20 years and older were newly diagnosed with diabetes in 2010;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas a joint <cato:entity-ref entity-id="7529" entity-type="federal-body">National Institutes of Health</cato:entity-ref> and <cato:entity-ref entity-id="7523" entity-type="federal-body">CDC</cato:entity-ref> study found that each year between 2002 and 2005, approximately 15,600 youth were diagnosed with type 1 diabetes and approximately 3,600 youth were diagnosed with type 2 diabetes in the United States;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas according to the <cato:entity-ref entity-id="7523" entity-type="federal-body">CDC</cato:entity-ref>, the prevalence of diabetes in the United States increased by more than 300 percent between 1980 and 2010;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the <cato:entity-ref entity-id="7523" entity-type="federal-body">CDC</cato:entity-ref> reports that more than 27 percent of individuals with diabetes in the United States have not been diagnosed with the disease;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas more than 11 percent of adults and 26.9 percent of individuals age 65 and older in the United States have diabetes;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas as many as 1 in 3 adults in the United States will have diabetes in 2050 if the present trend continues;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas after accounting for the difference of the average age of each population, data surveying individuals age 20 years and older in the United States between 2007 and 2009 indicate that   7.1 percent of non-Hispanic whites, 12.6 percent of non-Hispanic blacks, 11.8 percent of Hispanics, and  8.4 percent of Asian Americans suffered from diagnosed diabetes;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas after accounting for the difference of the average age of each population, data surveying Hispanic individuals age 20 years and older in the United States between 2007 and 2009 indicate that 7.6 percent of individuals of Cuban, Central American, and South American descent, 13.3 percent of individuals of  Mexican descent, and 13.8 percent of individuals of Puerto Rican descent suffered from diagnosed diabetes;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas according to the American Diabetes Association, the United States spent an estimated $245,000,000,000  on cases of diagnosed diabetes in 2012;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the American Diabetes Association reports that 20 percent of the money that the United States spent on health care in 2012 went towards caring for individuals with diabetes;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas a Mathematica Policy Research study found that total expenditures for individuals with diabetes receiving benefits under the Medicare program under <cato:entity entity-type="law-citation">
          <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Social Security Act/t:XVIII">title XVIII of the Social Security Act</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395">
          <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/42/1395/etseq">42 U.S.C. 1395 et seq.</cato:entity-ref>
        </external-xref>)</cato:entity> in fiscal year 2005 comprised 32.7 percent of the budget for such program in  such fiscal year;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas according to the <cato:entity-ref entity-id="7523" entity-type="federal-body">CDC</cato:entity-ref>, in 2007, diabetes was the seventh leading cause of death in the United States, contributing to the death of more than 230,000 individuals in the United States that year;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas a cure for diabetes does not exist as of November 2013;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas there are successful means to reduce the incidence of and delay the onset of type 2 diabetes;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas with proper management and treatment, individuals with diabetes live healthy, productive lives; and</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas individuals in the United States celebrate American Diabetes Month in November: Now, therefore, be it</text>
    </whereas>
  </preamble>
  <resolution-body>
    <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="S1" section-type="undesignated-section">
      <enum/>
      <text>That the <cato:entity-ref entity-id="0010" entity-type="federal-body">Senate</cato:entity-ref>—</text>
      <paragraph id="id62a68c005f9a4e9c95a34e26fc92be4d">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text>supports the goals and ideals of American Diabetes Month, including—</text>
        <subparagraph id="id8428ac4f6d974be1b89dea10529bb3c5">
          <enum>(A)</enum>
          <text>encouraging individuals in the United States to fight diabetes through public awareness of prevention and treatment options; and</text>
        </subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="id2a224fffb31e49a4882a1ea2a83c2f63">
          <enum>(B)</enum>
          <text>enhancing diabetes education;</text>
        </subparagraph>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id5162d4a56d9b4963b325ca542ac2bf4c">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text>recognizes the importance of early detection, awareness of the symptoms, and understanding the risk factors of diabetes, including—</text>
        <subparagraph id="id76bd8618a1294bc895d1d85163898c12">
          <enum>(A)</enum>
          <text>being over the age of 45;</text>
        </subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="id5168bc32310441dda71456d3d4c89006">
          <enum>(B)</enum>
          <text>having a specific racial and ethnic background;</text>
        </subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="id81cc50351cc043aa9e90eb9ab26deada">
          <enum>(C)</enum>
          <text>being overweight;</text>
        </subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="id5f9eeace1cc54c9a923de8c9fc5c7ba2">
          <enum>(D)</enum>
          <text>having a low level of physical activity;</text>
        </subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="id2166e8c763504f639586b48487bec608">
          <enum>(E)</enum>
          <text>having high blood pressure; and</text>
        </subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="id47a6314169124ca0ae6188ad0ebc32ac">
          <enum>(F)</enum>
          <text>having a family history of diabetes or a history of diabetes during pregnancy; and</text>
        </subparagraph>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="idb99cdec6aa414f52a9f2de2eca71a201">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <text>supports decreasing the prevalence of type 1, type 2, and gestational diabetes in the United States through increased research, treatment, and prevention.</text>
      </paragraph>
    </section>
  </resolution-body>
</resolution>
</doc>