<doc>
  <docmeta id="113sres332ats">
    <bill congress="113" type="sres" number="332" version="ats"/>
    <revision size="3013" annotations="0" status="complete" id="5" commit-time="2014-02-11T14:49:16Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113sres332ats/5.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <resolution xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print">
  <metadata>
<dublinCore>
<dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">113 SRES 332 ATS: Congratulating the North Dakota State University football team for winning the 2013 National Collegiate Athletic Association Division I Football Championship Subdivision title. </dc:title>
<dc:publisher xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">2014-01-13</dc:date>
<dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code>
    <congress display="yes">113th CONGRESS</congress>
    <session display="yes">2d Session</session>
    <legis-num>S. RES. 332</legis-num>
    <current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
    <action display="yes">
      <action-date date="20140113">January 13, 2014</action-date>
      <action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="S344">Mr. Hoeven</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S360">Ms. Heitkamp</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was considered and agreed to</action-desc>
    </action>
    <legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
    <official-title display="yes">Congratulating the North Dakota State University football team for winning the 2013 National Collegiate Athletic Association Division I Football Championship Subdivision title. </official-title>
  </form>
  <preamble>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the North Dakota State University (referred to in this preamble as <quote>NDSU</quote>) Bison won the 2013 National Collegiate Athletic Association (referred to in this preamble as the <quote>NCAA</quote>) Division I Football Championship Subdivision title game in Frisco, Texas, on January 4, 2014, in a hard fought victory over the Towson University Tigers of Maryland by a score of 35 to 7;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the NDSU Bison and coach Craig Bohl had an incredible 2013 season and finished unbeaten for the first time since 1990;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas NDSU has won 11 NCAA Football Championships and has now won 3 consecutive NCAA Football Championships since 2011;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas during the championship game, the NDSU Bison offense scored 35 points against the Towson University Tigers;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas Coach Bohl and his staff have instilled character and confidence in the NDSU players and have done an outstanding job with the Bison football program;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the leadership of President Dean Bresciani and Athletic Director Gene Taylor has helped bring both academic and athletic excellence to NDSU;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas an estimated 17,000 Bison fans attended the Championship game, reflecting the tremendous spirit and dedication of Bison Nation that has helped propel the success of the team; and</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the 2013 NCAA Division I Football Championship Subdivision title was a victory not only for the NDSU football team, but also for the entire State of North Dakota: Now, therefore, be it</text>
    </whereas>
  </preamble>
  <resolution-body>
    <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="S1" section-type="undesignated-section">
      <enum/>
      <text>That the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0010">Senate</cato:entity-ref>—</text>
      <paragraph id="ide3b977da5ee147af9b9a659ad1d1abb2">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text>congratulates the North Dakota State University football team as the champion of the 2013 National Collegiate Athletic Association Division I Football Championship Subdivision title;</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="idd89b8f1e464b4d599b094c085ee05b26">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text>commends the North Dakota State University players, coaches, and staff for their hard work and dedication; and</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id6367fd85750749bda8f678eff9db5c2e">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <text>recognizes the students, alumni, and loyal fans for supporting the Bison on the successful quest of the team to capture another Division I trophy for North Dakota State University.</text>
      </paragraph>
    </section>
  </resolution-body>
</resolution>
</doc>