<doc>
  <docmeta id="113sres156is">
    <bill congress="113" type="sres" number="156" version="is"/>
    <revision size="6472" annotations="0" status="complete" id="5" commit-time="2013-07-16T16:48:46Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113sres156is/5.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <resolution xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print">
	<metadata>
<dublinCore>
<title>113 SRES 156 IS: Expressing the sense of the Senate on the 10-year anniversary of NATO Allied Command Transformation.</title>
<publisher>U.S. Senate</publisher>
<date>2013-05-23</date>
<format>text/xml</format>
<language>EN</language>
<rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">113th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session display="yes">1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. RES. 156</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20130523">May 23, 2013</action-date>
			<action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="S327">Mr. Warner</sponsor> submitted the
			 following resolution; which was referred to the
			 <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign
			 Relations</committee-name>
      </action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">Expressing the sense of the Senate on the
		  10-year anniversary of NATO Allied Command Transformation.</official-title>
	</form>
	<preamble>
		<whereas>
      <text>Whereas, on June 19, 2003, NATO’s Allied Command
			 Transformation (ACT), was formally established to increase military
			 effectiveness and prepare the Alliance for future security challenges;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas, on June 19, 2013, the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="19RN">North Atlantic Treaty
			 Organization</cato:entity-ref> (NATO) will celebrate the 10-year anniversary of the establishment
			 of NATO ACT;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the security of the United States and its NATO
			 allies have been enhanced by the establishment and continued work of NATO
			 ACT;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas, for the past 10 years, ACT has been leading the
			 charge for NATO military transformation, and providing relevant and timely
			 support to NATO operations, and developing partnerships around the globe to
			 adapt to the changing global security environment;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas ACT is the only <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="19RN">NATO</cato:entity-ref> headquarters in the United
			 States, and the only permanent NATO headquarters outside of Europe;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas ACT provides state-of-the-art education, training,
			 and application of best practices and lessons learned from past operations, and
			 equips Alliance troops with the tools they need to win today’s wars;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas ACT improves <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="19RN">NATO’s</cato:entity-ref> defense planning and develops
			 compatible equipment and common standards necessary to keep Alliance
			 capabilities aligned;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas NATO ACT has been integral to a <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="19RN">NATO</cato:entity-ref> mission of
			 promoting a Europe that is whole, undivided, free, and at peace;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas NATO ACT strengthened the ability of <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="19RN">NATO</cato:entity-ref> to
			 perform a full range of missions throughout the world;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas NATO ACT has provided crucial support and
			 participation in the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" value="International Security Assistance Force in Afghanistan" entity-parent-id="19RN">NATO International Security Assistance Force in
			 Afghanistan</cato:entity-ref>, as <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="19RN">NATO</cato:entity-ref> endeavors to help the people of Afghanistan create the
			 conditions necessary for security and successful development and
			 reconstruction;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas ACT employs personnel from 26 NATO member nations
			 and 6 NATO Partner nations and contributes more than $100,000,000 annually to
			 the local economy;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="19RN">NATO</cato:entity-ref> has been the cornerstone of transatlantic
			 security cooperation and an enduring instrument for promoting stability in
			 Europe and throughout the world for over 60 years, representing the vital
			 transatlantic bond of solidarity between the United States and Europe, as <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="19RN">NATO</cato:entity-ref>
			 nations share similar values and interests and are committed to the maintenance
			 of democratic principles;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the Chicago Summit Communique affirms that all
			 NATO members <quote>are determined that NATO will continue to play its unique
			 and essential role in ensuring our common defense and security</quote> and that
			 NATO <quote>continues to be effective in a changing world, against new threats,
			 with new capabilities and new partners</quote>;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas, through the Alliance, the United States and
			 Europe are effective and steadfast partners in security, and ACT is well
			 positioned to contribute to the strength of the Alliance on both
			 continents;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas NATO ACT has done much to help NATO meet the
			 global challenges of the 21st century, including the threat of terrorism, the
			 spread of weapons of mass destruction, instability caused by failed states, and
			 threats to global energy security; and</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the 10th anniversary of NATO ACT is an opportunity
			 to enhance and more deeply entrench those principles, which continue to bind
			 the alliance together and guide our efforts today: Now, therefore, be it</text>
		</whereas>
  </preamble>
	<resolution-body>
		<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="S1" section-type="undesignated-section">
      <enum/>
      <text>That the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0010">Senate</cato:entity-ref>—</text>
			<paragraph id="id17525CE9A2D64772833AD94092B18F92">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text>celebrates the
			 10th anniversary of the establishment of NATO Allied Command Transformation
			 (NATO ACT);</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id2B1EAA444EF14B98B33ACC18AA34A2D4">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text>recognizes NATO
			 ACT’s leading role to continue to transform alliance forces and capabilities,
			 using new concepts such as the NATO Response Force and new doctrines in order
			 to improve the alliance’s military effectiveness;</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id8901CFC5C1ED4BD0907EB62B5D452CC0">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <text>expresses
			 appreciation for the continuing and close partnership between the United States
			 Government and NATO to transform the alliance;</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id4237077D2B5842B9844CF4A4CCF7512A">
        <enum>(4)</enum>
        <text>remembers the 65
			 years <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="19RN">NATO</cato:entity-ref> has served to ensure peace, security, and stability in Europe
			 throughout the world, and urges the United States Government to continue to
			 seek new ways to deepen and expand its important relationships with
			 <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="19RN">NATO</cato:entity-ref>;</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id335DA329871D462F89724A004B558906">
        <enum>(5)</enum>
        <text>recognizes the
			 service of the brave men and women who have served to safeguard the freedom and
			 security of the United States and the whole of the transatlantic
			 alliance;</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id566034B159D44D44B645805E3E4AED73">
        <enum>(6)</enum>
        <text>honors the
			 sacrifices of United States personnel, allies of the North American Treaty
			 Organization (referred to in this resolution as <quote>NATO</quote>), and
			 partners in Afghanistan;</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id20964EF909ED4251913618890E7DFF95">
        <enum>(7)</enum>
        <text>recognizes the
			 outstanding partnership between the local community in Norfolk, Virginia, and
			 NATO personnel assigned to ACT;</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="idB41271EC1C074943BD62070FBCD9BF7A">
        <enum>(8)</enum>
        <text>reaffirms that
			 <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="19RN">NATO</cato:entity-ref>, through the new Strategic Concept, is oriented toward the changing
			 international security environment and the challenges of the future;</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id50FAA1399E8F4E49A2AFD6C8B6682AA2">
        <enum>(9)</enum>
        <text>urges all <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="19RN">NATO</cato:entity-ref>
			 members to take concrete steps to implement the Strategic Concept and to
			 utilize the taskings from the 2012 <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="19RN">NATO</cato:entity-ref> summit in Chicago, Illinois, to address
			 current <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="19RN">NATO</cato:entity-ref> operations, future capabilities and burden-sharing issues, and
			 strengthen the relationship between <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="19RN">NATO</cato:entity-ref> and partners around the world;
			 and</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="idDC9BE65C53F0416A8E248DC6E677CC98">
        <enum>(10)</enum>
        <text>conveys
			 appreciation for the steadfast partnership between <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="19RN">NATO</cato:entity-ref> and the United
			 States.</text>
			</paragraph>
    </section>
  </resolution-body>
</resolution>
</doc>