<doc>
  <docmeta id="113sres531is">
    <bill congress="113" type="sres" number="531" version="is"/>
    <revision size="3100" annotations="0" status="complete" id="6" commit-time="2014-10-27T20:28:31Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113sres531is/6.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <resolution xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print">
	<metadata>
<dublinCore>
<dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">113 SRES 531 IS: Honoring the life, accomplishments, and legacy of Louis Zamperini and expressing condolences on his passing.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">2014-07-31</dc:date>
<dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">113th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session display="yes">2d Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. RES. 531</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20140731">July 31, 2014</action-date>
			<action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="S221">Mrs. Feinstein</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="S197">Mr. McCain</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>
      </action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">Honoring the life, accomplishments, and legacy of Louis Zamperini and expressing condolences on his
			 passing.</official-title>
	</form>
	<preamble>
		<whereas>
      <text>Whereas Louis Silvie <quote>Lou</quote> Zamperini was born on January 26, 1917, to Anthony and Louise Zamperini,
			 in Olean, New York;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas Louis Zamperini represented the United States in the 1936 Olympics in Berlin as a distance
			 runner;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas Louis Zamperini graduated from the University of Southern California in 1940 and enlisted
			 in the United States Army Air Corps in 1941, earning the rank of
			 lieutenant;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas in May 1943, Louis Zamperini’s B–24 bomber malfunctioned and crashed during a
			 search-and-rescue mission over the Pacific Ocean, leaving him and 2 other
			 individuals stranded;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas Louis Zamperini survived for 47 days adrift in a life raft with Second Lieutenant Russell
			 Phillips before being captured by Japanese forces and placed in a prisoner
			 of war camp;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas for more than 2 years, during his imprisonment, Louis Zamperini endured brutal treatment
			 and
			 forced labor with courage and resilience;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas upon the conclusion of World War II, Louis Zamperini was released from the prisoner of war
			 camp in September 1945;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas Louis Zamperini was promoted to captain and awarded multiple distinguishing military
			 honors, including the Purple Heart, the Distinguished Flying Cross, and
			 the Prisoner of War Medal;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas Louis Zamperini was given the honor of carrying the Olympic flame in 1984, 1996, and 1998;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas in the years after World War II, Louis Zamperini traveled as an inspirational public
			 speaker, using his experiences to inspire a message of forgiveness;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the airport in Torrance, California, was named <quote>Zamperini Field</quote> in honor of Louis Zamperini; and</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas Louis Zamperini leaves a legacy as a national hero and an inspiration to future
			 generations: Now, therefore, be it</text>
		</whereas>
  </preamble>
	<resolution-body>
		<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="S1" section-type="undesignated-section">
      <enum/>
      <text>That the <cato:entity-ref entity-id="0010" entity-type="federal-body">Senate</cato:entity-ref>—</text>
			<paragraph id="id204cb592439448fa8659df548966c4ab">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text>honors the life, accomplishments, and legacy of Louis Zamperini;</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id52a9ba0b74fe4e558a0d175dc499111f">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text>extends heartfelt sympathies and condolences to the family of Louis Zamperini; and</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id8558939451fa473e9bc55ae26615a1ca">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <text>requests the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> to identify an appropriate and lasting program of the United States
			 Government to honor the legacy of Louis Zamperini.</text>
      </paragraph>
    </section>
  </resolution-body>
</resolution>
</doc>