<doc>
  <docmeta id="113s1052is">
    <bill congress="113" type="s" number="1052" version="is"/>
    <revision size="19818" annotations="0" status="complete" id="5" commit-time="2013-08-01T23:33:22Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113s1052is/5.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>113 S1052 IS: Growing Education Achievement Training Academies for Teachers and Principals Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2013-05-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
		<congress>113th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. 1052</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20130523">May 23, 2013</action-date>
			<action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="S330">Mr. Bennet</sponsor> (for himself,
			 <cosponsor name-id="S289">Mr. Alexander</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S182">Ms. Mikulski</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S339">Mr.
			 Kirk</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S311">Ms. Klobuchar</cosponsor>, and
			 <cosponsor name-id="S258">Ms. Landrieu</cosponsor>) introduced the following
			 bill; which was read twice and referred to the
			 <committee-name committee-id="SSHR00">Committee on Health, Education, Labor,
			 and Pensions</committee-name>
      </action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To create and expand innovative teacher and principal
		  preparation programs known as teacher and principal preparation
		  academies.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body>
		<section id="S1" section-type="section-one">
      <enum>1.</enum>
      <header>Short
			 title; table of contents</header>
			<subsection id="idE1100894D5324763A7DC80DFB0C898EB">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Short
			 title</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act may be cited
			 as the <quote>
            <short-title>Growing Education Achievement
			 Training Academies for Teachers and Principals Act</short-title>
          </quote> or the
			 <quote>
            <short-title>GREAT Teachers and Principals
			 Act</short-title>
          </quote>.</text>
			</subsection>
      <subsection id="id3F546D5837F64646A42EE2FB2687F21D">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Table of
			 contents</header>
        <text>The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text>
				<toc>
					<toc-entry idref="S1" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title; table of
				contents.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="IDd3bf53ccf25247fb93d0c661173946f6" level="section">Sec. 2. Purpose.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="ID759f93649cd44808b765da9bd95f8416" level="section">Sec. 3. Definitions.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="IDb4ee550d3e414fa5b4a9ed61c4bfc0c0" level="section">Sec. 4. State grants.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="ID3e481a861c79473d8a322488a2b01a80" level="section">Sec. 5. Subgrants to teacher or principal preparation
				academies.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="IDa3dbd9711fd24cca96172df7ea87ee49" level="section">Sec. 6. Coordination with the Corporation for National and
				Community Service.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="IDf23c02faea0345218b646a8de9ee65a6" level="section">Sec. 7. Authorization of appropriations.</toc-entry>
				</toc>
			</subsection>
    </section>
    <section id="IDd3bf53ccf25247fb93d0c661173946f6">
      <enum>2.</enum>
      <header>Purpose</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">The purpose of this Act is to encourage
			 innovation in the field of teacher and principal preparation by creating and
			 expanding teacher or principal preparation academies that will increase the
			 number of effective teachers and principals serving in high-needs schools and
			 hard-to-staff subjects.</text>
		</section>
    <section id="ID759f93649cd44808b765da9bd95f8416">
      <enum>3.</enum>
      <header>Definitions</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text>
			<paragraph id="IDe543a0dbecde4d60853458bd446c6b78">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <header>Principal
			 preparation academy</header>
        <text>The term <term>principal preparation
			 academy</term> means a public or other nonprofit institution for preparing
			 principals that—</text>
				<subparagraph id="ID34060f53bf13407bb60663df84717d40">
          <enum>(A)</enum>
          <text>enters into a
			 charter with a State authorizer that specifies the goals and outcomes expected
			 of the principal preparation academy and the obligations of the State
			 authorizer, including—</text>
					<clause id="ID10e77819c70e4758998f8c8254f7f362">
            <enum>(i)</enum>
            <text>a
			 requirement that—</text>
						<subclause id="id631373F932544BB89944E07D859C3CA6">
              <enum>(I)</enum>
              <text>principal
			 candidates, or principals serving on alternative certificates, licenses, or
			 credentials, who are enrolled in the principal preparation academy receive a
			 significant part of their training through clinical preparation that partners
			 the principal candidate with a mentor principal; and</text>
						</subclause>
            <subclause id="idB6FB3D6112784527A070E68B2C882941">
              <enum>(II)</enum>
              <text>the academy will
			 provide instruction to the principal candidate that links to the clinical
			 preparation experience;</text>
						</subclause>
          </clause>
          <clause id="IDf49e4a7492bb40429697980d6b2edc4b">
            <enum>(ii)</enum>
            <text>the number of
			 principals the principal preparation academy will produce and the minimum
			 number and percentage of effective principals with a demonstrated track record
			 of success in getting a school's students on track to being career and college
			 ready;</text>
					</clause>
          <clause id="ID4cd32edf52024487bd1b263c0c14f0aa">
            <enum>(iii)</enum>
            <text>a
			 requirement that a certificate of completion (or degree, if the principal
			 preparation academy is, or is affiliated with, an institution of higher
			 education) will be conferred upon a graduate from the principal preparation
			 academy only after the graduate demonstrates a track record of success in
			 getting a school's students on track to being college and career ready;</text>
					</clause>
          <clause id="ID04c39611e9034c98bb563d6f7e2f324d">
            <enum>(iv)</enum>
            <text>a
			 requirement that the principal preparation academy survey the academy's alumni
			 not less than once every 3 years to track the number of alumni employed as
			 principals and in education; and</text>
					</clause>
          <clause id="ID23982026efd7498b94ecfcd4079acc45">
            <enum>(v)</enum>
            <text>timelines for
			 producing cohorts of graduates and conferring certificates of completion (or
			 degrees, if the principal preparation academy is, or is affiliated with, an
			 institution of higher education) from the principal preparation academy;</text>
					</clause>
        </subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="ID7c8f26e1a2a7479fabb1a7684b2b5ece">
          <enum>(B)</enum>
          <text>shall not have
			 unnecessary restrictions on the methods the principal preparation academy will
			 use to train principal candidates, including restrictions or
			 requirements—</text>
					<clause id="IDefe8e002fd8b4772bfc739700ab4b375">
            <enum>(i)</enum>
            <text>obligating the
			 faculty of the principal preparation academy faculty to hold advanced
			 degrees;</text>
					</clause>
          <clause id="ID7f3e7b9695ca4c99bf9d70825912d05d">
            <enum>(ii)</enum>
            <text>obligating such
			 faculty to conduct academic research;</text>
					</clause>
          <clause id="ID60d0bfd167d146cfa2ee240d0fe5d29d">
            <enum>(iii)</enum>
            <text>related to the
			 physical infrastructure of the principal preparation academy; or</text>
					</clause>
          <clause id="IDc47266ae4f6c46a68092d2bba858a2c8">
            <enum>(iv)</enum>
            <text>related to the
			 number of course credits required as part of the program of study; and</text>
					</clause>
        </subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="IDe113f13382e04b38bcca385ecddb12ba">
          <enum>(C)</enum>
          <text>limits admission
			 to its program to candidates who demonstrate strong potential to be effective
			 principals, based on a rigorous, competency-based selection process that
			 reviews a candidate's prior academic achievement or record of professional
			 accomplishment.</text>
				</subparagraph>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="IDaa07539a2aed426bb78ea38caa0bf432">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <header>State
			 authorizer</header>
        <text>The term <term>State authorizer</term> means an entity
			 designated by the State to recognize teacher or principal preparation academies
			 within the State that—</text>
				<subparagraph id="IDde656098d5cb4b7ab8b918333dfad3b7">
          <enum>(A)</enum>
          <text>may be a
			 nonprofit organization, State educational agency, or other public entity, or
			 consortium of such entities (including a consortium of States); and</text>
				</subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="ID9d2a7a515f0e4f3ba6eb2f86ca6e46eb">
          <enum>(B)</enum>
          <text>does not renew a
			 teacher or principal preparation academy’s charter if the academy fails to
			 produce the minimum number or percentage of effective teachers or principals,
			 respectively, identified in the academy's charter.</text>
				</subparagraph>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id13A02A55639542DCB0F17066888518DD">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <header>Teacher or
			 principal preparation academy</header>
        <text>The term <term>teacher or principal
			 preparation academy</term> means a teacher preparation academy or a principal
			 preparation academy.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="ID04b0be8d1c8c4c208e10ede3a5fa7d41">
        <enum>(4)</enum>
        <header>Teacher
			 preparation academy</header>
        <text>The term <term>teacher preparation
			 academy</term> means a public or other nonprofit institution for preparing
			 teachers that—</text>
				<subparagraph id="ID8192cd50ccd349cdbb51f74820a0f5b6">
          <enum>(A)</enum>
          <text>enters into a
			 charter with a State authorizer that specifies the goals and outcomes expected
			 of the teacher preparation academy and the obligations of the State authorizer,
			 including—</text>
					<clause id="IDeba3d088aaed45a68fb1322e82c0619a">
            <enum>(i)</enum>
            <text>a
			 requirement that—</text>
						<subclause id="idAA526FC06D72407EABBA28E8FF20FB24">
              <enum>(I)</enum>
              <text>teacher
			 candidates, or teachers teaching on alternative certificates, licenses, or
			 credentials, who are enrolled in the teacher preparation academy receive a
			 significant part of their training through clinical preparation that partners
			 teacher candidates with mentor teachers with a demonstrated track record of
			 success in improving academic achievement in the classroom; and</text>
						</subclause>
            <subclause id="id03CFCB6F35014DB9915C0C21F2369B05">
              <enum>(II)</enum>
              <text>the academy will
			 provide instruction to teacher candidates that links to the clinical
			 preparation experience;</text>
						</subclause>
          </clause>
          <clause id="IDb256b610d8b149febf336e3d438af822">
            <enum>(ii)</enum>
            <text>the number of
			 teachers the teacher preparation academy will produce and the minimum number
			 and percentage of effective teachers with a demonstrated track record of
			 success in getting students on track to being college and career ready, based
			 on multiple measures of student achievement;</text>
					</clause>
          <clause id="ID5a1a19146a734fb4a7d2b1dca2f55ec1">
            <enum>(iii)</enum>
            <text>a
			 requirement that a teacher preparation academy will only award a certificate of
			 completion (or degree, if the teacher preparation academy is, or is affiliated
			 with, an institution of higher education) after the graduate demonstrates the
			 track record of success described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="GREAT Teachers and Principles Act/s:3/p:4/sp:A/cl:ii" proposed="true">clause (ii)</cato:entity-ref>, either as a student teacher
			 or teacher-of-record on an alternative certificate, license, or
			 credential;</text>
					</clause>
          <clause id="IDdcaf436416cb4084aa6799032b57d979">
            <enum>(iv)</enum>
            <text>a
			 requirement that the teacher preparation academy survey the academy's alumni
			 not less than once every 3 years to track the number of alumni employed as
			 teachers and in education; and</text>
					</clause>
          <clause id="IDc9fc0569be3744cab95d9beb1d936306">
            <enum>(v)</enum>
            <text>timelines for
			 producing cohorts of graduates and conferring certificates of completion (or
			 degrees, if the teacher preparation academy is, or is affiliated with, an
			 institution of higher education) from the teacher preparation academy;</text>
					</clause>
        </subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="ID59d5bde8a5ae47b4a35501c7128b8a65">
          <enum>(B)</enum>
          <text>shall not have
			 unnecessary restrictions on the methods or inputs the teacher preparation
			 academy will use to train teacher candidates or teachers teaching on
			 alternative certificates, licenses, or credentials, including restrictions or
			 requirements—</text>
					<clause id="ID7f19e48f18204d46aa89c29d2915b729">
            <enum>(i)</enum>
            <text>obligating the
			 faculty of the teacher preparation academy to hold advanced degrees;</text>
					</clause>
          <clause id="IDe7b7141cae20402493ebacc14e4aa711">
            <enum>(ii)</enum>
            <text>obligating such
			 faculty to conduct academic research;</text>
					</clause>
          <clause id="IDce6653d72173407187c223e7eeab18d2">
            <enum>(iii)</enum>
            <text>related to the
			 physical infrastructure of the teacher preparation academy;</text>
					</clause>
          <clause id="ID51a5c2fa50ad4126bfb8ba7933565423">
            <enum>(iv)</enum>
            <text>related to the
			 number of course credits required as part of the program of study;</text>
					</clause>
          <clause id="id4E9CCFBC586A4865B39A68015B5A9D9B">
            <enum>(v)</enum>
            <text>related to the
			 undergraduate coursework completed by teachers teaching on alternative
			 certificates, licenses, or credentials, as long as such teachers have
			 successfully passed all relevant State-approved content area examinations;
			 or</text>
					</clause>
          <clause id="id2AD24E198C534904915E752B5C785213">
            <enum>(vi)</enum>
            <text>related to
			 obtaining additional accreditation from a national accrediting body; and</text>
					</clause>
        </subparagraph>
        <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ID7b1c26a3135c45828fe1d429edcbd564">
          <enum>(C)</enum>
          <text>limits admission
			 to its program to candidates who demonstrate strong potential to be effective
			 teachers, based on a rigorous selection process that reviews a candidate's
			 prior academic achievement or record of professional accomplishment.</text>
				</subparagraph>
      </paragraph>
    </section>
    <section id="IDb4ee550d3e414fa5b4a9ed61c4bfc0c0">
      <enum>4.</enum>
      <header>State
			 grants</header>
			<subsection id="ID48c08917328244aaac11e3ed8d3450c6">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>In
			 general</header>
        <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="9100">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> is authorized to award grants to States
			 having applications approved under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="GREAT Teachers and Principles Act/s:4/ss:b" proposed="true">subsection (b)</cato:entity-ref> to enable such States to
			 create or expand teacher or principal preparation academies.</text>
			</subsection>
      <subsection id="ID00ea7bea1e99466492a840a4f0742dd0">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Applications</header>
        <text>Each
			 State that desires a grant under this Act shall submit an application to the
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="9100">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="9100">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> may reasonably require. The application shall include—</text>
				<paragraph id="ID4dcc7330dd6a4c9c9d668e2ecfb0fa96">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>an assurance that
			 the State does not have in place legal, statutory, or regulatory barriers to
			 the creation or operation of teacher or principal preparation academies;</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="ID5b3ed765f89c4745afc5a109f5ee3873">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>a description of
			 how the State will promote the creation and expansion of teacher or principal
			 preparation academies;</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="ID2d1e903adfca477f9db369fecb71eb84">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <text>a description of
			 how the authorization and approval of teacher or principal preparation
			 academies is separate and distinct from the requirements otherwise established
			 by the State for approval of other teacher or principal preparation
			 programs;</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="IDdae2874ac8f2463585638fcfc730166a">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
          <text>a description of
			 the process the State authorizer will use to authorize and approve a teacher or
			 principal preparation academy that—</text>
					<subparagraph id="IDd47f1aa2c1134dad9780faa131954995">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>enables
			 participants in the academy to be eligible for State financial aid to the same
			 extent as participants in other State-approved teacher or principal preparation
			 programs, including alternative certification, licensure, or credential
			 programs;</text>
					</subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="idB54001F2B2CB41348E998DCC95FC8E4B">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>enables teachers
			 who are teaching on alternative certificates, licenses, or credentials to teach
			 in the State while enrolled in a teacher preparation academy; and</text>
					</subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="ID39d6fac3d1c949f98e1614972065b15f">
            <enum>(C)</enum>
            <text>enables graduates
			 from teacher preparation academies to be eligible to teach in such State and
			 graduates from principal preparation academies to be eligible to be a principal
			 in a school in such State;</text>
					</subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="ID4f4a8bd633a24c37873612067de0a8ca">
          <enum>(5)</enum>
          <text>a description of
			 the process the State authorizer will use to monitor the success of—</text>
					<subparagraph id="ID0fdd575369974b86bd57810b1c6844ab">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>a teacher
			 preparation academy in—</text>
						<clause id="id3EB6F0D2A95A433F9D39D9BAB94E5475">
              <enum>(i)</enum>
              <text>producing
			 effective teachers that demonstrate a track record of success in getting
			 students on track to being college and career ready, based on multiple measures
			 of student achievement; and</text>
						</clause>
            <clause id="id6BADB65914594FEC905ACF72E3611ED1">
              <enum>(ii)</enum>
              <text>preparing
			 teachers to teach in high-needs schools or hard-to-staff subjects, such as
			 science, technology, engineering, mathematics, and computer science; and</text>
						</clause>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="IDd7662f2a99204e5787a5c5d618e63d99">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>a principal
			 preparation academy in—</text>
						<clause id="idB43271863C544342A49DB8FEC9E8C6D9">
              <enum>(i)</enum>
              <text>producing
			 effective principals that demonstrate a track record of success in getting
			 students in a school on track to being career and college ready; and</text>
						</clause>
            <clause id="idB17C7845C2E24107B8B4657F1AEFDD01">
              <enum>(ii)</enum>
              <text>preparing
			 principals to serve in high-needs schools or hard-to-staff subjects;</text>
						</clause>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="IDd06ba63554804c7a93c671fea4c69ce6">
          <enum>(6)</enum>
          <text>the criteria the
			 State authorizer will apply in renewing or denying a teacher or principal
			 preparation academy’s charter, including the minimum number and percentage of
			 effective teachers or principals such academy must produce in order to renew
			 its charter; and</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="id28596DD1DE1748D1874E704359CE6CAF">
          <enum>(7)</enum>
          <text>an assurance that
			 the State will recognize a certificate of completion (from a teacher or
			 principal preparation academy that is not, or is unaffiliated with, an
			 institution of higher education), as at least the equivalent of a master’s
			 degree in education for the purposes of teacher or principal hiring, retention,
			 compensation, and promotion in the State.</text>
				</paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="ID46d4301d16a94f528df1926ab5243d54">
        <enum>(c)</enum>
        <header>Uses of
			 funds</header>
        <text>A State receiving a grant under this Act shall use grant
			 funds to—</text>
				<paragraph id="ID18e84462cfb549488a6d25db6c01f2c2">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>implement a
			 process by which to—</text>
					<subparagraph id="id63990F46D48D478BBB6E424E8292CA1D">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>create or
			 designate State authorizers; and</text>
					</subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="id5AF3E4ED7C2944D1B8FB8A9F0A7AAC75">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>create or approve
			 teacher or principal preparation academies;</text>
					</subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="ID6119da52c8a344558773366c6cd1cff1">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>support, directly
			 or through a nonprofit intermediary organization, the establishment and
			 operation of teacher or principal preparation academies by assisting entities
			 with the planning, program design, and implementation of such programs;
			 and</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="ID68a267893129433c907afab6dfd2a244">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <text>award subgrants
			 to teacher or principal preparation academies in the State in accordance with
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="GREAT Teachers and Principles Act/s:5" proposed="true">section 5</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
				</paragraph>
      </subsection>
    </section>
    <section id="ID3e481a861c79473d8a322488a2b01a80">
      <enum>5.</enum>
      <header>Subgrants to
			 teacher or principal preparation academies</header>
			<subsection id="IDf9d986a690c747d2be98159119531c44">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>In
			 general</header>
        <text>From the amounts made available under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="GREAT Teachers and Principles Act/s:4/ss:c/p:3" proposed="true">section 4(c)(3)</cato:entity-ref>, a
			 State shall award subgrants to nonprofit entities to carry out activities
			 described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="GREAT Teachers and Principles Act/s:5/ss:d" proposed="true">subsection (d)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
			</subsection>
      <subsection id="IDa87110c88782474b892ff81476b7eb54">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Applications</header>
        <text>Each
			 nonprofit entity desiring a subgrant under this section from a State shall
			 submit an application to a State authorizer designated by the State to receive
			 such applications. The application shall include, at a minimum—</text>
				<paragraph id="ID9932464162984be0be94d73bdef50c0b">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>a description of
			 the teacher or principal preparation academy's proposed curriculum, training of
			 teacher or principal candidates (including clinical training), and approach to
			 teacher or principal development;</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="ID1f652b66eba84e2f805e040223144c18">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>the student
			 achievement outcomes the entity will require of academy graduates before
			 conferring a degree or certificate of completion from the program, with
			 timelines for obtaining such outcomes;</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="ID79909cfb2b4e4d2fb9f1bd5a321298ee">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <text>a multi-year
			 financial and operating model for the entity;</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="IDdb629827c209455aa21a8fff46310d86">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
          <text>the
			 qualifications of the entity’s chief executive officer or organization leader;
			 and</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="id494578B4D8A548DBA0CEE2D0F9346C33">
          <enum>(5)</enum>
          <text>a description of
			 how the teacher or principal preparation academy is designed to prepare
			 teachers or principals to serve in high-need areas (including rural areas and
			 Native American communities), or hard-to-staff subjects.</text>
				</paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="IDf32caa81ba3a4f3ab217cdebc558f722">
        <enum>(c)</enum>
        <header>Priority</header>
        <text>In
			 awarding subgrants under this section, a State shall give a priority to
			 entities proposing to expand previously existing teacher or principal
			 preparation programs, as of the date of application, with a demonstrated track
			 record of success in getting students on track to being college and career
			 ready.</text>
			</subsection>
      <subsection id="ID3fb8ffb92e564e34afc0f30acc78e860">
        <enum>(d)</enum>
        <header>Uses of
			 funds</header>
        <text>An entity that receives a subgrant under this section shall
			 use its subgrant—</text>
				<paragraph id="IDe538947044a9404da6fab39d828bdfc6">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>to establish a
			 teacher or principal preparation academy;</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="ID481754cc5f934970aad6b2268472eb3d">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>to expand the
			 capacity of a teacher or principal preparation academy;</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="ID494809d896f14ccf97a27379655e717b">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <text>to measure the
			 effectiveness of a teacher or principal preparation academy in improving
			 student academic achievement, as demonstrated by getting students on track to
			 be college and career ready; or</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="ID5f2c25c8436343a8ac3af91084db143a">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
          <text>to recruit
			 candidates for a teacher or principal preparation academy who have demonstrated
			 strong potential to be effective teachers or principals, based on a rigorous,
			 competency-based selection process that reviews a candidate's prior academic
			 achievement or record of professional accomplishment.</text>
				</paragraph>
      </subsection>
    </section>
    <section commented="no" id="IDa3dbd9711fd24cca96172df7ea87ee49">
      <enum>6.</enum>
      <header>Coordination
			 with the Corporation for National and Community Service</header>
			<subsection id="IDdfb17307f0614629a70e033122658037">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Interagency
			 agreement</header>
        <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="9100">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall enter into an interagency agreement
			 with the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="9577">Corporation for National and Community Service</cato:entity-ref> under <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="National and Community Service Act of 1990/s:121/ss:b">section 121(b) of
			 the National and Community Service Act of 1990</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12571">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/42/12571/b">42 U.S.C. 12571(b)</cato:entity-ref>
            </external-xref>)</cato:entity> under which
			 the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="9577">Corporation</cato:entity-ref> shall approve positions, for candidates at each teacher or
			 principal preparation academy that receives financial assistance under this
			 Act, as approved national service positions, as defined in <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="National and Community Service Act of 1990/s:101">section 101 of the
			 National and Community Service Act of 1990</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12511">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/42/12511">42 U.S.C. 12511</cato:entity-ref>
            </external-xref>)</cato:entity>. Such interagency
			 agreement shall specify how a degree or certificate of completion for a term of
			 service as a participant at a teacher or principal preparation academy will be
			 submitted to the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="9577">Corporation</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
			</subsection>
      <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ID459a460c39794e219eb1bffc5c9a3578">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Special
			 rule</header>
        <text>Notwithstanding <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="National and Community Service Act of 1990/s:148">section 148 of the National and Community
			 Service Act of 1990</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12604">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/42/12604">42 U.S.C. 12604</cato:entity-ref>
            </external-xref>)</cato:entity>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="9100">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="9577">Chief Executive
			 Officer of the Corporation for National and Community Service</cato:entity-ref> shall develop a
			 program under which national service educational awards may be disbursed to a
			 teacher or principal preparation academy to cover or reimburse the costs of
			 attending the academy.</text>
			</subsection>
    </section>
    <section id="IDf23c02faea0345218b646a8de9ee65a6">
      <enum>7.</enum>
      <header>Authorization of
			 appropriations</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">
        <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="auth-auth-approp">There are
			 authorized to be appropriated <cato:property name="purpose">to carry out <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="GREAT Teachers and Principles Act" proposed="true">this Act</cato:entity-ref>
          </cato:property> <cato:funds-and-year amount="indefinite" year="2014,2015,2016,2017,2018">such sums as may be
			 necessary for each of fiscal years 2014 through 2018</cato:funds-and-year>.</cato:entity>
      </text>
		</section>
  </legis-body>
</bill>
</doc>