<doc><docmeta id="113s101is">
    <bill congress="113" type="s" number="101" version="is"/>
    <revision id="5" commit-time="2013-03-07T23:25:32+00:00" comitter="/users/favila.xml" doc="/docs/113s101is/5.xml" status="complete"><description/></revision>
</docmeta><bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" public-private="public">
	<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
		<congress>113th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. 101</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20130123" legis-day="20130103">January 23
			 (legislative day, January 3), 2013</action-date>
			<action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="S299">Mr. Vitter</sponsor> introduced
			 the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the
			 <committee-name committee-id="SSBK00">Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban
			 Affairs</committee-name>
      </action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To prohibit the provision of Federal funds to State and
		  local governments for payment of obligations, to prohibit the Board of
		  Governors of the Federal Reserve System from financially assisting State and
		  local governments, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body>
		<section id="id6DB85E49459A4BFD93AA0603A4732E54" section-type="section-one">
      <enum>1.</enum>
      <header>Prohibition on the use of
			 Federal funds to pay State and local obligations</header>
			<subsection id="id2B3E640504E04CC595F7231A57BEA922">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>In
			 general</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any
			 other provision of law, no Federal funds may be used to purchase or guarantee
			 obligations of, issue lines of credit to, or provide direct or indirect
			 grants-and-aid to, any State government, municipal government, local
			 government, or county government which, on or after January 26, 2011, has
			 defaulted on its obligations, is at risk of defaulting, or is likely to
			 default, absent such assistance from the United States Government.</text>
			</subsection>
      <subsection id="ID296be60133d94a539ec59e83736218f0">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Limit on Use of
			 Borrowed Funds</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary
			 of the Treasury</cato:entity-ref> shall not, directly or indirectly, use general fund revenues or
			 funds borrowed pursuant to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc/31">title 31, United States Code</cato:entity-ref>, to purchase or
			 guarantee any asset or obligation of any State government, municipal
			 government, local government, or county government, or otherwise to assist such
			 government entity, if, on or after January 26, 2011, that State government,
			 municipal government, or county government has defaulted on its obligations, is
			 at risk of defaulting, or is likely to default, absent such assistance from the
			 United States Government.</text>
			</subsection>
      <subsection id="idCC0D84C4A8CC418AB19149C9192CAA6A">
        <enum>(c)</enum>
        <header>Prohibition on
			 Federal Reserve assistance</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law,
			 the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="9559">Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System</cato:entity-ref> shall not provide or
			 extend to, or authorize with respect to, any State government, municipal
			 government, local government, county government, or other entity that has
			 taxing authority or bonding authority, any funds, loan guarantees, credits, or
			 any other financial instrument or other authority, including the purchasing of
			 the bonds of such State, municipality, locality, county, or other bonding
			 authority, or to otherwise assist such government entity under any authority of
			 the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="9559">Board of Governors</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
			</subsection>
      <subsection id="IDcbc55ddddba9455986ede940c2d6dacb">
        <enum>(d)</enum>
        <header>Limitation</header>
        <text>
          <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="113s101is/s:1/ss:a..c" proposed="true">Subsections
			 (a) through (c)</cato:entity-ref> shall not apply to Federal assistance provided in response to a
			 natural disaster.</text>
			</subsection>
    </section>
  </legis-body>
</bill></doc>