<doc>
  <docmeta id="113sres459ats">
    <bill congress="113" type="sres" number="459" version="ats"/>
    <revision size="3887" annotations="0" status="complete" id="4" commit-time="2014-08-27T18:58:04Z" committer="mnewby" doc="113sres459ats/4.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <resolution xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print">
	<metadata>
<dublinCore>
<dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">113 SRES 459 ATS: Expressing the sense of the Senate with respect to childhood stroke and recognizing May 2014 as “National Pediatric Stroke Awareness Month”. </dc:title>
<dc:publisher xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">2014-05-22</dc:date>
<dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">113th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session display="yes">2d Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. RES. 459</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20140522">May 22, 2014</action-date>
			<action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="S341">Mr. Blumenthal</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S290">Mr. Chambliss</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was considered and agreed to</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">Expressing the sense of the Senate with
		  respect to childhood stroke and recognizing May 2014 as <quote>National
		  Pediatric Stroke Awareness Month</quote>. </official-title>
	</form>
	<preamble>
		<whereas>
      <text>Whereas a stroke, also known as cerebrovascular disease,
			 is an acute neurologic injury that occurs when the blood supply to a part
			 of
			 the brain is interrupted by a clot in the artery or a burst of the
			 artery;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas a stroke is a medical emergency that can cause
			 permanent neurologic damage or even death if not promptly diagnosed and
			 treated;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas a stroke occurs in approximately 1 out of every
			 3,500 live births,  and 4.6 out of 100,000 children ages 19 and under
			 experience a stroke each year;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas a stroke can occur before birth;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas stroke is among the top 12 causes of death for
			 children between the ages of 1 and 14 in the United States;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas 20 to 40 percent of children who have suffered a
			 stroke die as a result;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas a stroke recurs within 5 years in 10 percent of
			 children who have had an ischemic or hemorrhagic stroke;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the death rate for children who experience a
			 stroke before the age of 1 is the highest out of all child age
			 groups;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas there are no approved therapies for the treatment
			 of acute stroke in infants and children;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas approximately 60 percent of infants and children
			 who have a pediatric stroke will have serious, permanent neurological
			 disabilities, including paralysis, seizures, speech and vision problems,
			 and
			 attention, learning, and behavioral difficulties;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas such disabilities may require ongoing physical
			 therapy and surgeries;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the permanent health concerns of and treatments
			 for strokes that occur during childhood and young adulthood
			 have
			 considerable impacts on children, families, and society;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas more information is necessary regarding the cause, treatment,
			 and prevention of pediatric strokes;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas medical research is the only means by which the
			 people of the United States can identify and develop effective treatment
			 and
			 prevention strategies for pediatric strokes; and</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas early diagnosis and treatment of pediatric strokes
			 greatly improves the chances that an affected child will recover and not
			 experience a recurrence of a stroke: Now, therefore, be it</text>
		</whereas>
  </preamble>
	<resolution-body>
		<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="S1" section-type="undesignated-section">
      <enum/>
      <text>That the <cato:entity-ref entity-id="0010" entity-type="federal-body">Senate</cato:entity-ref>—</text>
      <paragraph id="id08e85693e5e94b20b95dc49ee5315f92">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text>recognizes May
			 2014 as <quote>National Pediatric Stroke Awareness Month</quote>;</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id0d6ce9fc5d734a25886ce9f4b8437d3f">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text>urges the people
			 of the United States to support the efforts, programs, services, and
			 organizations that enhance public awareness of pediatric stroke;</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id5538e27606b84654820d2d3a8f92f767">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <text>supports the work
			 of the <cato:entity-ref entity-id="7529" entity-type="federal-body">National Institutes of Health</cato:entity-ref> in pursuit of medical progress on
			 pediatric stroke; and</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0ac19d365396413c990e41cda1e9dbc0">
        <enum>(4)</enum>
        <text>urges continued
			 coordination and cooperation between the Federal Government, State and
			 local
			 governments, researchers, families, and the public to improve treatments
			 and
			 prognoses for children who suffer from strokes.</text>
			</paragraph>
    </section>
  </resolution-body>
</resolution>
</doc>