<doc>
  <docmeta id="113s1745is">
    <bill congress="113" type="s" number="1745" version="is"/>
    <revision size="12183" annotations="0" status="complete" id="5" commit-time="2013-12-13T19:24:37Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113s1745is/5.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public">
  <metadata>
<dublinCore>
<dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">113 S1745 IS: Somalia Stabilization Act of 2013</dc:title>
<dc:publisher xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">2013-11-20</dc:date>
<dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
    <congress>113th CONGRESS</congress>
    <session>1st Session</session>
    <legis-num>S. 1745</legis-num>
    <current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
    <action>
      <action-date date="20131120">November 20, 2013</action-date>
      <action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="S337">Mr. Coons</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations</committee-name>
      </action-desc>
    </action>
    <legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
    <official-title>To promote security, stability and good governance in Somalia through a coordinated interagency strategy that supports the consolidation of recent security and political gains in Somalia.</official-title>
  </form>
  <legis-body>
    <section id="S1" section-type="section-one">
      <enum>1.</enum>
      <header>Short title</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the
		  <quote>
          <short-title>
            Somalia Stabilization Act of 2013
          </short-title>
        </quote>.</text>
    </section>
    <section id="id85f9173c71454d4483ffb2ed0f8e3f58">
      <enum>2.</enum>
      <header>Findings</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">
        <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> makes the following findings:</text>
      <paragraph id="id2fb3c546ef3840ada5460fca2e4a4aa0">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text>Since the collapse of the Siad Barre regime in 1991, Somalia has struggled to rebuild a government and assert order and control over warlords, clan militias, and extremist groups.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id366d3558025e4b02a3d79f1994470490">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text>The lack of functioning state and governing structures led to chronic humanitarian need within Somalia and enabled terrorist groups, maritime crime, illicit trafficking, and mass refugee flows to flourish.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id460f74b877d94ae4a0a26262f7d0e61d">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <text>In 2007, the Ethiopian military ousted the Islamic Courts Union and the United Nations authorized the African Union to deploy a peacekeeping force to Somalia, the African Union Mission to Somalia (AMISOM), in order to support the Transitional Federal Government to establish order in Somalia. AMISOM currently consists of  troops from Burundi, Djibouti, Kenya, Sierra Leone, and Uganda.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id0af163034d904a5b95594217f8583b4c">
        <enum>(4)</enum>
        <text>In 2008, Harakat al-Shabaab al-Mujahideen (al-Shabaab) was designated a Foreign Terrorist Organization and a Specially Designated Global Terrorist entity by the United States Government.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id63f71ff4a15042cab5cb3a0e6dba8e64">
        <enum>(5)</enum>
        <text>In 2010, al-Shabaab took control of southern and central Somalia and instituted strict Sharia law.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="ide24eeb0bc04948b384c65b2e6065bc3c">
        <enum>(6)</enum>
        <text>In July 2010, Al-Shabaab retaliated against a contributor to AMISOM by carrying out an attack in Kampala, Uganda, which killed 74 people and injured 70 others.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="idc6641e36ac1c4dd696bf657b443a1e81">
        <enum>(7)</enum>
        <text>In 2010, in response to growing al-Shabaab dominance and brutality, the AMISOM mandate was expanded to directly target and counter al-Shabaab in Somalia.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id268a8088e346431287dd0c7632b56833">
        <enum>(8)</enum>
        <text>In 2011 and 2012, when many parts of the country were suffering from severe food insecurity and famine, al-Shabaab denied humanitarian access to its residents, resulting in the death of close to 260,000 people and acute food insecurity for millions.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id052f42da21c04b688a1f57fc8675e039">
        <enum>(9)</enum>
        <text>In 2011, the Kenyan Defense Force joined AMISOM, to help take control of urban areas like Mogadishu and Kismayo from al-Shabaab control.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id74e63bde715340d2acaedaa6f5b7afa0">
        <enum>(10)</enum>
        <text>In 2012, improved security in much of urban Somalia enabled the Transitional Federal Government to complete a draft constitution and end its transitional term.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="idf5a9323986d840629f7d7414e03d5842">
        <enum>(11)</enum>
        <text>In 2012, a regionally representative Somali constituent assembly elected a new Federal parliament, which in turn elected President Hassan Sheikh Mohamud.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="ide0a8277b5648475a9f8ad4dce4218321">
        <enum>(12)</enum>
        <text>The United States, Arab and European countries, the United Nations, and the African Union officially recognized the new Somali government, citing the process that created it as being the most credible and inclusive process to date.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id8da2b198976c47f89ea1c25ecd8a4e7a">
        <enum>(13)</enum>
        <text>On March 6, 2013, the United Nations Security Council passed Resolution 2093, creating a new exemption to the  21-year-old arms embargo for a period of 12 months, to allow for <quote>deliveries of weapons or military equipment or the provision of advice, assistance or training, intended solely for the development of the National Security Forces of the Federal Government of Somalia</quote>,  and calling  for the training, equipping, and capacity-building of Somali Security Forces, including both its armed forces and police, with special focus on the development of infrastructure to <quote>ensure the safe storage, registration, maintenance and distribution of military equipment,</quote> and <quote>procedures and codes of conduct … for the registration, distribution, use, and storage of weapons</quote>.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id19bfe299de084727a36ca505bd7058fd">
        <enum>(14)</enum>
        <text>On May 2, 2013, the United National Security Council passed Resolution 2102, establishing the United Nations Assistance Mission in Somalia (UNSOM) under the leadership of a Special Representative of the Secretary-General to support the Government of Somalia with peace-building, state-building and governance, as well as the coordination of international assistance.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id24a4f266e95d49caa1781e660cf5ea0a">
        <enum>(15)</enum>
        <text>Though greeted with great optimism, the Government of Somalia  has run into many challenges, which has stalled its efforts to finalize the constitution, guide the structure of the new state, or provide services to the population.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id7710b6ee933246be8c1c20bca6d728c0">
        <enum>(16)</enum>
        <text>President Hassan Sheikh Mohamud and his government have committed to the completion of these tasks and to holding a constitutional referendum and national election by 2016.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id0f5fedf9614e46efa4d7145368fb03eb">
        <enum>(17)</enum>
        <text>On September 16, 2013, the international community and a high level Somali delegation endorsed a compact based on the <quote>New Deal Strategy for Engagement in Fragile States.</quote> Donors pledged $2,400,000,000 over three years to support Somali development priorities, including $69,000,000 from the United States.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id89262a2e5a024f60b0826fd621154cf8">
        <enum>(18)</enum>
        <text>Al Shabaab continues to use terrorist tactics to attack soft targets. On September 21–24, 2013, al-Shabaab perpetrated an attack on the Westgate mall in Nairobi, Kenya, killing at least 67 people.</text>
      </paragraph>
    </section>
    <section id="id99dfed8e5965490695a3afb85a195760">
      <enum>3.</enum>
      <header>Sense of Congress</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> that the United States should—</text>
      <paragraph id="id57368296eef74254932537ee4750eb6c">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text>support the Somali Federal Government, regional administrations, Federal units, and people in their ongoing efforts to consolidate political gains and develop credible, transparent, and  representative government systems and institutions, and foster complementary processes at the local, regional, and national levels;</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id9c959dc8d5014cf3ad7dd320a8698e6d">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text>continue to support African-led regional efforts to improve security and stability in Somalia, including through the African Union Mission to Somalia (AMISOM) and the United Nations Assistance Mission in Somalia (UNSOM);</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id4140a0e4497347faa7f16242b0c7b7ef">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <text>support the people and Government of Somalia  to develop professional and regionally and ethnically representative Somali security forces that are capable of maintaining and expanding security within Somalia, confronting international security threats such as terrorism, and preventing human rights abuses;</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id513b074d893d4ae8ba2c6704402288d5">
        <enum>(4)</enum>
        <text>continue to provide lifesaving humanitarian assistance as needed, while bolstering resilience and building a foundation for sustained, inclusive development for the people of Somalia; and</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id66863b5bb9c14df6bc2275d3892548d7">
        <enum>(5)</enum>
        <text>carry out all diplomatic, economic, intelligence, military, and development activities in Somalia within the context of a comprehensive strategy coordinated through an interagency process.</text>
      </paragraph>
    </section>
    <section id="idbffa8238f27a40fd9c7ada3c82b99ed8">
      <enum>4.</enum>
      <header>Requirement of a strategy to support the consolidation of security and governance gains in Somalia</header>
      <subsection id="idc1108ca7b15144afbbfbf08ebf12c2b2">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Requirement for strategy</header>
        <text>Not later than 120 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> shall submit to the appropriate committees of <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> a strategy to guide future United States action in support of the Government and people of Somalia to foster economic growth and opportunity, counter armed threats to stability, and develop credible, transparent, and representative government systems and institutions.</text>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="id583416dc560b414eb3fd4c7a58992f56">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Content of strategy</header>
        <text>The strategy required under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Somalia Stabilization Act of 2013/s:4/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref> should include the following elements:</text>
        <paragraph id="id0b870df2ecdf49529b9dac9491b213c6">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>A clearly stated policy toward Somalia on supporting the consolidation of political gains at the national level, while also encouraging and supporting complementary processes at the local and regional levels.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="ided4b341d80354580aede31cb0006418b">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>Measures to support the development goals identified by the people and Government of Somalia.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="idc00b452a705240ca8ad7100eb2ad6c1c">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <text>Plans for strengthening efforts by the Government of Somalia, the African Union, and regional governments to stabilize the security situation within Somalia and further degrade al-Shabaab’s capabilities, in order to enable the eventual transfer of security operations to Somali security forces capable of—</text>
          <subparagraph id="idFA23FBF908304F608220108D746EEACC">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>maintaining and expanding security within Somalia;</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="idCB4D6FDBE8AF45188FD478730B97D427">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>confronting international security threats; and</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="id0DFD7484C2914FBD9CA6F72DE9BC50CF">
            <enum>(C)</enum>
            <text>preventing human rights abuses.</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="id854cbb5ee4bd4b3b824eeae6dc5d1f54">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
          <text>Plans for supporting the development and professionalization of regionally and ethnically representative Somali security forces, including  the infrastructure and procedures required to ensure chain of custody and the safe storage of military equipment and an assessment of the benefits and risks of the provision of weaponry to the Somali security forces by the United States.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="id85c1526d3d33484491438e42648dfe0d">
          <enum>(5)</enum>
          <text>A description of United States  national security objectives addressed through military-to-military cooperation activities with Somali security forces.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="id1c86dcaaaba84fa2a36478fc81492fa6">
          <enum>(6)</enum>
          <text>A description of security risks to United States  personnel conducting security cooperation activities within Somalia and plans to assist the Somali security forces in preventing infiltration and insider attacks, including through the application of lessons learned in United States  military training efforts in Afghanistan.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="idb3ec917278ab4c09af90a41bed787f0f">
          <enum>(7)</enum>
          <text>A description of United States tools for monitoring and responding to violations of the United Nations Security Council arms embargo, charcoal ban, and other international agreements affecting the stability of Somalia.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="idff10e95c7d8a4ee08358e7658868491a">
          <enum>(8)</enum>
          <text>A description of mechanisms for coordinating United States  military and non-military assistance with other international donors, regional governments, and relevant multilateral organizations.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="idc6e2a2cf0bf84efb8d9b80e0c383129e">
          <enum>(9)</enum>
          <text>Plans to increase United States  diplomatic engagement with Somalia, including through the future establishment of an embassy or other diplomatic posts in Mogadishu.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="id62b9fa4df241478e9c697d49b1a6fcb5">
          <enum>(10)</enum>
          <text>Any other element the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> determines appropriate.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="id4ab800cde103458a9130c48d000d08e2">
        <enum>(c)</enum>
        <header>Reports</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days from the submission of the strategy required under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Somalia Stabilization Act of 2013/s:4/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref>, and annually thereafter for three years, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> shall submit to the appropriate committees of <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> an update on implementation of the strategy and progress made in Somalia in security, stability, development, and governance.</text>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="idd79441a9abd94fac849272639fb0dbf2">
        <enum>(d)</enum>
        <header>Form</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The strategy under this section shall be submitted in unclassified form, but may include a classified annex. The reports may take the form of a briefing, unclassified report, or unclassified report with a classified annex.</text>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="idfa95e77164a945eb9ec3c13da20ab36a">
        <enum>(e)</enum>
        <header>Appropriate committees of congress defined</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <term>appropriate committees of Congress</term> means—</text>
        <paragraph id="id464f4b5389a244de944adc295a257929">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="committee" entity-id="SSAP00">Committee on Appropriations</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="committee" entity-id="SSAS00">Committee on Armed Services</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="committee" entity-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations</cato:entity-ref>, and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="committee" entity-id="SLIN00">Select Committee on Intelligence of the Senate</cato:entity-ref>; and</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="id29174d26bdc146268fbcdeef9584ec4c">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="committee" entity-id="HAP00">Committee on Appropriations</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="committee" entity-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="committee" entity-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</cato:entity-ref>, and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="committee" entity-id="HIG00">Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence of the House of Representatives</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
    </section>
  </legis-body>
</bill>
</doc>