<doc>
  <docmeta id="113sres242is">
    <bill congress="113" type="sres" number="242" version="is"/>
    <revision size="2267" annotations="0" status="complete" id="3" commit-time="2013-09-23T18:54:59Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113sres242is/3.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <resolution xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print">
  <metadata>
<dublinCore>
<title>113 SRES 242 IS: Supporting the goals and ideals of “Growth Awareness Week”.</title>
<publisher>U.S. Senate</publisher>
<date>2013-09-19</date>
<format>text/xml</format>
<language>EN</language>
<rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code>
    <congress display="yes">113th CONGRESS</congress>
    <session display="yes">1st Session</session>
    <legis-num>S. RES. 242</legis-num>
    <current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
    <action display="yes">
      <action-date date="20130919">September 19, 2013</action-date>
      <action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="S339">Mr. Kirk</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>
      </action-desc>
    </action>
    <legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
    <official-title display="yes">Supporting the goals and ideals of <quote>Growth Awareness Week</quote>.</official-title>
  </form>
  <preamble>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas, according to the Pictures of Standard Syndromes and Undiagnosed Malformations database (commonly known as the <quote>POSSUM</quote> database), more than 600 serious diseases and health conditions cause growth failure;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas health conditions that cause growth failure may affect the overall health of a child;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas short stature may be a symptom of a serious underlying health condition;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas growth failure in children is often undiagnosed;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas, according to the MAGIC Foundation for Children’s Growth, 48 percent of children in the United States who were evaluated for the 2 most common causes of growth failure were undiagnosed with growth failure;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the longer a child with growth failure goes undiagnosed, the greater the potential for damage and higher costs of care;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas early detection and a diagnosis of growth failure are crucial to ensure a healthy future for a child with growth failure;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas raising public awareness of, and educating the public about, growth failure is a vital public service;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas providing resources for identification of growth failure will allow for early detection; and</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the MAGIC Foundation for Children's Growth has designated the third week of September as <quote>Growth Awareness Week</quote>: Now, therefore, be it</text>
    </whereas>
  </preamble>
  <resolution-body>
    <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="S1" section-type="undesignated-section">
      <enum/>
      <text>That the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0010">Senate</cato:entity-ref>—</text>
      <paragraph id="id8ed71cc5fef44a8187e2e6189789dfa5">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text>designates the third week of September 2013 as <quote>Growth Awareness Week</quote>; and</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="idb90d37ccec5c40b7a436362f04491e2e">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text>supports the goals and ideals of <quote>Growth Awareness Week</quote>.</text>
      </paragraph>
    </section>
  </resolution-body>
</resolution>
</doc>