<doc>
  <docmeta id="113s298rs">
    <bill congress="113" type="s" number="298" version="rs"/>
    <revision size="13547" annotations="0" status="complete" id="5" commit-time="2013-09-20T15:14:13Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113s298rs/5.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <bill bill-stage="Reported-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public">
	<metadata>
<dublinCore>
<title>113 S298 RS: North Korea Nonproliferation and Accountability Act of 2013</title>
<publisher>U.S. Senate</publisher>
<date/>
<format>text/xml</format>
<language>EN</language>
<rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
		<calendar>Calendar No. 16</calendar>
		<congress>113th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. 298</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date>February 13, 2013</action-date>
			<action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="S306">Mr. Menendez</sponsor> (for
			 himself, <cosponsor name-id="S310">Mr. Corker</cosponsor>,
			 <cosponsor name-id="S308">Mr. Cardin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S350">Mr.
			 Rubio</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S221">Mrs. Feinstein</cosponsor>,
			 <cosponsor name-id="S223">Mrs. Boxer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S236">Mr.
			 Inhofe</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S356">Mr. Donnelly</cosponsor>)
			 introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to
			 the<committee-name committee-id="SSFR00"> Committee on Foreign Relations of the
			 Senate</committee-name>
      </action-desc>
		</action>
		<action stage="Reported-in-Senate">
			<action-date>February 14, 2013</action-date>
			<action-desc>Reported by <sponsor name-id="S306">Mr.
			 Menendez</sponsor>, with amendments</action-desc>
			<action-instruction>Omit the part struck through and insert the part
			 printed in italic</action-instruction>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To prevent nuclear proliferation in North Korea, and for
		  other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body>
		<section id="S1" section-type="section-one">
      <enum>1.</enum>
      <header>Short
			 title</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as
			 the <quote>
          <short-title>North Korea Nonproliferation and
			 Accountability Act of 2013</short-title>
        </quote>.</text>
		</section>
    <section id="id78744A44F41A458C84B0B0247EBA65CA">
      <enum>2.</enum>
      <header>Findings</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">
        <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="0001" entity-type="federal-body">Congress</cato:entity-ref> makes the following
			 findings:</text>
			<paragraph id="id70279D51FBDB4C9E94025971E9A9F42C">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text>On February 12,
			 2013, the Government of North Korea declared that it had conducted its third
			 test of a nuclear device, following its first self-declared test on October 9,
			 2006, and its second test on May 25, 2009.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="idE0A3A9EFE4C14D0D93D5B62090107514">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text>United Nations
			 Security Council Resolution 1718, adopted on October 14, 2006, condemned the
			 nuclear test proclaimed by North Korea on October 9, 2006, in flagrant
			 disregard of its relevant resolutions, in particular Security Council
			 Resolution 1695 (2006), and demanded that North Korea not conduct any further
			 nuclear test or launch of a ballistic missile; immediately retract its
			 announcement of withdrawal from the Treaty on the Non-Proliferation of Nuclear
			 Weapons, done at Washington, London, and Moscow July 1, 1968, and entered into
			 force March 5, 1970 (NPT); and return to the NPT and International Atomic
			 Energy Agency (IAEA) safeguards.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id5DAC8100E133408CA072CB255D2E6B47">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <text>United Nations
			 Security Council Resolution 1718 further decided that North Korea shall suspend
			 all activities related to its ballistic missile program and in this context
			 re-establish its pre-existing commitments to a moratorium on missile launching;
			 shall abandon all nuclear weapons and existing nuclear programs in a complete,
			 verifiable, and irreversible manner; shall act strictly in accordance with the
			 obligations applicable to parties under the NPT and the terms and conditions of
			 its IAEA Safeguards Agreement; shall provide the IAEA transparency measures
			 extending beyond these requirements, including such access to individuals,
			 documentation, equipments and facilities as may be required and deemed
			 necessary by the IAEA; and shall abandon all other existing weapons of mass
			 destruction (WMD) and its ballistic missile program in a complete, verifiable,
			 and irreversible manner.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id1a5d748326fa4dd8996d6c2ca184d293">
        <enum>(4)</enum>
        <text>United Nations
			 Security Council Resolution 1718 also required United Nations Member States to
			 prevent—</text>
				<subparagraph id="id4388431A0DE242B2AF8D707FCC79BF08">
          <enum>(A)</enum>
          <text>transfers to, and
			 procurement from, North Korea of—</text>
					<clause id="idA5E999CE5B124EFA9E2F9B9C53CDB9F3">
            <enum>(i)</enum>
            <text>items, materials,
			 equipment, goods, and technology listed in the resolution; and</text>
					</clause>
          <clause id="id7A3E75466770448E95A2F8ABCDA485B5">
            <enum>(ii)</enum>
            <text>other items,
			 determined by the Security Council or the 1718 Committee, which could
			 contribute to North Korea’s nuclear-related, ballistic missile-related, or
			 other weapons of mass destruction-related programs;</text>
					</clause>
        </subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="idDD65DF1BE31C4B139D35FC7D5F3B4BF2">
          <enum>(B)</enum>
          <text>certain military
			 equipment or technology transfers related to the prohibited items; and</text>
				</subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="id0CD988EEEC9A4933BF5A0BA9ADA4F531">
          <enum>(C)</enum>
          <text>the transfer of
			 luxury goods to North Korea.</text>
				</subparagraph>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="ida01e8914754544159679d025a6e6ea8c">
        <enum>(5)</enum>
        <text>United Nations
			 Security Council Resolution 1718 further required United Nations Member States
			 to prevent the entry into and transit through their territories of individuals
			 designated by the Security Council or the 1718 Committee as being responsible
			 for North Korea’s ballistic missile-related, nuclear-related, or other weapons
			 of mass destruction-related programs, and the immediate freezing of funds,
			 other financial assets, and economic resources of persons or entities
			 designated by the Security Council or the 1718 Committee as being engaged in or
			 providing support for such programs, or by persons or entities acting on their
			 behalf or at their direction.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id47ffcd85ceb0437084e7441af7203e58">
        <enum>(6)</enum>
        <text>On May 25, 2009,
			 the Government of North Korea declared that it had conducted a second test of a
			 nuclear device.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="idd89343ce28d94da0b81903df80f98251">
        <enum>(7)</enum>
        <text>United Nations
			 Security Council Resolution 1874, adopted on June 12, 2009—</text>
				<subparagraph id="idF481E548BC4944E4BB51D96EE08FA76F">
          <enum>(A)</enum>
          <text>decided that
			 North Korea shall abandon all nuclear weapons and existing nuclear programs in
			 a complete, verifiable, and irreversible manner;</text>
				</subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="id3E6ABE62CB964C35AA2C82DB33111A98">
          <enum>(B)</enum>
          <text>authorized and
			 required United Nations Member States to seize and dispose of proscribed
			 illicit North Korea items related to its missile, nuclear, and WMD programs
			 identified in inspections called for by the resolution;</text>
				</subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="id43931B1756EE42C3A61D48A2E865EE64">
          <enum>(C)</enum>
          <text>banned the export
			 to North Korea of all arms and related material other than small arms and light
			 weapons; and</text>
				</subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="idF425FB9FEBA24F4C865DD8A24D1216FB">
          <enum>(D)</enum>
          <text>decided that
			 Member States shall—</text>
					<clause id="id0A48F53ADA1C44F4B93807545F3F03DC">
            <enum>(i)</enum>
            <text>prevent the
			 provision of financial services or the transfer to, through, or from their
			 territory of any financial or other assets or resources that could contribute
			 to North Korea’s nuclear-related, ballistic missile-related, or other
			 WMD-related programs or activities; and</text>
					</clause>
          <clause id="idC1BB144A332148F188E7010E380CCEFA">
            <enum>(ii)</enum>
            <text>deny fuel or
			 supplies to service the vessels carrying them except where necessary on
			 humanitarian grounds.</text>
					</clause>
        </subparagraph>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id05e7f8da1447469788af13b7ded852a4">
        <enum>(8)</enum>
        <text>On December 12,
			 2012, in flagrant defiance of past United Nations Security Council resolutions,
			 the international community, and its Six-Party partners, the Government of
			 North Korea launched a three-stage, long-range missile, which overflew Japanese
			 territory near Okinawa and dropped debris into the Yellow Sea, the East China
			 Sea, and waters adjacent to the Philippines.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id854DBF1AEF0C4D7D848286401EA8B5CB">
        <enum>(9)</enum>
        <text>The United
			 Nations Security Council adopted Security Council Resolution 2087 on January
			 22, 2013, which condemned North Korea's December 12, 2012, missile launch as a
			 breach of Security Council Resolutions 1718 and 1874, demanded that North Korea
			 <quote>abandon all nuclear weapons and existing nuclear programs in a complete,
			 verifiable, and irreversible manner,</quote> and expressed the determination of
			 the Security Council <quote>to take significant action in the event of a
			 further DPRK launch or nuclear test</quote>.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id7C9CD15FE37449A1B2FEECFE52C626D2">
        <enum>(10)</enum>
        <text>the transition
			 to the leadership of Kim Jong-Un after the death of Kim Jong-Il has introduced
			 new uncertainties, yet the fundamental human rights and humanitarian conditions
			 inside North Korea remain deplorable, thousands of North Koreans remain
			 imprisoned in modern-day gulags, North Korean refugees remain acutely
			 vulnerable, and the findings in the <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
            <cato:entity-ref value="North Korean Human Rights Act of 2004" entity-type="act">North Korean Human Rights Act of 2004</cato:entity-ref>
			 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/108/333">
              <cato:entity-ref value="public-law/108/333" entity-type="public-law">Public Law 108–333</cato:entity-ref>
            </external-xref>; <cato:entity-ref value="usc/22/7801/etseq" entity-type="uscode">
              <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/7801">22 U.S.C. 7801 et seq.</external-xref>
            </cato:entity-ref>)</cato:entity>, the <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
            <cato:entity-ref value="North Korean Human Rights Reauthorization Act of 2008" entity-type="act">North Korean Human Rights
			 Reauthorization Act of 2008</cato:entity-ref> (<cato:entity-ref value="public-law/110/346" entity-type="public-law">
              <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/110/346">Public Law 110–346</external-xref>
            </cato:entity-ref>)</cato:entity>, and the <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
            <cato:entity-ref value="Ambassador James R. Lilley and Congressman Stephen J. Solarz North Korea Human Rights Reauthorization Act of 2012" entity-type="act">Ambassador James R.
			 Lilley and Congressman Stephen J. Solarz North Korea Human Rights
			 Reauthorization Act of 2012</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/112/172">
              <cato:entity-ref value="public-law/112/172" entity-type="public-law">Public Law 112–172</cato:entity-ref>
            </external-xref>)</cato:entity> remain substantially accurate
			 today.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="idC502365AF7B54C0CB64B608418A71262">
        <enum>(11)</enum>
        <text>There has been
			 extensive military cooperation between the Governments of North Korea and Iran
			 that dates back to the 1980s.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="idAB21DC94641F4798B22EBB818D6CAFC3">
        <enum>(12)</enum>
        <text>The latest
			 provocative and defiant action by the Government of North Korea represents a
			 direct threat to the United States and to our regional allies and
			 partners.</text>
			</paragraph>
    </section>
    <section id="id43F1F6CF4F5A47EA92391B4AF6373A97">
      <enum>3.</enum>
      <header>Sense of
			 Congress</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="0001" entity-type="federal-body">Congress</cato:entity-ref> that—</text>
			<paragraph id="iddb5ef59699804e5bba77a5e093346820">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text>the test of a
			 nuclear device by the Government of North Korea on February 12, 2013, and the
			 missile launch of December 12, 2012, represent flagrant violations of the
			 sanctions regime created by United Nations Security Council Resolutions 1695
			 (2006), 1718 (2006), and 1874 (2009), the test of the nuclear device on
			 February 12, 2013, is a clear, deliberate, and provocative violation of United
			 Nations Security Resolution 2087 (2013), and the Government of North Korea
			 continues to defy the United Nations, its Six-Party partners, and the
			 international community;</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="idC8774FAA6F794EB99CF603A3B9038939">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text>all Member States
			 of the United Nations should immediately implement and enforce sanctions
			 imposed by these resolutions and censure North Korea;</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id893ed1af2f5349f88111293f6d20174b">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <text>the Government of
			 North Korea should abandon and dismantle its provocative ballistic missile and
			 nuclear weapons programs, cease its proliferation activities, and come into
			 immediate compliance with all United Nations Security Council resolutions and
			 its commitments under the 2005 Joint Statement of the Six-Party Talks;</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id86b4dff35ce745978f1b900788b874e8">
        <enum>(4)</enum>
        <text>restrictions
			 against the Government of North Korea, including sanctions that ban the
			 importation into the United States of unlicensed North Korean products and
			 goods, should remain in effect until the Government of North Korea no longer
			 engages in activities that threaten the United States, our allies and partners,
			 and global peace and stability;</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id9d0e6eefe4b74627901fc97baadbd193">
        <enum>(5)</enum>
        <text>the United States
			 Government should seek a new round of United Nations Security Council
			 sanctions, including the public identification of all North Korean and foreign
			 banks, business, and government agencies suspected of conduct that violates
			 United Nations Security Council resolutions, and implementing necessary
			 measures to ensure enforcement of such sanctions;</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="idb74e2d322f1745b39446ef256aff027d">
        <enum>(6)</enum>
        <text>all United
			 Nations Member States should—</text>
				<subparagraph id="id00509726564646A88465CB7F2449566E">
          <enum>(A)</enum>
          <text>further
			 strengthen efforts to prevent the transfer of military and dual-use
			 technologies to North Korea, including an expansion of the list of sanctioned
			 materials identified by the United Nations Panel of Experts on North Korea
			 sanctions and the items on the Nuclear Suppliers Group lists;</text>
				</subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="idEA241800218B484EBBE51DA9A7F0F214">
          <enum>(B)</enum>
          <text>exercise enhanced
			 vigilance including monitoring the activities of their nationals, persons in
			 their territories, financial institutions, and other entities with or on behalf
			 of financial institutions in North Korea, or of those that act on behalf or at
			 the direction of financial institutions in North Korea, including their
			 branches, representatives, agents, and subsidiaries abroad; and</text>
				</subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="idF54E9593499D4C3595BF832EEEF46229">
          <enum>(C)</enum>
          <text>prevent
			 transshipments that relate to North Korean military, missile, and nuclear
			 programs and proliferation activities;</text>
				</subparagraph>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id5486db623b0148dc8d51db9ada00354e">
        <enum>(7)</enum>
        <text>the United States
			 Government should explore
			 <deleted-phrase reported-display-style="strikethrough">all appropriate measures
			 for enhanced military operations by the United States Armed
			 Forces</deleted-phrase>
          <added-phrase reported-display-style="italic">appropriate measures by the United States Armed
			 Forces</added-phrase> in the Asia-Pacific region, including in partnership with
			 the armed forces of others countries in the region, to safeguard the national
			 interests, security, and livelihood of the United States and its people, as
			 well as those of United States allies and partners in the region; and</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id1df5e9a8b6fd4f2b865a54ccc49460e0">
        <enum>(8)</enum>
        <text>the United States
			 Government, acting through its appropriate diplomatic representatives, should
			 secure the agreement of the United Nations Human Rights Council and General
			 Assembly to adopt the recommendations made in the February 1, 2013, report of
			 Marzuki Darusman, Special Rapporteur on the situation of human rights in the
			 Democratic People’s Republic of Korea, that an inquiry mechanism should be
			 established to investigate North Korea’s <quote>grave, widespread and
			 systematic violations of human rights,</quote> as well as to analyze whether
			 crimes against humanity are being perpetrated in North Korea.</text>
			</paragraph>
    </section>
    <section id="idf4659c4d99bb41a7ba95f32ef7aed6de">
      <enum>4.</enum>
      <header>Report</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than May 15, 2013, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1900" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary
			 of State</cato:entity-ref> shall conduct, coordinate, and submit to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="0001" entity-type="federal-body">Congress</cato:entity-ref> a comprehensive
			 report on United States policy towards North Korea based on a full and complete
			 interagency review of current policy and possible alternatives, including North
			 Korea’s weapons of mass destruction and missile programs and human rights
			 atrocities. The report shall include recommendations for such legislative or
			 administrative action as the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1900" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> considers appropriate in light of the
			 results of the review.</text>
		</section>
    <section changed="added" id="id26D9049B4FAB4658A48CE5DCAA0F17B3" reported-display-style="italic">
      <enum>5.</enum>
      <header>Rule of
			 construction</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this
			 Act shall be construed as a declaration of war or an authorization for the use
			 of force against North Korea.</text>
		</section>
  </legis-body>
	<endorsement>
		<action-date>February 14, 2013</action-date>
		<action-desc>Reported with amendments</action-desc>
	</endorsement>
</bill>
</doc>