<doc>
  <docmeta id="113s867is">
    <bill congress="113" type="s" number="867" version="is"/>
    <revision size="10222" annotations="0" status="complete" id="5" commit-time="2013-07-15T19:17:01Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113s867is/5.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>113 S867 IS: Medicare Prescription Drug Program Integrity and Transparency Act of 2013</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2013-05-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
		<congress>113th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. 867</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20130506">May 6, 2013</action-date>
			<action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="S295">Mr. Pryor</sponsor> (for himself,
			 <cosponsor name-id="S347">Mr. Moran</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S318">Mr.
			 Wicker</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S343">Mr. Boozman</cosponsor>)
			 introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the
			 <committee-name committee-id="SSFI00">Committee on
			 Finance</committee-name>
      </action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to
		  provide for pharmacy benefits manager standards under the Medicare prescription
		  drug program, to establish basic audit standards of pharmacies, to further
		  transparency of payment methodology to pharmacies, and to provide for
		  recoupment returns to Medicare.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body>
		<section id="S1" section-type="section-one">
      <enum>1.</enum>
      <header>Short
			 title</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as
			 the <quote>
          <short-title>Medicare Prescription Drug Program
			 Integrity and Transparency Act of 2013</short-title>
        </quote>.</text>
		</section>
    <section id="id8f8bd790d28f44eb84f4b65f7d7ccb7b">
      <enum>2.</enum>
      <header>Pharmacy
			 benefits manager standards under the Medicare program</header>
			<subsection id="idb8f3f3a2c7be40448182a47ec7124612">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>In
			 general</header>
        <text>
          <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
            <cato:entity-ref value="Social Security Act/s:1860D–12/ss:b" entity-type="act">Section 1860D–12(b) of the Social Security Act</cato:entity-ref> (<cato:entity-ref value="usc/42/1395w–112/b" entity-type="uscode">42 U.S.C.
			 1395w–112(b)</cato:entity-ref>
          </cato:entity>) is amended by adding at the end the following new
			 paragraphs:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7cbdea08f636479bac211d2944502ee7" style="OLC">
					<paragraph id="idd327508c367b43de8129f5e0a8843cad">
            <enum>(7)</enum>
            <header>Pharmacy
				benefits manager transparency and proper operations requirements</header>
						<subparagraph id="id3C8DE4E4152045A691B0484B0ADB5125">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <header>In
				general</header>
              <text>Each contract entered into with a PDP sponsor under this
				part with respect to a prescription drug plan offered by such sponsor shall
				provide that the PDP may not enter into a contract with any pharmacy benefits
				manager (referred to in this paragraph as a <quote>PBM</quote>) to manage the
				prescription drug coverage provided under such plan, or to control the costs of
				the prescription drug coverage under such plan, unless the PBM satisfies the
				requirements described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" proposed="true" value="Medicare Prescription Drug Program Integrity and Transparency Act of 2013/s:1860D-12/ss:b/p:7/sp:B" entity-type="act">subparagraph (B)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
						</subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="id29A79A6AD6B54D60B2F6869C9373D997">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <header>Requirements</header>
              <text>The
				requirements described in this subparagraph are as follows:</text>
							<clause id="id1e7d4f24991c43c1a2c50ab76c0d1674">
                <enum>(i)</enum>
                <header>Proper audit
				procedures</header>
                <text>The following shall apply to each audit of a pharmacy
				conducted by or for the pharmacy benefits manager with respect to such
				prescription drug plan:</text>
								<subclause id="ida795319554ea471381e7c84b9409d900">
                  <enum>(I)</enum>
                  <header>Assuring
				recoveries to Medicare</header>
									<item id="id5af3af4e2ea84f089262518c27af4b4d">
                    <enum>(aa)</enum>
                    <text>The PBM (or
				auditing entity) shall disclose the amount of each payment recovered pursuant
				to the audit to the PDP sponsor with a copy to the pharmacy.</text>
									</item>
                  <item id="id54b745bd56fd438fa3647a3944932b67">
                    <enum>(bb)</enum>
                    <text>Any payment
				recovered by the PBM (or auditing entity) pursuant to the audit shall be
				returned to the PDP sponsor.</text>
									</item>
                </subclause>
                <subclause id="idd2fb4f8b7e384bc986e060d62e9ab1d3">
                  <enum>(II)</enum>
                  <header>Assuring
				clinical decisions in audits</header>
									<item id="id1e1706e3a3074704a3a9851ffc1d04e0">
                    <enum>(aa)</enum>
                    <text>In
				the case the audit involves clinical or professional judgment, the audit shall
				be conducted by, or in consultation with, a pharmacist licensed in the State of
				the audit or the State board of pharmacy.</text>
									</item>
                  <item id="id3ae52b5a523f4bf09fc672f72059e9c4">
                    <enum>(bb)</enum>
                    <text>The pharmacy,
				practice site, or other entity may use a nursing home’s medication
				administration record (MAR), the records of a hospital, physician,
				rehabilitation facility, State-licensed healthcare facility, or other
				authorized practitioner to validate the pharmacy records and any legal
				prescription (one that complies with State Board of Pharmacy requirements) may
				be used to validate claims submitted by the pharmacy in connection with
				prescriptions, refills, proof of delivery, or changes in prescriptions during
				any phase of the audit, including appeal.</text>
									</item>
                </subclause>
                <subclause id="idc8fc40e358de452bbfad702ad7725792">
                  <enum>(III)</enum>
                  <header>Assuring
				proper procedures</header>
									<item id="id68d748ddc7c343abaa950df464907202">
                    <enum>(aa)</enum>
                    <text>The PBM (or
				auditing entity) may not apply recordkeeping or other requirements on the
				pharmacy that are more stringent than such requirements applied under Federal
				law or the State law involved.</text>
									</item>
                  <item id="id951fbc3b96584fba988991d109a6aff7">
                    <enum>(bb)</enum>
                    <text>The PBM (or
				auditing entity) shall accept all pharmacy prescription records related to the
				audit in an electronic format or other digital media.</text>
									</item>
                  <item id="id34fa1bac56b943cebf2fa026b8069538">
                    <enum>(cc)</enum>
                    <text>The PBM (or
				auditing entity) may not, pursuant to the audit, disallow the entire payment
				with respect to a claim submitted by the pharmacy because of a clerical or
				recordkeeping error (such as a typographical error, scrivener's error, or
				computer error) if there is an absence of intent to commit fraud, as defined in
				<cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" value="usc/18/1347" entity-type="uscode">
                        <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/18/1347">section 1347</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code</cato:entity-ref>. In the case of errors that have
				no financial harm to the patient or plan, the PBM shall not assess any
				chargebacks.</text>
									</item>
                  <item id="id48b5a264cc754f6fa51be5833f13afa3">
                    <enum>(dd)</enum>
                    <text>The PBM (or
				auditing entity) may not use extrapolation or other statistical expansion
				techniques in calculating any recoupment or penalty pursuant to the
				audit.</text>
									</item>
                  <item id="ide3f7f79f7e644ab090cf42bdd0449829">
                    <enum>(ee)</enum>
                    <text>The period
				covered by the audit may not exceed 2 years from the date the claim involved
				was submitted to, or adjusted by, the PBM (or auditing entity).</text>
									</item>
                  <item id="id595eb56b789545f49b05fc03d195dc41">
                    <enum>(ff)</enum>
                    <text>The PBM (or
				auditing entity) shall have in place a written appeals process that affords the
				pharmacy a minimum of 60 days to respond to the auditor findings, shall include
				procedures for appeals from preliminary reports and final reports related to
				such audit, and shall permit the pharmacy to introduce any documentation which
				would validate a claim contested in the audit until the final written decision
				is issued on appeal.</text>
									</item>
                </subclause>
              </clause>
              <clause id="idf8126cab75f1432b919837166b09c3b4">
                <enum>(ii)</enum>
                <header>Business
				practice predictability</header>
                <text>A PBM shall provide a particular
				aggregate average reimbursement rate for generics or a maximum average discount
				off of an accepted pharmaceutical pricing benchmark for multi-source generics
				as a whole (often referred to as a <term>generic effective rate</term>) and
				provide a process for the generic effective rate to be appealed. For the
				purposes of this rate or benchmark amount, the PBM shall utilize a
				pharmaceutical pricing benchmark published by a nationally available
				compendium. The aggregate average reimbursement rate for generics (generic
				effective rate) shall be calculated using the actual amount paid to the
				pharmacy (typically the amount of reimbursement to the PBM plus the patient
				co-pay), excluding the dispensing fee, shall not be calculated solely according
				to the amount allowed by the plan, and shall include all generics dispensed,
				regardless of whether they are subject to MAC pricing.</text>
							</clause>
              <clause id="idf0bae04d85a546e8906394638e0b734a">
                <enum>(iii)</enum>
                <header>Protecting
				patient and claims related data</header>
                <text>A PBM shall adhere to the
				following criteria when handling personally identifiable utilization and claims
				data or other sensitive patient data:</text>
								<subclause id="id3d3b22c501104155b4000128ff51cb0e">
                  <enum>(I)</enum>
                  <text>A PBM may not
				transmit any personally identifiable utilization or claims data to a pharmacy
				owned by a PBM if the plan enrollee has not voluntarily elected in writing or
				via secure electronic means to fill that particular prescription at the
				PBM-owned pharmacy.</text>
								</subclause>
                <subclause id="id181930d1b94d4eceb72fdbcc8db49ca7">
                  <enum>(II)</enum>
                  <text>A PBM may not
				require that a plan enrollee use a retail pharmacy, mail order pharmacy,
				specialty pharmacy, or other pharmacy entity providing pharmacy services in
				which the PBM has an ownership interest or that has an ownership interest in
				the PBM or provide an incentive to a beneficiary to encourage the individual to
				use a retail pharmacy, mail order pharmacy, specialty pharmacy, or other
				pharmacy entity providing pharmacy services in which the PBM has an ownership
				interest or that has an ownership interest in the PBM, if the incentive is
				applicable only to such
				pharmacies.</text>
								</subclause>
              </clause>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
        </quoted-block>
			</subsection>
      <subsection id="id9BA918AA5B1F4A0A9523B83D071E8538">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Disclosure and
			 regular update of prescription drug reimbursement</header>
        <text>
          <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
            <cato:entity-ref value="Social Security Act/s:1860D–12/ss:b" entity-type="act">Section
			 1860D–12(b) of the Social Security Act</cato:entity-ref> (<cato:entity-ref value="usc/42/1395w–112/b" entity-type="uscode">
              <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-112">42 U.S.C. 1395w–112(b)</external-xref>
            </cato:entity-ref>
          </cato:entity>) is amended to
			 read as follows:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idCDF986A56C584EA8A906D6B97DDCC8F5" style="OLC">
					<paragraph id="idA2B21C5015BA4FF58CAC376514A86797">
            <enum>(6)</enum>
            <header>Disclosure and
				regular update of prescription drug reimbursement</header>
            <text>Each contract
				entered into with a PDP sponsor under this part with respect to a prescription
				drug plan offered by such sponsor shall provide that the sponsor or
				subcontractor of such sponsor shall—</text>
						<subparagraph id="idC4F03595689E4A80B50BF688363A49DF">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>disclose to a
				pharmacy, at the time when a contract is offered, the methodology and actual
				per unit reimbursement amount for each covered drug for each such pharmacy;
				and</text>
						</subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="id879B303ED89A4CCFB666F41A7AFB3E36">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>not less
				frequently than once every 7 days, beginning with an initial update on January
				1 of each year—</text>
							<clause id="id700026C0003E471E8B10707AF4945F40">
                <enum>(i)</enum>
                <text>update such
				reimbursement amount to accurately reflect the market price of acquiring the
				drug; and</text>
							</clause>
              <clause id="idCC3E2E2A18D348A59A301BD780248D50">
                <enum>(ii)</enum>
                <text>disclose to each
				contracted pharmacy such methodology and reimbursement
				amounts.</text>
							</clause>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
        </quoted-block>
			</subsection>
      <subsection id="id37D6B7294E3C4AC48A6D94F3154BA09F">
        <enum>(c)</enum>
        <header>Effective
			 date</header>
        <text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to plan
			 years beginning on or after January 1, 2015.</text>
			</subsection>
    </section>
  </legis-body>
</bill>
</doc>