<doc>
  <docmeta id="113s2649is">
    <bill congress="113" type="s" number="2649" version="is"/>
    <revision size="1967" annotations="0" status="complete" id="3" commit-time="2014-08-04T23:08:49Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113s2649is/3.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public">
	<metadata>
<dublinCore>
<dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">113 S2649 IS: To provide certain legal relief from politically motivated charges by the Government of Egypt.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">2014-07-23</dc:date>
<dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
		<congress>113th CONGRESS</congress>
    <session>2d Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. 2649</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20140723">July 23, 2014</action-date>
			<action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="S293">Mr. Graham</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S324">Mrs. Shaheen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S339">Mr. Kirk</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S362">Mr. Kaine</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S197">Mr. McCain</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations</committee-name>
      </action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To provide certain legal relief from politically motivated charges by the Government of Egypt.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body>
		<section id="S1" section-type="section-one">
      <enum>1.</enum>
      <header>Relief from politically motivated charges by Government of Egypt</header>
			<subsection id="id9EED7BB3CBF647999F7CCF05AD9F580C">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Treatment of charges under United States law</header>
        <text>For purposes of United States law, and for activities undertaken within the jurisdiction of the
			 United States, no verdict, order, warrant, or writ issued by the
			 Government of Egypt or any court, administrative tribunal, or other
			 authority of the Government of Egypt in any instance relating to the legal
			 charges, trial proceedings, and convictions issued by the Cairo Criminal
			 Court on June 4, 2013, in <quote>Public Prosecution Case No. 1110 for the Year 2012</quote> against 43 staff of five international nongovernmental organizations shall be considered a
			 conviction and no person named in such verdict, order, warrant, or writ
			 shall be considered to have been charged, accused, found guilty, or
			 convicted.</text>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="id07AD7E28364A49CFABAD1D8FDABB8B5B">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Recognition of charges as politically motivated</header>
        <text>It is the policy of the United States to recognize any legal charges, trial proceedings, and
			 convictions issued by the Cairo Criminal Court on June 4, 2013, in <quote>Public Prosecution Case No. 1110 for the Year 2012</quote>  as being politically motivated in origin and invalid.</text>
      </subsection>
    </section>
  </legis-body>
</bill>
</doc>