<doc>
  <docmeta id="113s208is">
    <bill congress="113" type="s" number="208" version="is"/>
    <revision size="4546" annotations="0" id="6" commit-time="2013-04-23T21:50:26+00:00" committer="favila" doc="113s208is/6.xml" status="complete">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public">
	<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
		<congress>113th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. 208</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20130204">February 4, 2013</action-date>
			<action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="S221">Mrs. Feinstein</sponsor> (for
			 herself and <cosponsor name-id="S223">Mrs. Boxer</cosponsor>) introduced the
			 following bill; which was read twice and referred to the
			 <committee-name committee-id="SSCM00">Committee on Commerce, Science, and
			 Transportation</committee-name>
      </action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To require the Federal Aviation Administration to
		  prescribe regulations to reduce helicopter noise pollution in residential areas
		  in Los Angeles County, California.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body>
		<section id="S1" section-type="section-one">
      <enum>1.</enum>
      <header>Short
			 title</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as
			 the <quote>
          <short-title>Los Angeles Residential Helicopter
			 Noise Relief Act of 2013</short-title>
        </quote>.</text>
		</section>
    <section id="id08cb829a618842aaaaad4c7190f16a83">
      <enum>2.</enum>
      <header>Findings</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">
        <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> finds the following:</text>
			<paragraph id="id5074578ad55c45f4a0470be593639eec">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text>Residents
			 throughout Los Angeles County suffer intrusive and disruptive low-flying
			 helicopter traffic above their neighborhoods. The unique terrain of canyons and
			 valleys that surround residential neighborhoods in Los Angeles County often
			 concentrate high decibel level noise from the low-flying helicopters in and
			 around Los Angeles County residences. The concentrated noise interrupts daily
			 life for many Los Angeles County residents by drowning out conversations and
			 disrupting sleep cycles.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id0e4ad40e7c91498d80d2647e0ace6d58">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text>Los Angeles
			 County is home to a uniquely large concentration of scenic, historic,
			 entertainment, and transportation venues, including sight-seeing, movie
			 studios, movie star homes, outdoor entertainment facilities, Griffith Park, the
			 Hollywood Sign, freeways, and many others, that generate extensive helicopter
			 activity.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id330F27013F184D6C8D7FAF5CFB8456D4">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <text>Los Angeles
			 County is home to the world’s leading civil helicopter manufacturer that
			 conducts extensive helicopter operational testing across the region.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id505357F045354AA4B017F6A782EE0DFA">
        <enum>(4)</enum>
        <text>Despite multiple
			 efforts from several community and homeowner organizations in Los Angeles
			 County to address these disturbances, helicopter traffic in Los Angeles County
			 is not currently regulated by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="6920">Federal Aviation Administration</cato:entity-ref> or any other
			 agency.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id1e3e0929e1ce4b5398bd8959993e18b8">
        <enum>(5)</enum>
        <text>At the request of
			 members of Congress, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="6920">Federal Aviation Administration</cato:entity-ref> formed an internal
			 working group in July 2012 to solicit input from local communities and
			 stakeholders on helicopter noise and safety issues in Los Angeles
			 County.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id5BD2CDB853A24AE49EB1C20D9A199FCD">
        <enum>(6)</enum>
        <text>As part of that
			 process, several public meetings were held in the fall and summer of 2012 that
			 have allowed the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="6920">Federal Aviation Administration</cato:entity-ref> and stakeholders to hear and
			 better understand the concerns and complaints of affected residents.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id9acecf2837b342ee9e92014a5e093685">
        <enum>(7)</enum>
        <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="6920">Federal
			 Aviation Administration</cato:entity-ref> is scheduled to release a report in May 2013 evaluating
			 a full set of voluntary and regulatory options to reduce helicopter noise and
			 address safety issues in Los Angeles County.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id1D3109BEFF0943919C5846F4252B343E">
        <enum>(8)</enum>
        <text>The report is
			 expected to explore how helicopters can be regulated in Los Angeles County in a
			 manner that provides relief to residents from helicopter noise while also
			 meeting the needs of relevant stakeholders, including first responders.</text>
			</paragraph>
    </section>
    <section id="ida05dd3881f784afc9374e621e94bf5a7">
      <enum>3.</enum>
      <header>Regulations to
			 reduce helicopter noise pollution in certain residential areas</header>
			<subsection id="id8f89c2c1746149edabb57f0334657de3">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Rulemaking</header>
        <text>Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of
			 this Act, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="6920">Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration</cato:entity-ref> shall
			 prescribe regulations for helicopter operations in Los Angeles County,
			 California, that include requirements relating to the flight paths and
			 altitudes associated with such operations to reduce helicopter noise pollution
			 in residential areas, increase safety, and minimize scheduled commercial
			 aircraft delays.</text>
			</subsection>
      <subsection id="id4778706fe55943a09af6aada19263ec1">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Exemptions</header>
        <text>In
			 prescribing regulations under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Los Angeles Residential Helicopter Noise Relief Act of 2013/s:3/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="6920">Administrator</cato:entity-ref> shall exempt
			 helicopter operations related to emergency, law enforcement, or military
			 activities from the requirements described in that subsection.</text>
			</subsection>
      <subsection id="id5b3fdeaefdb24b9e82a44dc633e6c3b0">
        <enum>(c)</enum>
        <header>Consultations</header>
        <text>In
			 prescribing regulations under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Los Angeles Residential Helicopter Noise Relief Act of 2013/s:3/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="6920">Administrator</cato:entity-ref> shall make
			 reasonable efforts to consult with local communities and local helicopter
			 operators in order to develop regulations that meet the needs of local
			 communities, helicopter operators, and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="6920">Federal Aviation
			 Administration</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
			</subsection>
    </section>
  </legis-body>
</bill>
</doc>