<doc>
  <docmeta id="113s1662is">
    <bill congress="113" type="s" number="1662" version="is"/>
    <revision size="5759" annotations="0" status="complete" id="5" commit-time="2013-11-15T21:29:58Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113s1662is/5.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public">
  <metadata>
<dublinCore>
<dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">113 S1662 IS: Veterans Health Care Improvement Act of 2013</dc:title>
<dc:publisher xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">2013-11-07</dc:date>
<dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
    <congress>113th CONGRESS</congress>
    <session>1st Session</session>
    <legis-num>S. 1662</legis-num>
    <current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
    <action>
      <action-date date="20131107">November 7, 2013</action-date>
      <action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="S174">Mr. McConnell</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSVA00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name>
      </action-desc>
    </action>
    <legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
    <official-title>To provide for the introduction of pay-for-performance compensation mechanisms into contracts of the Department of Veterans Affairs with community-based outpatient clinics for the provision of health care services, and for other purposes.</official-title>
  </form>
  <legis-body>
    <section id="S1" section-type="section-one">
      <enum>1.</enum>
      <header>Short title</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the
		  <quote>
          <short-title>Veterans Health Care Improvement Act of 2013</short-title>
        </quote>.</text>
    </section>
    <section id="idf46c1118c44746328eac8e3b0e238199">
      <enum>2.</enum>
      <header>Findings</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">
        <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> makes the following findings:</text>
      <paragraph id="id01f453e5ee60497f81c30b18f45eb8ec">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text>Veterans of the Armed Forces have made tremendous sacrifices in the defense of freedom and liberty.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="iddc097d18efbf4a4aa17750d407cc0098">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text>
          <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> recognizes these great sacrifices and reaffirms America’s strong commitment to its veterans.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="idd59be3204f8848ebb09b6324a21bb3fe">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <text>As part of the on-going congressional effort to recognize the sacrifices made by America’s veterans, <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> has dramatically increased funding for the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="3600">Department of Veterans Affairs</cato:entity-ref> for veterans health care in the years since September 11, 2001.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id3177c9157670432eaaeaf19d6417f766">
        <enum>(4)</enum>
        <text>Part of the funding for the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="3600">Department of Veterans Affairs</cato:entity-ref> for veterans health care is allocated toward community-based outpatient clinics (CBOCs).</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id0ebcb95ec45d4f15a17aa5113499c260">
        <enum>(5)</enum>
        <text>A number of CBOCs are administered by private contractors.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id366d6fb857d44838a2eedcc9bfd55d91">
        <enum>(6)</enum>
        <text>CBOCs administered by private contractors operate on a capitated basis.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id213eab5b371d46549aa1b1216281de0c">
        <enum>(7)</enum>
        <text>Some current contracts for CBOCs may create an incentive for contractors to enroll as many veterans as possible, without ensuring timely access to high quality health care for such veterans.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="ide7e28a3c73fb4970aa5f74921265e2f5">
        <enum>(8)</enum>
        <text>The top priorities for CBOCs should be to provide quality health care and patient satisfaction for America’s veterans.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="ida16ed89f4e754363b11559b4a079e79f">
        <enum>(9)</enum>
        <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="3600">Department of Veterans Affairs</cato:entity-ref> currently tracks the quality of patient care through its Computerized Patient Record System. However, fees paid to contractors are not currently adjusted automatically to reflect the quality of care provided to patients.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id597c074a006540a6862fc8f53eaaceae">
        <enum>(10)</enum>
        <text>A pay-for-performance payment model offers a promising approach to health care delivery by aligning the payment of fees to contractors with the achievement of better health outcomes for patients.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id58d515b0dcfc441ebc760335f9d480b2">
        <enum>(11)</enum>
        <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="3600">Department of Veterans Affairs</cato:entity-ref> should begin to emphasize pay-for-performance in its contracts with CBOCs.</text>
      </paragraph>
    </section>
    <section id="id99fbe922d0064d279ac0d18ca9083aa4">
      <enum>3.</enum>
      <header>Pay-for-performance under Department of Veterans Affairs contracts with community-based outpatient health care clinics</header>
      <subsection id="iddb3cfad7f8a5451c95be91d047cb8db2">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Plan required</header>
        <text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="3600">Secretary of Veterans Affairs</cato:entity-ref> shall submit to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> a plan to introduce pay-for-performance measures into contracts which compensate contractors of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="3600">Department of Veterans Affairs</cato:entity-ref> for the provision of health care services through community-based outpatient clinics (CBOCs).</text>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="id5f0f987ec26145aa9d48482598103318">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Elements</header>
        <text>The plan required by <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Veterans Health Care Improvement Act of 2013/s:3/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref> shall include the following:</text>
        <paragraph id="id78aea796b7ef46df96a412f9b7f402f4">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>Measures to ensure that contracts of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="3600">Department</cato:entity-ref> for the provision of health care services through CBOCs begin to utilize pay-for-performance compensation mechanisms for compensating contractors for the provision of such services through such clinics, including mechanisms as follows:</text>
          <subparagraph id="id3196935c329f4ff484ff56a232bbf58a">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>To provide incentives for clinics that provide high-quality health care.</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="id43c08bb17f90498e920f5b54347d407c">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>To provide incentives to better assure patient satisfaction.</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="idba52901097894c7eafdc4bde26d6201c">
            <enum>(C)</enum>
            <text>To impose penalties (including termination of contract) for clinics that provide substandard care.</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="id20efe38c43a94720a35299cade65a923">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>Mechanisms to collect and evaluate data on the outcomes of the services generally provided by CBOCs in order to provide for an assessment of the quality of health care provided by such clinics.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="ida8aefb87258a4cb192b724fe3e8b3a11">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <text>Mechanisms to eliminate abuses in the provision of health care services by CBOCs under contracts that continue to utilize capitated-basis compensation mechanisms for compensating contractors.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="id6612e1ea80c341179e959e28102eba84">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
          <text>Mechanisms to ensure that veterans are not denied care or face undue delays in receiving care.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="ide7da09a98cf0461c95e9ff87e997d19a">
        <enum>(c)</enum>
        <header>Implementation</header>
        <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="3600">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall commence the implementation of the plan on the date that is 60 days after the date of the submittal of the plan. In implementing the plan, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="3600">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> may initially carry out one or more pilot programs to assess the feasibility and advisability of mechanisms under the plan.</text>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="id3cfaaf347ef04738907b9c89fcd00044">
        <enum>(d)</enum>
        <header>Reports</header>
        <text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act and every 180 days thereafter, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="3600">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall submit to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> a report setting forth the recommendations of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="3600">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> as to the feasibility and advisability of utilizing pay-for-performance compensation mechanisms in the provision of health care services by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="3600">Department</cato:entity-ref> by means in addition to CBOCs.</text>
      </subsection>
    </section>
  </legis-body>
</bill>
</doc>