<doc>
  <docmeta id="113s779is">
    <bill congress="113" type="s" number="779" version="is"/>
    <revision size="25507" annotations="0" status="complete" id="4" commit-time="2013-06-25T19:40:31Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113s779is/4.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>113 S779 IS: Public Employee Pension Transparency Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2013-04-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
		<congress>113th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. 779</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20130423">April 23, 2013</action-date>
			<action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="S300">Mr. Burr</sponsor> (for himself,
			 <cosponsor name-id="S301">Mr. Coburn</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S303">Mr. Thune</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was
			 read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFI00">Committee
			 on Finance</committee-name>
      </action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide for
		  reporting and disclosure by State and local public employee retirement pension
		  plans.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H78626ACB2F0B4ABB80141C6E941691B4" style="OLC">
		<section id="HF16C28392C094C2C971522B3B8D183DE" section-type="section-one">
      <enum>1.</enum>
      <header>Short title</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the
			 <quote>
          <short-title>Public Employee Pension Transparency
			 Act</short-title>
        </quote>.</text>
		</section>
    <section id="HC8E958A863DC4B68ACCC0ACC8A59CCEB">
      <enum>2.</enum>
      <header>Findings</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> finds the following:</text>
			<paragraph id="H6FD654519E584ED499C4CC56E65560E9">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text>Pursuant to
			 clauses 1 and 3 of section 8 of article I of the Constitution of the United
			 States, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> has the authority to condition the continuation of certain
			 specified Federal tax benefits upon State or local government employee pension
			 benefit plans on the provision of meaningful disclosure under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:4980J" proposed="true">section 4980J of
			 the Internal Revenue Code of 1986</cato:entity-ref>, as added by this Act.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HECA3B012065149EFBF72F5B1466C775F">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text>State and local
			 government employee pension benefit plans have promised pension benefits to
			 approximately 20,000,000 Americans who are active employees of these entities.
			 An additional 7,000,000 retirees and their dependents currently receive
			 benefits from State or local government employee pension benefit plans. The
			 interests of participants in many of such plans are in the nature of property
			 rights under State law.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HCF2129C1ED7C4AE0B56E6574C9935C23">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <text>State and local
			 government employee pension benefit plans are substantially facilitated by the
			 favorable tax treatment of participants and beneficiaries, investment earnings,
			 and employee contributions with respect to such plans provided by the Federal
			 Government under the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986">Internal Revenue Code of 1986</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HF0B66433E19E4996A250FCCDBBCFC21E">
        <enum>(4)</enum>
        <text>The investment of
			 State or local government employee pension benefit plan assets, the
			 distribution of benefits under such plans, and other related financial
			 activities are facilitated through the use of instrumentalities of, and
			 substantially affect, interstate commerce. These activities, which are
			 interstate in nature and have a substantial impact on the national economy,
			 affect capital formation, regional growth and decline, the national markets for
			 insurance, and the markets for securities and the trading of securities of
			 State and local governments.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H397F650426B34BE7B538CC3C9CFA820F">
        <enum>(5)</enum>
        <text>The financial
			 status of State or local government employee pension benefit plans also has a
			 direct impact on the national markets for insurance and trading of securities
			 of State and local governments.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HF8F4723F6FBE4F03818990DAB84F76BA">
        <enum>(6)</enum>
        <text>State or local
			 government employee pension benefit plans additionally have a substantial
			 impact on interstate commerce as a consequence of the interstate movement of
			 participants.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H343C8E98E67C4753AF1FD3976CD789BE">
        <enum>(7)</enum>
        <text>State or local
			 government employee pension benefit plans are becoming a large financial burden
			 on certain State and local governments and have already resulted in tax
			 increases and the reduction of services.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HAE7B5768532E435AB7871D74152F1E7C">
        <enum>(8)</enum>
        <text>In fact, a recent
			 study published in the Journal of Economic Perspectives found that the present
			 value of the already promised pension liabilities of the 50 States amount to
			 $5,170,000,000,000 and that these pension plans are unfunded by
			 $3,230,000,000,000. Another study determined that the total unfunded liability
			 for all municipal plans in the United States is $574,000,000,000.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HCA6AA8F009F945FF85FD4DF8458D75A6">
        <enum>(9)</enum>
        <text>Some economists
			 and observers have stated that the extent to which State or local government
			 employee pension benefit plans are underfunded is obscured by governmental
			 accounting rules and practices, particularly as they relate to the valuation of
			 plan assets and liabilities. This results in a misstatement of the value of
			 plan assets and an understatement of plan liabilities, a situation that poses a
			 significant threat to the soundness of State and local budgets.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HEA94D49C704E4AB2963B646041BD8112">
        <enum>(10)</enum>
        <text>There currently
			 is a lack of meaningful disclosure regarding the value of State or local
			 government employee pension benefit plan assets and liabilities. This lack of
			 meaningful disclosure poses a direct and serious threat to the financial
			 stability of such plans and their sponsoring governments, impairs the ability
			 of State and local government taxpayers and officials to understand the
			 financial obligations of their government, and reduces the likelihood that
			 State and local government processes will be effective in assuring the prudent
			 management of their plans. The status quo also constitutes a serious threat to
			 the future economic health of the Nation and places an undue burden upon State
			 and local government taxpayers, who will be called upon to fully fund existing,
			 and future, pension promises.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HC548960694F54B7AB8253DA003E37F1E">
        <enum>(11)</enum>
        <text>State or local
			 government employee pension benefit plans affect the national public interest
			 and meaningful disclosure of the value of their assets and liabilities is
			 necessary and desirable in order to adequately protect plan participants and
			 their beneficiaries and the general public. Meaningful disclosure would also
			 further efforts to provide for the general welfare and the free flow of
			 commerce.</text>
			</paragraph>
    </section>
    <section id="HFADD77E0C0B94BC6B649EE2ED40A21A7">
      <enum>3.</enum>
      <header>Reporting of
			 information with respect to State or local government employee pension benefit
			 plans treated as a tax exemption, etc., requirement for State and local
			 bonds</header>
			<subsection id="H9D34CCB0A21541B0805332F8441BD3F4">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>In
			 general</header>
        <text>
          <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/ch:1/sch:B/pt:IV/spt:B">Subpart B of part IV of subchapter B of chapter 1 of the
			 Internal Revenue Code of 1986</cato:entity-ref> is amended by adding at the end the following new
			 section:</text>
				<quoted-block id="HC41155FB64A746838CCBED3FAFE99EB2" style="OLC">
					<section id="HE237EDF2503D4794A0DCD7C2FE4A1E40">
            <enum>149A.</enum>
            <header>Reporting with
				respect to State or local government employee pension benefit plans</header>
						<subsection id="H77F03C099E2647289834B8062309F3B8">
              <enum>(a)</enum>
              <header>In
				general</header>
              <text>In the case of a failure to satisfy any requirement of
				<cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:4980J/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref> or <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:4980J/ss:b" proposed="true">(b) of section 4980J</cato:entity-ref> with respect to any plan maintained with
				respect to employees of one or more States or political subdivisions of one or
				more States, no specified Federal tax benefit shall be allowed or made with
				respect to any specified bond issued by any such State or political subdivision
				(or by any bonding authority acting on behalf, or for the benefit, of such
				State or political subdivision) during the noncompliance period.</text>
						</subsection>
            <subsection id="H1CBFB4957B3044B180AC2504B05E372B">
              <enum>(b)</enum>
              <header>Noncompliance
				period</header>
              <text>For purposes of this section, the term <term>noncompliance
				period</term> means, with respect to any State or political subdivision in
				connection with any failure described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:149A/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref>, the period beginning
				on the date that the Secretary notifies such State or political subdivision of
				such failure and ending on the date that such failure is cured (as determined
				by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary</cato:entity-ref>).</text>
						</subsection>
            <subsection id="H74D26931FA5D435488198FAF1473B183">
              <enum>(c)</enum>
              <header>Specified
				bond</header>
              <text>For purposes of this section, the term <term>specified
				bond</term> means—</text>
							<paragraph id="H11A6612FDEE54BDA9D769E45211DF35A">
                <enum>(1)</enum>
                <text>any State or local
				bond within the meaning of <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:103">section 103</cato:entity-ref>,</text>
							</paragraph>
              <paragraph id="H02D4849E2CAA42C9B67A202FF7FC86BE">
                <enum>(2)</enum>
                <text>any qualified tax
				credit bond within the meaning of <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:54A">section 54A</cato:entity-ref>, and</text>
							</paragraph>
              <paragraph id="H321BE56D830A4BE79360C4604A1ED98E">
                <enum>(3)</enum>
                <text>any build America
				bond within the meaning of <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:54AA">section 54AA</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
							</paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="H00DEBAD8F1E84498B66DD83973D33347">
              <enum>(d)</enum>
              <header>Specified
				federal tax benefit</header>
              <text>For purposes of this section, the term
				<term>specified Federal tax benefit</term> means—</text>
							<paragraph id="H6433661906D0462ABDFDD8C0FCBB5BB8">
                <enum>(1)</enum>
                <text>any exemption from
				gross income allowed under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:103">section 103</cato:entity-ref> (relating to interest on State and local
				bonds),</text>
							</paragraph>
              <paragraph id="H14E2DBDD63EC40E29DCEE505AB5EB4D7">
                <enum>(2)</enum>
                <text>any credit allowed
				under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:54A">section 54A</cato:entity-ref> (relating to credit to holders of qualified tax credit
				bonds),</text>
							</paragraph>
              <paragraph id="H731116E2465F4CD28D7B6A8FD6E2D271">
                <enum>(3)</enum>
                <text>any credit allowed
				under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:54AA">section 54AA</cato:entity-ref> (relating to build America bonds), and</text>
							</paragraph>
              <paragraph id="H3864B09061704DB3BC7D0FF887C8BFDB">
                <enum>(4)</enum>
                <text>any credit or
				payment allowed or made under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:6431">section 6431</cato:entity-ref> (relating to credit for qualified
				bonds allowed to
				issuer).</text>
							</paragraph>
            </subsection>
          </section>
          <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
        </quoted-block>
			</subsection>
      <subsection id="H3240A541EBB74E89AF1B93A6107DA155">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Reporting
			 requirements</header>
        <text>
          <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/ch:43">Chapter 43 of such Code</cato:entity-ref> is amended by adding at the
			 end the following new section:</text>
				<quoted-block id="H44F3DCA2132B496CB707181EFDDFDC4F" style="OLC">
					<section id="H76D12A1E71DA4645AA9F0506AF8723A9">
            <enum>4980J.</enum>
            <header>Failure of
				State or local government employee pension benefit plans to meet reporting
				requirements</header>
						<subsection id="HC75462B6F73C4CFE94205F437ACDD95A">
              <enum>(a)</enum>
              <header>Annual
				report</header>
              <text>For purposes of <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:149A" proposed="true">section 149A</cato:entity-ref>, the requirements of this
				subsection are as follows:</text>
							<paragraph id="HF4BF9B5EB4ED439AB57EC6F576862243">
                <enum>(1)</enum>
                <header>In
				general</header>
                <text>The plan sponsor of a State or local government employee
				pension benefit plan shall file with the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary</cato:entity-ref>, in such form and manner as
				shall be prescribed by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary</cato:entity-ref>, a report for each plan year beginning on
				or after January 1, 2014, setting forth the following information with respect
				to the plan, as determined by the plan sponsor as of the end of such plan
				year:</text>
								<subparagraph id="H6AB85AC0E0A544C088E7CC7D7F07C3B1">
                  <enum>(A)</enum>
                  <text>A schedule of
				funding status, which shall include a statement as to the current liability of
				the plan, the amount of plan assets available to meet that liability, the
				amount of the net unfunded liability (if any), and the funding percentage of
				the plan.</text>
								</subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="H6B55E278718741B7A5E233E8F495C3AF">
                  <enum>(B)</enum>
                  <text>A schedule of
				contributions by the plan sponsor for the plan year, indicating which are or
				are not taken into account under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:4980J/ss:a/p:1/sp:A" proposed="true">subparagraph (A)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
								</subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="HBA9EF0D10F124F8DBC0D5C96D13D74F9">
                  <enum>(C)</enum>
                  <text>Alternative
				projections which shall be specified in regulations of the Secretary for each
				of the next 60 plan years following the plan year of the cash flows associated
				with the current liability, together with a statement of the assumptions used
				in connection with such projections. The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall specify in such
				regulations the projection assumptions to be used as necessary to achieve
				comparability across plans.</text>
								</subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="H7E18EE5817E745AAA1C5072CE25E8979">
                  <enum>(D)</enum>
                  <text>A statement of the
				actuarial assumptions used for the plan year, including the rate of return on
				investment of plan assets and assumptions as to such other matters as the
				<cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> may prescribe by regulation.</text>
								</subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="H8F0777DAFE78436FBB87C928A3AD7F4B">
                  <enum>(E)</enum>
                  <text>A statement of the
				number of participants who are each of the following—</text>
									<clause id="H848D802489C84E2EA258AD5DEA9D50B5">
                    <enum>(i)</enum>
                    <text>those who are
				retired or separated from service and are receiving benefits,</text>
									</clause>
                  <clause id="H48B94824A46D4887B086715B887C4DE8">
                    <enum>(ii)</enum>
                    <text>those who are
				retired or separated and are entitled to future benefits, and</text>
									</clause>
                  <clause id="H51DC3FCEA3F8469490E468F01699E184">
                    <enum>(iii)</enum>
                    <text>those who are
				active under the plan.</text>
									</clause>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="H51E66B0A44E14972ADF6B593D010E7D7">
                  <enum>(F)</enum>
                  <text>A statement of the
				plan’s investment returns, including the rate of return, for the plan year and
				the 5 preceding plan years.</text>
								</subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="H64D3D369A64048A2A5D8B1788199457D">
                  <enum>(G)</enum>
                  <text>A statement of the
				degree to which, and manner in which, the plan sponsor expects to eliminate any
				unfunded current liability that may exist for the plan year and the extent to
				which the plan sponsor has followed the plan’s funding policy for each of the
				preceding 5 plan years. The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall prescribe by regulation the
				specific criteria to be used for meeting the requirements of this
				paragraph.</text>
								</subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="HA8EDB41996B54E6681D3E457643360A4">
                  <enum>(H)</enum>
                  <text>A statement of the
				amount of pension obligation bonds outstanding.</text>
								</subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="H0A8351ADFEDF4612A087FB2BB78E11E9">
                  <enum>(I)</enum>
                  <text>A statement of the
				current cost of the plan for the plan year.</text>
								</subparagraph>
              </paragraph>
              <paragraph id="H36B9136DBC104F4191B79CAF033D6FD0">
                <enum>(2)</enum>
                <header>Timing of
				report</header>
                <text>The plan sponsor of a State or local government employee
				pension benefit plan shall make the filing required under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:4980J/ss:a/p:1" proposed="true">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref> for
				each plan year not later than 210 days after the end of such plan year (or
				within such time as may be required by regulations prescribed by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary</cato:entity-ref>
				in order to reduce duplicative filing).</text>
							</paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="H9E3108DBD3D340BFBE2CC4BAD995F03C">
              <enum>(b)</enum>
              <header>Additional
				reporting requirements</header>
              <text>For purposes of <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:149A" proposed="true">section 149A</cato:entity-ref>, the
				requirements of this subsection are as follows:</text>
							<paragraph id="HB9476934748E4CF68DA3E6A09B4DAA91">
                <enum>(1)</enum>
                <header>Supplementary
				reports</header>
                <text>In any case in which, in determining the information
				filed in the annual report for a plan year under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:4980J/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref>—</text>
								<subparagraph id="HF68616AA76274C4B8943F11B1031F0B3">
                  <enum>(A)</enum>
                  <text>the value of plan
				assets is determined using a standard other than fair market value, or</text>
								</subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="HAB64D29DF4DE4FAEB9D8CC6211C83B04">
                  <enum>(B)</enum>
                  <text>the interest rate
				or rates used to determine the value of liabilities or as the discount value
				for liabilities are not the interest rates described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:4980J/ss:b/p:3" proposed="true">paragraph (3)</cato:entity-ref>, the plan
				sponsor shall include in the annual report filed for such plan year pursuant to
				<cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:4980J/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref> the supplementary report for such plan year described in
				<cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:4980J/ss:b/p:2" proposed="true">paragraph (2)</cato:entity-ref> of this subsection.</text>
								</subparagraph>
              </paragraph>
              <paragraph id="H9B649D5B57594E1BBF203BCA1F6E4405">
                <enum>(2)</enum>
                <header>Use of
				prescribed valuation method and interest rates</header>
                <text>A supplementary
				report for a plan year filed for a plan year pursuant to this subsection shall
				include the information specified as required in the annual report under
				<cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:4980J/ss:a/p:1/sp:A" proposed="true">subparagraphs (A)</cato:entity-ref>, <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:4980J/ss:a/p:1/sp:F" proposed="true">(F)</cato:entity-ref>, <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:4980J/ss:a/p:1/sp:G" proposed="true">(G)</cato:entity-ref> and <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:4980J/ss:a/p:1/sp:I" proposed="true">(I) of subsection (a)(1)</cato:entity-ref>, determined as of the
				end of such plan year by valuing plan assets at fair market value and by using
				the interest rates described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:4980J/ss:b/p:3" proposed="true">paragraph (3)</cato:entity-ref> to value liabilities and as the
				discount value for liabilities.</text>
							</paragraph>
              <paragraph id="H79B7B1481712416F8CD1DC5173834BA8">
                <enum>(3)</enum>
                <header>Interest rates
				based on U.S. Treasury obligation yield curve rate</header>
								<subparagraph id="H04A9A0CE8B5D4E0FA27B3BF5F9F0B5A0">
                  <enum>(A)</enum>
                  <header>In
				general</header>
                  <text>The interest rates described in this subsection are, with
				respect to any day, the rates of interest which shall be determined by the
				<cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> for such day on the basis of the U.S. Treasury obligation yield curve
				for such day.</text>
								</subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="H4DAF98CA4AC54726B37DDD96926632CA">
                  <enum>(B)</enum>
                  <header>U.S. treasury
				obligation yield curve</header>
                  <text>For purposes of this subsection, the term
				<term>U.S. Treasury obligation yield curve</term> means, with respect to any
				day, a yield curve which shall be prescribed by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> for such day on
				interest-bearing obligations of the United States.</text>
								</subparagraph>
              </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="H5D9ACF70806E42B29BFA05A68F8B93EB">
              <enum>(c)</enum>
              <header>Definitions and
				special rules</header>
              <text>For purposes of this section—</text>
							<paragraph id="H353B5E9C29084F42A3F22381EE1134FD">
                <enum>(1)</enum>
                <header>State or local
				government employee pension benefit plan</header>
                <text>The terms <term>State or
				local government employee pension benefit plan</term> and <term>plan</term>
				mean any plan, fund, or program, other than a defined contribution plan (within
				the meaning of <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:414/ss:i">section 414(i)</cato:entity-ref>), which was heretofore or is hereafter
				established or maintained, in whole or in part, by a State, a political
				subdivision of a State, or any agency or instrumentality of a State or
				political subdivision of a State, to the extent that by its express terms or as
				a result of surrounding circumstances such plan, fund, or program—</text>
								<subparagraph id="H9D90338C182643DBA994CCE498AA7BE3">
                  <enum>(A)</enum>
                  <text>provides
				retirement income to employees, or</text>
								</subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="H25B58F32F44145B8ABAD6B78AA84AC2C">
                  <enum>(B)</enum>
                  <text>results in a
				deferral of income by employees for periods extending to the termination of
				covered employment or beyond, regardless of the method of calculating the
				contributions made to the plan, the method of calculating the benefits under
				the plan, or the method of distributing benefits from the plan.</text>
								</subparagraph>
              </paragraph>
              <paragraph id="H1B26AE59D1654036A310B4A26C256B74">
                <enum>(2)</enum>
                <header>Funding
				percentage</header>
                <text>The term <term>funding percentage</term> for a plan
				year means the ratio (expressed as a percentage) which—</text>
								<subparagraph id="HEAA99015FFDA4A96AC5D15202E1580C7">
                  <enum>(A)</enum>
                  <text>the value of plan
				assets as of the end of the plan year bears to</text>
								</subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="HD247AF628EF64FECB47B8F4AAE648C4A">
                  <enum>(B)</enum>
                  <text>the current
				liability of the plan for the plan year.</text>
								</subparagraph>
              </paragraph>
              <paragraph commented="no" id="HC0E009ED625E4FEFAD6786046C1D64FF">
                <enum>(3)</enum>
                <header>Current
				liability</header>
                <text>The term <term>current liability</term> of a plan for a
				plan year means the present value of all benefits accrued or earned under the
				plan as of the end of the plan year.</text>
							</paragraph>
              <paragraph commented="no" id="H3991086D12764305A73ED3E9D10B06A6">
                <enum>(4)</enum>
                <header>Present
				value</header>
								<subparagraph commented="no" id="HC48505CA4FAD4090A74D3E73FF8C3707">
                  <enum>(A)</enum>
                  <header>In
				general</header>
                  <text>The present value of an accrued benefit shall be
				determined by discounting its future cash flows in accordance with <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:4980J/ss:b/p:3" proposed="true">subsection
				(b)(3)</cato:entity-ref>. The present value of all benefits accrued for a participant shall be
				calculated as the sum of the present value of the accrued benefit for each exit
				event multiplied by the probability of the associated exit event.</text>
								</subparagraph>
                <subparagraph commented="no" id="HBF888A568DF64170AA40D669C278B71E">
                  <enum>(B)</enum>
                  <header>Exit
				event</header>
                  <text>An <term>exit event</term> occurs when the employment of a
				plan participant terminates. For each currently employed plan participant as of
				the measurement date, there are one or more potential future exit events. Each
				exit event is associated with a termination date, a cause of termination (e.g.,
				retirement, death, disability, quit, etc.), a contractual benefit, and a
				probability that the participant will exit employment via the particular
				event.</text>
								</subparagraph>
              </paragraph>
              <paragraph commented="no" id="H810CF3FEBF2E45CB95B17BA68B12D673">
                <enum>(5)</enum>
                <header>Accrued
				benefit</header>
								<subparagraph commented="no" id="H357B93633A6D4847876347F05E522460">
                  <enum>(A)</enum>
                  <header>In
				general</header>
                  <text>An <term>accrued benefit</term> is determined for each
				exit event as the projected benefit multiplied by service earned as of the
				measurement date divided by service projected to be earned by the event date.
				For participants retired or separated from service as of the measurement date,
				the accrued benefit equals the projected benefit.</text>
								</subparagraph>
                <subparagraph commented="no" id="HCA32A2F0D2A34AC68699916A632CAF60">
                  <enum>(B)</enum>
                  <header>Projected
				benefit</header>
                  <text>As of the measurement date, a <term>projected
				benefit</term> (consisting of future cash flows) is calculated for each
				possible exit event using service projected to be earned to the event date and
				salary as of the measurement date. Such projected benefit shall reflect any
				cost-of-living adjustments payable in the future based on the law in effect as
				of the measurement date.</text>
								</subparagraph>
              </paragraph>
              <paragraph commented="no" id="H09105EAED3DF423B894F7B3005F4E197">
                <enum>(6)</enum>
                <header>Measurement
				date</header>
                <text>The term <term>measurement date</term> means the date as of
				which the value of the pension obligation is determined (sometimes referred to
				as the <quote>valuation date</quote>).</text>
							</paragraph>
              <paragraph id="HDAFEDD5A816A4422A233067EACE65CAC">
                <enum>(7)</enum>
                <header>Current
				cost</header>
                <text>The term <term>current cost</term> of a plan for a plan year
				means the present value as of the end of the plan year of all benefits accrued
				or earned under the plan during the plan year.</text>
							</paragraph>
              <paragraph id="H686B08B1AD4A4663B4186B28B70D2A7B">
                <enum>(8)</enum>
                <header>Plan
				sponsor</header>
                <text>The term <term>plan sponsor</term> means, in connection
				with a State or local government employee pension benefit plan, the State,
				political subdivision of a State, or agency or instrumentality of a State or a
				political subdivision of a State which establishes or maintains the
				plan.</text>
							</paragraph>
              <paragraph id="H945FC071B8944A1382B93159110560A5">
                <enum>(9)</enum>
                <header>Participant</header>
								<subparagraph id="H2397F73218564ADC902099D51918A607">
                  <enum>(A)</enum>
                  <header>In
				general</header>
                  <text>The term <term>participant</term> means, in connection
				with a State or local government employee pension benefit plan, an
				individual—</text>
									<clause id="HBDEB7E0F34D14812B2E78E41D1A4943D">
                    <enum>(i)</enum>
                    <text>who is an employee
				or former employee of a State, political subdivision of a State, or agency or
				instrumentality of a State or a political subdivision of a State which is the
				plan sponsor of such plan, and</text>
									</clause>
                  <clause id="H27110F63993A49FBA73B8AA0E7788319">
                    <enum>(ii)</enum>
                    <text>who is or may
				become eligible to receive a benefit of any type from such plan or whose
				beneficiaries may be eligible to receive any such benefit.</text>
									</clause>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="H8FF6BB6AC8F448D8A280589F8DC4ECBE">
                  <enum>(B)</enum>
                  <header>Beneficiary</header>
                  <text>The
				term <term>beneficiary</term> means a person designated by a participant, or by
				the terms of the plan, who is or may become entitled to a benefit
				thereunder.</text>
								</subparagraph>
              </paragraph>
              <paragraph id="H2A7F8CED96A2464899F03CAE50B3B807">
                <enum>(10)</enum>
                <header>Plan
				year</header>
                <text>The term <term>plan year</term> means, in connection with a
				plan, the calendar or fiscal year on which the records of the plan are
				kept.</text>
							</paragraph>
              <paragraph id="H9DA2D5ADC1BD45738B9E573DC2C0AE10">
                <enum>(11)</enum>
                <header>State</header>
                <text>The
				term <term>State</term> includes any State of the United States, the District
				of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the United States Virgin Islands,
				American Samoa, Guam, and the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana
				Islands.</text>
							</paragraph>
              <paragraph id="H31D4CAC94E2140F58C0A4EA16E1F694E">
                <enum>(12)</enum>
                <header>Fair market
				value</header>
                <text>The term <term>fair market value</term> has the meaning of
				such term under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:430/ss:g/p:3/sp:A">section 430(g)(3)(A)</cato:entity-ref> (without regard to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:430/ss:g/p:3/sp:B">section
				430(g)(3)(B)</cato:entity-ref>).</text>
							</paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="H6D7B9F12C5E445AA9404236CEA6A06E3">
              <enum>(d)</enum>
              <header>Model reporting
				statement</header>
              <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall develop model reporting statements
				for purposes of <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:4980J/ss:a" proposed="true">subsections (a)</cato:entity-ref> and <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:4980J/ss:b" proposed="true">(b)</cato:entity-ref>. Plan sponsors of State or local
				government employee pension plans may elect, in such form and manner as shall
				be prescribed by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary</cato:entity-ref>, to utilize the applicable model reporting
				statement for purposes of complying with requirements of such
				subsections.</text>
						</subsection>
            <subsection id="HA138AC282B4A49FABAA63912111C984A">
              <enum>(e)</enum>
              <header>Transparency of
				information filed</header>
              <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall create and maintain a
				public Web site, with searchable capabilities, for purposes of posting the
				information received by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> pursuant to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:4980J/ss:a" proposed="true">subsections (a)</cato:entity-ref> and <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:4980J/ss:b" proposed="true">(b)</cato:entity-ref>. Any
				such information received by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> (including any updates to such
				information received by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary</cato:entity-ref>) shall be posted on the Web site not
				later than 60 days after receipt and shall not be treated as return information
				for purposes of this
				title.</text>
						</subsection>
          </section>
          <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
        </quoted-block>
			</subsection>
      <subsection id="H45F40F4282E34E5A86B01D0AC315DECB">
        <enum>(c)</enum>
        <header>Clerical
			 amendments</header>
				<paragraph id="H041D93887CDA4A5B8DE7170DC2EAF807">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>The table of
			 sections for <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/ch:1/sch:B/pt:IV/spt:B">subpart B of part IV of subchapter B of chapter 1 of such Code</cato:entity-ref> is
			 amended by adding at the end the following new item:</text>
					<quoted-block id="H95150EC32317404786BC7D15B6BF4F78" style="OLC">
						<toc regeneration="no-regeneration">
							<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 149A. Reporting with respect to State
				or local government employee pension benefit
				plans.</toc-entry>
						</toc>
						<after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
          </quoted-block>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HCE43FDC44ACB48199B29D0A2B9EDD4A3">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>The table of
			 sections for <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/ch:43">chapter 43 of such Code</cato:entity-ref> is amended by adding at the end the
			 following new item:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H48BAEFAB82C04D12AF3D428F1A420016" style="OLC">
						<toc container-level="quoted-block-container" idref="H44F3DCA2132B496CB707181EFDDFDC4F" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded" lowest-level="section" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" regeneration="yes-regeneration">
							<toc-entry idref="H76D12A1E71DA4645AA9F0506AF8723A9" level="section">Sec. 4980J. Failure of State or local government employee
				pension benefit plans to meet reporting
				requirements.</toc-entry>
						</toc>
						<after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
          </quoted-block>
				</paragraph>
      </subsection>
    </section>
    <section id="HB64780BE51234D02B9E98B83F0DFB184">
      <enum>4.</enum>
      <header>General
			 provisions and rules of construction</header>
			<subsection id="H64FE861F1E494F4884ED8FF0B4C22FB3">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Limitations on
			 federal responsibilities relating to plan obligations and
			 liabilities</header>
        <text>The United States shall not be liable for any
			 obligation related to any current or future shortfall in any State or local
			 government employee pension plan. Nothing in this Act (or any amendment made by
			 this Act) or any other provision of law shall be construed to provide Federal
			 Government funds to diminish or meet any current or future shortfall in, or
			 obligation of, any State or local government employee pension plan. The
			 preceding sentence shall also apply to the Federal Reserve.</text>
			</subsection>
      <subsection id="H48935E561FCA4C17BCF2816C85D69640">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>No federal
			 funding standards</header>
        <text>Nothing in this Act (or any amendment made by
			 this Act) shall be construed to alter existing funding standards for State or
			 local government employee pension plans or to require Federal funding standards
			 for such plans.</text>
			</subsection>
      <subsection id="H1E059A86ADE4420FA779C6727EBCAAC6">
        <enum>(c)</enum>
        <header>Definitions</header>
        <text>Terms
			 used in this section which are also used in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:4980J" proposed="true">section 4980J of the Internal
			 Revenue Code of 1986</cato:entity-ref> shall have the same meaning as when used in such
			 section.</text>
			</subsection>
    </section>
  </legis-body>
</bill>
</doc>