<doc>
  <docmeta id="113s1810is">
    <bill congress="113" type="s" number="1810" version="is"/>
    <revision size="56337" annotations="0" status="complete" id="11" commit-time="2014-01-03T19:50:04Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113s1810is/11.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" public-private="public">
  <metadata>
<dublinCore>
<dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">113 S1810 IS: Family and Medical Insurance Leave Act of 2013</dc:title>
<dc:publisher xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">2013-12-12</dc:date>
<dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
    <congress>113th CONGRESS</congress>
    <session>1st Session</session>
    <legis-num>S. 1810</legis-num>
    <current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
    <action>
      <action-date date="20131212" legis-day="20131211">December 12 (legislative day, December 11), 2013</action-date>
      <action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="S331">Mrs. Gillibrand</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFI00">Committee on Finance</committee-name>
      </action-desc>
    </action>
    <legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
    <official-title>To provide paid family and medical leave benefits to certain individuals, and for other purposes.</official-title>
  </form>
  <legis-body id="H5BA2599BB14E41368D0219B262F5EE8D" style="OLC">
    <section id="HD711709576AE4F1EA7FAC55834638CFF" section-type="section-one">
      <enum>1.</enum>
      <header>Short title</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote>
          <short-title>
            <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Family and Medical Insurance Leave Act of 2013" proposed="true">Family and Medical Insurance Leave Act of 2013</cato:entity-ref>
          </short-title>
        </quote>.</text>
    </section>
    <section id="HC3413FB91AB941E298A3A79121FB8B38">
      <enum>2.</enum>
      <header>Findings and purpose</header>
      <subsection id="HA471B635EEAE4F079EB87A12CE286863">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Findings</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">
          <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> finds the following:</text>
        <paragraph id="HFEACC4A1844942D4954B3BA0CC94AE37">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>In nearly two-thirds of families with children, all adults in the household work. Three in four caregivers have worked at a paying job at some point during their caregiving experience. Without paid family and medical leave, many workers are unable to take time away from work to care for newborn children, ill or aging parents and relatives, or themselves.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HB84001B738FA4B2A91843CB758913732">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>Both women and men need to be able to take time off work to participate in early care of their children, in the care of seriously ill family members, and to address their own serious health conditions. Yet, a mere 12 percent of workers in the United States have access to paid family leave through their employers, and fewer than 40 percent have access to short-term disability insurance provided by their employer to use for their own illnesses.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H63DF5867FFF64DAC817B36CC63B7562B">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Many workers cannot afford to take unpaid time off work to provide care. According to the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1600">Department of Labor</cato:entity-ref>, nearly half of workers who qualified for leave under the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Family and Medical Leave Act of 1993">Family and Medical Leave Act of 1993</cato:entity-ref> (FMLA) in 2011 were unable to take the leave because they could not afford to take time off without pay. Six in ten workers who took partially paid or unpaid leave reported difficulty making ends meet; half of these workers were forced to cut their leaves short due to financial constraints.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H1D206830038D42238EC89D473C88EF26">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Only 12 percent of all workers had access to paid family leave in 2012 and it was available to only 4 percent of individuals working in the lowest paying jobs. Workers who lack paid family leave face lost wages or even job loss when they miss work because of their own illness or to care for an ill child or parent. In this way, access to paid leave plays a critical role in families’ efforts to maintain employment and economic security.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H9C6B2BC4D8F5446EB334B5D5DB196EF6">
          <enum>(5)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Caregiving has a high value but also comes at a high cost for family caregivers. The estimated value of unpaid family care provided in 2009 was $450 billion. Caregivers face financial, physical and emotional hardships, and in many cases their careers, incomes, and retirement security suffer because of their family responsibilities. Working caregivers should not have to risk their family’s economic security to fulfill their caregiving obligations. The average worker age 50 and older who leaves the workforce to care for an elderly parent loses more than $300,000 in earnings and retirement income.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H06BEDAFC141B438690138F9C764C04F4">
          <enum>(6)</enum>
          <text>The population over age 65 is expected to double within the next few decades. The number of people with chronic conditions is expected to reach 157 million by 2020. Many of these individuals will at some point require family care, and for older workers still in the workforce, many will need time off at some point to address serious health conditions.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HE17C087C19024FAF8A5BD9739C1934A2">
          <enum>(7)</enum>
          <text>Ensuring working family caregivers have paid family leave to care for ailing elders could drive down Medicare costs by decreasing recurrences of ailments and re-admittance into hospitals.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H2B127B7A7C91478390F4C462C7CC607A">
          <enum>(8)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Many workers are forced to quickly return to work after the birth or arrival of a child because they have no access to paid family and medical leave. Only half of new mothers take paid leave of any duration after the birth of their first child, and among women with less than a high school education the figure is less than 20 percent—a rate that has not changed in half a century.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HEE67D360BDDF4287A8EE98D23699B881">
          <enum>(9)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">When new mothers have no choice but to return to work without taking leave, children can experience a variety of negative outcomes including higher rates of infant mortality, lower rates of breastfeeding, lower rates of immunization, and a higher incidence of maternal physical and mental health concerns. California’s paid family leave insurance program has increased the number of weeks of leave that women take after childbirth, with larger effects among women in jobs that do not provide paid leave.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H76CA9C79648D4A268DFD73A439A5A836">
          <enum>(10)</enum>
          <text>A nationwide paid family leave program would address the persistent sex discrimination in the utilization of leave benefits and reduce the disparity between women and men regarding who takes time off from work to fulfill caregiving duties. This disparity is driven in part by the fact that men continue to earn more than women, and, as a result, it often makes more economic sense for women in two-parent families to take unpaid leave and forgo their lower salary.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H0438102D49994B62A94A356C88EA3854">
          <enum>(11)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Many men would like to be more involved in caregiving and report greater work-family conflict than ever before. In California, men’s use of the State’s paid family leave insurance program to care for a new child has doubled since the program’s implementation.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HF19CABDD7C29450C96AE71D9F5720A3B">
          <enum>(12)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Paid family and medical leave promotes families’ financial security and independence, increases worker retention, and promotes savings for taxpayers. Women who take paid leave after a child’s birth are more likely to be in the labor force in the 9 to 12 months after a child’s birth and to earn higher wages in the year following their child’s birth. Both men and women who take paid leave after a child’s birth are less likely to receive food stamps and public assistance in the year following a child’s birth.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H940DED9F10394989A71A6A5CB7A11984">
          <enum>(13)</enum>
          <text>Without paid medical leave, workers who are ill or injured may return to work before being fully recovered, thus making them susceptible to a relapse or recurrence, and potentially placing additional burdens on the health care system. When a job requires physical stamina or ability, individuals who return to work too early may put themselves or others in jeopardy.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H9112E7436C5A474FAB9CF73DE670751E">
          <enum>(14)</enum>
          <text>A social insurance model of providing paid family leave pioneered by the states of California and New Jersey has worked well for workers, their families, and employers. Between 2004 and 2012, Californians took more than 1.4 million leaves to care for a family member or bond with a new child. Between 2009 and 2012, more than 100,000 New Jersey workers filed eligible claims for family leave. The overwhelming majority of California employers report that the program had a positive or neutral effect on their business. Researchers conclude that some employers experienced cost savings by coordinating their own benefits with those offered through the State paid family leave program.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H2D91C2DB27E347BF9641C50559E575A5">
          <enum>(15)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Employers and employees benefit when workers have access to paid leave. Social Security is one of the Nation’s primary social insurance systems and it provides retirement assistance and disability benefits. When Social Security was created in 1934, most families had a stay at home caregiver. That is no longer the case. For the first time in the Nation’s history, half of all workers in the United States are women. The system needs to be changed to reflect the realities of today’s workforce and provide workers with income when they need leave from work due to the birth of a child or a serious health condition.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H6FD9B33E88DE410698221E9C2D1CF966">
          <enum>(16)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">When workers can care for themselves and their loved ones, employers experience positive impacts. More than four times as many worksites covered by <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Family and Medical Leave Act of 1993">FMLA</cato:entity-ref> reported positive effects on employee productivity, absenteeism, turnover, career advancement and morale, as well as the business’ profitability as reported negative effects in the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1600">Department of Labor’s</cato:entity-ref> 2012 survey on the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Family and Medical Leave Act of 1993">FMLA</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="HDBA338D53FB54F78B870A823BFE07739">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Purpose</header>
        <text>It is the purpose of this Act—</text>
        <paragraph id="HABF3F3FBCF63412F8ABF3999F45C2BC5">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to help working families, including single working parents and dual-earner families, afford to take time away from work to provide care for a family member and be good workers;</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HE5F561C2EDFA49FA9ED6364BB06FD048">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>to provide workers with a reasonable level of wage replacement during time away from work for a serious health condition, for the birth or adoption of a child, for the care of a child, spouse, or parent who has a serious health condition, for the care of an injured servicemember, or for qualifying exigencies arising from the deployment of a servicemember;</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H9CB9CD05A92242FCB0DC00E8CE5B7B58">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <text>to address sex discrimination, promote the goal of equal employment opportunity for women and men, and to provide relief when employers violate the law; and</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HD1C53F3C536546599ECBC2E5C0DCDD94">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
          <text>to accomplish the purposes described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Family and Medical Insurance Leave Act of 2013/s:2/ss:b/p:1" proposed="true">paragraphs (1)</cato:entity-ref>, <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Family and Medical Insurance Leave Act of 2013/s:2/ss:b/p:2" proposed="true">(2)</cato:entity-ref>, and <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Family and Medical Insurance Leave Act of 2013/s:2/ss:b/p:3" proposed="true">(3)</cato:entity-ref> in a manner that accommodates the legitimate interests of employers.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
    </section>
    <section id="H64DB075E1EB348AD9FB4489A6C323E3C">
      <enum>3.</enum>
      <header>Definitions</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act, the following definitions apply:</text>
      <paragraph id="H9CBE34744C4649AE8629783C94B28E03">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <header>Caregiving day</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>caregiving day</term> means, with respect to an individual, a calendar day in which the individual engaged in qualified caregiving.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H27731EFD26454471ABA9A859F11AC9DB">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <header>Commissioner</header>
        <text>The term <term>Commissioner</term> means the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2800">Commissioner of Social Security</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H80261ED6C44C404EAF86BBD013249E37">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <header>Deputy Commissioner</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Deputy Commissioner</term> means the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Deputy Commission of the Office of Paid Family and Medical Leave" entity-parent-id="2800" proposed="true">Deputy Commissioner</cato:entity-ref> who heads the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Office of Paid Family and Medical Leave" entity-parent-id="2800" proposed="true">Office of Paid Family and Medical Leave</cato:entity-ref> established under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Family and Medical Insurance Leave Act of 2013/s:4/ss:a" proposed="true">section 4(a)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H3DD357A178B04123960804C9FF5FF815">
        <enum>(4)</enum>
        <header>Eligible individual</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>eligible individual</term> means an individual who is entitled to a benefit under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Family and Medical Insurance Leave Act of 2013/s:5" proposed="true">section 5</cato:entity-ref> for a particular month, upon filing an application for such benefit for such month.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HC7B4513770684CF6A3DF7AA242368FF7">
        <enum>(5)</enum>
        <header>Initial waiting period</header>
        <text>The term <term>initial waiting period</term> means a period beginning with the first caregiving day of an individual occurring during the individual’s benefit period and ending after the earlier of—</text>
        <subparagraph id="H28FF33C669AD48998EE79108A5371B3D">
          <enum>(A)</enum>
          <text>the fifth caregiving day of the individual occurring during the benefit period; or</text>
        </subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="H23EA71C59014431889C3B8B1B3989A59">
          <enum>(B)</enum>
          <text>the month preceding the first month in the benefit period during which occur not less than 15 caregiving days of the individual.</text>
        </subparagraph>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HA76636E027434401A8E1E90BE4EE4468">
        <enum>(6)</enum>
        <header>Qualified caregiving</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>qualified caregiving</term> means any activity engaged in by an individual, other than regular employment, for a reason for which an eligible employee would be entitled to leave under <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Family and Medical Leave Act of 1993/s:102/ss:a/p:1/sp:A..E">subparagraphs (A) through (E) of paragraph (1) of section 102(a) of the Family and Medical Leave Act of 1993</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/2612">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/29/2612/a">29 U.S.C. 2612(a)</cato:entity-ref>
          </external-xref>)</cato:entity>.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H57FB87F6B993417FBF459CB389CEDF97">
        <enum>(7)</enum>
        <header>Self-employment income</header>
        <text>The term <term>self-employment income</term> has the same meaning as such term in <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Social Security Act/s:211/ss:b">section 211(b) of such Act</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/411">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/42/411/b">42 U.S.C. 411(b)</cato:entity-ref>
          </external-xref>)</cato:entity>.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H8E622A610B2042278DC91B6F394DB1EB">
        <enum>(8)</enum>
        <header>State</header>
        <text>The term <term>State</term> means any State of the United States or the District of Columbia or any Territory or possession of the United States.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H1142ED6815F94363B8494A4B327E6C45">
        <enum>(9)</enum>
        <header>Wages</header>
        <text>The term <term>wages</term>, except as such term is used in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Family and Medical Insurance Leave Act of 2013/s:5/ss:i/p:2" proposed="true">subsection (i)(2) of section 5</cato:entity-ref>, has the same meaning as such term in <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Social Security Act/s:209">section 209 of the Social Security Act</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/409">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/42/409">42 U.S.C. 409</cato:entity-ref>
          </external-xref>)</cato:entity>.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H9FF9DA9B882A43F7B6F7BB0DF150182E">
        <enum>(10)</enum>
        <header>
          <enum-in-header>60-</enum-in-header>day limitation period</header>
        <text>The term <term>60-day limitation period</term> means a period—</text>
        <subparagraph id="HE4F2E846FA0743B2BCF5DE099D3005A9">
          <enum>(A)</enum>
          <text>beginning with the first caregiving day of an individual occurring during the individual’s benefit period and after the expiration of the individual’s 5-day waiting period, if applicable; and</text>
        </subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="H80446F1E924542B6A921B169D0DF14E5">
          <enum>(B)</enum>
          <text>ending with the 60th caregiving day of the individual occurring during the benefit period and after the expiration of the 5-day waiting period,</text>
        </subparagraph>
        <continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph">disregarding any caregiving day of the individual occurring during any month in the benefit period after the first 20 caregiving days of the individual occurring during such month.</continuation-text>
      </paragraph>
    </section>
    <section id="HECBDB47C1F5A4B3191738DB5E955290C">
      <enum>4.</enum>
      <header>Office of Paid Family and Medical Leave</header>
      <subsection id="H04D9884C43D645F180332A6F41CE6013">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Establishment of Office</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is established within the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2800">Social Security Administration</cato:entity-ref> an office to be known as the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Office of Paid Family and Medical Leave" entity-parent-id="2800" proposed="true">Office of Paid Family and Medical Leave</cato:entity-ref>. The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Office of Paid Family and Medical Leave" entity-parent-id="2800" proposed="true">Office</cato:entity-ref> shall be headed by a <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Deputy Commission of the Office of Paid Family and Medical Leave" entity-parent-id="2800" proposed="true">Deputy Commissioner</cato:entity-ref> who shall be appointed by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2800">Commissioner</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="H87AC5C03C1CA4E3DB1171C83C3E354FF">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Responsibilities of Deputy Commissioner</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2800">Commissioner</cato:entity-ref>, acting through the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Deputy Commission of the Office of Paid Family and Medical Leave" entity-parent-id="2800" proposed="true">Deputy Commissioner</cato:entity-ref>, shall be responsible for—</text>
        <paragraph id="H4B78B92439EE406093B7F744C8AE4B5E">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>hiring personnel and making employment decisions with regard to such personnel;</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HE7674D87E1CE455890DE1438AC0E46F0">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>issuing such regulations as may be necessary to carry out the purposes of this Act;</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H57E7E205D66D4B1497C5C74F98CFBCBA">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <text>entering into cooperative agreements with other agencies and departments to ensure the efficiency of the administration of the program;</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H203E4F8D6C5A4A9B9FE1B60D42191A80">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
          <text>determining eligibility for family and medical leave insurance benefits under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Family and Medical Insurance Leave Act of 2013/s:5" proposed="true">section 5</cato:entity-ref>;</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H15A03168E96E4D4D8D5715C3DA5F82F2">
          <enum>(5)</enum>
          <text>determining benefit amounts for each month of such eligibility and making timely payments of such benefits to entitled individuals in accordance with such section;</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H8DCE1219BFAB4C01A89FEC8C5900DC6C">
          <enum>(6)</enum>
          <text>establishing and maintaining a system of records relating to the administration of such section;</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H626E9AD98D3A46CBB3E228ABD3E25BF5">
          <enum>(7)</enum>
          <text>preventing fraud and abuse relating to such benefits;</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph commented="no" id="HA5C72C810D5D465FB99F4196FDE52548">
          <enum>(8)</enum>
          <text>providing information on request regarding eligibility requirements, the claims process, benefit amounts, maximum benefits payable, notice requirements, non-discrimination rights, confidentiality, coordination of leave under this Act and other laws, collective bargaining agreements, and employer policies;</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph commented="no" id="HF60F02E9A78C45D3A0C3B2D61929EEFE">
          <enum>(9)</enum>
          <text>annually providing employers a notice informing employees of the availability of such benefits;</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph commented="no" id="HE9BC308993FA44D1ADBFD16ADA82B26C">
          <enum>(10)</enum>
          <text>annually making available to the public a report that includes the number of individuals who received such benefits, the purposes for which such benefits were received, and an analysis of utilization rates of such benefits by gender, race, ethnicity, and income levels; and</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph commented="no" id="HC399D78E667145CFBB2A8960E5E134BF">
          <enum>(11)</enum>
          <text>tailoring culturally and linguistically competent education and outreach toward increasing utilization rates of benefits under such section.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="HB66064B4258945EDA105740F584CBC9B">
        <enum>(c)</enum>
        <header>Availability of data</header>
        <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2800">Commissioner</cato:entity-ref> shall make available to the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Deputy Commission of the Office of Paid Family and Medical Leave" entity-parent-id="2800" proposed="true">Deputy Commissioner</cato:entity-ref> such data as the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2800" value="Deputy Commission of the Office of Paid Family and Medical Leave">Commissioner</cato:entity-ref> determines necessary to enable the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Deputy Commission of the Office of Paid Family and Medical Leave" entity-parent-id="2800" proposed="true">Deputy Commissioner</cato:entity-ref> to effectively carry out the responsibilities described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Family and Medical Insurance Leave Act of 2013/s:4/ss:b" proposed="true">subsection (b)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
      </subsection>
    </section>
    <section id="HFAA2BD69BEE947A39308DFF76747C971">
      <enum>5.</enum>
      <header>Family and Medical Leave Insurance benefit payments</header>
      <subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H938A93CE54BB4D7F9F78CE6A1FD61F52">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>In general</header>
        <text>Every individual who—</text>
        <paragraph id="HC6588D027EDB419BAE773F04D68B864C">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is insured for disability insurance benefits (as determined under <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Social Security Act/s:223/ss:c">section 223(c) of the Social Security Act</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/423">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/42/423/c">42 U.S.C. 423(c)</cato:entity-ref>
            </external-xref>)</cato:entity>) at the time such individual’s application is filed;</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H80FC8E4D8E394422A5A8115B2A913112">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>has earned income from employment during the 12 months prior to the month in which the application is filed;</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HA127598E9C4042E180D8160449FA3289">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <text>has filed an application for a family and medical leave insurance benefit in accordance with <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Family and Medical Insurance Leave Act of 2013/s:5/ss:d" proposed="true">subsection (d)</cato:entity-ref>; and</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H52367671F3814652ADAA7FE1546C1224">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">was engaged in qualified caregiving, or anticipates being so engaged, during the period that begins 90 days before the date on which such application is filed or within 30 days after such date,</text>
        </paragraph>
        <continuation-text continuation-text-level="subsection">shall be entitled to such a benefit for each month in the benefit period specified in 
            <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Family and Medical Insurance Leave Act of 2013/s:5/ss:c" proposed="true">subsection (c)</cato:entity-ref>
          , not to exceed 60 caregiving days per benefit period.</continuation-text>
      </subsection>
      <subsection commented="no" id="H3BAC88B6813945508C9B220867BECF5E">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Benefit amount</header>
        <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF590F832AE944D548E38A6CA377DCF37">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>In general</header>
          <text>Except as otherwise provided in this subsection, the benefit amount to which an individual is entitled under this section for a month shall be an amount equal to the greater of—</text>
          <subparagraph commented="no" id="H56EBA94EBADE4E6B94F95E2705186FC5">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the lesser of <fraction>1/18</fraction> of the wages and self-employment income of the individual for the calendar year in which such wages and self-employment income are the highest among the most recent three calendar years, or the maximum benefit amount determined under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Family and Medical Insurance Leave Act of 2013/s:5/ss:b/p:2" proposed="true">paragraph (2)</cato:entity-ref>; or</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph commented="no" id="H3107183F578B4CDABDE76CC15CB2143E">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the minimum benefit amount determined under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Family and Medical Insurance Leave Act of 2013/s:5/ss:b/p:2" proposed="true">paragraph (2)</cato:entity-ref>,</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph">multiplied by the quotient (not greater than 1) obtained by dividing the number of caregiving days of the individual in such month by 20.</continuation-text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph commented="no" id="H969D8AAD75B6429493FB15BE55F4F4BF">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Annual increase of maximum and minimum benefit amounts</header>
          <subparagraph commented="no" id="H4E81087A07914393B161312203BE9875">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>For individuals who initially become eligible for family and medical leave insurance benefits in the first full calendar year after the date of enactment of this Act, the maximum monthly benefit amount and the minimum monthly benefit amount shall be $4,000 and $580, respectively.</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph commented="no" id="H44A12FCD81F44001B7104BB46ADAA4A0">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For individuals who initially become eligible for family and medical leave insurance benefits in any calendar year after such first full calendar year the maximum benefit amount and the minimum benefit amount shall be, respectively, the product of the corresponding amount determined with respect to the first calendar year under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Family and Medical Insurance Leave Act of 2013/s:5/ss:b/p:2/sp:A" proposed="true">subparagraph (A)</cato:entity-ref> and the quotient obtained by dividing—</text>
            <clause commented="no" id="H079CB03307EF4C4399FEB51789A29310">
              <enum>(i)</enum>
              <text>the national average wage index (as defined in <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
                  <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Social Security Act/s:209/ss:k/p:1">section 209(k)(1) of the Social Security Act</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/409">
                  <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/42/409/k/1">42 U.S.C. 409(k)(1)</cato:entity-ref>
                </external-xref>)</cato:entity>) for the second calendar year preceding the first calendar year for which the determination is made, by</text>
            </clause>
            <clause commented="no" id="H5D416A6252EA4F05A7C13AB6F52AEA66">
              <enum>(ii)</enum>
              <text>the national average wage index (as so defined) for 2013.</text>
            </clause>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H3ABC87753D2A4306AD56F4BCC285E384">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <header>Limitations on benefits paid</header>
          <subparagraph id="H5B3FE1B525AB4DAFA13A07F128BDB195">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <header>Nonpayable waiting period</header>
            <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any calendar day during an individual’s benefit period which occurs before the expiration of an initial waiting period shall not be taken into account under this subsection as a caregiving day of the individual.</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="HE7648DD673394E5DB1EA7745E9E6A1BF">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <header>Limitation on total benefits paid</header>
            <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any calendar day during an individual’s benefit period which occurs after the expiration of a 60-day limitation period shall not be taken into account under this subsection as a caregiving day of the individual.</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HA34821B142324C9DAC673C9FBDAA3193">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
          <header>Reduction in benefit amount on account of receipt of certain benefits</header>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A benefit under this section for a month shall be reduced by the amount, if any, in certain benefits (as determined under regulations issued by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2800">Commissioner</cato:entity-ref>) as may be otherwise received by an individual. For purposes of the preceding sentence, certain benefits include—</text>
          <subparagraph id="H9128D39601E94DE79DD89D17AC486B56">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">periodic benefits on account of such individual’s total or partial disability under a workmen’s compensation law or plan of the United States or a State; and</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="HF877CEC0CDDA4E349D6476A2697E899D">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>periodic benefits on account of an individual’s employment status under an unemployment law or plan of the United States or a State.</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H45179935EFAC4942A580020C1F7742FA">
          <enum>(5)</enum>
          <header>Coordination of benefit amount with certain state benefits</header>
          <text>A benefit received under this section shall be coordinated, in a manner determined by regulations issued by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2800">Commissioner</cato:entity-ref>, with the periodic benefits received from temporary disability insurance or family leave insurance programs under any law or plan of a State, a political subdivision (as that term is used in <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Social Security Act/s:218/ss:b/p:2">section 218(b)(2) of the Social Security Act</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/418">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/42/418/b/2">42 U.S.C. 418(b)(2)</cato:entity-ref>
            </external-xref>)</cato:entity>), or an instrumentality of 2 or more States (as that term is used in <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Social Security Act/s:218/ss:g">section 218(g) of such Act of the Social Security Act</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/418">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/42/418/g">42 U.S.C. 418(g)</cato:entity-ref>
            </external-xref>)</cato:entity>).</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="HF37B893C468C479B851358C08CA2F52C">
        <enum>(c)</enum>
        <header>Benefit period</header>
        <paragraph id="H13234184C17E4458947036D632DDC92A">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>In general</header>
          <text>Except as provided in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Family and Medical Insurance Leave Act of 2013/s:5/ss:c/p:2" proposed="true">paragraph (2)</cato:entity-ref>, the benefit period specified in this subsection shall begin on the 1st day of the 1st month in which the individual meets the criteria specified in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Family and Medical Insurance Leave Act of 2013/s:5/ss:a/p:1" proposed="true">paragraphs (1)</cato:entity-ref>, <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Family and Medical Insurance Leave Act of 2013/s:5/ss:a/p:2" proposed="true">(2)</cato:entity-ref>, and <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Family and Medical Insurance Leave Act of 2013/s:5/ss:a/p:3" proposed="true">(3) of subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref>, and shall end on the date that is 365 days after the 1st day of the benefit period.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HC8CDC14498124F39A2CBC877930D4264">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Retroactive benefits</header>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of an application for benefits under this section for qualified caregiving in which the individual was engaged at any time during the 90-day period preceding the date on which such application is submitted, the benefit period specified in this subsection shall begin on the later of—</text>
          <subparagraph id="HC598AEF3A1D74B368373E8F6C80BEB50">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>the 1st day of the 1st month in which the individual engaged in such qualified caregiving; or</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H7DDF5AC1FE96400DA7632CD692D2B172">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>the 1st day of the 1st month that begins during such 90-day period,</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph">and shall end on the date that is 365 days after the 1st day of the benefit period.</continuation-text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="HE324B02A5CFF4E80A0B4B2FAE0CBCE35">
        <enum>(d)</enum>
        <header>Application</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An application for a family and medical leave insurance benefit shall include—</text>
        <paragraph id="H8493D4AEA1594F97BD9337CEF3CE81BD">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>a statement that the individual was engaged in qualified caregiving, or anticipates being so engaged, during the period that begins 90 days before the date on which the application is submitted or within 30 days after such date;</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HCA604DB960C44F43925B96EE14F36A12">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>if the qualified caregiving described in the statement in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Family and Medical Insurance Leave Act of 2013/s:5/ss:d/p:1" proposed="true">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref> is engaged in by the individual because of a serious health condition of the individual or a relative of the individual, a certification, issued by the health care provider treating such serious health condition, that affirms the information specified in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Family and Medical Insurance Leave Act of 2013/s:5/ss:d/p:1" proposed="true">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref> and contains such information as the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2800">Commissioner</cato:entity-ref> shall specify in regulations, which shall be no more than the information that is required to be stated under <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Family and Medical Leave Act of 1993/s:103/ss:b">section 103(b) of the Family and Medical Leave Act of 1993</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/2613">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/29/2613/b">29 U.S.C. 2613(b)</cato:entity-ref>
            </external-xref>)</cato:entity>;</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HF69E7A8F2AA94036A3AA7FFA5AF45F17">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <text>if such qualified caregiving is engaged in by the individual for any other authorized reason, a certification, issued by a relevant authority determined under regulations issued by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2800">Commissioner</cato:entity-ref>, that affirms the circumstances giving rise to such reason; and</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph commented="no" id="H7FCACF913D884691AF2DABD9F1F268F8">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an attestation from the applicant that his or her employer has been provided with written notice of the individual’s intention to take family or medical leave, if the individual has an employer, or to the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2800">Commissioner</cato:entity-ref> in all other cases.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H66FDF76A0E114B0F8D09D5A0F0C6C5F1">
        <enum>(e)</enum>
        <header>Ineligibility; disqualification</header>
        <paragraph id="H2E7A90760F094F78817DD561F87E4BFA">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>Ineligibility for benefit</header>
          <text>An individual shall be ineligible for a benefit under this section for any month for which the individual is entitled to—</text>
          <subparagraph id="H48A62C5C0D2F4703B68B9A7CDE5EB2D5">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">disability insurance benefits under <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Social Security Act/s:223">section 223 of the Social Security Act</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/423">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/42/423">42 U.S.C. 423</cato:entity-ref>
              </external-xref>)</cato:entity> or a similar permanent disability program under any law or plan of a State or political subdivision or instrumentality of a State (as such terms are used in <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Social Security Act/s:218">section 218 of the Social Security Act</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/418">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/42/418">42 U.S.C. 418</cato:entity-ref>
              </external-xref>)</cato:entity>);</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H1034461D88D7405B979BB8CD3BD2029E">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">monthly insurance benefits under <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Social Security Act/s:202">section 202 of such Act</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/402">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/42/402">42 U.S.C. 402</cato:entity-ref>
              </external-xref>)</cato:entity> based on such individual's disability (as defined in <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Social Security Act/s:223/ss:d">section 223(d) of such Act</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/423">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/42/423/d">42 U.S.C. 423(d)</cato:entity-ref>
              </external-xref>)</cato:entity>); or</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H5997411941F34FF2A48A9DFE82335E3B">
            <enum>(C)</enum>
            <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">benefits under <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Social Security Act/t:XVI">title XVI of such Act</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1381">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/42/1381/etseq">42 U.S.C. 1381 et seq</cato:entity-ref>.</external-xref>)</cato:entity> based on such individual’s status as a disabled individual (as determined under <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Social Security Act/s:1614">section 1614 of such Act</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1382c">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/42/1382c">42 U.S.C. 1382c</cato:entity-ref>
              </external-xref>)</cato:entity>).</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H67A1483FF4A847ED9B1C328B97B31AEA">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Disqualification</header>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An individual who has been convicted of a violation under <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Social Security Act/s:208">section 208 of the Social Security Act</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/408">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/42/408">42 U.S.C. 408</cato:entity-ref>
            </external-xref>)</cato:entity> or who has been found to have used false statement to secure benefits under this section, shall be ineligible for benefits under this section for a 1-year period following the date of such conviction.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection commented="no" id="H0FD18300FE4E4B58BB2A7BFCB16B1414">
        <enum>(f)</enum>
        <header>Review of eligibility and benefit payment determinations</header>
        <paragraph commented="no" id="HB4255EF665684F2FB9106C99C0FA4694">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>Eligibility determinations</header>
          <subparagraph id="HEB3779D2AF694518901B462A6AEF1F24">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <header>In general</header>
            <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2800">Commissioner</cato:entity-ref> shall provide notice to an individual applying for benefits under this section of the initial determination of eligibility for such benefits, and the estimated benefit amount for a month in which one caregiving day of the individual occurs, as soon as practicable after the application is received.</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="HB2A5A1A47D7A4F8A90A61B16A881FD73">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <header>Review</header>
            <text>An individual may request review of an initial adverse determination with respect to such application at any time before the end of the 20-day period that begins on the date notice of such determination is received, except that such 20-day period may be extended for good cause. As soon as practicable after the individual requests review of the determination, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2800">Commissioner</cato:entity-ref> shall provide notice to the individual of a final determination of eligibility for benefits under this section.</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H62AB04C49D8E40368E805C7B959B2F74">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Benefit payment determinations</header>
          <subparagraph id="H744CA3ADA6DC4F04844A1F66BA626FB0">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <header>In general</header>
            <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2800">Commissioner</cato:entity-ref> shall make any monthly benefit payment to an individual claiming benefits for a month under this section, or provide notice of the reason such payment will not be made if the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2800">Commissioner</cato:entity-ref> determines that the individual is not entitled to payment for such month, not later than 20 days after the individual’s monthly benefit claim report for such month is received. Such monthly report shall be filed with the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2800">Commissioner</cato:entity-ref> not later than 15 days after the end of each month.</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H6B99B005B0E74DDCB812CD7BE23CDF5D">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <header>Review</header>
            <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2800">Commissioner</cato:entity-ref> determines that payment will not be made to an individual for a month, or if the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2800">Commissioner</cato:entity-ref> determines that payment shall be made based on a number of caregiving days in the month inconsistent with the number of caregiving days in the monthly benefit claim report of the individual for such month, the individual may request review of such determination at any time before the end of the 20-day period that begins on the date notice of such determination is received, except that such 20-day period may be extended for good cause. Not later than 20 days after the individual requests review of the determination, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2800">Commissioner</cato:entity-ref> shall provide notice to the individual of a final determination of payment for such month, and shall make payment to the individual of any additional amount not included in the initial payment to the individual for such month to which the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2800">Commissioner</cato:entity-ref> determines the individual is entitled.</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph commented="no" id="H566860F8389441808AB52325BB78DFC4">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <header>Burden of proof</header>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An application for benefits under this section and a monthly benefit claim report of an individual shall each be presumed to be true and accurate, unless the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2800">Commissioner</cato:entity-ref> demonstrates by a preponderance of the evidence that information contained in the application is false.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HA172A9C552BE446A996DD194CCBFC994">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
          <header>Definition of monthly benefit claim report</header>
          <text>For purposes of this subsection, the term <term>monthly benefit claim report</term> means, with respect to an individual for a month, the individual’s report to the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2800">Commissioner</cato:entity-ref> of the number of caregiving days of the individual in such month, which shall be filed no later than 15 days after the end of each month.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H46F87463935C4061AA4B964F56623CA2">
          <enum>(5)</enum>
          <header>Review</header>
          <text>All final determinations of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2800">Commissioner</cato:entity-ref> under this subsection shall be reviewable according to the procedures set out in <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Social Security Act/s:205">section 205 of the Social Security Act</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/405">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/42/405">42 U.S.C. 405</cato:entity-ref>
            </external-xref>)</cato:entity>.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="H0FC0790DCEFB48E1AF19CBDAC788FF01">
        <enum>(g)</enum>
        <header>Relationship with State law; employer benefits</header>
        <paragraph id="H304FEFB110C247109C476C9CFF5E88C1">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>In general</header>
          <text>This section does not preempt or supercede any provision of State or local law that authorizes a State or local municipality to provide paid family and medical leave benefits similar to the benefits provided under this section.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HE367BEEF97CF40468D3F7BE23F1A2D3A">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Greater benefits allowed</header>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this Act shall be construed to diminish the obligation of an employer to comply with any contract, collective bargaining agreement, or any employment benefit program or plan that provides greater paid leave or other leave rights to employees than the rights established under this Act.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="H7EB7BD0C967A4D6FBC6DF3E357218933">
        <enum>(h)</enum>
        <header>Prohibited Acts; enforcement</header>
        <paragraph id="HD760C1DA10ED48478410A896DBCE5BA3">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>In general</header>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It shall be unlawful for any person to discharge or in any other manner discriminate against an individual because the individual has applied for, indicated an intent to apply for, or received family and medical leave insurance benefits.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6837CD3F55B54AE0A36D7AF8E9122918">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Civil Action by an individual</header>
          <subparagraph id="HCDB74670C49548A9881258F8D38D5FD7">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <header>Liability</header>
            <text>Any person who violates <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Family and Medical Insurance Leave Act of 2013/s:5/ss:h/p:1" proposed="true">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref> shall be liable to any individual employed by such person who is affected by the violation—</text>
            <clause id="H8F978D8449C340749EFC354CDBBBED06">
              <enum>(i)</enum>
              <text>for damages equal to the sum of—</text>
              <subclause id="H35EB4518B8DD44AAB075899108381700">
                <enum>(I)</enum>
                <text>the amount of—</text>
                <item id="H1545A97A048143F2984830C5A2A63AB6">
                  <enum>(aa)</enum>
                  <text>any wages, salary, employment benefits, or other compensation denied or lost to such individual by reason of the violation; or</text>
                </item>
                <item id="HF2D0623784F84F76962A6FBFD4844FD4">
                  <enum>(bb)</enum>
                  <text>in a case in which wages, salary, employment benefits, or other compensation have not been denied or lost to the individual, any actual monetary losses sustained by the individual as a direct result of the violation, such as the cost of providing care, up to a sum equal to 60 calendar days of wages or salary for the individual;</text>
                </item>
              </subclause>
              <subclause id="H7272B9364E4543E4A6BA41F6AC67B386">
                <enum>(II)</enum>
                <text>the interest on the amount described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Family and Medical Insurance Leave Act of 2013/s:5/ss:h/p:2/sp:A/cl:i/scl:I" proposed="true">subclause (I)</cato:entity-ref> calculated at the prevailing rate; and</text>
              </subclause>
              <subclause id="H506F179097B24B47854C2DB3AE6533A0">
                <enum>(III)</enum>
                <text>an additional amount as liquidated damages equal to the sum of the amount described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Family and Medical Insurance Leave Act of 2013/s:5/ss:h/p:2/sp:A/cl:i/scl:I" proposed="true">subclause (I)</cato:entity-ref> and the interest described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Family and Medical Insurance Leave Act of 2013/s:5/ss:h/p:2/sp:A/cl:i/scl:II" proposed="true">subclause (II)</cato:entity-ref>, except that if a person who has violated <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Family and Medical Insurance Leave Act of 2013/s:5/ss:h/p:1" proposed="true">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref> proves to the satisfaction of the court that the act or omission which violated <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Family and Medical Insurance Leave Act of 2013/s:5/ss:h/p:1" proposed="true">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref> was in good faith and that the person had reasonable grounds for believing that the act or omission was not a violation of <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Family and Medical Insurance Leave Act of 2013/s:5/ss:h/p:1" proposed="true">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref>, such court may, in the discretion of the court, reduce the amount of the liability to the amount and interest determined under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Family and Medical Insurance Leave Act of 2013/s:5/ss:h/p:2/sp:A/cl:i/scl:I" proposed="true">subclauses (I)</cato:entity-ref> and <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Family and Medical Insurance Leave Act of 2013/s:5/ss:h/p:2/sp:A/cl:i/scl:II" proposed="true">(II)</cato:entity-ref>, respectively; and</text>
              </subclause>
            </clause>
            <clause id="H4DC05959DAB341E5B060C4396BF3EE7F">
              <enum>(ii)</enum>
              <text>for such equitable relief as may be appropriate, including employment, reinstatement, and promotion.</text>
            </clause>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H8996E6B1BB8047BAB691F0658773EA6E">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <header>Right of action</header>
            <text>An action to recover the damages or equitable relief prescribed in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Family and Medical Insurance Leave Act of 2013/s:5/ss:h/p:2/sp:A" proposed="true">subparagraph (A)</cato:entity-ref> may be maintained against any person in any Federal or State court of competent jurisdiction by any individual for and on behalf of—</text>
            <clause id="H8E0F119A0DC9475AB03416C7D94B2973">
              <enum>(i)</enum>
              <text>the individual; or</text>
            </clause>
            <clause id="HD044A63D60FD4E4CA31D2871B25FB1E0">
              <enum>(ii)</enum>
              <text>the individual and other individuals similarly situated.</text>
            </clause>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H7D4FB62A0A844BEE9E6B5CC9E65B9403">
            <enum>(C)</enum>
            <header>Fees and costs</header>
            <text>The court in such an action shall, in addition to any judgment awarded to the plaintiff, allow a reasonable attorney's fee, reasonable expert witness fees, and other costs of the action to be paid by the defendant.</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H36F31CD7183A4125813DD84011CE9567">
            <enum>(D)</enum>
            <header>Limitations</header>
            <text>The right provided by <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Family and Medical Insurance Leave Act of 2013/s:5/ss:h/p:2/sp:B" proposed="true">subparagraph (B)</cato:entity-ref> to bring an action by or on behalf of any individual shall terminate—</text>
            <clause id="HB524D7AF24DF49D8B896562663FD6C8E">
              <enum>(i)</enum>
              <text>on the filing of a complaint by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2800">Commissioner</cato:entity-ref> in an action under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Family and Medical Insurance Leave Act of 2013/s:5/ss:h/p:5" proposed="true">paragraph (5)</cato:entity-ref> in which restraint is sought of any further delay in the payment of the amount described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Family and Medical Insurance Leave Act of 2013/s:5/ss:h/p:2/sp:A/cl:I" proposed="true">subparagraph (A)(I)</cato:entity-ref> to such individual by the person responsible under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Family and Medical Insurance Leave Act of 2013/s:5/ss:h/p:2/sp:A" proposed="true">subparagraph (A)</cato:entity-ref> for the payment; or</text>
            </clause>
            <clause id="H69C8FCB98E7141B7BCD85EE3F6AD2CBD">
              <enum>(ii)</enum>
              <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">on the filing of a complaint by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2800">Commissioner</cato:entity-ref> in an action under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Family and Medical Insurance Leave Act of 2013/s:5/ss:h/p:3" proposed="true">paragraph (3)</cato:entity-ref> in which a recovery is sought of the damages described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Family and Medical Insurance Leave Act of 2013/s:5/ss:h/p:2/sp:A/cl:i" proposed="true">subparagraph (A)(I)</cato:entity-ref> owing to an individual by a person liable under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Family and Medical Insurance Leave Act of 2013/s:5/ss:h/p:2/sp:A" proposed="true">subparagraph (A)</cato:entity-ref>,</text>
            </clause>
            <continuation-text continuation-text-level="subparagraph">unless the action described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Family and Medical Insurance Leave Act of 2013/s:5/ss:h/p:2/sp:A/cl:i" proposed="true">clause (I)</cato:entity-ref> or <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Family and Medical Insurance Leave Act of 2013/s:5/ss:h/p:2/sp:A/cl:ii" proposed="true">(ii)</cato:entity-ref> is dismissed without prejudice on motion of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2800">Commissioner</cato:entity-ref>.</continuation-text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB3EB4EA504044FE7B167E8E869C854FF">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <header>Action by the Commissioner</header>
          <subparagraph id="H7C51E9A5DA5D4C6AB32C9DC2D6CD5B32">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <header>Civil action</header>
            <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2800">Commissioner</cato:entity-ref> may bring an action in any court of competent jurisdiction to recover the damages described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Family and Medical Insurance Leave Act of 2013/s:5/ss:h/p:2/sp:A/cl:i" proposed="true">paragraph (2)(A)(I)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H5AE47AE50F5B4E509ECA1AB156B9439D">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <header>Sums recovered</header>
            <text>Any sums recovered by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2800">Commissioner</cato:entity-ref> pursuant to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Family and Medical Insurance Leave Act of 2013/s:5/ss:h/p:3/sp:A" proposed="true">subparagraph (A)</cato:entity-ref> shall be held in a special deposit account and shall be paid, on order of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2800">Commissioner</cato:entity-ref>, directly to each individual affected. Any such sums not paid to an individual because of inability to do so within a period of 3 years shall be deposited into the Federal Family and Medical Leave Insurance Trust Fund.</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H6F0CA24A447044BBB9EBD9F82B764C1F">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
          <header>Limitation</header>
          <subparagraph id="H3782CE5CB4B74C6D9953770F6F91894C">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <header>In general</header>
            <text>An action may be brought under this subsection not later than 3 years after the date of the last event constituting the alleged violation for which the action is brought.</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="HB178DFF36A924E18B60D7D0D2B04E3DF">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <header>Commencement</header>
            <text>An action brought by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2800">Commissioner</cato:entity-ref> under this subsection shall be considered to be commenced on the date when the complaint is filed.</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H01F51B011CE14B8A95EF39DF92DB2779">
          <enum>(5)</enum>
          <header>Action for Injunction by Commissioner</header>
          <text>The district courts of the United States shall have jurisdiction, for cause shown, in an action brought by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2800">Commissioner</cato:entity-ref>—</text>
          <subparagraph id="H30ECFB4F65104814A62FDECDAEACD98E">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>to restrain violations of <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Family and Medical Insurance Leave Act of 2013/s:5/ss:h/p:1" proposed="true">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref>, including the restraint of any withholding of payment of wages, salary, employment benefits, or other compensation, plus interest, found by the court to be due to an individual; or</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H9D7D3C609A04458597B8B1181B6C651A">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>to award such other equitable relief as may be appropriate, including employment, reinstatement, and promotion.</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="H3B88B6D02EFB407382DF71802DB1FD26">
        <enum>(i)</enum>
        <header>Special rule for railroad employees</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Family and Medical Insurance Leave Act of 2013/s:5/ss:a/p:1" proposed="true">subsection (a)(1)</cato:entity-ref>, an individual shall be deemed to be insured for disability insurance benefits if the individual would be so insured if the individual’s service as an employee (as defined in the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Railroad Retirement Act of 1974/s:1/ss:b">section 1(b) of the Railroad Retirement Act of 1974</cato:entity-ref>) after December 31, 1936, were included within the meaning of the term <term>employment</term> for purposes of <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Social Security Act/t:II">title II of the Social Security Act</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/401">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/42/401/etseq">42 U.S.C. 401 et seq</cato:entity-ref>.</external-xref>)</cato:entity>.</text>
      </subsection>
      <subsection commented="no" id="HE88811AA80EE4E6AA37A74AC581DF0AF">
        <enum>(j)</enum>
        <header>Determination of whether an activity constitutes qualified caregiving</header>
        <paragraph commented="no" id="HCB4A79F3AAB04440967E1817EB2354F5">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>In general</header>
          <text>For purposes of determining whether an activity engaged in by an individual constitutes qualified caregiving under this section—</text>
          <subparagraph commented="no" id="H4039809FAB5F4497A5E5E66FC9EFF1D3">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <term>spouse</term> (as used in <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Family and Medical Leave Act/s:102/ss:a">section 102(a) of the Family and Medical Leave Act</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/2612">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/29/2612/a">29 U.S.C. 2612(a)</cato:entity-ref>
              </external-xref>)</cato:entity>) includes the individual’s domestic partner; and</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph commented="no" id="H94D5041EB36E47B49F4525ABA0C9048B">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <term>son or daughter</term> (as used in such section) includes a son or daughter (as defined in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Family and Medical Leave Act/s:101">section 101</cato:entity-ref> of such Act) of the individual’s domestic partner.</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph commented="no" id="H35542AE0E76E478E91B173E8F416F068">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Domestic partner</header>
          <subparagraph commented="no" id="H4EE30EF7AD9D421497BEF2B896F8E030">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <header>In general</header>
            <text>For purposes of <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Family and Medical Insurance Leave Act of 2013/s:5/ss:j/p:1" proposed="true">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref>, the term <term>domestic partner</term>, with respect to an individual, means another individual with whom the individual is in a committed relationship.</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph commented="no" id="H0B17B8B881EF44D890BC1EE4905BE677">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <header>Committed relationship defined</header>
            <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>committed relationship</term> means a relationship between two individuals (each at least 18 years of age) in which each individual is the other individual’s sole domestic partner and both individuals share responsibility for a significant measure of each other’s common welfare. The term includes any such relationship between two individuals, including individuals of the same sex, that is granted legal recognition by a State or political subdivision of a State as a marriage or analogous relationship, including a civil union or domestic partnership.</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="H92443C09E41F416D875AA2F61BA30FF8">
        <enum>(k)</enum>
        <header>Applicability of certain Social Security Act provisions</header>
        <text>The provisions of <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Social Security Act/s:204">sections 204</cato:entity-ref>, <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Social Security Act/s:205">205</cato:entity-ref>, <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Social Security Act/s:206">206</cato:entity-ref>, and <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Social Security Act/s:208">208 of the Social Security Act</cato:entity-ref> shall apply to benefit payments authorized by and paid out pursuant to this section in the same way that such provisions apply to benefit payments authorized by and paid out pursuant to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Social Security Act/t:II">title II</cato:entity-ref> of such Act.</text>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="H15B7C46A1D9D4FD89836638CEBF03DB8">
        <enum>(l)</enum>
        <header>Effective date for applications</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Applications described in this section may be filed beginning 18 months after the date of enactment of this Act.</text>
      </subsection>
    </section>
    <section id="H7B6EF69F60D84BBF9EE58044B4584423">
      <enum>6.</enum>
      <header>Establishment of Family and Medical Leave Insurance Trust Fund</header>
      <subsection id="HFDEB851D44A742C9A79F8D941B7A19E6">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>In general</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is hereby created on the books of the Treasury of the United States a trust fund to be known as the <term>Federal Family and Medical Leave Insurance Trust Fund</term>. The Federal Family and Medical Leave Insurance Trust Fund shall consist of such gifts and bequests as may be made as provided in <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Social Security Act/s:201/ss:i/p:1">section 201(i)(1) of the Social Security Act</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/401">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/42/401/i/1">42 U.S.C. 401(i)(1)</cato:entity-ref>
          </external-xref>)</cato:entity> and such amounts as may be appropriated to, or deposited in, the Federal Family and Medical Leave Insurance Trust Fund as provided in this section.</text>
      </subsection>
      <subsection commented="no" id="HE95F8625F76445EE81945FEFCCE45C00">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Authorization of Appropriations</header>
        <paragraph commented="no" id="H51268E7EB4BC4A0189086969ED35D068">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>In general</header>
          <text>
            <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="auth-auth-approp">There is authorized to be appropriated to the Federal Family and Medical Leave Insurance Trust Fund out of moneys in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated—</cato:entity>
          </text>
          <subparagraph commented="no" id="HA5B45BC33F7A4AC4B5E079FF758337EB">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>
              <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="auth-auth-approp">for the first three fiscal years beginning after the date of enactment of this Act, <cato:funds-and-year amount="indefinite">such sums as may be necessary</cato:funds-and-year> <cato:property name="purpose">for the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2800">Commissioner</cato:entity-ref> to administer the office established under <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Family and Medical Insurance Leave Act of 2013/s:4" proposed="true">section 4</cato:entity-ref> and pay the benefits under <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Family and Medical Insurance Leave Act of 2013/s:5" proposed="true">section 5</cato:entity-ref>
                </cato:property>;</cato:entity>
            </text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph commented="no" id="H2B7F039839A342E8BE00DAD8E5923F00">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>
              <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="auth-auth-approp">
                <cato:funds-and-year amount="indefinite">100 percent of the taxes imposed by <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:3101/ss:c">sections 3101(c)</cato:entity-ref> and <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:3111/ss:c">3111(c) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986</cato:entity-ref>
                </cato:funds-and-year> with respect to wages (as defined in <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:3121">section 3121</cato:entity-ref> of such Code) reported to the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary of the Treasury</cato:entity-ref> pursuant to <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/st:F">subtitle F</cato:entity-ref> of such Code, as determined by the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary of the Treasury</cato:entity-ref> by applying the applicable rate of tax under such sections to such wages;</cato:entity>
            </text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph commented="no" id="H5400749057B24964B89D4311FED8C50B">
            <enum>(C)</enum>
            <text>
              <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="auth-auth-approp">
                <cato:funds-and-year amount="indefinite">100 percent of the taxes imposed by <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:1401/ss:c" proposed="true">section 1401(c)</cato:entity-ref> of such Code with respect to self-employment income</cato:funds-and-year> (as defined in <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:1402">section 1402</cato:entity-ref> of such Code) reported to the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary of the Treasury</cato:entity-ref> on tax returns under <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/st:F">subtitle F</cato:entity-ref> of such Code, as determined by the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary of the Treasury</cato:entity-ref> by applying the applicable rate of tax under such section to such self-employment income; and</cato:entity>
            </text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph commented="no" id="HB7D213A387C244A3AA811FDB16949973">
            <enum>(D)</enum>
            <text>
              <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="auth-auth-approp">
                <cato:funds-and-year amount="indefinite">100 percent of the taxes imposed by <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:3201/ss:c">sections 3201(c)</cato:entity-ref>, <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:3211/ss:c">3211(c)</cato:entity-ref>, and <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:3221/ss:c">3221(c)</cato:entity-ref> of such Code</cato:funds-and-year> with respect to compensation (as defined in <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:3231">section 3231</cato:entity-ref> of such Code) reported to the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary of the Treasury</cato:entity-ref> on tax returns under <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/st:F">subtitle F</cato:entity-ref> of such Code, as determined by the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary of the Treasury</cato:entity-ref> by applying the applicable rate of tax under such sections to such compensation.</cato:entity>
            </text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph commented="no" id="H165AF5500A484D3EA498DFF34DEE8028">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Repayment of initial appropriation</header>
          <text>Amounts appropriated pursuant to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Family and Medical Insurance Leave Act of 2013/s:6/ss:b/p:1/sp:A" proposed="true">subparagraph (A) of paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref> shall be repaid to the Treasury of the United States not later than 10 years after the first appropriation is made pursuant to such subparagraph.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph commented="no" id="HA739E0A7A09B4EA7ADF7DCDCAD7B915A">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <header>Transfer to Trust Fund</header>
          <text>The amounts described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Family and Medical Insurance Leave Act of 2013/s:6/ss:b/p:2" proposed="true">paragraph (2)</cato:entity-ref> shall be transferred from time to time from the general fund in the Treasury to the Federal Family and Medical Leave Insurance Trust Fund, such amounts to be determined on the basis of estimates by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2000">Secretary of the Treasury</cato:entity-ref> of the taxes, specified in such paragraph, paid to or deposited into the Treasury. Proper adjustments shall be made in amounts subsequently transferred to the extent prior estimates were inconsistent with the taxes specified in such paragraph.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="H8AE945403C464919940BD6EA0189403F">
        <enum>(c)</enum>
        <header>Management of Trust Fund</header>
        <text>The provisions of <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Social Security Act/s:201/ss:c">subsections (c)</cato:entity-ref>, <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Social Security Act/s:201/ss:d">(d)</cato:entity-ref>, <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Social Security Act/s:201/ss:e">(e)</cato:entity-ref>, <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Social Security Act/s:201/ss:f">(f)</cato:entity-ref>, <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Social Security Act/s:201/ss:i">(i)</cato:entity-ref>, and <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Social Security Act/s:201/ss:m">(m) of section 201 of the Social Security Act</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/401">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/42/401">42 U.S.C. 401</cato:entity-ref>
          </external-xref>)</cato:entity> shall apply with respect to the Federal Family and Medical Leave Insurance Trust Fund in the same manner as such provisions apply to the Federal Old-Age and Survivors Insurance Trust Fund and the Disability Insurance Trust Fund.</text>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="H228E2378FEEB4B33866C15DEE7291C58">
        <enum>(d)</enum>
        <header>Benefits paid from Trust Fund</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Benefit payments required to be made under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Family and Medical Insurance Leave Act of 2013/s:5" proposed="true">section 5</cato:entity-ref> shall be made only from the Federal Family and Medical Leave Insurance Trust Fund.</text>
      </subsection>
      <subsection commented="no" id="H44C25940833D4A848BD4511693EC9579">
        <enum>(e)</enum>
        <header>Administration</header>
        <text>There are authorized to be made available for expenditure, out of the Federal Family and Medical Leave Insurance Trust Fund, such sums as may be necessary to pay the costs of the administration of <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Family and Medical Insurance Leave Act of 2013/s:5" proposed="true">section 5</cato:entity-ref>, including start-up costs, technical assistance, outreach, education, evaluation, and reporting.</text>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="H96DE6062C4EE4F39B52896813A283093">
        <enum>(f)</enum>
        <header>Prohibition</header>
        <text>No funds from the Social Security Trust Fund or appropriated to the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2800">Social Security Administration</cato:entity-ref> to administer Social Security programs may be used for Federal Family and Medical Leave Insurance benefits or administration set forth under this Act.</text>
      </subsection>
    </section>
    <section id="H6AC66A3E1B0A44AC82743F9293255112">
      <enum>7.</enum>
      <header>Internal Revenue Code provisions</header>
      <subsection id="HD3EF95738F1E4153BAAB4466BD0D79E0">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>In general</header>
        <paragraph id="HE1BA4ADA47B04E198C3DAFDB68C0835E">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>Employee contribution</header>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">
            <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:3101">
              <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/3101">Section 3101</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986</cato:entity-ref> is amended—</text>
          <subparagraph id="H9BE9775DD4DB4677AF85514A57A2880F">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>by redesignating <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:3101/ss:c">subsection (c)</cato:entity-ref> as <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:3101/ss:d" proposed="true">subsection (d)</cato:entity-ref>, and</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="HFD395CE1ED224EE48EA0A0A673E7EBE3">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>by inserting after <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:3101/ss:b">subsection (b)</cato:entity-ref> the following:</text>
            <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6A23882B4F45423CBA7F13922F4FE8EF" style="OLC">
              <subsection id="H0AF9128A6C2748E1B63129FBA7C70E7B">
                <enum>(c)</enum>
                <header>Family and medical leave insurance</header>
                <paragraph id="HF19402191F7B4FED86B8095582962E4A">
                  <enum>(1)</enum>
                  <header>In general</header>
                  <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In addition to other taxes, there is hereby imposed on the income of every individual a tax equal to the applicable percentage of the wages (as defined in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:3121/ss:a">section 3121(a)</cato:entity-ref>) received by the individual with respect to employment (as defined in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:3121/ss:b">section 3121(b)</cato:entity-ref>).</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph commented="no" id="H58C24B2997024D25960D0121E8305CA6">
                  <enum>(2)</enum>
                  <header>Applicable percentage</header>
                  <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:3101/ss:c/p:1" proposed="true">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref>, the term <term>applicable percentage</term> means 0.2 percent in the case of wages received in any calendar year.</text>
                </paragraph>
              </subsection>
              <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
            </quoted-block>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H7F8AAA82BC434C3C8BA0DEF45953CAD6">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Employer contribution</header>
          <text>
            <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:3111">Section 3111</cato:entity-ref> of such Code is amended—</text>
          <subparagraph id="H3871FA79072E40D2B8254500141DA9D8">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>by redesignating <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:3111/ss:c">subsections (c)</cato:entity-ref> and <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:3111/ss:d">(d)</cato:entity-ref> as <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:3111/ss:d" proposed="true">subsections (d)</cato:entity-ref> and <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:3111/ss:e" proposed="true">(e)</cato:entity-ref>, respectively, and</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="HD8682A3E5E86431FA44B7CD8F9B8B942">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>by inserting after <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:3111/ss:b">subsection (b)</cato:entity-ref> the following:</text>
            <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE311AFA3C6654634938F2AD5286BE7BC" style="OLC">
              <subsection id="H90AC7C00E45B4B569752C48F22C25B7C">
                <enum>(c)</enum>
                <header>Family and medical leave insurance</header>
                <paragraph id="HB019F949CB424AEE91BD6407E8474BEB">
                  <enum>(1)</enum>
                  <header>In general</header>
                  <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In addition to other taxes, there is hereby imposed on every employer an excise tax, with respect to having individuals in his employ, equal to the applicable percentage of the wages (as defined in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:3121/ss:a">section 3121(a)</cato:entity-ref>) paid by the employer with respect to employment (as defined in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:3121/ss:b">section 3121(b)</cato:entity-ref>).</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="H680C96DF8E7047AC8310D4A223B05033">
                  <enum>(2)</enum>
                  <header>Applicable percentage</header>
                  <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:3111/ss:c/p:1" proposed="true">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref>, the term <term>applicable percentage</term> means 0.2 percent in the case of wages paid in any calendar year.</text>
                </paragraph>
              </subsection>
              <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
            </quoted-block>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HA617DA64CB404C3C834440DEBFE552BA">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <header>Self-employment income contribution</header>
          <subparagraph id="HE05F9B6D68C2402ABF61D26F08E9A425">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <header>In general</header>
            <text>
              <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:1401">Section 1401</cato:entity-ref> of such Code is amended—</text>
            <clause id="HFEDEB05885B44E41872620294E3ADA49">
              <enum>(i)</enum>
              <text>by redesignating <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:1401/ss:c">subsection (c)</cato:entity-ref> as <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:1401/ss:d" proposed="true">subsection (d)</cato:entity-ref>, and</text>
            </clause>
            <clause id="H453717575F0D486B857B8CBBF09188AC">
              <enum>(ii)</enum>
              <text>by inserting after <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:1401/ss:b">subsection (b)</cato:entity-ref> the following:</text>
              <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8F8379DD800047988D6C4FC08E643E4F" style="OLC">
                <subsection id="H848CA5EDE74943BE813010C53571947E">
                  <enum>(c)</enum>
                  <header>Family and medical leave insurance</header>
                  <paragraph id="HF5D1C72437B24C0492140B2AA39B4E90">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
                    <header>In general</header>
                    <text>In addition to other taxes, there is hereby imposed for each taxable year, on the self-employment income of every individual, a tax equal to the applicable percentage of the amount of the self-employment income for such taxable year.</text>
                  </paragraph>
                  <paragraph id="H65C635C2D45C48EA9C5F88FB4FA9D912">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
                    <header>Applicable percentage</header>
                    <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:1401/ss:c/p:1" proposed="true">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref>, the term <term>applicable percentage</term> means 0.4 percent in the case of self-employment income in any taxable year.</text>
                  </paragraph>
                </subsection>
                <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
              </quoted-block>
            </clause>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="HFD26E89C47044B3AB691427226F2726E">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <header>Exclusion of certain net earnings from self-employment</header>
            <text>
              <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:1402/ss:b/p:1">Section 1402(b)(1)</cato:entity-ref> of such Code is amended by striking <quote>tax imposed by section 1401(a)
              </quote> and inserting <quote>taxes imposed by <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:1401/ss:a">subsections (a)</cato:entity-ref> and <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:1401/ss:c" proposed="true">(c) of section 1401</cato:entity-ref>
              </quote>.</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="HA1B6F3DD4FDB411FBA6918A932F3DCA0">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Railroad Retirement Tax Act</header>
        <paragraph id="H4B96223DAFF24A06AB3F273E825C7583">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>Employee contribution</header>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">
            <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:3201">Section 3201</cato:entity-ref> of such Code is amended—</text>
          <subparagraph id="H1B946DBFB32E4924B3358D325C292F13">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>by redesignating <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:3201/ss:c">subsection (c)</cato:entity-ref> as <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:3201/ss:d" proposed="true">subsection (d)</cato:entity-ref>, and</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H49E7B04BC3604ED2A60FA7E954FC3FB8">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>by inserting after <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:3201/ss:b">subsection (b)</cato:entity-ref> the following:</text>
            <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H45DA4BEF3FFD40C2A482385934DBB9F5" style="OLC">
              <subsection id="HB8CB827D3386486EBEBA9D7CF1703C1A">
                <enum>(c)</enum>
                <header>Family and Medical Leave insurance</header>
                <paragraph id="H34917E43DEF8415B976FF52628153A58">
                  <enum>(1)</enum>
                  <header>In general</header>
                  <text>In addition to other taxes, there is hereby imposed on the income of each employee a tax equal to the applicable percentage of the compensation received during any calendar year by such employee for services rendered by such employee.</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="H5C5F218011A3403AB9B4486947A57CD1">
                  <enum>(2)</enum>
                  <header>Applicable percentage</header>
                  <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:3201/ss:c/p:1" proposed="true">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref>, the term <term>applicable percentage</term> means 0.2 percent in the case of compensation received in any calendar year.</text>
                </paragraph>
              </subsection>
              <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
            </quoted-block>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H7304DC93F6CA471E8DA355C006D436DE">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Employee representative contribution</header>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">
            <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:3211">Section 3211</cato:entity-ref> of such Code is amended—</text>
          <subparagraph id="HE3148AF0AF794E7EAAD9930591E0E44D">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>by redesignating <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:3211/ss:c">subsection (c)</cato:entity-ref> as <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:3211/ss:d" proposed="true">subsection (d)</cato:entity-ref>, and</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="HB9B9EC586CE74F41BF503B301B7A14E9">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>by inserting after <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:3211/ss:b">subsection (b)</cato:entity-ref> the following:</text>
            <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0964C9494D514E5F9144AC4CC0D82A51" style="OLC">
              <subsection id="HE5ADDCF643B842C0B21BC1856FAA6938">
                <enum>(c)</enum>
                <header>Family and Medical Leave insurance</header>
                <paragraph id="HF338810B04C64AD2AEE620F1D1358A2C">
                  <enum>(1)</enum>
                  <header>In general</header>
                  <text>In addition to other taxes, there is hereby imposed on the income of each employee representative a tax equal to the applicable percentage of the compensation received during any calendar year by such employee representative for services rendered by such employee representative.</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="H3498480F5AD34D46A7BD9C577B3F36A7">
                  <enum>(2)</enum>
                  <header>Applicable percentage</header>
                  <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:3211/ss:c/p:1" proposed="true">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref>, the term <term>applicable percentage</term> means 0.2 percent in the case of compensation received in any calendar year.</text>
                </paragraph>
              </subsection>
              <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
            </quoted-block>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H7CD94AA89C454360874F449BD050BB49">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <header>Employer contribution</header>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">
            <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:3221">Section 3221</cato:entity-ref> of such Code is amended—</text>
          <subparagraph id="HA9F23DC1350743669587FF73E75669A3">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by redesignating <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:3221/ss:c">subsections (c)</cato:entity-ref> and <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:3221/ss:d">(d)</cato:entity-ref> as <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:3221/ss:d" proposed="true">subsections (d)</cato:entity-ref> and <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:3221/ss:e" proposed="true">(e)</cato:entity-ref>, respectively, and</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="HE42B205581724892B27B495DF8478775">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>by inserting after <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:3221/ss:b">subsection (b)</cato:entity-ref> the following:</text>
            <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2086903E448F4CAE900F4446D20EC964" style="OLC">
              <subsection id="H28188789AC224729ABD1EBC33B6281B8">
                <enum>(c)</enum>
                <header>Family and Medical Leave insurance</header>
                <paragraph id="H948451138B9646BBA3FF432B1F1FF82C">
                  <enum>(1)</enum>
                  <header>In general</header>
                  <text>In addition to other taxes, there is hereby imposed on every employer an excise tax, with respect to having individuals in his employ, equal to the applicable percentage of the compensation paid during any calendar year by such employer for services rendered to such employer.</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="H9DA3E8062A434EC18A6D7E7B2DA3D726">
                  <enum>(2)</enum>
                  <header>Applicable percentage</header>
                  <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:3221/ss:c/p:1" proposed="true">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref>, the term <term>applicable percentage</term> means 0.2 percent in the case of compensation paid in any calendar year.</text>
                </paragraph>
              </subsection>
              <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
            </quoted-block>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="H931808EB70804CA1A9094410D3918693">
        <enum>(c)</enum>
        <header>Effective date</header>
        <text>The amendments made by <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Family and Medical Insurance Leave Act of 2013/s:7/ss:a" proposed="true">subsections (a)</cato:entity-ref> and <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Family and Medical Insurance Leave Act of 2013/s:7/ss:b" proposed="true">(b)</cato:entity-ref> shall take effect 120 days after the date of enactment of this Act.</text>
      </subsection>
    </section>
    <section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFB4F0A99BF984845AD4C008071265053" section-type="subsequent-section">
      <enum>8.</enum>
      <header>Regulations</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2800">Commissioner</cato:entity-ref>, in consultation with the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1600">Secretary of Labor</cato:entity-ref>, shall prescribe regulations necessary to carry out this Act. In developing such regulations, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2800">Commissioner</cato:entity-ref> shall consider the input from a volunteer advisory body comprised of not more than 15 individuals, including experts in the relevant subject matter and officials charged with implementing State paid family and medical leave insurance programs. The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="2800">Commissioner</cato:entity-ref> shall take such programs into account when proposing regulations. Such individuals shall be appointed as follows:</text>
      <paragraph id="HE4235FA13A404F2FAAF6B18B71F6E1BD">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text>Five individuals to be appointed by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H1599F4E6043C4FDFB2B4385B47F39C4B">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Three individuals to be appointed by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Majority Leader of the Senate" entity-parent-id="0010">majority leader of the Senate</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HD402935A63AD4D749B8CE7770D95299A">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Two individuals to be appointed by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Minority Leader of the Senate" entity-parent-id="0010">minority leader of the Senate</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H38ADB8CF9F3644E2BF0DC713BDCDA402">
        <enum>(4)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Three individuals to be appointed by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Speaker of the House of Representatives" entity-parent-id="0050">Speaker of the House of Representatives</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H7A59450FFC92454499719FBD9C2AB9BB">
        <enum>(5)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Two individuals to be appointed by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Minority Leader of the House of Representatives" entity-parent-id="0050">minority leader of the House of Representatives</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
      </paragraph>
    </section>
    <section id="H14BB5F5FBC804F988FDAADCECCC93BE4">
      <enum>9.</enum>
      <header>GAO Study</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 3 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0500">Comptroller General</cato:entity-ref> shall submit to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> a report on family and medical leave insurance benefits paid under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Family and Medical Insurance Leave Act of 2013/s:5" proposed="true">section 5</cato:entity-ref> for any month during the 1-year period beginning on January 1, 2015. The report shall include the following:</text>
      <paragraph id="H14D0DD341A5648D8BDA240555DF4CE19">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An identification of the total number of applications for such benefits filed for any month during such 1-year period, and the average number of days occurring in the period beginning on the date on which such an application is received and ending on the date on which the initial determination of eligibility with respect to the application is made.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H171146DD281641D5A67362FFDD2EF33B">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An identification of the total number of requests for review of an initial adverse determination of eligibility for such benefits made during such 1-year period, and the average number of days occurring in the period beginning on the date on which such review is requested and ending on the date on which the final determination of eligibility with respect to such review is made.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H1B7743628E894846BF5EDE6B2B15A2CD">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An identification of the total number of monthly benefit claim reports for such benefits filed during such 1-year period, and the average number of days occurring in the period beginning on the date on which such a claim report is received and ending on the date on which the initial determination of eligibility with respect to the claim report is made.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H23E0D2599DA942209D873F0E837FD67D">
        <enum>(4)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An identification of the total number of requests for review of an initial adverse determination relating to a monthly benefit claim report for such benefits made during such 1-year period, and the average number of days occurring in the period beginning on the date on which such review is requested and ending on the date on which the final determination of eligibility with respect to such review is made.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H79F76D614E3A402AAA9EA2E3CBC53279">
        <enum>(5)</enum>
        <text>An identification of any excessive delay in any of the periods described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Family and Medical Insurance Leave Act of 2013/s:9/p:1..4" proposed="true">paragraphs (1) through (4)</cato:entity-ref>, and a description of the causes for such delay.</text>
      </paragraph>
    </section>
    <section commented="no" id="H4427BE3537704EA3BFA9375971F7A120">
      <enum>10.</enum>
      <header>Conforming amendments</header>
      <subsection commented="no" id="HF9115C29FCA74D54B9B6669941426426">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Internal Revenue Code amendments</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">
          <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:6413/ss:c">
            <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/6413">Section 6413(c)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986</cato:entity-ref> is amended—</text>
        <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD7C928E1719243E6808C6A9CFB235001">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:6413/ss:c/p:1">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref>—</text>
          <subparagraph commented="no" id="H3AC44775CBDB4910BDD1FDFF815EB04F">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>by inserting <quote>, <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:3101/ss:c" proposed="true">section 3101(c)</cato:entity-ref>,</quote> after <quote>by <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:3101/ss:a">section 3101(a)</cato:entity-ref>
              </quote>; and</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph commented="no" id="H89772B22F03E4600929AC84415023E96">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>by striking <quote>both</quote> and inserting <quote>each</quote>; and</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph commented="no" id="HE2201A442F0149E5AB4F4D89FB5DA142">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:6413/ss:c/p:2">paragraph (2)</cato:entity-ref>—</text>
          <subparagraph commented="no" id="H66FC39F78916444A940934D2D7C1B39F">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:6413/ss:c/p:2/sp:B">subparagraph (B)</cato:entity-ref>—</text>
            <clause commented="no" id="H1A3F308B8B57454E90BCAD9C9EE85BFD">
              <enum>(i)</enum>
              <text>by inserting <quote>or <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:3101/ss:c" proposed="true">3101(c)</cato:entity-ref>
                </quote> after <quote>
                  <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:3101/ss:a">3101(a)</cato:entity-ref>
                </quote> each place it appears; and</text>
            </clause>
            <clause commented="no" id="H988886F4487E4C2FB4463EEBF9D7B66D">
              <enum>(ii)</enum>
              <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by inserting <quote>or <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:235">235</cato:entity-ref>
                </quote> after <quote>
                  <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:218">218</cato:entity-ref>
                </quote> each place it appears; and</text>
            </clause>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph commented="no" id="HA0D8B6D605544ADA8697775B73769FC8">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:6413/ss:c/p:2/sp:C">subparagraph (C)</cato:entity-ref>, by inserting <quote>or <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:3101/ss:c" proposed="true">3101(c)</cato:entity-ref>
              </quote> after <quote>
                <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:3101/ss:a">3101(a)</cato:entity-ref>
              </quote> each place it appears.</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection commented="no" id="H51D2AAFC8EF5439098DCE3204B692A99">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Railroad Retirement Act of 1974 amendment</header>
        <text>
          <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Railroad Retirement Act of 1974/s:15/ss:a">Section 15(a) of the Railroad Retirement Act of 1974</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/45/231n">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/45/231n/a">45 U.S.C. 231n(a)</cato:entity-ref>
          </external-xref>)</cato:entity> is amended by inserting <quote>(other than <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:3201/ss:c" proposed="true">sections 3201(c)</cato:entity-ref>, <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:3211/ss:c" proposed="true">3211(c)</cato:entity-ref>, and <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Internal Revenue Code of 1986/s:3221/ss:c" proposed="true">3221(c)</cato:entity-ref>)</quote> before the period at the end.</text>
      </subsection>
    </section>
  </legis-body>
</bill>
</doc>