<doc>
  <docmeta id="113sres167rs">
    <bill congress="113" type="sres" number="167" version="rs"/>
    <revision size="11073" annotations="0" status="complete" id="5" commit-time="2014-01-15T23:28:08Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113sres167rs/5.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <resolution xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Reported-in-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print">
	<metadata>
<dublinCore>
<dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">113 SRES 167 RS: Reaffirming the strong support of the United States for the peaceful resolution of territorial, sovereignty, and jurisdictional disputes in the Asia-Pacific maritime domains.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">2013-06-10</dc:date>
<dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code>
		<calendar>Calendar No. 97</calendar>
		<congress>113th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. RES. 167</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20130610">June 10, 2013</action-date>
			<action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="S306">Mr. Menendez</sponsor> (for
			 himself, <cosponsor name-id="S350">Mr. Rubio</cosponsor>,
			 <cosponsor name-id="S308">Mr. Cardin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S310">Mr.
			 Corker</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S356">Mr. Donnelly</cosponsor>, and
			 <cosponsor name-id="S364">Mr. Murphy</cosponsor>) submitted the following
			 resolution; which was referred to the
			 <committee-name added-display-style="italic" committee-id="SSFR00" deleted-display-style="strikethrough">Committee on Foreign
			 Relations</committee-name>
      </action-desc>
		</action>
		<action stage="Reported-in-Senate">
			<action-date>June 25, 2013</action-date>
			<action-desc>Reported by <sponsor name-id="S306">Mr.
			 Menendez</sponsor>, without amendment</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">Reaffirming the strong support of the
		  United States for the peaceful resolution of territorial, sovereignty, and
		  jurisdictional disputes in the Asia-Pacific maritime domains.</official-title>
	</form>
	<preamble>
		<whereas>
      <text>Whereas the maritime domain of the Asia-Pacific region
			 includes critical sea lines of communication and commerce between the Pacific
			 and Indian oceans;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the United States has a national interest in
			 freedom of navigation and overflight in the Asia-Pacific maritime domains, as
			 provided for by universally recognized principles of international law;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the United States has a national interest in the
			 maintenance of peace and stability, open access by all to maritime domains,
			 respect for universally recognized principles of international law, prosperity
			 and economic growth, and unimpeded lawful commerce;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the United States has a clear interest in
			 encouraging and supporting the nations of the region to work collaboratively
			 and diplomatically to resolve disputes without coercion, without intimidation,
			 without threats, and without the use of force;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the South China Sea contains great natural
			 resources, and their stewardship and responsible use offers immense potential
			 benefit for generations to come;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas, in recent years, there have been numerous
			 dangerous and destabilizing incidents in this region, including Chinese vessels
			 cutting the seismic survey cables of a Vietnamese oil exploration ship in May
			 2011; Chinese vessels barricading the entrance to the Scarborough Reef lagoon
			 in April 2012; China issuing an official map that newly defines the contested
			 <term>nine-dash line</term> as China's national border; and, since May 8, 2013,
			 Chinese naval and marine surveillance ships maintaining a regular presence in
			 waters around the Second Thomas Shoal, located approximately 105 nautical miles
			 northwest of the Philippine island of Palawan;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the Association of Southeast Asian Nations (ASEAN)
			 has promoted multilateral talks on disputed areas without settling the issue of
			 sovereignty, and in 2002 joined with China in signing a Declaration on the
			 Conduct of Parties in the South China Sea that committed all parties to those
			 territorial disputes to <quote>reaffirm their respect for and commitment to the
			 freedom of navigation in and over flight above the South China Sea as provided
			 for by the universally recognized principles of international law</quote> and
			 to <quote>resolve their territorial and jurisdictional disputes by peaceful
			 means, without resorting to the threat or use of force</quote>;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas Japan and Taiwan reached an agreement on April 10,
			 2013, to jointly share and administer the fishing resources in their
			 overlapping claimed exclusive economic zones in the East China Sea, an
			 important breakthrough after 17 years of negotiations and a model for other
			 such agreements;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas other incidences of the joint administrations of
			 resources in disputed waters in the South China Sea have de-escalated tensions
			 and promoted economic development, such as Malaysia and Brunei’s 2009 agreement
			 to partner on exploring offshore Brunei waters, with drilling in offshore oil
			 and gas fields off Brunei beginning in 2011; and Thailand and Vietnam's
			 agreement to jointly develop areas of the Gulf of Thailand for gas exports,
			 despite ongoing territorial disputes;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the Government of the Republic of the Philippines
			 states that it <quote>has exhausted almost all political and diplomatic avenues
			 for a peaceful negotiated settlement of its maritime dispute with China</quote>
			 and in his statement of January 23, 2013, Republic of Philippines Secretary of
			 Foreign Affairs Del Rosario stated that therefore <quote>the Philippines has
			 taken the step of bringing China before the Arbitral Tribunal under Article 287
			 and Annex VII of the 1982 Convention on the Law of the Sea in order to achieve
			 a peaceful and durable solution to the dispute</quote>;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas, in January 2013, a Chinese naval ship allegedly
			 fixed its weapons-targeting radar on Japanese vessels in the vicinity of the
			 Senkaku islands, and, on April 23, 2013, eight Chinese marine surveillance
			 ships entered the 12-nautical-mile territorial zone off the Senkaku Islands,
			 further escalating regional tensions;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas, on May 8, 2013, the Chinese Communist Party’s
			 main newspaper, The People’s Daily, published an article by several Chinese
			 scholars questioning Japan’s sovereignty over Okinawa, where key United States
			 military installations are located which contribute to preserving security and
			 stability in the Asia-Pacific region;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the Government of the People’s Republic of China
			 has recently taken other unilateral steps, including declaring the Senkaku
			 Islands a <term>core interest</term>, <term>improperly drawing</term> baselines
			 around the Senkaku Islands in September 2102, which the 2013 Annual Report to
			 Congress on Military and Security Developments Involving the People’s Republic
			 of China found to be “inconsistent with international law”, and maintaining a
			 continuous military and paramilitary presence around the Senkaku
			 Islands;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas, although the United States does not take a
			 position on the ultimate sovereignty of the Senkaku Islands, the United States
			 Government acknowledges that they are under the administration of Japan and
			 opposes any unilateral actions that would seek to undermine such
			 administration, affirms that the unilateral actions of a third party will not
			 affect the United States acknowledgment of the administration of Japan over the
			 Senkaku Islands, remains committed under the Treaty of Mutual Cooperation and
			 Security to respond to any armed attack in the territories under the
			 administration of Japan, and has urged all parties to take steps to prevent
			 incidents and manage disagreements through peaceful means;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas, on August 3, 2012, a <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Department of State</cato:entity-ref>
			 spokesperson expressed concern over <quote>China’s upgrading of the
			 administrative level of Sansha City and the establishment of a new military
			 garrison there,</quote> encouraged ASEAN and China <quote>to make meaningful
			 progress toward finalizing a comprehensive Code of Conduct,</quote> and called
			 upon claimants to <quote>explore every diplomatic or other peaceful avenue for
			 resolution, including the use of arbitration or other international legal
			 mechanisms as needed</quote>;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the United States recognizes the importance of
			 strong, cohesive, and integrated regional institutions, including the East Asia
			 Summit (EAS), ASEAN, and the Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation (APEC) forum, as
			 foundation for effective regional frameworks to promote peace and security and
			 economic growth, including in the maritime domain, and to ensure that the
			 Asia-Pacific community develops rules-based regional norms which discourage
			 coercion and the use of force;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the United States welcomes the development of a
			 peaceful and prosperous China, the government of which respects international
			 norms, international laws, international institutions, and international rules;
			 enhances security and peace; and seeks to advance a <term>new model</term> of
			 relations between the United States and China; and</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas ASEAN plays an important role, in partnership with
			 others in the regional and international community, in addressing maritime
			 security issues in the Asia-Pacific region and into the Indian Ocean, including
			 open access to the maritime domain of Asia: Now, therefore, be it</text>
		</whereas>
  </preamble>
	<resolution-body>
		<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="S1" section-type="undesignated-section">
      <enum/>
      <text>That the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0010">Senate</cato:entity-ref>—</text>
			<paragraph id="id04f4a72efb284a219da7061c1a9b4b73">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text>condemns the use
			 of coercion, threats, or force by naval, maritime security, or fishing vessels
			 and military or civilian aircraft in the South China Sea and the East China Sea
			 to assert disputed maritime or territorial claims or alter the status
			 quo;</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id61312d124c1e424597842538bfdaf3ca">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text>strongly urges
			 that all parties to maritime and territorial disputes in the region exercise
			 self-restraint in the conduct of activities that would undermine stability or
			 complicate or escalate disputes, including refraining from inhabiting presently
			 un­in­hab­it­ed islands, reefs, shoals, and other features and handle their
			 differences in a constructive manner;</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id33e1120fcdfa4cfc872a5a6769c66097">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <text>reaffirms the
			 strong support of the United States for the member states of ASEAN and the
			 Government of the People’s Republic of China as they seek to develop a code of
			 conduct of parties in the South China Sea, and urges all countries to
			 substantively support ASEAN in its efforts in this regard;</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id369429ae768e4809ae70b59c4adb7ba8">
        <enum>(4)</enum>
        <text>supports
			 collaborative diplomatic processes by all claimants in the South China Sea for
			 resolving outstanding maritime or territorial disputes, in a manner that
			 maintains peace and security, adheres to international law, and protects
			 unimpeded lawful commerce as well as freedom of navigation and overflight, and
			 including through international arbitration, allowing parties to peacefully
			 settle claims and disputes using universally recognized principles of
			 international law;</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="idc88f8efd100f4418a213f9e577ba67f1">
        <enum>(5)</enum>
        <text>encourages the
			 deepening of efforts by the United States Government to develop partnerships
			 with other countries in the region for maritime domain awareness and capacity
			 building; and</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id3a23fc8e8ce8427aaefcb42e42497218">
        <enum>(6)</enum>
        <text>supports the
			 continuation of operations by the United States Armed Forces in the Western
			 Pacific, including in partnership with the armed forces of other countries in
			 the region, in support of freedom of navigation, the maintenance of peace and
			 stability, and respect for universally recognized principles of international
			 law, including the peaceful resolution of issues of sovereignty and unimpeded
			 lawful commerce.</text>
			</paragraph>
    </section>
  </resolution-body>
	<endorsement>
		<action-date>June 25, 2013</action-date>
		<action-desc>Reported without amendment</action-desc>
	</endorsement>
</resolution>
</doc>