<doc>
  <docmeta id="113sres328is">
    <bill congress="113" type="sres" number="328" version="is"/>
    <revision size="3049" annotations="0" status="complete" id="3" commit-time="2014-01-15T23:43:43Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113sres328is/3.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <resolution xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution">
  <metadata>
<dublinCore>
<dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">113 SRES 328 IS: Expressing the sense of the Senate on steps the Government of Iran must take before further bilateral negotiations between the Government of Iran and the United States Government occur. </dc:title>
<dc:publisher xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">2014-01-06</dc:date>
<dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code>
    <congress>113th CONGRESS</congress>
    <session>2d Session</session>
    <legis-num>S. RES. 328</legis-num>
    <current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
    <action>
      <action-date date="20140106">January 6, 2014</action-date>
      <action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="S355">Mr. Cruz</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S236">Mr. Inhofe</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations</committee-name>
      </action-desc>
    </action>
    <legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
    <official-title display="yes">Expressing the sense of the Senate on steps the Government of Iran must take before further bilateral negotiations between the Government of Iran and the United States Government occur. </official-title>
  </form>
  <preamble>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas, on September 27, 2013, the President of Iran, Hassan Rouhani, and <cato:entity-ref entity-type="person" entity-id="O000167">President Barack Obama</cato:entity-ref> engaged in the first direct contact between Iranian and United States leaders since 1979;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the Government of Iran has yet to take any practical steps towards halting Iran’s nuclear programs and remains a committed state-sponsor of terrorist groups that have been responsible for American deaths in Lebanon, Saudi Arabia, Iraq, and Afghanistan;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas, since the election of President Rouhani, the persecution by the Government of Iran of religious minorities, notably Christians, has increased not decreased;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas United States citizens remain imprisoned in Iran, including Pastor Saeed Abedini, Amir Hekmati, and Robert Levinson;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas President Rouhani has called Israel the <quote>Zionist state</quote> that has been <quote>a wound that has sat on the body of the Muslim world for years and needs to be removed</quote>, and Iran’s Supreme Leader Ayatollah Khamenei has called Israel a <quote>rabid dog</quote> facing <quote>annihilation</quote>;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas a Joint Plan of Action was released from Geneva on November 24, 2013, outlining first step, voluntary measures to be taken over a six month duration providing the Government of Iran with some $7,000,000,000 in relief from economic sanctions, while extracting no substantive concessions from Iran on their nuclear program; and</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the representatives of the United States engaging in these negotiations failed to raise the issue of the United States citizens imprisoned in Iran and to rebuke their Iranian counterparts for their vicious rhetoric against Israel at the highest levels: Now, therefore, be it</text>
    </whereas>
  </preamble>
  <resolution-body>
    <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="S1" section-type="undesignated-section">
      <enum/>
      <text>That it is the sense of the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0010">Senate</cato:entity-ref> that, before further bilateral negotiations between the Government of Iran and the United States Government occur, the  Government of Iran must—</text>
      <paragraph id="id3ad6d43fe67a45e8a9818fdfcdf0805b">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text>immediately and without conditions release all United States citizens unjustly detained in Iran; and</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id82db5a2d54114665b1b101c99cffed14">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text>publicly affirm the right of Israel to exist as a Jewish state.</text>
      </paragraph>
    </section>
  </resolution-body>
</resolution>
</doc>