<doc>
  <docmeta id="113sres506is">
    <bill congress="113" type="sres" number="506" version="is"/>
    <revision size="3537" annotations="0" status="complete" id="4" commit-time="2014-08-26T18:27:38Z" committer="mnewby" doc="113sres506is/4.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <resolution xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print">
	<metadata>
<dublinCore>
<dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">113 SRES 506 IS: Recognizing the patriotism and contributions of auxiliaries of veterans service organizations.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">2014-07-17</dc:date>
<dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">113th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session display="yes">2d Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. RES. 506</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20140717">July 17, 2014</action-date>
			<action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="S223">Mrs. Boxer</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="S300">Mr. Burr</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSVA00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name>
      </action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">Recognizing the patriotism and contributions of auxiliaries of veterans service
			 organizations.</official-title>
	</form>
	<preamble>
		<whereas>
      <text>Whereas, for nearly a century, auxiliaries have served as a complementary and integral part of
			 veterans service organizations, supporting members of the Armed Forces,
			 veterans, and their families;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas, since their inception, auxiliary units have proudly supported members of the Armed
			 Forces, veterans, and the families of those who have served, volunteering
			 hundreds of thousands of hours and raising billions of dollars;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas auxiliaries have representatives in all 50 States and abroad;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas  auxiliaries have more than 1,000,000 members and are composed of wives, widows, mothers,
			 grandmothers, daughters, and granddaughters of veterans, as well as
			 veterans themselves;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas auxiliary units have raised money to aid and enhance the lives of members of the
			 Armed Forces, veterans, and their families through financial
			 support—providing assistance with essentials such as rent, child care,
			 utilities, and food;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas auxiliary units host <quote>stand-downs</quote> that focus on providing vital health and support services to homeless veterans;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas auxiliary units strengthen their local communities by conducting food drives, visiting
			 hospitals, and providing scholarships to youth;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas auxiliary units serve as advocates for veterans and their families;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas auxiliary units conduct welcome home and send-off events for members of the
			 Armed Forces;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas members of auxiliaries selflessly volunteer their services at facilities
			  of the <cato:entity-ref entity-id="3600" entity-type="federal-body">Department of Veterans Affairs</cato:entity-ref> throughout the country to enhance
			 the lives of veterans and their families; and</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas, each year, auxiliary units raise millions of dollars for cancer research: Now, therefore,
			 be it</text>
		</whereas>
  </preamble>
	<resolution-body>
		<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="S1" section-type="undesignated-section">
      <enum/>
      <text>That the <cato:entity-ref entity-id="0010" entity-type="federal-body">Senate</cato:entity-ref>—</text>
			<paragraph id="id4C40DCA5D26E4FD589B254D4AA0FCCD1">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text>honors and recognizes the patriotism and countless contributions to the United States by
			 generations of women in the auxiliaries of veterans service
			 organizations;</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id48b301947d9b4f7db34ec09e6b02f3e9">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text>commends members of auxiliaries in the United States and abroad for their dedicated service to and
			 support of members of the Armed Forces and veterans as well as their
			 families and communities;</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="idca4d94d491b14c1f8fb90eec8a13b137">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <text>encourages the people of the United States to promote awareness of the contributions and dedication
			 of members of auxiliaries to members of the Armed
			 Forces, veterans, and their families; and</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id0834abee9857417aaab52c4e53ee0da4">
        <enum>(4)</enum>
        <text>calls on the people of the United States to follow the noble example of the auxiliaries of veterans
			 service organizations and volunteer support and services
			 to those who have selflessly served the United States.</text>
			</paragraph>
    </section>
  </resolution-body>
</resolution>
</doc>