<doc>
  <docmeta id="113sres475ats">
    <bill congress="113" type="sres" number="475" version="ats"/>
    <revision size="3174" annotations="0" status="complete" id="4" commit-time="2014-08-18T21:25:22Z" committer="mnewby" doc="113sres475ats/4.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <resolution xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print">
	<metadata>
<dublinCore>
<dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">113 SRES 475 ATS: Congratulating the Alaska Aces hockey team on winning the 2014 Kelly Cup as champions of the East Coast Hockey League.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">2014-06-12</dc:date>
<dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">113th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session display="yes">2d Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. RES. 475</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20140612">June 12, 2014</action-date>
			<action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="S319">Mr. Begich</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S288">Ms. Murkowski</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was considered and agreed to</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">Congratulating the Alaska Aces hockey team on winning the 2014 Kelly Cup as champions of the East
			 Coast Hockey League.</official-title>
	</form>
	<preamble>
		<whereas>
      <text>Whereas on June 9, 2014, the Alaska Aces hockey team claimed the championship of the East Coast
			 Hockey League	with a 4-0 series-clinching win over the Cincinnati
			 Cyclones, which resulted in the Alaska Aces winning the East Coast Hockey
			 League’s Kelly Cup trophy;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the June 9 victory gave the Alaska Aces a 4-2 series win in the championship round and
			 resulted in  a 16-5 win-loss record for the Alaska Aces in the 2014
			 playoffs;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the 2014 East Coast Hockey League championship is the 3<superscript>rd</superscript> championship for the Alaska Aces in the past 9 years, making the Alaska Aces only the 2<superscript>nd </superscript>East Coast Hockey League team to win more than 2 East Coast Hockey League championships;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas in 2014, the Alaska Aces set an East Coast Hockey League record by winning the team's 4<superscript>th</superscript> straight Brabham Cup, which honors the East Coast Hockey League’s best regular-season record and
			 guarantees home-ice
			 advantage throughout the entire postseason;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the East Coast Hockey League is a premier “AA” hockey league featuring 22 teams from around
			 the country playing a 72-game regular season schedule;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the Alaska Aces are affiliated with the Calgary Flames of the National Hockey League,
			 opening a pathway to allow promising players to advance to the top tier of
			 professional hockey in the United States and Canada; and</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the people of the State of Alaska are proud of the dedication, hard work, and gritty
			 determination of the
			 players, coaches, and management of the Alaska Aces: Now, therefore, be it</text>
		</whereas>
  </preamble>
	<resolution-body>
		<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="S1" section-type="undesignated-section">
      <enum/>
      <text>That the <cato:entity-ref entity-id="0010" entity-type="federal-body">Senate</cato:entity-ref>—</text>
			<paragraph id="id67f8d071434a478f87e36048c6374fd4">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text>congratulates the Alaska Aces hockey team for winning the 2014 Kelly Cup as champions of the East
			 Coast Hockey League;</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="ide01905dd34ef4f71b9aa94f5328b54ec">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text>recognizes the players, coaches, students, staff, and fans whose dedication helped the Alaska Aces
			 win
			 the East Coast Hockey League championship; and</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id3a7473baaa884ff1b4fd1451a99c386a">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <text>respectfully requests the <cato:entity-ref entity-id="0010" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of the Senate</cato:entity-ref> to transmit an enrolled copy of this resolution
			 to—</text>
        <subparagraph id="idbf0734bcf7fd40689453879d87433f0b">
          <enum>(A)</enum>
          <text>the managing owner of the Alaska Aces, to be shared with the other team owners;</text>
        </subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="idf0b800b8bcc343a18303921e1ec14f34">
          <enum>(B)</enum>
          <text>the head coach of the Alaska Aces; and</text>
        </subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="idc0f8d2ceb83243dda35c869b80130646">
          <enum>(C)</enum>
          <text>the assistant coach of the Alaska Aces.</text>
				</subparagraph>
      </paragraph>
    </section>
  </resolution-body>
</resolution>
</doc>