<doc>
  <docmeta id="113sres165is">
    <bill congress="113" type="sres" number="165" version="is"/>
    <revision size="6001" annotations="0" status="complete" id="3" commit-time="2013-08-06T22:19:22Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113sres165is/3.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <resolution xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>113 SRES 165 IS: Calling for the release from prison of former Prime Minister of Ukraine Yulia Tymoshenko in light of the recent European Court of Human Rights ruling. </dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2013-06-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">113th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session display="yes">1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. RES. 165</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20130610">June 10, 2013</action-date>
			<action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="S253">Mr. Durbin</sponsor> (for himself,
			 <cosponsor name-id="S350">Mr. Rubio</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S223">Mrs.
			 Boxer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S317">Mr. Barrasso</cosponsor>, and
			 <cosponsor name-id="S364">Mr. Murphy</cosponsor>) submitted the following
			 resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign
			 Relations</committee-name>
      </action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">Calling for the release from prison of
		  former Prime Minister of Ukraine Yulia Tymoshenko in light of the recent
		  European Court of Human Rights ruling. </official-title>
	</form>
	<preamble>
		<whereas>
      <text>Whereas, in August 1991, the Ukrainian Parliament declared
			 independence from the Soviet Union and approved decrees to mint its own
			 currency and take command of all Soviet military units on its soil;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas, in December 1991, 90 percent of Ukrainians voted
			 in a referendum to support independence from the Soviet Union;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas Ukraine has experienced increased economic and
			 political cooperation with Europe and the United States since its independence
			 from the Soviet Union;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas, in 1996, Ukraine adopted its first democratic
			 constitution that included basic freedoms of speech, assembly, religion, and
			 press;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas, in 2004, Ukrainians organized a series of
			 historic protests, strikes, and sit-ins known as the <term>Orange
			 Revolution</term> to protest electoral fraud in the 2004 presidential
			 election;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas Yulia Tymoshenko was a leader of the Orange
			 Revolution and was first elected as Prime Minister in 2005;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas, in the 2010 presidential election, incumbent
			 President Viktor Yushchenko won only 5.5 percent in the first round of voting,
			 which left former Prime Minister Viktor Yanukovich and then Prime Minister
			 Yulia Tymoshenko to face one another in a run-off election;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas Mr. Yanukovich defeated Ms. Tymoshenko by a margin
			 of 49 percent to 44 percent;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas, on October 11, 2011, Ms. Tymoshenko was found
			 guilty and sentenced to seven years in prison on charges that she abused her
			 position as Prime Minister in connection with a Russian natural gas
			 contract;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas, on January 26, 2012, the Parliamentary Assembly
			 Council of Europe (PACE) passed a resolution (1862) that declared that the
			 articles under which Ms. Tymoshenko was convicted were <quote>overly broad in
			 application and effectively allow for ex post facto criminalization of normal
			 political decision making</quote>;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas, on May 30, 2012, the European Parliament passed a
			 resolution (C153/21) deploring the sentencing of Ms. Tymoshenko;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas, on September 22, 2012, the United States Senate
			 passed a resolution (<cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="112 SRES 466">S. Res. 466, 112th Congress</cato:entity-ref>) that condemned the selective
			 and politically motivated prosecution and imprisonment of Yulia Tymoshenko,
			 called for her release, and called on the Department of State to institute a
			 visa ban against those responsible for the imprisonment of Ms. Tymoshenko and
			 the other political leaders associated with the 2004 Orange Revolution;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas, on April 7, 2013, President of Ukraine Viktor
			 Yanukovich pardoned former interior minister Yuri Lutsenko and several other
			 opposition figures allied with Ms. Tymoshenko;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas, on April 30, 2013, the European Court of Human
			 Rights, which settles cases of rights abuses after plaintiffs have exhausted
			 appeals in their home country courts, ruled that Ms. Tymoshenko’s pre-trial
			 detention had been arbitrary; that the lawfulness of her detention had not been
			 properly reviewed; that her right to liberty had been restricted; and, that she
			 had no possibility to seek compensation for her unlawful deprivation of
			 liberty;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas, on April 30, 2013, Department of State Spokesman
			 Patrick Ventrell reiterated the United States call that Ms. Tymoshenko
			 <quote>be released and that the practice of selective prosecution end
			 immediately</quote> in light of the European Court of Human Rights
			 decision;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas Ukraine hopes to sign an association agreement
			 with the European Union during the Eastern Partnership Summit in November 2013;
			 and</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas, after the European Court of Human Rights ruling,
			 European Parliament Committee on Foreign Affairs chairman Elmar Brok stated
			 that <quote>Ukraine is still miles away from fulfilling European
			 standards</quote> and must <quote>end its selective justice</quote> before
			 signing the association agreement: Now, therefore, be it</text>
		</whereas>
  </preamble>
	<resolution-body>
		<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="S1" section-type="undesignated-section">
      <enum/>
      <text>That the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0010">Senate</cato:entity-ref>—</text>
			<paragraph id="id3707a41b55af4b588756c375f5760934">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text>calls on the
			 Government of Ukraine to release former Prime Minister Yulia Tymoshenko from
			 imprisonment in light of the April 2013 European Court of Human Rights
			 verdict;</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="idfde9083ffa8f448b88f2a40bba67c40c">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text>calls on the
			 European Union members to include the release of Ms. Tymoshenko from
			 imprisonment as an important criterion for signing an association agreement
			 with Ukraine at the upcoming Eastern Partnership Summit in Lithuania;</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id54b0cc4e106d4f19b0a66186b7a1aef2">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <text>expresses its
			 belief and hope that Ukraine’s future rests with stronger ties to Europe, the
			 United States, and others in the community of democracies; and</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="ida4e6d874e38747d3b83361a2524efd10">
        <enum>(4)</enum>
        <text>expresses its
			 concern and disappointment that the continued selective and politically
			 motivated imprisonment of former Prime Minister Yulia Tymoshenko unnecessarily
			 detracts from Ukraine’s otherwise strong relationship with Europe, the United
			 States, and the community of democracies.</text>
			</paragraph>
    </section>
  </resolution-body>
</resolution>
</doc>