<doc>
  <docmeta id="113s2442rs">
    <bill congress="113" type="s" number="2442" version="rs"/>
    <revision size="31302" annotations="0" status="complete" id="6" commit-time="2014-09-04T22:10:23Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113s2442rs/6.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <bill bill-stage="Reported-in-Senate" public-private="public">
  <metadata>
<dublinCore>
<dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">113 S2442 RS: Northern Cheyenne Lands Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">2014-06-05</dc:date>
<dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
    <calendar>Calendar No. 542</calendar>
    <congress>113th CONGRESS</congress>
    <session>2d Session</session>
    <legis-num>S. 2442</legis-num>
    <current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
    <action>
      <action-date date="20140605">June 5, 2014</action-date>
      <action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="S371">Mr. Walsh</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S314">Mr. Tester</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name added-display-style="italic" committee-id="SLIA00" deleted-display-style="strikethrough">Committee on Indian Affairs</committee-name>
      </action-desc>
    </action>
    <action stage="Reported-in-Senate">
      <action-date>August 26, 2014</action-date>
      <action-desc>Reported, under authority of the order of the Senate of August 5 (legislative day, August 1), 2014,
			 by <sponsor name-id="S314">Mr. Tester</sponsor>, with an amendment</action-desc>
      <action-instruction>Strike out all after the enacting clause and insert the part printed in italic</action-instruction>
    </action>
    <legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
    <official-title>To direct the Secretary of the Interior to take certain land and mineral rights on the reservation
			 of the Northern Cheyenne Tribe of Montana and other culturally important
			 land into trust for the benefit of the Northern Cheyenne Tribe, and for
			 other purposes.</official-title>
  </form>
  <legis-body>
    <section changed="deleted" committee-id="SLIA00" id="id3B19DDE3C5E941B7AD0758C93D13E651" reported-display-style="strikethrough" section-type="section-one">
      <enum>1.</enum>
      <header>Short title</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote>
          <short-title>Northern Cheyenne Lands Act</short-title>
        </quote>.</text>
    </section>
    <section changed="deleted" committee-id="SLIA00" id="id6c469f7f006145f196bbfee7836f404d" reported-display-style="strikethrough">
      <enum>2.</enum>
      <header>Findings</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds that—</text>
      <paragraph id="id3a3bf2b4b5ec48adac3cd3b7042cd4d9">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text>the Northern Cheyenne Tribe has depended on the land of the Tribe  and the land-based resources of
			 the Tribe to support its way of life since time immemorial;</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="idacd718c3f008404791cf8e8b2cec9481">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text>the Tribe has made supreme and historic sacrifices to repossess and maintain the homeland of the
			 Tribe, including the Reservation of the Tribe in the State of Montana;</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id6eee7f798871497d8a583b8536e1750e">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <text>the Tribe suffers from tremendous social and economic challenges, including a lack of employment
			 opportunities on the Reservation, which can be improved by strengthening
			 the control of the Tribe over the land base, natural resources, and trust
			 funds of the Tribe;</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="idf91606df1b6247009f6f5e1cf9584f87">
        <enum>(4)</enum>
        <text>the Tribe seeks a variety of resolutions to outstanding legal obstacles that have prevented the
			 Tribe from consolidating subsurface and surface trust ownership on the
			 Reservation;</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id2a5c1283758d448a878165cd40b79068">
        <enum>(5)</enum>
        <text>the Tribe and the members of the Tribe are the beneficial owners of more than 95 percent of the
			 surface land of the Reservation and all but approximately 5,000 subsurface
			 acres of the Reservation;</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="idccb1abd8535649dc817e79f53bf80d7a">
        <enum>(6)</enum>
        <text>the Tribe seeks to obtain ownership of approximately 5,000 subsurface acres on the Reservation that
			 the Tribe does not own as a result of an error made by the United States
			 when the Reservation was expanded in 1900;</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="idee0c91666e7347f9a435d38302ff6b82">
        <enum>(7)</enum>
        <text>in 2002, the Tribe agreed by settlement to dismiss a lawsuit against the United States	which
			 alleged that the United States failed to protect the Reservation from the
			 impacts of coal development  in return for assistance in securing tribal
			 ownership of the subsurface rights described in paragraph (6)
			 substantially in the form of this Act, and to secure mitigation funding to
			 address the impacts of coal development in areas adjacent to the
			 Reservation, among other conditions;</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id19bb9696acda4b209613d11e2e0dfe6c">
        <enum>(8)</enum>
        <text>to increase tribal ownership of the surface land, the Tribe has purchased approximately 932 acres
			 of land within the Reservation that were, for various reasons, taken out
			 of trust ownership status;</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id9c6c89c4842548cfa1cd120c8224c5d3">
        <enum>(9)</enum>
        <text>the Tribe has purchased approximately 635 acres of land near Bear Butte, South Dakota, which the
			 Tribe considers sacred ground for the members of the Tribe, as well as for
			 members of other Indian tribes;</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id657a2955b3c244da8060d5494cff905b">
        <enum>(10)</enum>
        <text>the Tribe seeks to have the land and subsurface within the Reservation and the Bear Butte land
			 described in this section taken into trust by the United States for the
			 benefit of the Tribe;</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id01cd0cdf9bc1436bb942ee4e2c3e866c">
        <enum>(11)</enum>
        <text>the Tribe seeks clarification, consistent with the 1999 settlement with the United States, that the
			 principal of the funds arising from the Northern Cheyenne Indian Reserved
			 Water Rights Settlement Act of 1992 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/102/374">Public Law 102–374</external-xref>; 106 Stat. 1186;
			 108 Stat. 707), the earnings from which are paid to the Tribe and managed
			 as the <quote>Northern Cheyenne Trust Fund</quote> by the Office of Special Trustee, may be transferred to the Northern Cheyenne Tribe Permanent
			 Fund, which has historically provided strong returns to the Tribe in
			 direct support of tribal self-determination and to offset limited Federal
			 funding of important tribal governmental services; and</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="idd1af88353e2d4fd18f764e069e2ab358">
        <enum>(12)</enum>
        <text>if the conveyances of land and funds authorized under this Act are carried out, the Tribe has
			 agreed to waive all legal claims against the United States arising out of
			 the longstanding loss of the subsurface rights and the management of the
			 Northern Cheyenne Trust Fund by the United States.</text>
      </paragraph>
    </section>
    <section changed="deleted" committee-id="SLIA00" id="id9680be1daf7349e6a8b6b1f46108a4bb" reported-display-style="strikethrough">
      <enum>3.</enum>
      <header>Definitions</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text>
      <paragraph id="id6f8077a96821438e9eab7b0c05173d7d">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <header>Fund</header>
        <text>The term <term>Fund</term> means the Northern Cheyenne Trust Fund identified in the June 7, 1999 Agreement Settling Certain
			 Issues Relating to the Tongue River Dam Project, which was entered into by
			 the Tribe, the State, and delegates of the Secretary, and managed by the
			 Office of Special Trustee in the Department of the Interior.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id58662a38e79c4b8ea2a70be83d1d023a">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <header>Great Northern Properties</header>
        <text>The term <term>Great Northern Properties</term> means the Great Northern Properties Limited Partnership, which is a Delaware limited partnership.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id3c788fc421c04f7189766f286f88d2d2">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <header>Permanent Fund</header>
        <text>The term <term>Permanent Fund</term> means the Northern Cheyenne Tribe Permanent Fund managed by the Tribe pursuant to the Plan for
			 Investment, Management and Use of the Fund, as amended by vote of the
			 tribal membership on November 2, 2010.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="idb60497ce366c4549b99f7dd02791c42c">
        <enum>(4)</enum>
        <header>Reservation</header>
        <text>The term <term>Reservation</term> means the Northern Cheyenne Reservation.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id02fdab522ecc43f5ada54a1451c8318c">
        <enum>(5)</enum>
        <header>Secretary</header>
        <text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of the Interior.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="idfd705b64682c412297ee3abd19556add">
        <enum>(6)</enum>
        <header>State</header>
        <text>The term <term>State</term> means the State of Montana.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id0549185ccabf42ee8e95f9384c2c15e4">
        <enum>(7)</enum>
        <header>Tribe</header>
        <text>The term <term>Tribe</term> means the Northern Cheyenne Tribe.</text>
      </paragraph>
    </section>
    <section changed="deleted" committee-id="SLIA00" id="idf460c9a560e14658a99edb09615658f2" reported-display-style="strikethrough">
      <enum>4.</enum>
      <header>Tribal fee land to be taken into trust</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than	60 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall take into
			 trust for the benefit of the Tribe the
			 approximately 1,567 acres of land depicted on—</text>
      <paragraph id="id08CB89D2F38448F0B9C57E39B63DE6A6">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the map entitled <quote>Northern Cheyenne Lands Act – Fee-to-Trust Lands</quote> and dated April 22, 2014; and</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idC2E0226B79124CB3AD1EDDB88CAE02F7">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the map entitled <quote>Northern Cheyenne Lands Act – Fee-to-Trust Lands – Lame Deer Townsite</quote> and dated April 22, 2014.</text>
      </paragraph>
    </section>
    <section changed="deleted" committee-id="SLIA00" id="id8ec6af7d0e004c68ba20053cdeabf0da" reported-display-style="strikethrough">
      <enum>5.</enum>
      <header>Mineral rights to be taken into trust</header>
      <subsection id="id8ab4e8707a5e414990457e5108522a02">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Completion of mineral conveyances</header>
        <paragraph id="idBBCB1997C776467CA22C6DD6E6B6780C">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>In general</header>
          <text>Not later than	60 days after the date on which the Secretary receives the notification described
			 in subsection (c), in a single transaction—</text>
          <subparagraph id="idb11fc766a7e04409ae0074fe6514a5ef">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>Great Northern Properties shall convey to the Tribe all right, title, and interest  of Great
			 Northern Properties, consisting of coal and iron ore mineral interests,
			 underlying the land on the Reservation generally depicted as <quote>Great Northern Properties</quote> on the map entitled <quote>Northern Cheyenne Land Act – Coal Tracts</quote> and dated April 22, 2014; and</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="idc708aa5aee3a4ceebc5752f828857c02">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>subject to paragraph (2), the Secretary shall convey to Great Northern Properties all right, title,
			 and interest of the
			 United States in and to the coal mineral interests underlying the land
			 generally depicted as <quote>Bull Mountains</quote> and <quote>East Fork</quote> on the map entitled <quote>Northern Cheyenne Federal Tracts</quote> and dated April 22, 2014.</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="id0695700352b54ac0ad40c277102616eb">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Requirement</header>
          <text>The Secretary shall ensure that the deed for the conveyance authorized by paragraph (1)(B) shall
			 include a covenant running with the land that—</text>
          <subparagraph id="idc540d97138c5416f864de73134b63ca0">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>precludes the coal conveyed from being mined by any method other than underground mining
			 techniques—</text>
            <clause id="id688B12A4F235411198F29E54E547944A">
              <enum>(i)</enum>
              <text>until any surface owner (as defined in section 714(e) of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/95/87">Public Law 95–87</external-xref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/1304">30 U.S.C. 1304(e)</external-xref>)) for
			 a
			 specific tract has provided to Great Northern Properties written consent
			 to enter the specific tract and commence surface mining; and</text>
            </clause>
            <clause id="id4c1e934f7f134e08a195ae4847d91e0e">
              <enum>(ii)</enum>
              <text>except as determined to be acceptable for further consideration for leasing in the document of the
			 Bureau of Land Management entitled <quote>Billings Resource Area Final EIS and Resource Management Plan</quote> and dated September 1984; and</text>
            </clause>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="id1cefb2cfbc0d4bfe8136488d4900586d">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>shall not create any property interest in the United States or any surface owner (as defined in
			 section 714(e) of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/95/87">Public Law 95–87</external-xref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/1304">30 U.S.C. 1304(e)</external-xref>)).</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="iddb409ed9b34644d68e894d3ad934ca88">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Treatment of land transferred to Tribe</header>
        <paragraph id="idDCC4C80080B94B0598D822ACC238697C">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>In general</header>
          <text>At the request of the Tribe, the Secretary shall take into trust for the benefit of the Tribe the
			 mineral interests conveyed to the Tribe under subsection (a)(1)(A).</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="idC90575FCFFCC4E96A20BC094955803E9">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>No State taxation</header>
          <text>The mineral interests conveyed to the Tribe under subsection (a)(1)(A) shall not be subject to
			 taxation by the State (including any political subdivision of the State).</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="id01d920d7f68a42c2a344027a62f09286">
        <enum>(c)</enum>
        <header>Revenue sharing agreement</header>
        <text>The Tribe shall notify the Secretary, in writing, that—</text>
        <paragraph id="id42365182B0964E528ABF4C388EE18C77">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>consistent with a settlement agreement entered into between the Tribe and the State in 2002, the
			 Tribe and Great Northern Properties have agreed on a formula for sharing
			 revenue from development of the mineral interests described in subsection
			 (a)(1)(B) if those mineral interests are developed;</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="idE0C25B3FB8D5463E9AA7343612EBF6E0">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>the revenue sharing agreement remains in effect as of the date of enactment of this Act; and</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="id673FD162E7414DEABB3DADCCF258ECDA">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <text>Great Northern Properties has offered to convey the mineral interests described in subsection
			 (a)(1)(A) to the Tribe.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="id7247780fb0e742dbafb1b3b96d4f3ac3">
        <enum>(d)</enum>
        <header>Waiver of legal claims</header>
        <text>As a condition of the conveyances of mineral interests under subsection (a)(1)—</text>
        <paragraph id="id0ff6a85c4c2f4c71bf60453bbbd7b717">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>the Tribe shall waive any and all claims relating to the failure of the United States to acquire
			 and take into trust on behalf of the Tribe the mineral interests described
			 in subsection (a)(1)(A), as directed by Congress in 1900; and</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="id45939a5cbe484dab96ded8095c77745b">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>Great Northern Properties shall waive any and all claims against the United States relating to the
			 value of the coal mineral interests described in subsection (a)(1)(B).</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="idb171700b46854c44a546608396eb15ad">
        <enum>(e)</enum>
        <header>Rescission of mineral conveyances</header>
        <text>If any portion of the mineral interests conveyed under subsection (a)(1) is invalidated by final
			 judgment of a court of the United States—</text>
        <paragraph id="idbb1f815d4d5142048571832cbf56d76f">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>not later than 1 year after the date on which the  final judgment is rendered, the Secretary or
			 Great Northern Properties may agree to rescind the conveyances under
			 subsection (a)(1); and</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="idf9183e1cb512412cb2cacb18e3169da2">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>if the conveyances are rescinded under paragraph (1), the waivers under subsection (d) shall no
			 longer apply.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
    </section>
    <section changed="deleted" committee-id="SLIA00" id="ide4e6049385974b89a1c903c613491f97" reported-display-style="strikethrough">
      <enum>6.</enum>
      <header>Transfer of Northern Cheyenne Trust Fund to Tribe</header>
      <subsection id="id354869f4bc1745499ae9869e78fc87fd">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>In general</header>
        <text>Not later than 30 days after the date of enactment of this Act, all amounts in the Fund shall be
			 deposited in the  Permanent Fund.</text>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="idc1a640b175b6463f8669c04f7bfb2e53">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Use of amounts</header>
        <text>Of the amounts transferred to the Permanent Fund under subsection (a)—</text>
        <paragraph id="idFE172F3534814C25B736CFB44EB202E5">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>the portion that is attributable to the principal of the Fund shall be maintained in perpetuity; 
			 and</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="id0A1F2790C78A4A799C4E541260712B12">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>any interest earned on the amounts described in paragraph (1) shall be used in the same manner as
			 interest earned on amounts in the Permanent Fund may be used.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="ida6e085200e2b4d8ab129b28c9ca07e29">
        <enum>(c)</enum>
        <header>Waiver of legal claims</header>
        <text>As a condition of the transfer under subsection (a), the Tribe shall waive any and all claims
			 arising from the management of the Fund by the United States.</text>
      </subsection>
    </section>
    <section changed="deleted" committee-id="SLIA00" id="idd5193162ee4a4b5392d69fa1cc5fd1b4" reported-display-style="strikethrough">
      <enum>7.</enum>
      <header>Land consolidation and fractionation reporting</header>
      <subsection id="idac5fb519f3cb4a438f2017cd6519d307">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Inventory</header>
        <paragraph id="id507f33f4a83943b3a55324373baaa1d6">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>In general</header>
          <text>The Secretary, in consultation with the Tribe, shall prepare an inventory of fractionated land
			 interests held  by the United States in trust for the benefit of—</text>
          <subparagraph id="idDFFA600BF7FD4130A4AB7BD4490D9009">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>the Tribe; or</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="id17F6AB93598E4B50BF28CA06F956D7B0">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>individual Indians on the Reservation.</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="id6ecc2a43fa3648ce9e69d263c0e4d5c1">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Agricultural purposes</header>
          <text>The inventory prepared by the Secretary under this subsection shall include details currently
			 available about fractionated land on the Reservation suitable for
			 agricultural purposes.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="id88c1e3493ae64e0d92cdcbc10ac72c7f">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <header>Submission</header>
          <text>The Secretary shall submit the inventory prepared under this subsection to the Committee on Indian
			 Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Natural Resources of the House
			 of Representatives by	not later than 180 days after the date of enactment
			 of this Act.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="id8eb286a6496647829c377ac7e728ebf8">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Report</header>
        <paragraph id="idf335e3044dcf4314bab738b3e450905c">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>In general</header>
          <text>The Secretary, in consultation with the Tribe, shall prepare periodic reports regarding obstacles
			 to consolidating trust land ownership on the Reservation.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="id466ebf28512d4edba5a7eae01c76b16f">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Contents</header>
          <text>The reports under this subsection shall include—</text>
          <subparagraph id="ida7e33c397d474fa1877fa3f0ec65d031">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>a description of existing obstacles to consolidating trust land ownership, including the extent of
			 fractionation;</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="idbcf4c2c91ef74dc29e811bfb509ea9a4">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>a description of progress achieved by the Tribe toward reducing fractionation and increasing trust
			 land ownership;</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="id9424cbb7a2774fc9a93a5b72d1c1cde5">
            <enum>(C)</enum>
            <text>an analysis of progress achieved by the Tribe toward making agricultural use economical on trust
			 land; and</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="id049da5a1f16e4af494154960b4dc3f05">
            <enum>(D)</enum>
            <text>any applicable outcomes and lessons learned from land consolidation activities undertaken pursuant
			 to the Indian Land Consolidation Act (25 U.S.C.
		2201 et seq.).</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="id165118649fcf4b61a040db1bbdd64ffd">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <header>Submission</header>
          <text>The Secretary shall submit the reports under this subsection to the Committee on Indian Affairs of
			 the Senate and the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of
			 Representatives not less frequently than once each calendar year for the
			 5-year period beginning on the date of enactment of this Act.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
    </section>
    <section changed="deleted" committee-id="SLIA00" id="id4f6978a933674a708a4892c3980ba416" reported-display-style="strikethrough">
      <enum>8.</enum>
      <header>Eligibility for other Federal benefits</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">The transfer  under section 6 shall not result in the reduction or denial of any Federal
			 service, benefit, or program to the Tribe or to any member of the Tribe to
			 which the Tribe or member is entitled or eligible because of—</text>
      <paragraph id="idcd17621eb8714cb98d886ddc8c5006e3">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text>the status of the Tribe as a federally recognized Indian tribe; or</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id8f1f74f508224fbdbcd9af5c180d9a4c">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text>the status of the member as a member of the Tribe.</text>
      </paragraph>
    </section>
    <section changed="deleted" commented="no" committee-id="SLIA00" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd9f5c7df5a584f3cb9a64316c83b0ee4" reported-display-style="strikethrough" section-type="subsequent-section">
      <enum>9.</enum>
      <header>Authorization of appropriations</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this Act such sums as are necessary.</text>
    </section>
  </legis-body>
  <legis-body display-enacting-clause="no-display-enacting-clause">
    <section changed="added" committee-id="SLIA00" id="id883369a2-9041-439a-a387-8cfed5845bdd" reported-display-style="italic" section-type="section-one">
      <enum>1.</enum>
      <header>Short title</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote>
          <short-title>
            <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Northern Cheyenne Lands Act" proposed="true">Northern Cheyenne Lands Act</cato:entity-ref>
          </short-title>
        </quote>.</text>
    </section>
    <section changed="added" committee-id="SLIA00" id="id85eccb87-57e4-4d51-a8f3-ec35853b8be0" reported-display-style="italic">
      <enum>2.</enum>
      <header>Findings</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">
        <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> finds that—</text>
      <paragraph id="id93b1be82-cc27-49ab-ab6f-6de08dd921ce">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text>the Northern Cheyenne Tribe has depended on the land of the Tribe  and the land-based resources of
			 the Tribe to support its way of life since time immemorial;</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="ide03c78d9-bcd5-4b70-9212-2446c41798f5">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text>the Tribe has made supreme and historic sacrifices to repossess and maintain the homeland of the
			 Tribe, including the Reservation of the Tribe in the State of Montana;</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id93975231-b64a-4987-becc-40d966e4ec4a">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <text>the Tribe suffers from tremendous social and economic challenges, including a lack of employment
			 opportunities on the Reservation, which can be improved by strengthening
			 the control of the Tribe over the land base, natural resources, and trust
			 funds of the Tribe;</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id676992fe-8368-4deb-ab8f-1451ee4e99e4">
        <enum>(4)</enum>
        <text>the Tribe seeks a variety of resolutions to outstanding legal obstacles that have prevented the
			 Tribe from consolidating subsurface and surface trust ownership on the
			 Reservation;</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="ide5c375d9-7f95-4f78-9218-c666567b41c2">
        <enum>(5)</enum>
        <text>the Tribe and the members of the Tribe are the beneficial owners of more than 95 percent of the
			 surface land of the Reservation and all but approximately 5,000 subsurface
			 acres of the Reservation;</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="idc243348b-6f10-4c50-baf1-a6ba13c03fe0">
        <enum>(6)</enum>
        <text>the Tribe seeks to obtain ownership of approximately 5,000 subsurface acres on the Reservation that
			 the Tribe does not own as a result of an error made by the United States
			 when the Reservation was expanded in 1900;</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id9d5e1326-699d-41e4-a2ed-72a3b204b025">
        <enum>(7)</enum>
        <text>in 2002, the Tribe agreed by settlement to dismiss a lawsuit against the United States	which
			 alleged that the United States failed to protect the Reservation from the
			 impacts of coal development  in return for assistance in securing tribal
			 ownership of the subsurface rights described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Northern Cheyenne Lands Act/s:2/p:6" proposed="true">paragraph (6)</cato:entity-ref>
			 substantially in the form of this Act, and to secure mitigation funding to
			 address the impacts of coal development in areas adjacent to the
			 Reservation, among other conditions;</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="idd690e22a-6311-4f60-81e2-cd884a7a2803">
        <enum>(8)</enum>
        <text>to increase tribal ownership of the surface land, the Tribe has purchased approximately 932 acres
			 of land within the Reservation that were, for various reasons, taken out
			 of trust ownership status;</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="ida7acb4e2-6059-4ee2-a5a7-b1f996ac3fce">
        <enum>(9)</enum>
        <text>the Tribe has purchased approximately 635 acres of land near Bear Butte, South Dakota, which the
			 Tribe considers sacred ground for the members of the Tribe, as well as for
			 members of other Indian tribes;</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id8facc55a-6b09-41ff-983b-7a9a2712e410">
        <enum>(10)</enum>
        <text>the Tribe seeks to have the land and subsurface within the Reservation and the Bear Butte land
			 described in this section taken into trust by the United States for the
			 benefit of the Tribe;</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id4e93e1d5-a97a-4bfe-9e44-7b66b41db602">
        <enum>(11)</enum>
        <text>the Tribe seeks clarification, consistent with the 1999 settlement with the United States, that the
			 principal of the funds arising from the <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Northern Cheyenne Indian Reserved Water Rights Settlement Act of 1992">Northern Cheyenne Indian Reserved
			 Water Rights Settlement Act of 1992</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/102/374">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="public-law" value="public-law/102/374">Public Law 102–374</cato:entity-ref>
          </external-xref>; <cato:entity-ref entity-type="statute-at-large" value="statute-at-large/106/1186">106 Stat. 1186</cato:entity-ref>;
			 <cato:entity-ref entity-type="statute-at-large" value="statute-at-large/108/707">108 Stat. 707</cato:entity-ref>)</cato:entity>, the earnings from which are paid to the Tribe and managed
			 as the <quote>Northern Cheyenne Trust Fund</quote> by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1415" entity-type="federal-body">Office of Special Trustee</cato:entity-ref>, may be transferred to the Northern Cheyenne Tribe Permanent
			 Fund, which has historically provided strong returns to the Tribe in
			 direct support of tribal self-determination and to offset limited Federal
			 funding of important tribal governmental services; and</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="ide2323e5a-88fc-4dcc-a3f9-c6645eca43b8">
        <enum>(12)</enum>
        <text>if the conveyances of land and funds authorized under this Act are carried out, the Tribe has
			 agreed to waive all legal claims against the United States arising out of
			 the longstanding loss of the subsurface rights and the management of the
			 Northern Cheyenne Trust Fund by the United States.</text>
      </paragraph>
    </section>
    <section changed="added" committee-id="SLIA00" id="id8889aaba-4b11-459f-88d1-946195959c10" reported-display-style="italic">
      <enum>3.</enum>
      <header>Definitions</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text>
      <paragraph id="idcc8d416d-b749-4e58-85fb-60875defa518">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <header>Fund</header>
        <text>The term <term>Fund</term> means the Northern Cheyenne Trust Fund identified in the June 7, 1999 Agreement Settling Certain
			 Issues Relating to the Tongue River Dam Project, which was entered into by
			 the Tribe, the State, and delegates of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1400">Secretary</cato:entity-ref>, and managed by the
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1415">Office of Special Trustee in the Department of the Interior</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id76c7fa7d-6d36-4c27-b062-0051b0bc01b0">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <header>Great Northern Properties</header>
        <text>The term <term>Great Northern Properties</term> means the Great Northern Properties Limited Partnership, which is a Delaware limited partnership.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id7aaeece0-0372-42ad-922f-8e8c1253c5c1">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <header>Permanent Fund</header>
        <text>The term <term>Permanent Fund</term> means the Northern Cheyenne Tribe Permanent Fund managed by the Tribe pursuant to the Plan for
			 Investment, Management and Use of the Fund, as amended by vote of the
			 tribal membership on November 2, 2010.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id326aa9c1-2363-450f-8248-4078607f1cbd">
        <enum>(4)</enum>
        <header>Reservation</header>
        <text>The term <term>Reservation</term> means the Northern Cheyenne Reservation.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="ide1ae3e62-21bc-4156-a105-4868f0a96080">
        <enum>(5)</enum>
        <header>Secretary</header>
        <text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1400" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of the Interior</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id0b8b4432-9f83-4b06-bd05-5f88b0ae768d">
        <enum>(6)</enum>
        <header>State</header>
        <text>The term <term>State</term> means the State of Montana.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id370111e3-4d7a-467b-8644-fd0977e376a1">
        <enum>(7)</enum>
        <header>Tribe</header>
        <text>The term <term>Tribe</term> means the Northern Cheyenne Tribe.</text>
      </paragraph>
    </section>
    <section changed="added" committee-id="SLIA00" id="id4abcfe4d-6da7-442a-8635-32798902fcf8" reported-display-style="italic">
      <enum>4.</enum>
      <header>Tribal fee land to be taken into trust</header>
      <subsection id="id7881E62326304CDBBF3C74832686EAC6">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>In general</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Northern Cheyenne Lands Act/s:4/ss:b" proposed="true">subsection (b)</cato:entity-ref>, not later than	60 days after the date of enactment of this Act,
			 the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1400">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall take into
			 trust for the benefit of the Tribe the
			 approximately 932 acres of land depicted on—</text>
        <paragraph id="idf6e4002e-6539-4754-9ba0-9f61249e10a3">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the map entitled <quote>
              Northern Cheyenne Lands Act – Fee-to-Trust Lands</quote> and dated April 22, 2014; and</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3e2b1421-3611-4985-8592-85cfbc067140">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the map entitled <quote>
              Northern Cheyenne Lands Act – Fee-to-Trust Lands – Lame Deer Townsite</quote> and dated April 22, 2014.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7BE41663F44C4ABEBFAD24F087834BA6">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Limitation</header>
        <text>Any land located in the State of South Dakota that is included on the maps referred to in
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Northern Cheyenne Lands Act/s:4/ss:a/p:1" proposed="true">paragraphs (1)</cato:entity-ref> and <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Northern Cheyenne Lands Act/s:4/ss:a/p:2" proposed="true">(2) of subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref> shall not be taken into trust
			 pursuant to that subsection.</text>
      </subsection>
    </section>
    <section changed="added" committee-id="SLIA00" id="ided5f4857-8d6c-41d0-9c0f-f91375a4206f" reported-display-style="italic">
      <enum>5.</enum>
      <header>Mineral rights to be taken into trust</header>
      <subsection id="id3e58a2be-ef8b-440e-80ab-dfd0897c0451">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Completion of mineral conveyances</header>
        <paragraph id="iddf720bfc-8acb-4506-973c-8b171b7f603a">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>In general</header>
          <text>Not later than	60 days after the date on which the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1400">Secretary</cato:entity-ref>
			 receives the notification described
			 in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Northern Cheyenne Lands Act/s:5/ss:c" proposed="true">subsection (c)</cato:entity-ref>, in a single transaction—</text>
          <subparagraph id="idf759ce3f-2d61-4cab-9b6a-e209f4824d47">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>Great Northern Properties shall convey to the Tribe all right, title, and interest  of Great
			 Northern Properties, consisting of coal and iron ore mineral interests,
			 underlying the land on the Reservation generally depicted as <quote>Great Northern Properties</quote> on the map entitled <quote>Northern Cheyenne Land Act – Coal Tracts</quote> and dated April 22, 2014; and</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="idd230f0b8-39d5-42ca-a33f-efbeb9b54bf6">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>subject to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Northern Cheyenne Lands Act/s:5/ss:a/p:2" proposed="true">paragraph (2)</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1400">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall convey to Great Northern Properties all right, title,
			 and interest of the
			 United States in and to the coal mineral interests underlying the land
			 generally depicted as <quote>Bull Mountains</quote> and <quote>East Fork</quote> on the map entitled <quote>Northern Cheyenne Federal Tracts</quote> and dated April 22, 2014.</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="iddce9f09d-2295-48ab-9d4e-ea0d5d05c689">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Requirement</header>
          <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1400">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall ensure that the deed for the conveyance authorized by <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Northern Cheyenne Lands Act/s:5/ss:a/p:1/sp:B" proposed="true">paragraph (1)(B)</cato:entity-ref> shall
			 include a covenant running with the land that—</text>
          <subparagraph id="id2cb51038-20f7-42a8-95a4-78607de2cfcc">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>precludes the coal conveyed from being mined by any method other than underground mining
			 techniques until any surface owner (as defined in <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="public-law" value="public-law/95/87/s:714/ss:e">section 714(e) of Public
			 Law 95–87</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/1304">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/30/1304/e">30 U.S.C. 1304(e)</cato:entity-ref>
              </external-xref>)</cato:entity>) for
			 a
			 specific tract has provided to Great Northern Properties written consent
			 to enter the specific tract and commence surface mining;</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="id8fc4dbaa-dac2-4f4c-92a0-1842d29e30c1">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>shall not create any property interest in the United States or any surface owner (as defined in
			 <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="public-law" value="public-law/95/87/s:714/ss:e">section 714(e) of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/95/87">
                Public Law 95–87
              </external-xref>
                  </cato:entity-ref> (
                <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/1304">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/30/1304/e">30 U.S.C. 1304(e)</cato:entity-ref>
              </external-xref>)</cato:entity>); and</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="id8041DA9FFBF641F48F07226533399B3A">
            <enum>(C)</enum>
            <text>shall not affect, abridge, or amend any valid existing rights of any surface owner of a specific
			 tract or any adjacent tracts.</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="id7ecd4dec-a86d-4638-bd65-2326df948199">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Treatment of land transferred to Tribe</header>
        <paragraph id="id3eea97c2-6f30-4e73-8d5b-5ff31562b5d8">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>In general</header>
          <text>At the request of the Tribe, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1400">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall take into trust for the benefit of the Tribe the
			 mineral interests conveyed to the Tribe under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Northern Cheyenne Lands Act/s:5/ss:a/p:1/sp:A" proposed="true">subsection (a)(1)(A)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="id9e20a2be-fbc4-479d-8d7a-77105104e5df">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>No State taxation</header>
          <text>The mineral interests conveyed to the Tribe under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Northern Cheyenne Lands Act/s:5/ss:a/p:1/sp:A" proposed="true">subsection (a)(1)(A)</cato:entity-ref> shall not be subject to
			 taxation by the State (including any political subdivision of the State).</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="id5a4b999d-0955-45d4-84db-bfd152f3fb21">
        <enum>(c)</enum>
        <header>Revenue sharing agreement</header>
        <text>The Tribe shall notify the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1400">Secretary</cato:entity-ref>, in writing, that—</text>
        <paragraph id="idd4a89537-6b66-4407-8e1e-cee3ce66a36a">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>consistent with a settlement agreement entered into between the Tribe and the State in 2002, the
			 Tribe and Great Northern Properties have agreed on a formula for sharing
			 revenue from development of the mineral interests described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Northern Cheyenne Lands Act/s:5/ss:a/p:1/sp:B" proposed="true">subsection
			 (a)(1)(B)</cato:entity-ref> if those mineral interests are developed;</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="id5dfc39b7-b379-49bd-8b8d-7d868b13cee9">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>the revenue sharing agreement remains in effect as of the date of enactment of this Act; and</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="idb30c9ab7-6637-445d-8702-b8a481fbf912">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <text>Great Northern Properties has offered to convey the mineral interests described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Northern Cheyenne Lands Act/s:5/ss:a/p:1/sp:A" proposed="true">subsection
			 (a)(1)(A)</cato:entity-ref> to the Tribe.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="idcf789ac1-ca1a-4d00-94b2-b0b1960f5cae">
        <enum>(d)</enum>
        <header>Waiver of legal claims</header>
        <text>As a condition of the conveyances of mineral interests under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Northern Cheyenne Lands Act/s:5/ss:a/p:1" proposed="true">subsection (a)(1)</cato:entity-ref>—</text>
        <paragraph id="idbb38b8a7-86e7-46c1-80b3-a81200e9454f">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>the Tribe shall waive any and all claims relating to the failure of the United States to acquire
			 and take into trust on behalf of the Tribe the mineral interests described
			 in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Northern Cheyenne Lands Act/s:5/ss:a/p:1/sp:A" proposed="true">subsection (a)(1)(A)</cato:entity-ref>, as directed by <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> in 1900; and</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="id571796d1-cd19-4f57-bfb1-513d296493a4">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>Great Northern Properties shall waive any and all claims against the United States relating to the
			 value of the coal mineral interests described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Northern Cheyenne Lands Act/s:5/ss:a/p:1/sp:B" proposed="true">subsection (a)(1)(B)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="id9696920b-e0da-44b3-8a03-9ff210d2ffca">
        <enum>(e)</enum>
        <header>Rescission of mineral conveyances</header>
        <text>If any portion of the mineral interests conveyed under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Northern Cheyenne Lands Act/s:5/ss:a/p:1" proposed="true">subsection (a)(1)</cato:entity-ref> is invalidated by final
			 judgment of a court of the United States—</text>
        <paragraph id="idd768fc8d-9ad0-47c7-8cbe-ff6afd024ae5">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>not later than 1 year after the date on which the  final judgment is rendered, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1400">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> or
			 Great Northern Properties may agree to rescind the conveyances under
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Northern Cheyenne Lands Act/s:5/ss:a/p:1" proposed="true">subsection (a)(1)</cato:entity-ref>; and</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="ida6ab9088-7041-467b-b5fc-391e1196890f">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>if the conveyances are rescinded under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Northern Cheyenne Lands Act/s:5/ss:e/p:1" proposed="true">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref>, the waivers under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Northern Cheyenne Lands Act/s:5/ss:d" proposed="true">subsection (d)</cato:entity-ref> shall no
			 longer apply.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
    </section>
    <section changed="added" committee-id="SLIA00" id="id4025ee48-dfb2-4bd6-9b63-e29935d77d9e" reported-display-style="italic">
      <enum>6.</enum>
      <header>Transfer of Northern Cheyenne Trust Fund to Tribe</header>
      <subsection id="id98650de8-6c1b-4f9c-94c4-085c08665441">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>In general</header>
        <text>Not later than 30 days after the date of enactment of this Act, all amounts in the Fund shall be
			 deposited in the  Permanent Fund.</text>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="id86e3b9e1-618a-4320-aeb8-1c0a4d93a682">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Use of amounts</header>
        <text>Of the amounts transferred to the Permanent Fund under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Northern Cheyenne Lands Act/s:6/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref>—</text>
        <paragraph id="idbe2ff2a3-f411-47db-8b15-81a62a87b323">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>the portion that is attributable to the principal of the Fund shall be maintained in perpetuity; 
			 and</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="id02d5311c-bf14-4f79-aed2-8e1781fdff45">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>any interest earned on the amounts described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Northern Cheyenne Lands Act/s:6/ss:b/p:1" proposed="true">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref> shall be used in the same manner as
			 interest earned on amounts in the Permanent Fund may be used.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="ida0789f95-201b-4bd5-80e7-7b3053fc8eed">
        <enum>(c)</enum>
        <header>Waiver of legal claims</header>
        <text>As a condition of the transfer under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Northern Cheyenne Lands Act/s:6/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref>, the Tribe shall waive any and all claims
			 arising from the management of the Fund by the United States.</text>
      </subsection>
    </section>
    <section changed="added" committee-id="SLIA00" id="id16666ec7-18fa-41e6-9a45-18b18b4b3177" reported-display-style="italic">
      <enum>7.</enum>
      <header>Land consolidation and fractionation reporting</header>
      <subsection id="ideddddbbd-5c2e-454f-8ad6-763d48e4f271">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Inventory</header>
        <paragraph id="id75960083-8dc0-4fe7-a266-5f8b02c7276a">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>In general</header>
          <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1400">Secretary</cato:entity-ref>, in consultation with the Tribe, shall prepare an inventory of fractionated land
			 interests held  by the United States in trust for the benefit of—</text>
          <subparagraph id="iddb68b9c6-55a4-4edd-9e10-5b5d4b3fef13">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>the Tribe; or</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="idbeb7a274-c492-4c67-b5b4-da799dcf0222">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>individual Indians on the Reservation.</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="idb931ce31-5b7e-4658-8637-5a1651dc3922">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Agricultural purposes</header>
          <text>The inventory prepared by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1400">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> under this subsection shall include details currently
			 available about fractionated land on the Reservation suitable for
			 agricultural purposes.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="idb9196fc7-158c-4e8c-a0e9-233287a68ca1">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <header>Submission</header>
          <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1400">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall submit the inventory prepared under this subsection to the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="SLIA00" entity-type="committee">Committee on Indian
			 Affairs of the Senate</cato:entity-ref> and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="HII00" entity-type="committee">Committee on Natural Resources of the House
			 of Representatives</cato:entity-ref> by	not later than 180 days after the date of enactment
			 of this Act.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="id95b571f4-d595-49a5-b119-8eb277a4fcbb">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Report</header>
        <paragraph id="idf2904fbd-4711-46b2-87e1-9cfbb498cd68">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>In general</header>
          <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1400">Secretary</cato:entity-ref>, in consultation with the Tribe, shall prepare periodic reports regarding obstacles
			 to consolidating trust land ownership on the Reservation.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="id693f6b23-291f-43d5-acfb-d2de217cf741">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Contents</header>
          <text>The reports under this subsection shall include—</text>
          <subparagraph id="id0111d2d5-d9de-4aa7-a290-4bd891a0f12f">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>a description of existing obstacles to consolidating trust land ownership, including the extent of
			 fractionation;</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="id2cbfe57d-2bb7-487c-90ff-1fec89ea570e">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>a description of progress achieved by the Tribe toward reducing fractionation and increasing trust
			 land ownership;</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="idffdf7327-6b01-4567-bebd-fe6a42ed4dd1">
            <enum>(C)</enum>
            <text>an analysis of progress achieved by the Tribe toward making agricultural use economical on trust
			 land; and</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="ide61dd1cf-8e42-458a-ba0a-87c2cb7675d2">
            <enum>(D)</enum>
            <text>any applicable outcomes and lessons learned from land consolidation activities undertaken pursuant
			 to the <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Indian Land Consolidation Act">Indian Land Consolidation Act</cato:entity-ref> (<cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/25/2201/etseq">25 U.S.C.
		2201 et seq.</cato:entity-ref>)</cato:entity>.</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc01ed688-5d35-4ebb-b73a-bd9431a820bb">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <header>Submission</header>
          <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1400">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall submit the reports under this subsection to the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="SLIA00" entity-type="committee">Committee on Indian Affairs of
			 the Senate</cato:entity-ref> and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="HII00" entity-type="committee">Committee on Natural Resources of the House of
			 Representatives</cato:entity-ref> not less frequently than once each calendar year for the
			 5-year period beginning on the date of enactment of this Act.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
    </section>
    <section changed="added" committee-id="SLIA00" id="id9a6906ff-a7db-4435-8a5a-0f7619abea5e" reported-display-style="italic">
      <enum>8.</enum>
      <header>Eligibility for other Federal benefits</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">The transfer  under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Northern Cheyenne Lands Act/s:6" proposed="true">section 6</cato:entity-ref> shall not result in the reduction or denial of any Federal
			 service, benefit, or program to the Tribe or to any member of the Tribe to
			 which the Tribe or member is entitled or eligible because of—</text>
      <paragraph id="id0519f50d-8c23-4c58-81ee-ea3db1433af0">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text>the status of the Tribe as a federally recognized Indian tribe; or</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id3d5a4fe6-fcdb-4f9f-99b3-452f6173fcf4">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text>the status of the member as a member of the Tribe.</text>
      </paragraph>
    </section>
    <section changed="added" commented="no" committee-id="SLIA00" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb239336f-16df-4d7c-b31f-f87e6b3efb8e" reported-display-style="italic" section-type="subsequent-section">
      <enum>9.</enum>
      <header>Authorization of appropriations</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">
        <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="auth-auth-approp">There are authorized to be appropriated <cato:property name="purpose">to carry out <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Northern Cheyenne Lands Act" proposed="true">this Act</cato:entity-ref>
          </cato:property> <cato:funds-and-year amount="indefinite">such sums as are necessary</cato:funds-and-year>.</cato:entity>
      </text>
    </section>
  </legis-body>
  <endorsement>
    <action-date>August 26, 2014</action-date>
    <action-desc>Reported with an amendment</action-desc>
  </endorsement>
</bill>
</doc>