<doc>
  <docmeta id="113sres298ats">
    <bill congress="113" type="sres" number="298" version="ats"/>
    <revision size="2673" annotations="0" status="complete" id="4" commit-time="2013-12-03T21:38:17Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113sres298ats/4.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <resolution xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print">
  <metadata>
<dublinCore>
<dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">113 SRES 298 ATS: To authorize testimony, documents, and representation in United States v. Allen.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">2013-11-18</dc:date>
<dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code>
    <congress display="yes">113th CONGRESS</congress>
    <session display="yes">1st Session</session>
    <legis-num>S. RES. 298</legis-num>
    <current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
    <action display="yes">
      <action-date date="20131118">November 18, 2013</action-date>
      <action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="S198">Mr. Reid</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S174">Mr. McConnell</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was considered and agreed to</action-desc>
    </action>
    <legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
    <official-title display="yes">To authorize testimony, documents, and representation in <italic>United States v. Allen.</italic>
    </official-title>
  </form>
  <preamble>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas, in the case of <italic>United States v. Allen</italic>, Crim. No. 12–112, pending in the United States District Court for the Middle District of Florida, the prosecution has requested the production of documents and testimony from current and former employees of the offices of Senators Bill Nelson and Marco Rubio;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas, pursuant to <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Ethics in Government Act of 1978/s:703/ss:a">sections 703(a)</cato:entity-ref> and <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Ethics in Government Act of 1978/s:704/ss:a/p:2">704(a)(2) of the Ethics in Government Act of 1978</cato:entity-ref>, <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/2/288b/a">2 U.S.C. §§ 288b(a)</cato:entity-ref> and <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/2/288c/a/2">288c(a)(2)</cato:entity-ref>, the Senate may direct its counsel to represent current and former employees of the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0010">Senate</cato:entity-ref> with respect to any subpoena, order, or request for testimony relating to their official responsibilities;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas, by the privileges of the Senate of the United States and Rule XI of the Standing Rules of the Senate, no evidence under the control or in the possession of the Senate may, by the judicial or administrative process, be taken from such control or possession but by permission of the Senate; and</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas, when it appears that evidence under the control or in the possession of the Senate may promote the administration of justice, the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0010">Senate</cato:entity-ref> will take such action as will promote the ends of justice consistent with the privileges of the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0010">Senate</cato:entity-ref>: Now, therefore, be it</text>
    </whereas>
  </preamble>
  <resolution-body style="traditional">
    <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="S1" section-type="undesignated-section">
      <enum/>
      <text>That Peter Mitchell and Grace Pettus, a current and a former employee, respectively, of the Office of Senator Bill Nelson, and Adele Griffin and Ashley Cook, current employees of the Office of Senator Marco Rubio, and any other current or former employee from either office from whom relevant evidence may be sought, are authorized to produce documents and provide testimony in the case of <italic>United States v. Allen</italic>, except concerning matters for which a privilege should be asserted.</text>
    </section>
    <section id="id20FCE61689BF4A8A895048420964C78D">
      <enum>2.</enum>
      <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" value="Senate Legal Counsel" entity-parent-id="0010">Senate Legal Counsel</cato:entity-ref> is authorized to represent current and former employees of the offices of Senators Nelson and Rubio in connection with the production of evidence authorized in section one of this resolution.</text>
    </section>
  </resolution-body>
</resolution>
</doc>