<doc>
  <docmeta id="113s931is">
    <bill congress="113" type="s" number="931" version="is"/>
    <revision size="9988" annotations="0" status="complete" id="4" commit-time="2013-07-30T21:59:26Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113s931is/4.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" public-private="public">
	<metadata>
<dublinCore>
<title>113 S931 IS: Breast Cancer Patient Education Act of 2013</title>
<publisher>U.S. Senate</publisher>
<date>2013-05-13</date>
<format>text/xml</format>
<language>EN</language>
<rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
		<congress>113th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. 931</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20130513">May 13, 2013</action-date>
			<action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="S342">Mr. Blunt</sponsor> (for himself,
			 <cosponsor name-id="S307">Mr. Brown</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S314">Mr.
			 Tester</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S221">Mrs. Feinstein</cosponsor>)
			 introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the
			 <committee-name committee-id="SSHR00">Committee on Health, Education, Labor,
			 and Pensions</committee-name>
      </action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To amend the Public Health Service Act to raise awareness
		  of, and to educate breast cancer patients anticipating surgery, especially
		  patients who are members of racial and ethnic minority groups, regarding the
		  availability and coverage of breast reconstruction, prostheses, and other
		  options.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="HA585CEFFF2D74C3299F68E039D0B876F" style="OLC">
		<section id="HF57FCCAD4AA446C8995BFF2FF43C7BA5" section-type="section-one">
      <enum>1.</enum>
      <header>Short title</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the
			 <quote>
          <short-title>Breast Cancer Patient Education Act of
			 2013</short-title>
        </quote>.</text>
		</section>
    <section id="H91E2EEF02E8742FAA6BDA8A557588B70">
      <enum>2.</enum>
      <header>Findings</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">
        <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> makes the following
			 findings:</text>
			<paragraph id="H56573DC31A62456499520130DECAD308">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text>The American
			 Cancer Society estimates that in 2013, about 232,340 new cases of breast cancer
			 will be diagnosed in American women.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HF7D4C39BFF0749A58CE11387CD4ED1E8">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text>Breast cancer has
			 a disproportionate and detrimental impact on African-American women and is the
			 most common cancer among Hispanic women.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H14C1E99EF1984B3A8C0000A585B30C56">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <text>African-American
			 women under the age of 40 have a greater incidence of breast cancer than
			 Caucasian women of the same age.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H57B270F23FD14865877D30EEA60CD23E">
        <enum>(4)</enum>
        <text>According to the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7526">Health Resources and Services Administration</cato:entity-ref>, women residing in rural areas may have lower rates of mammography screening compared to non-rural women because of barriers to health care, such as greater distances to medical facilities and lower educational, income, and health insurance levels.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id4871AB25BB6F4CDAB0596BF5D8B0CA06">
        <enum>(5)</enum>
        <text>Individuals
			 undergoing surgery for breast cancer should have the opportunity to give due
			 consideration to the option of breast reconstructive surgery, either at the
			 same time as the breast cancer surgery or at a later date.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HECFDAC11392340E3B7BAA8D3DDB2941E">
        <enum>(6)</enum>
        <text>According to the
			 American Cancer Society, immediate breast reconstruction offers the advantage
			 of combining the breast cancer surgery with the reconstructive surgery and is
			 cost effective, while delayed breast reconstruction may be advantageous in
			 women who require post-surgical radiation or other treatments.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HCA9E032D132A494E95FD4F2303C62564">
        <enum>(7)</enum>
        <text>A
			 woman who has had a breast removed may not be a candidate for surgical breast
			 reconstruction or may choose not to undergo additional surgery and instead
			 choose breast prostheses.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H2AAD3596238046849445833D1BC8B67D">
        <enum>(8)</enum>
        <text>The <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Women’s Health and Cancer Rights Act of 1998">Women’s Health
			 and Cancer Rights Act of 1998</cato:entity-ref> (WHCRA; <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/105/277">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="public-law" value="public-law/105/277">Public Law 105–277</cato:entity-ref>
            </external-xref>)</cato:entity> requires health plans
			 that offer medical and surgical benefits with respect to a mastectomy to also
			 provide coverage for all stages of reconstruction of the breast on which the
			 mastectomy has been performed, surgery and reconstruction of the other breast
			 to produce a symmetrical appearance, prostheses, and physical complications of
			 mastectomy, including lymphedemas.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H4DFEEF9A835745C88CFCC6596954066D">
        <enum>(9)</enum>
        <text>A
			 2007 study by Amy Alderman, M.D. at the University of Michigan reported that up
			 to 70 percent of women eligible for breast reconstruction are not informed of
			 their reconstructive options by their general surgeon.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id857316c4746a49f790555f2c816dec25">
        <enum>(10)</enum>
        <text>A 2003 study by
			 Alderman and others found that race is a significant predictor of
			 reconstruction. Compared with the odds of reconstruction for Caucasians, the
			 odds of reconstruction for African-Americans, Hispanics, and Asians are
			 significantly less.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="idf1dc64fde1b9434b806dd96dd66401cd">
        <enum>(11)</enum>
        <text>A 2007 study by
			 Caprice Greenberg, M.D. of the Dana Farber Cancer Institute and others found
			 that Hispanic patients were less likely to receive reconstruction. This may be
			 because of language barriers between the patient and provider. Although 72
			 percent of patients who primarily spoke English went on to receive
			 reconstruction after discussing it with their providers, no patient in the
			 study with a primary language other than English went on to receive
			 reconstruction.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id3a76c1483bf64b2399322108561c773e">
        <enum>(12)</enum>
        <text>A 2009 study by
			 Alderman and others also found that the relationship between race and
			 reconstruction rates persisted when demographic and clinical factors were
			 controlled for. Minority women are significantly less likely than Caucasians to
			 see a plastic surgeon before initial surgery, were most likely to desire more
			 information about reconstruction, and satisfaction was lowest among minority
			 women without reconstruction.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="idde41f406d2f148428e5232593577e485">
        <enum>(13)</enum>
        <text>The low use of reconstruction for minorities is not explained by lower demand for the procedure. Lower health literacy, financial issues, and less access to plastic surgeons emerged as barriers to reconstruction in the 2009 Alderman study. These results suggest that there is a substantial unmet need for information, especially among racial and ethnic minority groups regarding reconstruction options and coverage required by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Women's Health and Cancer Rights Act of 1998" proposed="true">Women's Health and Cancer Rights Act of 1998</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id9b234f062d4f4cbba22615f5994a9be9">
        <enum>(14)</enum>
        <text>A 2010 study by
			 Warren H. Tseng, M.D. and others at the University of California Davis found
			 that patients from rural areas are less likely to undergo breast reconstruction
			 following mastectomy for breast cancer than their urban counterparts.</text>
			</paragraph>
    </section>
    <section id="H4D34807AE3EE4E0F963499C76995FD7D">
      <enum>3.</enum>
      <header>Breast
			 reconstruction education</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">
        <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
          <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Public Health Service Act/t:III/pt:V">Part
			 V of title III of the Public Health Service Act</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/280m">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/42/280m">42 U.S.C. 280m</cato:entity-ref>
          </external-xref>
        </cato:entity>; programs
			 relating to breast health and cancer) is amended by adding at the end the
			 following:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCDDFD6621D694764BAD8CF7BCB9AFD06" style="OLC">
				<section id="H8F62DD5DB50644A1BB591DECA33F84C3">
          <enum>399NN–1.</enum>
          <header>Breast
				reconstruction education</header>
					<subsection id="H9FA48A2F47274C4D9D2ED70B70213643">
            <enum>(a)</enum>
            <header>In
				general</header>
            <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall provide for the planning and implementation of an education campaign to inform breast cancer patients anticipating surgery regarding the availability and coverage of breast reconstruction, prostheses, and other options, with a focus on informing patients who are members of racial and ethnic minority groups.</text>
					</subsection>
          <subsection id="H4D878E54FB634620BC1DF2002BC22C19">
            <enum>(b)</enum>
            <header>Information To
				Be disseminated</header>
						<paragraph id="H6831072A05494407A318256AA820A846">
              <enum>(1)</enum>
              <header>Specific
				information</header>
              <text>Such campaign shall include dissemination of the
				following information:</text>
							<subparagraph id="HEAB465ACCA4F459889D983AB4479D255">
                <enum>(A)</enum>
                <text>Breast
				reconstruction is possible at the time of breast cancer surgery, or at a later
				time.</text>
							</subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="H1281A4A9FE0147D1AFD15A346977F0A7">
                <enum>(B)</enum>
                <text>Prostheses or
				breast forms may be available.</text>
							</subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="H64D249929D1841A6A61F38B0E52ADD86">
                <enum>(C)</enum>
                <text>Federal law
				mandates both public and private health plans to include coverage of breast
				reconstruction and prostheses.</text>
							</subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="HC88614EA8EF64F46879AF5C4C77EACAA">
                <enum>(D)</enum>
                <text>The patient has a
				right to choose a provider of reconstructive care, including the potential
				transfer of care to a surgeon that provides breast reconstructive care.</text>
							</subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="HCB2AF96903E943EFBAD260F3C74A0CBD">
                <enum>(E)</enum>
                <text>The patient may
				opt to undergo breast reconstruction some time after the time of breast cancer
				surgery for personal or medical reasons, during treatment or after completion
				of all other breast cancer treatments.</text>
							</subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="H85995DC6758740BA95F677ACC53F0126">
              <enum>(2)</enum>
              <header>Other
				information</header>
              <text>In addition to the information described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Public Health Service Act/s:399NN–1/ss:b/p:1" proposed="true">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref>, such campaign may include dissemination of such other information (whether developed by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> or by other entities) as the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> determines relevant.</text>
						</paragraph>
            <paragraph id="idC6AE172B7FF14D01A376D51FB5CC3CCC">
              <enum>(3)</enum>
              <header>Required
				publication</header>
              <text>The information required to be disseminated under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Public Health Service Act/s:399NN–1/ss:b/p:1" proposed="true">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref> and any information disseminated in accordance with <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Public Health Service Act/s:399NN–1/ss:b/p:2" proposed="true">paragraph (2)</cato:entity-ref> shall be posted on the Internet Web sites of relevant Federal agencies, including the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Office of Women’s Health, the Office of Minority Health" entity-parent-id="7500">Office of Women’s Health, the Office of Minority Health</cato:entity-ref>, and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Office of Rural Health Policy" entity-parent-id="7500">Office of Rural Health Policy</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
						</paragraph>
            <paragraph id="HA61B6D647F3649F08B657E60352A3E15">
              <enum>(4)</enum>
              <header>Restriction</header>
              <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Such campaign shall not specify, or be
				designed to serve as a tool to limit, the health care providers available to
				patients.</text>
						</paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection id="HD6B4F2CB6A224612BC7382CC5F6A01DE">
            <enum>(c)</enum>
            <header>Consultation</header>
            <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In developing the information to be disseminated under this section, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall consult with appropriate medical societies and patient advocates related to breast cancer, breast reconstructive surgery, breast prostheses, and breast forms and with patient advocates representing racial and ethnic minority groups with a special emphasis on African-American and Hispanic populations.</text>
					</subsection>
          <subsection id="idA587F12526994774906C221E192D3117">
            <enum>(d)</enum>
            <header>Definitions</header>
            <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the terms <term>racial and ethnic minority group</term> and <term>Hispanic</term> have the meanings given such terms in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Public Health Service Act/s:1707">section 1707</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
					</subsection>
          <subsection id="id9E1917C89337418F99F5AA53570B2E2B">
            <enum>(e)</enum>
            <header>Report</header>
            <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 2 years after date of enactment of the <short-title>
                <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Breast Cancer Patient Education Act of 2013" proposed="true">Breast Cancer Patient Education Act of 2013</cato:entity-ref>
              </short-title> and every 2 years thereafter, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall submit to the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="committee" entity-id="SSHR00">Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate</cato:entity-ref> and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="committee" entity-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives</cato:entity-ref> a report describing the activities carried out under this section during the preceding 2 fiscal years, which shall include an evaluation of the extent to which such activities have been effective in improving the health and well-being of racial and ethnic minority groups.</text>
					</subsection>
        </section>
        <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
      </quoted-block>
		</section>
  </legis-body>
</bill>
</doc>