<doc>
  <docmeta id="113sres497ats">
    <bill congress="113" type="sres" number="497" version="ats"/>
    <revision size="3642" annotations="0" status="complete" id="4" commit-time="2014-08-27T18:34:01Z" committer="mnewby" doc="113sres497ats/4.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <resolution xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print">
	<metadata>
<dublinCore>
<dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">113 SRES 497 ATS: Honoring the life and career of Charles “Chuck” Noll. </dc:title>
<dc:publisher xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">2014-07-09</dc:date>
<dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">113th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session display="yes">2d Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. RES. 497</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20140709">July 9, 2014</action-date>
			<action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="S351">Mr. Toomey</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S309">Mr. Casey</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was considered and agreed to</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">Honoring the life and career of Charles <quote>Chuck</quote> Noll. </official-title>
	</form>
	<preamble>
		<whereas>
      <text>Whereas Chuck Noll was born on January 5, 1932, in Cleveland, Ohio;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas Chuck Noll excelled at multiple positions on the football field during a preparatory 
			 career at
			 Benedictine High School in Cleveland, Ohio and during a college career at
			 the University of Dayton;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas, after being drafted in the 20<superscript>th</superscript> round of the 1953 National Football League Draft by his hometown team, the Cleveland Browns, Chuck
			 Noll enjoyed a 7-year career as a linebacker and offensive lineman;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas, after his playing career ended, Chuck Noll joined coaching staffs headed by 2 future
			 Hall-of-Famers, including Sid Gillman of the San Diego Chargers;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas, after serving as an assistant coach for nearly a decade, Chuck Noll was selected by the
			 Rooney family to serve as 14<superscript>th</superscript> head coach of the Pittsburgh Steelers football team on January 27, 1969;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the current owner of the Pittsburgh Steelers is quoted as saying <quote>hiring Chuck Noll was the best decision we ever made for the Steelers</quote>;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas, in 1972, in Chuck Noll’s fourth season as head coach of the Pittsburgh Steelers, the
			 Pittsburgh Steelers won 11 games and made the
			 playoffs for the first time since 1947;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas, on January 12, 1975, the Pittsburgh Steelers dynasty was born when Chuck Noll led the
			 Pittsburgh Steelers to a victory over the Minnesota Vikings to win Super
			 Bowl IX—the first of the Pittsburgh Steelers' now 6 Super Bowl titles;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas, over the 5 football seasons after winning Super Bowl IX, Chuck Noll’s Pittsburgh Steelers
			 went on to capture an
			 additional 3 Super Bowl titles—Super Bowl X and XIII, both by defeating
			 the
			 Dallas Cowboys, and Super Bowl XIV, by defeating the Los Angeles Rams;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas Chuck Noll is best known for masterminding the <quote>Steel Curtain</quote>, one of the most stout and prolific defensive units in National Football League history;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas both Chuck Noll’s ability to identify talent and his hands-on coaching technique led to
			 Hall of Fame careers for more than 10 of Chuck Noll's players;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas, following 23 football seasons and 193 football game wins, including a record 4 Super Bowl
			 titles as a head coach of the Pittsburgh Steelers, Chuck Noll was
			 enshrined in the Pro Football Hall of Fame in Canton, Ohio as part of the
			 Class of 1993; and</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas, on June 13, 2014, Chuck Noll passed away surrounded by loved ones at his home in
			 Sewickley, Pennsylvania at the age of 82: Now, therefore, be it</text>
		</whereas>
  </preamble>
	<resolution-body>
		<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="S1" section-type="undesignated-section">
      <enum/>
      <text>That  the <cato:entity-ref entity-id="0010" entity-type="federal-body">Senate</cato:entity-ref>—</text>
      <paragraph id="id52916fd0c3264d5f84cccfb7aecd2ede">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text>recognizes the life and career of Chuck Noll and his contributions to the city of Pittsburgh,
			 Pennsylvania and the National Football League; and</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="idC8B2569A8D9C4768B722C47D415DBA5C">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text>expresses its sympathies to Chuck Noll's family and friends, the Pittsburgh Steelers, Steelers
			 fans, and football fans all around the world.</text>
      </paragraph>
    </section>
  </resolution-body>
</resolution>
</doc>