<doc>
  <docmeta id="113sres104is">
    <bill congress="113" type="sres" number="104" version="is"/>
    <revision size="4922" annotations="0" status="complete" id="5" commit-time="2013-07-16T16:50:49Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113sres104is/5.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <resolution xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution">
	<metadata>
<dublinCore>
<title>113 SRES 104 IS: Supporting the goals and ideals of National Youth HIV ? AIDS Awareness Day.</title>
<publisher>U.S. Senate</publisher>
<date>2013-04-22</date>
<format>text/xml</format>
<language>EN</language>
<rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code>
		<congress>113th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. RES. 104</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20130422">April 22, 2013</action-date>
			<action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="S341">Mr. Blumenthal</sponsor> (for
			 himself, <cosponsor name-id="S306">Mr. Menendez</cosponsor>,
			 <cosponsor name-id="S307">Mr. Brown</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S166">Mr. Lautenberg</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution;
			 which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSHR00">Committee on
			 Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions</committee-name>
      </action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">Supporting the goals and ideals of National
		  Youth HIV &amp; AIDS Awareness Day.</official-title>
	</form>
	<preamble>
		<whereas>
      <text>Whereas, more than 30 years into the epidemic, the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7523">Centers
			 for Disease Control and Prevention</cato:entity-ref> estimates that in the United States more
			 than 1,100,000 people are living with HIV, and every year approximately 50,000
			 people acquire HIV;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas 1 in 4 new HIV infections occurs among young
			 people between the ages of 13 and 24, accounting for approximately 1,000 new
			 cases every month;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas 60 percent of HIV positive youth do not know that
			 they carry the HIV virus;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas there are approximately 76,400 young people living
			 with HIV;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas African-American youth bear a disproportionate
			 burden of the epidemic, representing 60 percent of new infections in young
			 people;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas new HIV infections among 13- to 29-year-old
			 African-American men who have sex with men increased 48 percent from 2006 to
			 2009;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" value="Division of Adolescent and School Health" entity-parent-id="7523">Division of Adolescent and School Health</cato:entity-ref> is
			 the only Federal program supporting HIV prevention for adolescents in
			 schools;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the largest Federal program dedicated to providing
			 care and treatment for people living with HIV was named after Ryan White, a
			 teenager from Indiana who helped educate the people of the United States about
			 HIV and AIDS in the 1980s;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the Ryan White Part D Program is one of the
			 national efforts to link HIV positive youth to medical care and support
			 services;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the <cato:entity entity-type="law-citation">
          <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act">Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act</cato:entity-ref> (<cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/42/18001/etseq">42
			 U.S.C. 18001 et seq.</cato:entity-ref>)</cato:entity> includes many provisions that benefit young people and
			 help achieve the goal of an AIDS-free generation, including funding for sex
			 education to help ensure that every young person in the United States is
			 educated about HIV/AIDS, a prohibition against denying people living with HIV
			 access to health care, HIV testing for women without a co-pay, and expanded
			 access to Medicaid which will help more HIV-positive youth receive care;
			 and</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas April 10 of each year is now recognized as
			 National Youth HIV &amp; AIDS Awareness Day: Now, therefore, be it</text>
		</whereas>
  </preamble>
	<resolution-body>
		<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HD79D17573B734AB5942EF78C1AC7A076" section-type="undesignated-section">
      <enum/>
      <text>That the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0010">Senate</cato:entity-ref>—</text>
			<paragraph id="H31AEE38295454885B98E9A303B84E2D1">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">supports the goals and ideals of National
			 Youth HIV &amp; AIDS Awareness Day;</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HE195B4DD7D814BC3A5DFC1E3C66E9113">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text>encourages State
			 and local governments, including public health agencies, education agencies,
			 schools, and media organizations to recognize and support such a day;</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H4B1C4E66AE054F0787FB204A3F95C977">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <text>promotes effective
			 and comprehensive HIV prevention education programs both in and out of schools
			 as a tool to ensure that all people in the United States are educated about
			 HIV, as called for in the National HIV/AIDS Strategy;</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H1C706F7790D64F2B9CDE92278EF7660E">
        <enum>(4)</enum>
        <text>urges
			 youth-friendly and accessible health care services to better provide for the
			 early identification of HIV through voluntary routine testing, and to connect
			 those in need to clinically and culturally appropriate care and treatment as
			 early as possible;</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H765D7C090CC74A2FB4BED4DC29482E6E">
        <enum>(5)</enum>
        <text>commends the work
			 of AIDS service organizations, community and faith-based organizations, and
			 school-based health centers that are providing youth-friendly and effective
			 prevention, treatment, care, and support services to young people living with
			 and vulnerable to HIV/AIDS;</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HFA48330EE2504C0C9A530B2BEAE2B8EE">
        <enum>(6)</enum>
        <text>recognizes the
			 importance of interventions that address structural barriers faced by young
			 people to living healthy lives, including accessible health care, safe and
			 inclusive schools and communities, family acceptance, secure housing, excellent
			 education, employment and legal protections, and poverty reduction initiatives;
			 and</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H53D15EBB206C455AB415BCA69F3C0AC2">
        <enum>(7)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">prioritizes youth leadership and
			 development in order to ensure the involvement of youths in decisions that
			 impact their health and well-being and to provide the next generation of
			 HIV/AIDS doctors, advocates, educators, researchers, and other professionals,
			 as a necessary means to achieving an AIDS-free generation.</text>
			</paragraph>
    </section>
  </resolution-body>
</resolution>
</doc>