<doc>
  <docmeta id="113sres492ats">
    <bill congress="113" type="sres" number="492" version="ats"/>
    <revision size="2846" annotations="0" status="complete" id="4" commit-time="2014-08-15T20:41:04Z" committer="mnewby" doc="113sres492ats/4.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <resolution xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print">
	<metadata>
<dublinCore>
<dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">113 SRES 492 ATS: Congratulating “A Prairie Home Companion” on its 40 years of engaging, humorous, and quality radio programming. </dc:title>
<dc:publisher xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">2014-06-26</dc:date>
<dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">113th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session display="yes">2d Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. RES. 492</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20140626">June 26, 2014</action-date>
			<action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="S311">Ms. Klobuchar</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="S332">Mr. Franken</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was considered and agreed to</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">Congratulating <quote>A Prairie Home Companion</quote> on its 40 years of engaging, humorous, and quality radio programming. </official-title>
	</form>
	<preamble>
		<whereas>
      <text>Whereas, for 40 years, <quote>A Prairie Home Companion</quote> has brought listeners from around the country to the fantastic town of Lake Wobegon, Minnesota;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas, in 2014, <quote>A Prairie Home Companion</quote> is a 2 hour radio variety program performed live that airs on	Saturday afternoons ;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas over 600 radio stations carry <quote>A Prairie Home Companion</quote> to 4,000,000 listeners each week;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas <quote>A Prairie Home Companion</quote>  was created by and is hosted by a Grammy Award winner who received the award in 1998 for  <quote>Lake Wobegon Days</quote>;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas 12 people were in the audience for the first broadcast of <quote>A Prairie Home Companion</quote> on July 6, 1974, at the Janet Wallace Auditorium at Macalester College in Saint Paul, Minnesota;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas, in 2014, <quote>A Prairie Home Companion</quote> is broadcast from the Fitzgerald Theater in Saint Paul, Minnesota, a historic building that is
			 over 100 years old and was named after United States citizen and author F.
			 Scott Fitzgerald;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas <quote>A Prairie Home Companion</quote> has won a Peabody Award;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas <quote>A Prairie Home Companion</quote> has broadcast from Canada, Ireland, Scotland, England, Germany, Iceland, and nearly every State in
			 the United States;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas <quote>A Prairie Home Companion</quote> inspired a movie by the same name, which itself won 4 international awards; and</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas in Lake Wobegon all the women are strong, all the men are good looking, and all the
			 children are above average: Now, therefore, be it</text>
		</whereas>
  </preamble>
	<resolution-body>
		<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="S1" section-type="undesignated-section">
      <enum/>
      <text>That the <cato:entity-ref entity-id="0010" entity-type="federal-body">Senate</cato:entity-ref>—</text>
			<paragraph id="idEBE84CF09E6D429A8E3884AC6BF2648A">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text>congratulates—</text>
        <subparagraph id="id591BCCFDE62F41D994FAE864D2DF63CD">
          <enum>(A)</enum>
          <text>the cast and crew of  <quote>A Prairie Home Companion</quote> for 40 years of engaging, humorous, and quality radio programming; and</text>
        </subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="idA570C1C970B94C0C8858BD0CCC0C8594">
          <enum>(B)</enum>
          <text>Minnesota Public Radio and American Public Media for bringing <quote>A Prairie Home Companion</quote> into the homes of millions for 40 years; and</text>
        </subparagraph>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="ida3cdd1af678e4b1a805dbe8d0d82e681">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text>directs the <cato:entity-ref entity-id="0010" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of the Senate</cato:entity-ref> to transmit an enrolled copy of this resolution to the creator
			 and host of  <quote>A Prairie Home Companion</quote>.</text>
      </paragraph>
    </section>
  </resolution-body>
</resolution>
</doc>