<doc>
  <docmeta id="113s2508rs">
    <bill congress="113" type="s" number="2508" version="rs"/>
    <revision size="64845" annotations="0" status="complete" id="6" commit-time="2014-08-07T22:04:00Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113s2508rs/6.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <bill bill-stage="Reported-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public">
  <metadata>
<dublinCore>
<dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">113 S2508 RS: Energize Africa Act of 2014</dc:title>
<dc:publisher xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">2014-06-19</dc:date>
<dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
    <calendar>Calendar No. 489</calendar>
    <congress>113th CONGRESS</congress>
    <session>2d Session</session>
    <legis-num>S. 2508</legis-num>
    <associated-doc role="report">[Report No. 113–219]</associated-doc>
    <current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
    <action>
      <action-date date="20140619">June 19, 2014</action-date>
      <action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="S306">Mr. Menendez</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S310">Mr. Corker</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S337">Mr. Coons</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S305">Mr. Isakson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S369">Mr. Markey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S321">Mr. Johanns</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S308">Mr. Cardin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S324">Mrs. Shaheen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S332">Mr. Franken</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S253">Mr. Durbin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S311">Ms. Klobuchar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S293">Mr. Graham</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S342">Mr. Blunt</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S284">Ms. Stabenow</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S325">Mr. Udall of Colorado</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S275">Ms. Cantwell</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations</committee-name>
      </action-desc>
    </action>
    <action stage="Reported-in-Senate">
      <action-date>July 24, 2014</action-date>
      <action-desc>Reported by <sponsor name-id="S306">Mr. Menendez</sponsor>, with amendments and an amendment to the title</action-desc>
      <action-instruction>Omit the part struck through and insert the part printed in italic</action-instruction>
    </action>
    <legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
    <official-title>To establish a comprehensive United States Government policy to assist countries in sub-Saharan
			 Africa to improve access to and the affordability, reliability, and
			 sustainability of power, and for other purposes. </official-title>
  </form>
  <legis-body>
    <section id="S1" section-type="section-one">
      <enum>1.</enum>
      <header>Short title; table of contents</header>
      <subsection id="idA67E2009A9084782B2374B286EE30DE3">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Short title</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the
		  <quote>
            <short-title>
              <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Energize Africa Act of 2014" proposed="true">Energize Africa Act of 2014</cato:entity-ref>
            </short-title>
          </quote>.</text>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="idB5A14488222F447B809B20D24127A99C">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Table of contents</header>
        <text>The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text>
        <toc>
          <toc-entry idref="S1" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title; table of contents.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="id9627566507db4fb580a112770767bc74" level="section">Sec. 2. Findings.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="id85a476c7d71e4821873783254c87dcc2" level="title">TITLE I—Policies to improve access to power in sub-Saharan Africa</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="id8b4e5e7e489b42ac8e8bb9f4eb4017c1" level="section">Sec. 101. Purpose.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="id452e512757e54769a2b9df75771a6c8e" level="section">Sec. 102. Statement of policy.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="id2d6d426c26044046bbe094cb9fa5bf25" level="section">Sec. 103. Development of comprehensive, multiyear strategy.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="id4fb2bf5c3f3d47baac5e10e17e23692f" level="section">Sec. 104. Sense of Congress on priorities with respect the energy sector of sub-Saharan African
			 countries.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="id23c6e92441064235b3aec4e3c19728a1" level="section">Sec. 105. Prioritization of assistance for power projects in sub-Saharan Africa by the United
			 States Agency for International Development.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="id95961c6f49c14cafb47e0412a17e79d3" level="section">Sec. 106. Prioritization of assistance for power projects in sub-Saharan Africa by the Trade and
			 Development Agency.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="id4a34d3d94419491d98d49060b334d5dc" level="section">Sec. 107. Prioritization of assistance for power projects in sub-Saharan Africa by the Overseas
			 Private Investment Corporation.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="id74dad20e07404e6fba407a998592bbf7" level="section">Sec. 108. Prioritization of assistance for power projects in sub-Saharan Africa by the World Bank
			 Group and the African Development Bank.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="id31ff378ca59245d8800684ecf061c8be" level="section">Sec. 109. Prioritization of assistance for power projects in sub-Saharan Africa by the United
			 States African Development Foundation.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="idfd862f2a96c549c588910075101e1370" level="section">
            <added-phrase reported-display-style="italic">Sec. 110. Prioritization of assistance for power projects in sub-Saharan Africa by the Millennium
			 Challenge Corporation.</added-phrase>
          </toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="idbfdf2ff7639e467bbc739ba266a1dcde" level="section">Sec. <deleted-phrase reported-display-style="strikethrough">110</deleted-phrase>
            <added-phrase reported-display-style="italic">111</added-phrase>. Progress report.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="id49437A2CEDEC487980F3D03AC39CE06A" level="title">TITLE II—Overseas Private Investment Corporation</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="id09fb35e5fe0e463c9460f9c0106114da" level="section">Sec. 201. Extension of issuing authority.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="id30ade47d05e64ee4b830a6144e80e5bb" level="section">Sec. 202. Expedited procedures for financing of small projects related to power generation and
			 distribution in sub-Saharan Africa.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="id600509f227074823b8992fd501fc3eba" level="section">Sec. 203. Activities in sub-Saharan Africa; investment advisory council.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="idaf085493d0124363b82cd650f8309c9a" level="section">Sec. 204. Pilot program for expansion of eligible investors.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="id25730c4d65fb4c5684cbf144ae9c66fa" level="section">Sec. 205. Pilot program for direct investment and local currency guaranties for power projects in
			 sub-Saharan Africa.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="idd0ecb0f146514e6080b3b35e9778cf47" level="section">Sec. 206. Extension of maximum term of obligation for renewable energy projects in sub-Saharan
			 Africa.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="idFFDCB93792CB4B17B7B2FCDD6BA60053" level="section">Sec. 207. Inspector General.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="id210dc1d4a6a74d76a77c350e4ab705ab" level="section">Sec. 208. Assessment of customer satisfaction.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="id6734e35f7650434d8086fdc82305f8c0" level="section">Sec. 209. Schedule B hiring authority.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="ide4125a555d9c4aadb65ac20e9c6b4512" level="section">Sec. 210. Sense of Congress on funding.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="id264565cc743744a9bca7fed0e89457c3" level="section">Sec. 211. Report on equity authority.</toc-entry>
				</toc>
      </subsection>
    </section>
    <section id="id9627566507db4fb580a112770767bc74">
      <enum>2.</enum>
      <header>Findings</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">
        <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> makes the following findings:</text>
      <paragraph id="id932189251e7e473abf657b78706f7fff">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text>As of 2010, approximately 589,000,000 people in sub-Saharan Africa, or 68 percent of the
			 population, did not have access to power.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id1de2e1cfedbb4d96aaeeb5c6a3c0c436">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text>Lack of access to power services disproportionally affects women, who often shoulder the burden of
			 seeking sources of heat and light such as dung, wood, or charcoal and are
			 often more exposed to the associated negative health effects.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id8cb0169ebac44675ba45e2645dfe72ac">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <text>Women and girls also face increased risks of assault from walking long distances to gather fuel
			 sources.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id50ca6da8b86842349b5ebcfe51f6299b">
        <enum>(4)</enum>
        <text>Access to power creates opportunities for people to work their way out of poverty, including
			 through entrepreneurship.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id400c5c36e505471dbad72c0e5e0d7bd5">
        <enum>(5)</enum>
        <text>A lack of power contributes to the high use of inefficient and often highly polluting fuel sources
			 for indoor cooking, heating, and lighting that produce toxic fumes
			 resulting in more than 3,000,000 annual premature deaths from respiratory
			 disease.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id9a55ef1bee2d48178fac7dc05028b275">
        <enum>(6)</enum>
        <text>Reliable access to power is crucial for the storage of vaccines and antiretroviral and other
			 lifesaving medical drugs, as well as for the operation of modern
			 lifesaving medical equipment.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="idab694c744a7149b48ac1d095cda365f6">
        <enum>(7)</enum>
        <text>Access to power can be used to improve food security by enabling post-harvest processing, pumping,
			 irrigation, dry grain storage, milling, and refrigeration, and for other
			 uses.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id5970f23291fe4857b2177d108ecdee4b">
        <enum>(8)</enum>
        <text>Access to power can provide improved information and communication technologies that can greatly
			 improve health and education outcomes as well as economic and commercial
			 opportunities.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id0c69cb2fd5de4df79e410d27bcfdd7ee">
        <enum>(9)</enum>
        <text>For the majority of people with access to power in sub-Saharan Africa, power services are highly
			 unreliable and remain at least twice as expensive compared to other
			 emerging regions.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id6326da41115846c8b48113b95487ccd1">
        <enum>(10)</enum>
        <text>According to Enterprise Surveys of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="11DR" entity-type="federal-body">World Bank</cato:entity-ref>, power cuts in sub-Saharan Africa cost companies
			 more than 10 percent of sales in certain countries.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="idf290961fd632483285c302b8c4895a11">
        <enum>(11)</enum>
        <text>The consumer base in sub-Saharan Africa of approximately 1,000,000,000 people is rapidly growing
			 and will create increasing demand for United States goods, services, and
			 technologies, but the current power deficit in sub-Saharan Africa limits
			 that growth in demand by restricting economic growth on the continent of
			 Africa.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="ida15e7288a3f1492dbd12a8a287d2dbd0">
        <enum>(12)</enum>
        <text>Approximately 30 countries in sub-Saharan Africa face endemic power shortages, and nearly 70
			 percent of surveyed businesses in sub-Saharan Africa cite unreliable power
			 as a major constraint to growth.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="idce2949822a604ac58bb8f7cf1bdb649c">
        <enum>(13)</enum>
        <text>The work of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="9543" entity-type="federal-body">Millennium Challenge Corporation</cato:entity-ref> in the energy sector shows high projected economic
			 rates of returns that translate to sustainable economic growth and the
			 highest returns are projected when infrastructure improvements are coupled
			 with significant legislative, policy, and regulatory reforms and
			 institutional strengthening.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id7c408ca1389b477899d80f95497d5fc0">
        <enum>(14)</enum>
        <text>Sub-Saharan Africa has abundant renewable and fossil fuel resources with which to generate power.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="idcd36a9ffbde14229bc81478a91c1d244">
        <enum>(15)</enum>
        <text>In some countries in sub-Saharan Africa, weak governance capacity, undue regulatory barriers, and
			 unnecessary legal constraints, as well as a lack of transparency and
			 accountability, stifle the ability of public and private investment to
			 assist in the generation and distribution of power.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id7372d25fafff4531b4aba4f71aa739f7">
        <enum>(16)</enum>
        <text>Without new policies and more effective public and private investments in power sector enterprises
			 to increase and expand access to power in sub-Saharan Africa, more than 70
			 percent of the rural population, and 48 percent of the total population,
			 are likely to remain without access to power through at least 2030.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id52d2d2a53ac545b8b400dbc4e0f8f4e3">
        <enum>(17)</enum>
        <text>Consumers in sub-Saharan Africa spend billions of dollars annually on kerosene and other fuels for
			 household needs, which can, for poor families, represent more than 15
			 percent of household income and can expose residents to significant fire
			 and toxicity risks.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id246f1c5fb3224731b9ebd5651d3d537f">
        <enum>(18)</enum>
        <text>Kerosene lamps used in homes can cause fires and severe burn injuries and expose users to hazardous
			 air pollutants in close quarters, and switching from fuel-based lighting
			 to
			 cheaper, cleaner systems would
			 provide higher quality light with no negative health effects while
			 achieving significant economic savings.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id55f37aab544942e385d3346957d7acaf">
        <enum>(19)</enum>
        <text>New technological advances in power generation coupled with more efficient appliances are resulting
			 in robust, affordable, and non-polluting off-grid power solutions and
			 entrepreneurs are developing new business models allowing off-grid
			 households to finance systems over time, resulting in
			 a rapidly growing off-grid power market.</text>
      </paragraph>
    </section>
    <title id="id85a476c7d71e4821873783254c87dcc2">
      <enum>I</enum>
      <header>Policies to improve access to power in sub-Saharan Africa</header>
      <section id="id8b4e5e7e489b42ac8e8bb9f4eb4017c1">
        <enum>101.</enum>
        <header>Purpose</header>
        <text display-inline="no-display-inline">The purpose of this title is to <deleted-phrase reported-display-style="strikethrough">assist</deleted-phrase>
          <added-phrase reported-display-style="italic">encourage the efforts of</added-phrase> countries in sub-Saharan Africa to improve access to
			 affordable and reliable power in order to unlock the potential for
			 economic growth and promote development, job creation, food security,
			 improved health, educational, and environmental outcomes, and reduce
			 poverty.</text>
      </section>
      <section id="id452e512757e54769a2b9df75771a6c8e">
        <enum>102.</enum>
        <header>Statement of policy</header>
        <text display-inline="no-display-inline">
          <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> declares that it is the policy of the United States to partner, consult, and coordinate
			 with the governments of sub-Saharan African countries, international
			 financial institutions, African regional economic communities, and the
			 private sector, in a concerted effort to—</text>
        <paragraph id="id04df30446eae4e26a32f64b93f8b54f0">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>promote first-time access to power and power services for at least 50,000,000 people in sub-Saharan
			 Africa by 2020 in both urban and rural areas;</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="id32dfad2aaee446b59351498caeb2d28d">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>encourage the installation of at least 20,000 additional megawatts of electrical power in
			 sub-Saharan Africa by 2020 using a broad mix of energy options to help
			 reduce poverty, promote sustainable development, and drive economic
			 growth;</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="id0eb5454eced841c4a5eafbb53118415b">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <text>promote reliable, affordable, and sustainable power in urban areas (including small urban areas) to
			 promote economic growth and job creation;</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="id99f9dfe6bf1d40bb8893138e42e11b31">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
          <text>promote efficient institutional platforms and financing to provide electrical service to rural and
			 underserved populations;</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="id9b67ce9aed334e569112aac4e5a76160">
          <enum>(5)</enum>
          <text>encourage the necessary in-country reforms to make such expansion of power access possible;</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="id35061f1d32b7451d91a504043eb942e2">
          <enum>(6)</enum>
          <text>promote reforms of power production, delivery, and pricing, as well as regulatory reforms and
			 transparency, to support long-term, market-based power generation and
			 distribution; <deleted-phrase reported-display-style="strikethrough">and</deleted-phrase>
          </text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="ida08d3ab7ba2d43e4937a28388a289642">
          <enum>(7)</enum>
          <text>promote policies to displace kerosene lighting with other technologies<deleted-phrase reported-display-style="strikethrough">.</deleted-phrase>
            <added-phrase reported-display-style="italic">; and</added-phrase>
          </text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph changed="added" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6C85F1FA28584A9BBA1B6A1CD6F9A499" reported-display-style="italic">
          <enum>(8)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">promote an all-of-the-above energy development strategy for sub-Saharan Africa that includes the
			 use of oil, natural gas, coal, hydroelectric, wind, solar, and geothermal
			 power, and other sources of
			 energy.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </section>
      <section id="id2d6d426c26044046bbe094cb9fa5bf25">
        <enum>103.</enum>
        <header>Development of comprehensive, multiyear strategy</header>
        <subsection id="id278925448f5c432ba5be103a812778e7">
          <enum>(a)</enum>
          <header>Strategy required</header>
          <paragraph id="idb4641bebb13e4eca97a997f42bcf2088">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <header>In general</header>
            <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> shall establish a comprehensive, integrated, multiyear strategy to <deleted-phrase reported-display-style="strikethrough">assist</deleted-phrase>
              <added-phrase reported-display-style="italic"> encourage the efforts of</added-phrase> countries
			 in sub-Saharan Africa to implement national power strategies and develop
			 an appropriate mix of power solutions, including renewable energy, to
			 provide access to sufficient reliable, affordable, and sustainable power
			 in order to reduce poverty and drive economic growth and job creation.</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="iddde55150e5064687b2675bb6a4d7fe26">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <header>Flexibility and responsiveness</header>
            <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> shall ensure that the strategy required by <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Energize Africa Act of 2014/s:103/ss:a/p:1" proposed="true">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref> maintains sufficient
			 flexibility for and remains responsive to technological innovation in the
			 power sector.</text>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="idbb344fdf7316462e884552b87822ea6e">
          <enum>(b)</enum>
          <header>Report required</header>
          <text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> shall submit to
			 the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="SSFR00" entity-type="committee">Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate</cato:entity-ref> and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="HFA00" entity-type="committee">Committee on
			 Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives</cato:entity-ref> a report that contains the
			 strategy required by <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Energize Africa Act of 2014/s:103/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref> and includes a discussion of the
			 following elements:</text>
          <paragraph id="id527a1da403d74d409fd0fae31e34f89f">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <text>The general and specific objectives of the strategy.</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="id5b334588b92446d0a85354f98d1e6e08">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <text>The criteria for determining the success of the strategy.</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="idf5c3c6a3071840a29e9477335560852c">
            <enum>(3)</enum>
            <text>A description of the manner in which the strategy will support efforts of countries <deleted-phrase reported-display-style="strikethrough">receiving
			 assistance pursuant to the strategy</deleted-phrase>
              <added-phrase reported-display-style="italic">in sub-Saharan Africa</added-phrase> to improve access to power using a
			 broad mix of energy options and improve the affordability and reliability
			 of power in sub-Saharan Africa.</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="idbb3aa3bbaf924b37a6c16f997bdae085">
            <enum>(4)</enum>
            <text>A general description of regional and country plans and significant local efforts, as appropriate,
			 in sub-Saharan Africa to—</text>
            <subparagraph id="id59ed9a6e21b343479d3c99401cfa74f6">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>increase power production;</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="id32f7f5ff9e854acaae4925741560770c">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>strengthen electrical transmission and distribution infrastructure;</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="idc6be048c7fbb4eb897c5b9a93f2771e2">
              <enum>(C)</enum>
              <text>provide for regulatory reform and transparent and accountable governance and oversight;</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="id9bd33d7adca3416a96214a8a09dd6083">
              <enum>(D)</enum>
              <text>improve the reliability of power;</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="ide8d9fcdbc7f8425e8f57181b4e4d2c56">
              <enum>(E)</enum>
              <text>maintain the affordability of power;</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="id10099f11a6e24915afbaa9deac37e617">
              <enum>(F)</enum>
              <text>maximize the financial sustainability of the power sector; and</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="id69bea2b138614a95b9e568b6f654ed38">
              <enum>(G)</enum>
              <text>improve access to power.</text>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="id63080a7aac774623ab8d44a01ebb185f">
            <enum>(5)</enum>
            <text>A description of plans to support efforts of countries <deleted-phrase reported-display-style="strikethrough">receiving assistance pursuant to the
			 strategy</deleted-phrase>
							<deleted-phrase reported-display-style="strikethrough"/>
              <added-phrase reported-display-style="italic">in sub-Saharan Africa</added-phrase> to increase access to power in urban and rural areas, including a
			 description of plans designed to address commercial, industrial, and
			 residential needs.</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="id78c6cce60eb74478ad4c00c34df90a83">
            <enum>(6)</enum>
            <text>A description of plans to support efforts of such countries to reduce waste and corruption and
			 improve existing power generation through the use of a broad power mix,
			 including fossil fuel and renewable energy, distributed generation models,
			 and other technological innovations, as appropriate.</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="id7a73fd2dd14d4f738cd1f31446137e4d">
            <enum>(7)</enum>
            <text>An analysis of existing mechanisms for ensuring, and recommendations to promote—</text>
            <subparagraph id="id2358ff956c0d41e9b46d7150040cbedf">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>commercial cost recovery <deleted-phrase reported-display-style="strikethrough">in countries receiving assistance</deleted-phrase>
                <deleted-phrase reported-display-style="strikethrough"> pursuant to the strategy</deleted-phrase>;</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="id8680d881ec334fcaa7e427079e2850d6">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>commercialization of electric service through distribution service providers to consumers;</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="idf5c2e3c87769472d96744e76482a89b4">
              <enum>(C)</enum>
              <text>improvements in revenue cycle management, power pricing, and fees assessed for service contracts
			 and connections;</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="ide7d47f40f7464285a3784bc1f2454b34">
              <enum>(D)</enum>
              <text>reductions in technical losses in the transmission systems and commercial losses resulting from
			 inefficiencies, including inefficiencies in the billing and collection
			 cycle, theft, and manipulation of meter reading and billing systems; and</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="idb397a2bb918548c9ae624266cab3866e">
              <enum>(E)</enum>
              <text>access to power, including recommendations on the creation of new service provider models that
			 mobilize community participation in the provision of power services.</text>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="id3c569251aff74449bb540dcf2caea859">
            <enum>(8)</enum>
            <text>A description of United States Government efforts to support the efforts of countries <deleted-phrase reported-display-style="strikethrough">receiving
			 assistance pursuant to the
			 strategy</deleted-phrase>
              <added-phrase reported-display-style="italic"> in sub-Saharan Africa</added-phrase> to leverage private sector resources and public sector financing
			 pursuant to the strategy.</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="idb282642af52e4f29a0a56b9e03fcbebd">
            <enum>(9)</enum>
            <text>A description of the reforms being undertaken or planned by countries in sub-Saharan Africa to
			 ensure the long-term economic viability of power projects and to increase
			 access
			 to power, including—</text>
            <subparagraph id="ida007355fbae94789a3aa5f07ff41bef6">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>reforms designed to allow third parties to connect power generation to the grid affordably,
			 quickly, and without undue regulatory burdens;</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="id06c75b7d4c7549b48003a0c956f59630">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>policies to ensure there is a viable, adequately resourced, independent, and capable utility
			 regulator;</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="id31392095a4534f42a63f946d7772506c">
              <enum>(C)</enum>
              <text>strategies to ensure utilities become or remain creditworthy;</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="id75cabb4d491d440fa67b0707889d160b">
              <enum>(D)</enum>
              <text>regulations that permit the participation of independent power producers and private-public
			 partnerships;</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="idf411bcd331c24b09a808654733d63a9e">
              <enum>(E)</enum>
              <text>policies that encourage private investment in power generation;</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="id670cff5151bb47c7963d9c28b28e745f">
              <enum>(F)</enum>
              <text>policies that ensure compensation for power provided to the electrical grid by on-site producers;</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="idc0e4a0b151ae4fa8ad7858eaa80db156">
              <enum>(G)</enum>
              <text>policies to unbundle power services; and</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="id284759a4547a446c8eadb077c9b0bb25">
              <enum>(H)</enum>
              <text>regulations to eliminate conflicts of interest in the utility sector.</text>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="id496b845457204e36b9e9a1970c9afea8">
            <enum>(10)</enum>
            <text>A description of plans to ensure—</text>
            <subparagraph id="id2813197864A442FB83FF61ADC5D5561E">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>local consultation, as appropriate, in the planning, long-term
			 maintenance, and management of investments designed to increase access to
			 power in sub-Saharan Africa; and</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="id333601C8D65145BA88E89548996D806F">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>that such investments are sustainable and
			 transparent, including through the provision of technical assistance and
			 training.</text>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="id3c25931c6862460d9b9c83f2aa33e0d1">
            <enum>(11)</enum>
            <text>An identification of the relevant United States Government departments and agencies that will be
			 involved in
			 carrying out the strategy.</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="id7d40af6dadd441fcb70307fe36a6fb67">
            <enum>(12)</enum>
            <text>A description of the level and distribution of resources that will be dedicated on an annual basis
			 among those departments and agencies.</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="id6222234fa96b4cdba7e6b87567145ae8">
            <enum>(13)</enum>
            <text>A description of the role of each such department or agency and the types of programs that each
			 such department or agency will
			 conduct.</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="id7c4fb0c449fc40b3a1e5717ffa555f48">
            <enum>(14)</enum>
            <text>A description of the mechanisms that will be used to coordinate the efforts of United States
			 Government departments and  agencies in
			 carrying out the strategy to avoid duplication of efforts, enhance
			 coordination, and ensure that each such department or agency conducts
			 programs primarily
			 in the areas in which that department or agency has the greatest
			 expertise, technical
			 capabilities, and potential for success.</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="idc6f9d62bd1774848b699ca634f8c1d79">
            <enum>(15)</enum>
            <text>A description of the mechanisms to be established for—</text>
            <subparagraph id="idb8949d43979c440ab6223ba553487a79">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>monitoring and evaluating increased access to, and reliability and affordability of, power in
			 sub-Saharan Africa for individuals, communities, and businesses;</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="id2e14131cb4784403b80ec9da2e025d28">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>maximizing the financial sustainability of power generation, transmission, and distribution in
			 sub-Saharan Africa;</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="id1b548c84dfc2423e974c1ed9e11e13fd">
              <enum>(C)</enum>
              <text>sharing best practices among relevant United States Government departments and agencies and with
			 other countries
			 and institutions participating in efforts to increase access to power in
			 sub-Saharan Africa;</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="id811f1bc0839b4e0cb39f1172c17dea8f">
              <enum>(D)</enum>
              <text>establishing metrics to demonstrate progress on meeting goals relating to access to power, power
			 generation, and distribution in sub-Saharan Africa; and</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="id957b2eab4bbe44b8be388b8b6b205b7e">
              <enum>(E)</enum>
              <text>terminating unsuccessful programs.</text>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="idb177ccbe23c6463a855b1f0c3a9869d3">
            <enum>(16)</enum>
            <text>A description of the engagement plan for working with local communities benefitting from or
			 affected by projects carried out pursuant to the strategy.</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="idc5bb9399864d4d0c84812e64c59c7e2a">
            <enum>(17)</enum>
            <text>A description of the mechanisms that will be used to ensure greater coordination between the United
			 States and foreign governments, international organizations, African
			 regional economic communities, international financial institutions,
			 international fora such as the G–8 and G–20, and private sector and civil
			 society organizations.</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="id8f69ec50ab1b4b42824574b8178e425d">
            <enum>(18)</enum>
            <text>An outline of how the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> intends to partner with foreign governments, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="11DR" entity-type="federal-body">World Bank</cato:entity-ref> Group,
			 the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="11DB" entity-type="federal-body">African Development Bank</cato:entity-ref>, the private sector, and other development
			 partners to <deleted-phrase reported-display-style="strikethrough">assist</deleted-phrase>
              <added-phrase reported-display-style="italic">encourage</added-phrase> sub-Saharan African countries to conduct project 
			 studies and facilitate project development.</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="idd58730a3230746ffa916974f1c6372e1">
            <enum>(19)</enum>
            <text>A description of how the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> intends to help facilitate transnational and regional
			 electrification projects where appropriate.</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="id2ea100e036824475b85f8414ce04f54d">
            <enum>(20)</enum>
            <text>A description of how the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> intends to help sub-Saharan countries use new or potential
			 fossil fuel and other resources in order to provide power to their
			 citizens.</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="idc54a51cbb54449b0b1af4e7770bac55f">
            <enum>(21)</enum>
            <text>A description of how the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> intends to promote trade in electrical equipment with countries
			 in sub-Saharan Africa, including a description of how the government of
			 each country receiving assistance pursuant to the strategy—</text>
            <subparagraph id="id35b8c21d411842508fec6df278681411">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>plans to lower or eliminate import tariffs or other taxes for energy and other power production and
			 distribution technologies destined for sub-Saharan Africa, including
			 equipment used to provide energy access, including solar lanterns, solar
			 home systems, and micro and mini grids; and</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="idea7040dce4734a5eb8441fa1052e19da">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>plans to protect the intellectual property of companies designing and manufacturing products that
			 can be used to provide energy access in sub-Saharan Africa.</text>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="idd688cf9e094b4fc499e20c9510475b5c">
            <enum>(22)</enum>
            <text>A description of how the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> intends to work with the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="11DB" entity-type="federal-body">African Development Bank</cato:entity-ref> and other
			 partners to increase the capacity of sub-Saharan African utilities to—</text>
            <subparagraph id="ide630de9c8de840ddb49e9c5190550f90">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>develop standardized power purchase agreements and other contracts to streamline project
			 development; and</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="idde59012730024466b06e50b879ec6660">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>negotiate and monitor compliance with power purchase agreements and other contracts entered into
			 with the private sector.</text>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="id5c26ab3a1a6e4daa99ab9f339b7295f8">
            <enum>(23)</enum>
            <text>A description of how the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> intends to encourage the growth of distributed renewable energy
			 markets in sub-Saharan Africa, including off-grid lighting and power, that
			 includes—</text>
            <subparagraph id="id4427887fca3d4fb4bd0dd5937459e9cf">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>a country-by-country analysis of the state of distributed renewable energy in sub-Saharan Africa,
			 including off-grid lighting and power;</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="id72fd5b80a6374aa88b18c5a93d464d3d">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>a description of market barriers to the deployment of distributed renewable energy technologies
			 both on- and off-grid in sub-Saharan Africa;</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="ide3a43235257b48989fbf221676adbab6">
              <enum>(C)</enum>
              <text>measures United States Government departments and agencies, including the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="7200" entity-type="federal-body">United States Agency for
			 International
			 Development</cato:entity-ref> and
			 the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="7100" entity-type="federal-body">Overseas Private Investment Corporation</cato:entity-ref>, can take—</text>
              <clause id="id54bca8727c6143cbb124dc267f5d94d6">
                <enum>(i)</enum>
                <text>to overcome or eliminate market barriers or enhance financing opportunities for distributed
			 renewable energy
			 solutions in sub-Saharan Africa; and</text>
              </clause>
              <clause id="idcc43f1d904fd40f2a98cde33b481e4b5">
                <enum>(ii)</enum>
                <text>to <deleted-phrase reported-display-style="strikethrough">assist</deleted-phrase>
                  <added-phrase reported-display-style="italic">encourage</added-phrase> multilateral organizations such as the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="11DR" entity-type="federal-body">World Bank</cato:entity-ref> Group in efforts to eliminate such
			 barriers or enhance such opportunities;</text>
              </clause>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="idd9baabaeda904c5f90ff375db2eabbd2">
              <enum>(D)</enum>
              <text>the amount and kind of financial support and financing provided to participants in distributed
			 energy markets by the United States Government, international financial
			 institutions, and other international organizations;</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="idf4cb39742d924e43b978411cdb372a13">
              <enum>(E)</enum>
              <text>an analysis of the efficacy of efforts by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="7100" entity-type="federal-body">Overseas Private Investment Corporation</cato:entity-ref> and the
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="7200" entity-type="federal-body">United States Agency for International Development</cato:entity-ref> to facilitate the
			 financing of the importation, distribution, sale, leasing, or marketing of
			 distributed renewable energy technologies; and</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="id622d4cf6bf364c40be8937960fa87e48">
              <enum>(F)</enum>
              <text>a description of how bolstering distributed renewable energy can enhance the overall effort to
			 increase power access in sub-Saharan Africa.</text>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="idc566ea68059b400c8b31445cae6fc4e7">
            <enum>(24)</enum>
            <text>Any other issues the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> determines are relevant to the strategy.</text>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection changed="added" id="id9ef2f4c9979a4764a9d1705d8f37966f" reported-display-style="italic">
          <enum>(c)</enum>
          <header>Interagency working group</header>
          <paragraph id="idbaf603df16e9408e9bce28750b774758">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <header>In general</header>
            <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> may, as appropriate, establish an Interagency Working Group to coordinate the
			 activities of relevant United States Government departments and agencies
			 involved in carrying out
			 the strategy required under this section.</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="idbd668d1541f94d16a4fdb10f983d099e">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <header>Functions</header>
            <text>The Interagency Working Group may, among other things, seek to coordinate the activities of the
			 United States Government departments and agencies involved in implementing
			 the strategy, ensure
			 efficient and effective coordination between participating departments and
			 agencies,
			 facilitate information sharing, and coordinate partnerships between United
			 States Government, the private sector, and other development partners to
			 achieve the goals of the strategy.</text>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="id85c56078c30345c49a13d4f49a62901c">
          <enum>
            <deleted-phrase reported-display-style="strikethrough">(c)</deleted-phrase>
            <added-phrase reported-display-style="italic">(d)</added-phrase>
          </enum>
          <header>African power advisory group</header>
          <paragraph id="idc383c79bfd4c49e09b587128f009fc7e">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <header>Establishment</header>
            <text>For the purposes of developing the strategy required by <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Energize Africa Act of 2014/s:103/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> shall
			 establish a  <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="African Power Advisory Group" proposed="true">African Power Advisory Group</cato:entity-ref> to advise on the development and
			 implementation of the strategy and report required by this section and
			 <deleted-phrase reported-display-style="strikethrough">assistance</deleted-phrase>
              <added-phrase reported-display-style="italic"> support</added-phrase> provided pursuant to this section.</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="idc99abbfada2346da8784d25419a9f437">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <header>Membership</header>
            <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="African Power Advisory Group" proposed="true">African Power Advisory Group</cato:entity-ref> shall be composed of <deleted-phrase reported-display-style="strikethrough">12</deleted-phrase>
              <added-phrase reported-display-style="italic"> 13</added-phrase>
              <deleted-phrase reported-display-style="strikethrough"/> members appointed by the President,
			 including the following:</text>
            <subparagraph id="idf3f8de2efcd14c3a8b179e030dc2479d">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>The Coordinator of the President’s Power Africa Initiative.</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="id04c04eea3dc6479bbfcb4290a92beeae">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>Seven individuals from the power sector, of whom—</text>
              <clause id="idac0472ee6726496c90e3fa7b311ad414">
                <enum>(i)</enum>
                <text>at least one shall have experience in the fossil fuel power sector;</text>
              </clause>
              <clause id="id8f30d347e4a94aad86516f74951137d2">
                <enum>(ii)</enum>
                <text>at least one shall have experience with the rural electrical cooperatives;</text>
              </clause>
              <clause id="idf5c70567332842768fc70c2fe0134bc2">
                <enum>(iii)</enum>
                <text>at least one shall have experience in the renewable energy sector; and</text>
              </clause>
              <clause id="id2c2d80039fb649318cf121e5734662c8">
                <enum>(iv)</enum>
                <text>at least one shall have experience in the distributed generation sector.</text>
              </clause>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="id40c47dd12f6443a08339405fa7bdc86d">
              <enum>(C)</enum>
              <text>Three individuals, other than individuals described in subparagraph (B), who shall have
			 experience in working with the business community in Africa or with
			 governments of countries in Africa.</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="id35bac3a94dbd40c89f02d117fb4243fe">
              <enum>(D)</enum>
              <text>One individual who shall have experience with utility regulation.</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph changed="added" id="idDEEE896DEE4C49F092B7EFBCA0DAE262" reported-display-style="italic">
              <enum>(E)</enum>
              <text>The official designated pursuant to <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
                  <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2014/s:1206/ss:d">section 1206(d) of the National Defense Authorization Act for
			 Fiscal Year 2014</cato:entity-ref> (<cato:entity-ref entity-type="public-law" value="public-law/113/66">Public law 113–66</cato:entity-ref>; <cato:entity-ref entity-type="statute-at-large" value="statute-at-large/127/902">127 Stat. 902</cato:entity-ref>; <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/22/2151/note">
                    <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2151">
                  22 U.S.C. 2151
                </external-xref> note</cato:entity-ref>)</cato:entity>
			 to coordinate efforts to increase United States exports to Africa.</text>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="idcbefe2738c3d414dad44536914adcd35">
            <enum>(3)</enum>
            <header>Functions</header>
            <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> shall call upon members of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="African Power Advisory Group" proposed="true">African Power  Advisory Group</cato:entity-ref>, either collectively or
			 individually, to advise the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> regarding the development and
			 implementation of the strategy and report required by this section and
			 <deleted-phrase reported-display-style="strikethrough">assistance</deleted-phrase>
              <added-phrase reported-display-style="italic">support</added-phrase> provided pursuant to this section.</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="id845a775b0a6a4285a8b339a4c34c61e6">
            <enum>(4)</enum>
            <header>Meetings</header>
            <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="African Power Advisory Group" proposed="true">African Power Advisory Group</cato:entity-ref> shall meet not later than 60 days after the date of the enactment
			 of this Act and not less frequently than annually thereafter.</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="idd2c8c3cbd9fc49d7958454850b703fc7">
            <enum>(5)</enum>
            <header>Federal advisory committee act</header>
            <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="African Power Advisory Group" proposed="true">African Power Advisory Group</cato:entity-ref> established under this section shall not be subject to the <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Federal Advisory Committee Act">Federal
			 Advisory Committee Act</cato:entity-ref> (<cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc-appendix/5">5 U.S.C. App.</cato:entity-ref>)</cato:entity>.</text>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
      </section>
      <section id="id4fb2bf5c3f3d47baac5e10e17e23692f">
        <enum>104.</enum>
        <header>Sense of Congress on priorities with respect the energy sector of sub-Saharan African countries</header>
        <text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> that—</text>
        <paragraph id="idf9adfc63f03b4f8b8cafc4188e47b2e1">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>as the United States deepens its engagement with countries in sub-Saharan Africa pursuant to the
			 authorities provided under this Act, priority should be given to countries
			 with a demonstrated commitment to—</text>
          <subparagraph id="id4bf74c9ca7a64082852cca389679ca7b">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>transparency, accountability, and credibility in energy sector governance;</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="idd28c209ce13347068027da690a7c8ae1">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>prudent macroeconomic management of energy resources, including sound fiscal and debt management;</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="id9be12f54be094005a6624c8ed1255a12">
            <enum>(C)</enum>
            <text>energy sector reforms, including tariff reform, unbundling of vertically integrated utilities, and 
			 access for independent power producers;</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="id6973b9efe0d34cef8ae5c171607df450">
            <enum>(D)</enum>
            <text>responsible development of newly discovered energy resources;</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="id954cd146c9094e28af18fa11851c3b6c">
            <enum>(E)</enum>
            <text>expansion of power generation, transmission, and access, including distributed mini-grid and
			 off-grid solutions; and</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="id275096296b1049f3b0689d5e84172210">
            <enum>(F)</enum>
            <text>private sector and investment climate reforms, such as strong rule of law and robust controls over
			 the business regulatory environment; and</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="id38ab6a3e5bb34cbdb8cf7f73b538375f">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>the United States should consider, in prioritizing efforts carried out pursuant to this Act—</text>
          <subparagraph id="id5b40c766e3904fe29abc026c781e92fc">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>opportunities for the United States private sector to contribute to the energy sector in
			 sub-Saharan African countries through technology, innovation, and project
			 development;</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="ide83ff5ac10fc475289cd8e2f6f32c0a3">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>the potential of such efforts to facilitate regional power trade and expand power access across
			 borders;</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="id68f43d10ce284ad5ad63a61abb51acb0">
            <enum>(C)</enum>
            <text>private sector interest and participation in the energy sector of sub-Saharan African countries;</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="id8d27b47f45ff417e990f9bb2d2bf1f19">
            <enum>(D)</enum>
            <text>the long-term financial viability of energy sector projects in development;</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="id5c08c29e39e24594a2e5970429459966">
            <enum>(E)</enum>
            <text>opportunities to collaborate with international donors and partners in energy sector development
			 involving multilateral institutions such as the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="11DR" entity-type="federal-body">World Bank</cato:entity-ref> Group and the
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="11DB" entity-type="federal-body">African Development Bank</cato:entity-ref>;</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="ide90e77a59cb74b63b3d5ce3493fa8bda">
            <enum>(F)</enum>
            <text>the availability of United States Government resources and appropriate funds to support the
			 expansion
			 of technical assistance, delivery units, and transaction advisors and
			 teams to implement United States Government programs to expand power
			 access in sub-Saharan Africa; and</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="id10d1f63409b74f1c83000ae6860b02d5">
            <enum>(G)</enum>
            <text>mechanisms to promote efficient and effective coordination among United States Government
			 departments and agencies,
			 including allocation of well-defined roles for each such
			 department or agency.</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
      </section>
      <section id="id23c6e92441064235b3aec4e3c19728a1">
        <enum>105.</enum>
        <header>Prioritization of assistance for power projects in sub-Saharan Africa by the United States
			 Agency for International Development</header>
        <subsection id="iddb5742f179944cd4b8029fb361239070">
          <enum>(a)</enum>
          <header>Loan guarantees</header>
          <text>In pursuing the policy goals described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Energize Africa Act of 2014/s:102" proposed="true">section 102</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="7200" entity-type="federal-body">Administrator of the United States
			 Agency for International Development</cato:entity-ref> should prioritize loan guarantees to
			 local financial institutions in sub-Saharan Africa, as appropriate, to—</text>
          <paragraph id="id762ed186644f4c4c9d4dcccb965b684d">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <text>facilitate the involvement of such institutions in power projects and markets, both on-
			 and off-grid, in sub-Saharan Africa;</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="id6c88e909722a420f88736b78847a44bf">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <text>allow such institutions to partner with other investors to leverage expertise and increase the
			 impact of such loan guarantees for energy access and power production
			 projects in sub-Saharan Africa;</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="id8131c638328946ca85b619aceb02ad1a">
            <enum>(3)</enum>
            <text>allow such institutions to partner with other investors to fund local research, development, and
			 deployment of technology in order to specifically increase access to
			 reliable, affordable, and sustainable power in sub-Saharan Africa; and</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="idac337905daa840bb965788d7856b88c9">
            <enum>(4)</enum>
            <text>allow such institutions to fund the development of plans to increase distribution coverage,
			 including off-grid projects and services in rural areas of sub-Saharan
			 Africa.</text>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="id31cbf1815f824e70ace01fbc54c1039a">
          <enum>(b)</enum>
          <header>Grants</header>
          <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7200">Administrator</cato:entity-ref> <deleted-phrase reported-display-style="strikethrough">shall</deleted-phrase>
            <added-phrase reported-display-style="italic"> should, as appropriate,</added-phrase> prioritize assistance to—</text>
          <paragraph id="id3da0ad0655444eb299c3db9186d95a98">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <text>support the implementation or development, as appropriate, of national, regional, and local energy
			 and economically sustainable power policy plans in sub-Saharan Africa;</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="id35a9082cc34b48f4a63f262952aef62a">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <text>expand power access across sub-Saharan Africa, including specifically to the poorest populations
			 and rural and isolated communities;</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="id3093c2d74b1d431ebc42635e58bf4e08">
            <enum>(3)</enum>
            <text>build the capacity of countries in sub-Saharan Africa to monitor and appropriately and
			 transparently regulate the power sector and encourage private investment
			 in power production and distribution; and</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="idbcad829dcf0e43b483b3204915ab0fb8">
            <enum>(4)</enum>
            <text>increase access to reliable, affordable, and sustainable power in sub-Saharan Africa, including the
			 development of plans to increase power access in rural areas.</text>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="id546a8e362e934e819a78d938b0a9e1ae">
          <enum>(c)</enum>
          <header>Effectiveness measurement</header>
          <text>In providing the loan guarantees and assistance prioritized pursuant to this section, the
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7200">Administrator</cato:entity-ref> shall use clear, accountable, and metric-based targets to
			 measure the effectiveness of such guarantees and assistance in achieving
			 the goals described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Energize Africa Act of 2014/s:102" proposed="true">section 102</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="idcdc194c2fa5843daa25a46e084927022">
          <enum>(d)</enum>
          <header>Rule of construction</header>
          <text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to authorize modifying or limiting the portfolio of the
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="7200" entity-type="federal-body">United States Agency
			 for International Development</cato:entity-ref> in other developing regions.</text>
        </subsection>
      </section>
      <section id="id95961c6f49c14cafb47e0412a17e79d3">
        <enum>106.</enum>
        <header>Prioritization of assistance for power projects in sub-Saharan Africa by the Trade and Development
			 Agency</header>
        <subsection id="id203a53ec6b054e6bacb53046eef01b04">
          <enum>(a)</enum>
          <header>In general</header>
          <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1153" entity-type="federal-body">Director of the Trade and Development Agency</cato:entity-ref> should prioritize, as appropriate—</text>
          <paragraph id="id32219d79e1c34f37b41e8953a8784821">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <text>the promotion of United States private sector participation in energy sector development projects
			 in sub-Saharan Africa by conducting project preparation activities for
			 projects in sub-Saharan Africa, including feasibility studies, technical
			 assistance, pilot projects, reverse trade missions, conferences, and
			 workshops; and</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="id59b642aa259a4d9b8f13fcc5fd5a6ab6">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <text>the funding of project preparation activities for projects in sub-Saharan Africa that involve
			 increased access to power, including power generation and trade capacity
			 building.</text>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="idb4d709b84f134091aa52660249efb5a4">
          <enum>(b)</enum>
          <header>Focus</header>
          <text>The project preparation activities described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Energize Africa Act of 2014/s:106/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref> should focus on supporting projects
			 in sub-Saharan Africa that enhance efficiencies in the areas of power
			 generation, transmission, and distribution grids, including on-grid,
			 off-grid, and micro-grid solutions, and best practices in demand-side
			 management.</text>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="id6C928081DFDD4318806062FABF956898">
          <enum>(c)</enum>
          <header>Rule of construction</header>
          <text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to authorize modifying or limiting the portfolio of the
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1153" entity-type="federal-body">Trade and Development
			 Agency</cato:entity-ref> in other developing regions.</text>
        </subsection>
      </section>
      <section id="id4a34d3d94419491d98d49060b334d5dc">
        <enum>107.</enum>
        <header>Prioritization of assistance for power projects in sub-Saharan Africa by the Overseas Private
			 Investment
			 Corporation</header>
        <subsection id="id15a0dae56c304197b9f736f5a35f7eaa">
          <enum>(a)</enum>
          <header>In general</header>
          <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="7100" entity-type="federal-body">Overseas Private Investment Corporation</cato:entity-ref> should, as appropriate—</text>
          <paragraph id="id7cebb8b75a154fdd9298e93d8d69f336">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <text>prioritize support for private sector investments in the power sector of sub-Saharan Africa,
			 including in renewable energy, that will—</text>
            <subparagraph id="idde6f790e613d4c25af87534d80ac9284">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>maximize the number of people with new access to power and power services;</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="id9476a71c8dfd4e2c95108ef4319c690c">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>improve and expand the transmission and distribution of power and off-grid lighting and power
			 solutions;</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="id41646880afe8424d8fe08ffb86835e10">
              <enum>(C)</enum>
              <text>provide reliable power to people and businesses in urban and rural communities;</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="id20023ce0b8804f1b8422442e882aab6a">
              <enum>(D)</enum>
              <text>address the energy needs of people living in areas where there is little or no access to a power
			 grid;</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="id47bfcc36e6904c01866df67ef2e86aab">
              <enum>(E)</enum>
              <text>reduce transmission and distribution losses and improve end-use efficiency and demand-side
			 management; and</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="id48c7d04751ca4800889301841fb7035b">
              <enum>(F)</enum>
              <text>reduce energy-related impediments to business productivity and investment;</text>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="id514a8cec8f3446cc8221d101b5e8ca1c">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <text>implement procedures for expedited review of and, where appropriate, approval of, applications by
			 eligible investors (as defined in <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Foreign Assistance Act of 1961/s:238">section 238 of the Foreign Assistance
			 Act of 1961</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2198">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/22/2198">22 U.S.C. 2198</cato:entity-ref>
              </external-xref>)</cato:entity>) for loans, loan guarantees, and insurance
			 for such investments;</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="ide59410db16f14b43827e15dac0157915">
            <enum>(3)</enum>
            <text>encourage small- and medium-sized enterprises and cooperative service providers to participate in
			 energy investment activities in sub-Saharan Africa; and</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="id65b21c5972ea4803a4fe109f92229933">
            <enum>(4)</enum>
            <text>publish information on the effects of its energy investments on development in sub-Saharan Africa.</text>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="id1AB9F1C1DB5441EBA92BBFF9D90CAF40">
          <enum>(b)</enum>
          <header>Rule of construction</header>
          <text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to authorize modifying or limiting the portfolio of the
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="7100" entity-type="federal-body">Overseas Private
			 Investment Corporation</cato:entity-ref> in other developing regions.</text>
        </subsection>
      </section>
      <section id="id74dad20e07404e6fba407a998592bbf7">
        <enum>108.</enum>
        <header>Prioritization of assistance for power projects in sub-Saharan Africa by the World Bank
			 Group
			 and the African Development Bank</header>
        <subsection id="idBB30E0D32AEF4930862F27B2F330C208">
          <enum>(a)</enum>
          <header>In general</header>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="2000" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of the Treasury</cato:entity-ref> should direct the United States Executive Directors of the World Bank
			 Group and the African Development Bank to, as appropriate, use the voice,
			 vote, and influence of the United States to help ensure the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="11DR" entity-type="federal-body">World Bank</cato:entity-ref>
			 Group and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="11DB" entity-type="federal-body">African Development Bank</cato:entity-ref>—</text>
          <paragraph id="id269E65798E1943478F306CF8DDBB4FD6">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">prioritize—</text>
            <subparagraph id="idaae09120141f4cb28b5f593d6e12e20a">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>increasing their investment in, and efforts to promote investment in,
			 well-designed power sector and electrification projects in sub-Saharan
			 Africa;</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="id50f032ba3b4e4421b72c8f19f0e09cec">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>creating financing opportunities, provide financing, and provide technical assistance to promote
			 both
			 on- and off-grid power and lighting solutions in sub-Saharan Africa;</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="id7ef8517969784b43a5242378973065d4">
              <enum>(C)</enum>
              <text>stimulating private investment in reliable, affordable, and sustainable power in sub-Saharan
			 Africa; and</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="id68030a98c08b41bda1ecd471954e640e">
              <enum>(D)</enum>
              <text>providing technical assistance to the regulatory authorities of governments in sub-Saharan Africa
			 to—</text>
              <clause id="id09ab55a6fd2e42638b587701b77fdf08">
                <enum>(i)</enum>
                <text>remove unnecessary regulatory and legal barriers to investment in commercially viable power
			 projects and markets;</text>
              </clause>
              <clause id="id4f723694900c443f84503508c1828287">
                <enum>(ii)</enum>
                <text>modify regulatory and legal regimes to assist providers in reducing power transmission and
			 distribution technical losses;</text>
              </clause>
              <clause id="id5988fc5364bc4046a3775b8f7db3ac4c">
                <enum>(iii)</enum>
                <text>implement cost-based power tariffs and provide for commercial cost recovery;</text>
              </clause>
              <clause id="id0c15a02c20a6472b89339985e6d15d27">
                <enum>(iv)</enum>
                <text>encourage end-use efficiency and demand-side management in the power sector;</text>
              </clause>
              <clause id="ida1f1e3f9ff2942b6a8475540b9d9e10f">
                <enum>(v)</enum>
                <text>strengthen local power markets;</text>
              </clause>
              <clause id="id417e95e80cb149b3a040d1520680d556">
                <enum>(vi)</enum>
                <text>reduce corruption in the power industry, including in government and regulatory processes
			 associated with power production and distribution;</text>
              </clause>
              <clause id="idc1fd3e62d7e44d26a35c312de54d9ad6">
                <enum>(vii)</enum>
                <text>encourage domestic investment in the power sector;</text>
              </clause>
              <clause id="id6b893bcffe7a4edd91c0c0c5732c549f">
                <enum>(viii)</enum>
                <text>improve transparency and good governance with respect to regulatory and legal processes and
			 requirements in the power sector;</text>
              </clause>
              <clause id="id0fde026c6dc24d8ba89e810d43100d20">
                <enum>(ix)</enum>
                <text>encourage affordable and expedited interconnection for distributed energy systems and independent
			 power producers;</text>
              </clause>
              <clause id="id467c4e4b261b4033b9d58c75796593fc">
                <enum>(x)</enum>
                <text>ensure compliance with the best practices of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="11DR" entity-type="federal-body">World Bank</cato:entity-ref> Group and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="11DB" entity-type="federal-body">African Development Bank</cato:entity-ref>;
			 and</text>
              </clause>
              <clause id="id4b15e5f7a0ad45ceb03cc0f8f768f881">
                <enum>(xi)</enum>
                <text>implement regulatory and legal reforms that facilitate efficient power generation, transmission,
			 and distribution and  efficient off-grid energy markets;</text>
              </clause>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="id69316cfaeba540e592ce0e2bd527a5b1">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <text>use clear, accountable, and metric-based targets to measure the effectiveness of investment and
			 other assistance provided by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="11DR" entity-type="federal-body">World Bank</cato:entity-ref> Group or the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="11DB" entity-type="federal-body">African
			 Development Bank</cato:entity-ref>, as the case may be, for power sector and electrification
			 projects in
			 sub-Saharan Africa; and</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="id6057869459c24f7da645906eb90925b2">
            <enum>(3)</enum>
            <text>support the efforts of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="11DR" entity-type="federal-body">World Bank</cato:entity-ref> Group to foster growth in the off-grid lighting and power
			 markets.</text>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="id8f82e86632034a518bcdf6a0dd16fb38">
          <enum>(b)</enum>
          <header>Rule of construction</header>
          <text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to authorize the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="2000" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of the Treasury</cato:entity-ref> to advocate
			 for modifying or limiting the portfolio of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="11DR" entity-type="federal-body">World Bank</cato:entity-ref> Group or the
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="11DB" entity-type="federal-body">African Development Bank</cato:entity-ref> in other developing regions.</text>
        </subsection>
      </section>
      <section id="id31ff378ca59245d8800684ecf061c8be">
        <enum>109.</enum>
        <header>Prioritization of assistance  for power projects in sub-Saharan Africa by the United States African
			 Development Foundation</header>
        <subsection id="idb0dfefe6983c4f29925856c7a15d1e87">
          <enum>(a)</enum>
          <header>In general</header>
          <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Board of Directors" entity-parent-id="1141">Board of Directors</cato:entity-ref> and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1141">President of the United States African Development Foundation</cato:entity-ref> should
			 seek
			 opportunities to make grants and provide technical support to
			 businesses and organizations in sub-Saharan Africa that qualify for
			 assistance from the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1141">Foundation</cato:entity-ref> and are developing on- and
			 off-grid solutions to meet the power needs of rural communities
			 underserved by national grids.</text>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="id0a257d5f47774e36af5f4caa6b1c341f">
          <enum>(b)</enum>
          <header>Focus</header>
          <text>The mission of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1141">United States African Development Foundation</cato:entity-ref> under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Energize Africa Act of 2014/s:109/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref> is to meet the
			 needs of underserved communities
			 and close critical development gaps with speed, efficiency, and
			 effectiveness.</text>
        </subsection>
      </section>
      <section changed="added" id="idfd862f2a96c549c588910075101e1370" reported-display-style="italic">
        <enum>110.</enum>
        <header>Prioritization of assistance  for power projects in sub-Saharan Africa by the Millennium Challenge
			 Corporation</header>
        <subsection id="id2f487a5482e8462d8de182b8fa2e84d3">
          <enum>(a)</enum>
          <header>In general</header>
          <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Chief Executive Officer" entity-parent-id="9543">Chief Executive Officer</cato:entity-ref> and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Board of Directors" entity-parent-id="9543">Board of Directors of the Millennium Challenge Corporation</cato:entity-ref>
			 should—</text>
          <paragraph id="idEBA2A64FB5354EE79FD8F7DBCE00B60C">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <text>assess, as appropriate, the extent to which insufficient access to and reliability of electricity
			 is a binding
			 constraint on sustainable economic growth in countries in sub-Saharan
			 Africa; and</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="idBD3FECEE2D4B42EA8F8597DA69E3FB64">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <text>prioritize, as appropriate—</text>
            <subparagraph id="id4cb4c5612e93474db8d219ad49cee7a4">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>the provision of assistance to support private and public sector efforts to  increase access to and
			 the reliability of electricity in such countries,
			 including through on- and off-grid generation and electrical transmission
			 and distribution projects;</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="idb66a2e9dafc549c28c7ddd1307032c88">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>engagement with governments of such countries to assist in identifying and
			 establishing legal, regulatory, policy, and institutional reforms related
			 to power sector investments;</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="id9f04dce26a424c2a901e3bdb2da29266">
              <enum>(C)</enum>
              <text>consultation with independent power producers, public and private financial institutions, and other
			 power sector stakeholders during project planning; and</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="idd5d8ce79b3b6424599e56c623bb6353e">
              <enum>(D)</enum>
              <text>guidance, including in the design of project methodologies and performance metrics, as requested by
			 other
			 United States Government departments and agencies involved in activities
			 authorized under this title.</text>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="idc074340c272548c3828c7055529ab47d">
          <enum>(b)</enum>
          <header>Rule of construction</header>
          <text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to authorize modifying or limiting the assistance
			 programs of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="9543" entity-type="federal-body">Millennium Challenge Corporation</cato:entity-ref> in other developing
			 regions or sectors.</text>
        </subsection>
      </section>
      <section id="idbfdf2ff7639e467bbc739ba266a1dcde">
        <enum>
          <deleted-phrase reported-display-style="strikethrough">110.</deleted-phrase>
          <added-phrase reported-display-style="italic">111.</added-phrase>
        </enum>
        <header>Progress report</header>
        <subsection id="id608f6ec9fe884ae89f9d4076154c40b3">
          <enum>(a)</enum>
          <header>In general</header>
          <text>Not later than 3 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> shall submit to
			 the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="SSFR00" entity-type="committee">Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate</cato:entity-ref> and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="HFA00" entity-type="committee">Committee on
			 Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives</cato:entity-ref> a report on progress made
			 toward achieving the policy goals described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Energize Africa Act of 2014/s:102" proposed="true">section 102</cato:entity-ref> that includes
			 the following:</text>
          <paragraph id="id9daf4408cdd34f46963dad45336e919e">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <text>A report on United States programs supporting implementation of policy and legislative changes
			 leading to increased power generation and access in sub-Saharan Africa,
			 including a description of the number, type, and status of policy,
			 regulatory, and legislative changes initiated or implemented as a result
			 of programs funded or supported by the United States in countries in
			 sub-Saharan Africa to support increased power generation and access after
			 the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="idb26db53bcaf44c6c92859d550de75655">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <text>A description of power projects receiving United States Government support and how such
			 projects, including off-grid efforts, are intended to achieve the policy
			 goals described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Energize Africa Act of 2014/s:102" proposed="true">section 102</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="ida88b6072fef84e468bee37841fb2b262">
            <enum>(3)</enum>
            <text>For each project described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Energize Africa Act of 2014/s:111/ss:a/p:2" proposed="true">paragraph (2)</cato:entity-ref>—</text>
            <subparagraph id="idd8877588b92543c6a503232f4ad23fe9">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>a description of how the project  fits into, or encourages modifications of, the national energy
			 plan of the country in which the project will be carried out, including
			 encouraging regulatory reform in that county;</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="ida63d9a24bcfc47c4a8397c748e6fb8d0">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>an estimate of the total cost of the project to the consumer, the country in which the project will
			 be carried out, and other investors;</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="id9e1cc22f71d8411d84252559030b9745">
              <enum>(C)</enum>
              <text>the amount of financing provided or guaranteed by the United States Government for the project;</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="idadc09d01509f40c48de6eb59bba928a5">
              <enum>(D)</enum>
              <text>an estimate of United States Government resources for the project, itemized by funding source,
			 including from the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="7100" entity-type="federal-body">Overseas Private Investment Corporation</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="7200" entity-type="federal-body">United
			 States Agency for International Development</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="2000" entity-type="federal-body">Department of the
			 Treasury</cato:entity-ref>, or other appropriate United States Government departments and
			 agencies;</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="id52cba35e71304f3ea065a4c0a3aef82c">
              <enum>(E)</enum>
              <text>an estimate of the number of individuals, communities, businesses, schools, and health facilities
			 that have gained power connections as a result of the project, with a
			 description of how the reliability, affordability, and sustainability of
			 power has been improved as of the date of the report; and</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="id33e86ad2674640b9bf159a35ec8d9dc0">
              <enum>(F)</enum>
              <text>an assessment of the increase in the number of people and businesses with access to power and in
			 the operating electrical power capacity in megawatts as a result of the 
			 project 
			 between the date of the enactment of this Act and the date of the report.</text>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="idd608e76d8d0a4836b205eca5259cb9b1">
            <enum>(4)</enum>
            <text>A description of any significant estimated non-economic effects of the efforts carried out pursuant
			 to this Act.</text>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </title>
    <title id="id49437A2CEDEC487980F3D03AC39CE06A" style="OLC">
      <enum>II</enum>
      <header>Overseas Private Investment Corporation</header>
      <section id="id09fb35e5fe0e463c9460f9c0106114da">
        <enum>201.</enum>
        <header>Extension of issuing authority</header>
        <text display-inline="no-display-inline">
          <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Foreign Assistance Act of 1961/s:235/ss:a/p:2">Section 235(a)(2) of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2195">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/22/2195/a/2">22 U.S.C. 2195(a)(2)</cato:entity-ref>
          </external-xref>)</cato:entity> is amended by
			 striking <quote>2007</quote> and inserting <quote>2019</quote>.</text>
      </section>
      <section id="id30ade47d05e64ee4b830a6144e80e5bb">
        <enum>202.</enum>
        <header>Expedited procedures for financing of small projects related to power generation and distribution
			 in sub-Saharan Africa</header>
        <subsection id="id5330dc5c812c4e8dad02b078ad522562">
          <enum>(a)</enum>
          <header>In general</header>
          <text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="7100" entity-type="federal-body">Overseas Private
			 Investment Corporation</cato:entity-ref>  should, as
			 appropriate, simplify and streamline the application, approval, and
			 post-approval processes for insurance, financing, investment, or
			 reinsurance for projects or subprojects, including off-grid efforts, in
			 sub-Saharan
			 Africa for which the total support of	the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7100">Corporation</cato:entity-ref> is less than
			 $20,000,000, by—</text>
          <paragraph id="id9eada44710444cb7bb18af12fa880b7a">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <text>expediting the review and consideration of, and determinations with respect to, applications for
			 insurance, financing, investment, or reinsurance, consistent with
			 investment best practices, including appropriate risk management, for such
			 projects and subprojects; and</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="idd265dece7fa041b2811fe225129300d7">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <text>reducing the burdens of project management for, and eliminating duplicative or unnecessary
			 oversight of such projects and subprojects after approval of insurance,
			 financing, investment, or reinsurance for projects or subprojects.</text>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="idc9279900919149b0bc75f87b5e5149bc">
          <enum>(b)</enum>
          <header>Consideration of best practices</header>
          <text>In revising its procedures as required by <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Energize Africa Act of 2014/s:202/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="7100" entity-type="federal-body">Overseas Private Investment
			 Corporation</cato:entity-ref> should consider best
			 practices established by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="11DF" entity-type="federal-body">International Finance Corporation</cato:entity-ref> of the
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="11DR" entity-type="federal-body">World Bank</cato:entity-ref> Group.</text>
        </subsection>
      </section>
      <section id="id600509f227074823b8992fd501fc3eba">
        <enum>203.</enum>
        <header>Activities in sub-Saharan Africa; investment advisory council</header>
        <text display-inline="no-display-inline">
          <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Foreign Assistance Act of 1961/s:233/ss:e">Section 233(e) of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2193">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/22/2193/e">22 U.S.C. 2193(e)</cato:entity-ref>
          </external-xref>)</cato:entity> is amended to read as
			 follows:</text>
        <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id394e91a1464f4ac98aa2fe9b0e172b22" style="OLC">
          <subsection id="id8d1c424c981949a8a9849138a72fde87">
            <enum>(e)</enum>
            <header>Activities in sub-Saharan Africa; investment advisory council</header>
            <paragraph id="idccec33a9a0f74116b397ab851ef17c2a">
              <enum>(1)</enum>
              <header>In general</header>
              <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Board of Directors" entity-parent-id="7100">Board</cato:entity-ref> should take prompt measures to prioritize, as appropriate, the loan, guarantee, and
			 insurance programs, and financial commitments, of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7100">Corporation</cato:entity-ref> in
			 sub-Saharan Africa in the areas of power generation, distribution, and
			 off-grid power and lighting, including through the use of an investment
			 advisory council to assist the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Board of Directors" entity-parent-id="7100">Board</cato:entity-ref> in developing and implementing
			 policies, programs, and financial instruments with respect to sub-Saharan
			 Africa.</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="id50a5706cb3a9450a93c55483caba42d7">
              <enum>(2)</enum>
              <header>Recommendations</header>
              <text>The investment advisory council described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Foreign Assistance Act of 1961/s:233/ss:e/p:1" proposed="true">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref> shall make recommendations to the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Board of Directors" entity-parent-id="7100">Board</cato:entity-ref>
			 on how the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7100">Corporation</cato:entity-ref> can facilitate greater support by the United States
			 for private sector trade and investment with and in sub-Saharan Africa.</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="id49a06f0a68b946b6aad5658fc30dbac3">
              <enum>(3)</enum>
              <header>Termination</header>
              <text>The investment advisory council described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Foreign Assistance Act of 1961/s:233/ss:e/p:1" proposed="true">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref> shall terminate on December 31, 2018.</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="ided8249e684d74569a1987f212b8e78bf">
              <enum>(4)</enum>
              <header>Applicability of federal advisory committee act</header>
              <text>The investment advisory council described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Foreign Assistance Act of 1961/s:233/ss:e/p:1" proposed="true">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref> shall not be subject to the <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
                  <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Federal Advisory Committee Act">Federal
			 Advisory Committee Act</cato:entity-ref> (<cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc-appendix/5">5 U.S.C. App.</cato:entity-ref>)</cato:entity>.</text>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
        </quoted-block>
      </section>
      <section commented="no" id="idaf085493d0124363b82cd650f8309c9a">
        <enum>204.</enum>
        <header>Pilot program for expansion of eligible investors</header>
        <subsection commented="no" id="id447be47499004c52b64abb3b83f04e2b">
          <enum>(a)</enum>
          <header>In general</header>
          <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="7100" entity-type="federal-body">Overseas Private Investment Corporation</cato:entity-ref> shall conduct a pilot program under which  entities
			 that are covered by <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Foreign Assistance Act of 1961/s:238/ss:c/p:3">section 238(c)(3) of the Foreign Assistance Act of
			 1961</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2198">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/22/2198/c/3">22 U.S.C. 2198(c)(3)</cato:entity-ref>
            </external-xref>)</cato:entity> and are substantially beneficially owned by
			 United States citizens shall be considered eligible investors under
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Foreign Assistance Act of 1961/s:238/ss:c">section 238(c)</cato:entity-ref> of that Act for
			 the sole purpose of receiving assistance from the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7100">Corporation</cato:entity-ref> for power
			 projects in sub-Saharan Africa.</text>
        </subsection>
        <subsection commented="no" id="idF3D92B13263249059F6C6B33806BE1F0">
          <enum>(b)</enum>
          <header>Cap on assistance</header>
          <text>Assistance provided by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7100">Corporation</cato:entity-ref> for a power project in sub-Saharan Africa pursuant to
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Energize Africa Act of 2014/s:204/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref> to an entity that is covered by
			 <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Foreign Assistance Act of 1961/s:238/ss:c/p:3">section 238(c)(3) of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961</cato:entity-ref> (<cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/22/2198/c/3">22 U.S.C.
			 2198(c)(3)</cato:entity-ref>)</cato:entity> and is substantially beneficially owned by United States
			 citizens shall
			 not exceed the lesser of—</text>
          <paragraph id="id40a03d769094494a9f3145cbada8823f">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <text>the share of ownership in the entity of such United States citizens; or</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph commented="no" id="idFFA0CBE6717C4DAF83F7AD5175731E3E">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <text>the percentage of the investment of the entity in
			 the project.</text>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection commented="no" id="id51D6972FEBF145A1A35E52B2B0357B5B">
          <enum>(c)</enum>
          <header>Termination of pilot program</header>
          <text>The pilot program under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Energize Africa Act of 2014/s:204/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref> shall terminate on the date that is 5 years after the date
			 of the enactment of this Act.</text>
        </subsection>
        <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4c89971a219548828f955ddf34614c66">
          <enum>(d)</enum>
          <header>Continued validity of existing support</header>
          <text>Notwithstanding <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Energize Africa Act of 2014/s:204/ss:c" proposed="true">subsection (c)</cato:entity-ref>, any support provided before the date that is 5 years after the date
			 of the enactment of this Act pursuant to the pilot program under
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Energize Africa Act of 2014/s:204/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref> shall remain valid on and after that date.</text>
        </subsection>
      </section>
      <section id="id25730c4d65fb4c5684cbf144ae9c66fa">
        <enum>205.</enum>
        <header>Pilot program for direct investment and local currency guaranties for power projects
			 in
			 sub-Saharan Africa</header>
        <subsection commented="no" id="idAB8357520A394B389ACAEB8B4CF5A048">
          <enum>(a)</enum>
          <header>In general</header>
          <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="7100" entity-type="federal-body">Overseas Private Investment Corporation</cato:entity-ref> shall conduct a pilot program to—</text>
          <paragraph commented="no" id="idF4B2D66C728B4210A3D731703852AFFD">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <text>make loans to eligible investors under <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Foreign Assistance Act of 1961/s:234/ss:c">section 234(c) of the Foreign Assistance Act
			 of 1961</cato:entity-ref> (<cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/22/2194/c">22 U.S.C.
			 2194(c)</cato:entity-ref>)</cato:entity> for power projects in sub-Saharan Africa and for which the total
			 support of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7100">Corporation</cato:entity-ref> does not exceed $50,000,000; and</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph commented="no" id="id0CB4D941A4054511BE87C20D42C7FD06">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <text>issue local currency guarantees under <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Foreign Assistance Act of 1961/s:234/ss:h">section 234(h) of the Foreign Assistance Act
			 of 1961</cato:entity-ref> (<cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/22/2194/h">22 U.S.C.
			 2194(h)</cato:entity-ref>)</cato:entity> to African subsidiaries of foreign financial
			 institutions if the issuance of such guarantees directly facilitates
			 lending
			 for power
			 projects in sub-Saharan Africa undertaken by eligible investors.</text>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="idAEE0DAA9D2564681BEAC403C68F70FAE">
          <enum>(b)</enum>
          <header>Eligible investor defined</header>
          <text>In this section, the term <term>eligible investor</term> means an eligible investor as defined in <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Foreign Assistance Act of 1961/s:238/ss:c">section 238(c) of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961</cato:entity-ref> (<cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/22/2198/c">22
			 U.S.C. 2198(c)</cato:entity-ref>)</cato:entity> or described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Foreign Assistance Act of 1961/s:204/ss:a">section 204(a)</cato:entity-ref> of this Act.</text>
        </subsection>
        <subsection commented="no" id="idD6FA7733B90D4C31B67A21DCCA536E28">
          <enum>(c)</enum>
          <header>Termination of pilot program</header>
          <text>The pilot program under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Energize Africa Act of 2014/s:205/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref> shall terminate on the date that is 5 years after the date
			 of the enactment of this Act.</text>
        </subsection>
        <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id170A2409A65944ABBF01C158F38A2FE0">
          <enum>(d)</enum>
          <header>Continued validity of existing loans and guarantees</header>
          <text>Notwithstanding <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Energize Africa Act of 2014/s:205/ss:c" proposed="true">subsection (c)</cato:entity-ref>, any loans made or local currency guarantees issued pursuant to the
			 pilot program under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Energize Africa Act of 2014/s:205/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref> before the date that is 5 years after
			 the date of the enactment of this Act shall remain valid on and after that
			 date.</text>
        </subsection>
      </section>
      <section id="idd0ecb0f146514e6080b3b35e9778cf47">
        <enum>206.</enum>
        <header>Extension of maximum term of obligation for renewable energy projects in sub-Saharan Africa</header>
        <text display-inline="no-display-inline">
          <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Foreign Assistance Act of 1961/s:237/ss:e">Section 237(e) of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2197">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/22/2197/e">22 U.S.C. 2197(e)</cato:entity-ref>
          </external-xref>)</cato:entity> is amended to read as
			 follows:</text>
        <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3e83369c17a74e77bb42a2681e2f2488" style="OLC">
          <subsection id="idf34e6b6562774da08868080ca5be3905">
            <enum>(e)</enum>
            <header>Maximum term of obligation</header>
            <paragraph id="ided03dba9e625477f81b90494e308b2da">
              <enum>(1)</enum>
              <header>In general</header>
              <text>Except as provided in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Foreign Assistance Act of 1961/s:237/ss:e/p:2" proposed="true">paragraph (2)</cato:entity-ref>, no insurance, guaranty, or reinsurance of any equity
			 investment shall extend beyond 20 years after the date of issuance.</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="id216797cf29db494d8c079f51b72fc41f">
              <enum>(2)</enum>
              <header>Extended term of obligation for certain projects</header>
              <text>An insurance, guaranty, or reinsurance of an equity investment in a renewable energy project in
			 sub-Saharan Africa may extend up to 30 years after the date of issuance.</text>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
        </quoted-block>
      </section>
      <section id="idFFDCB93792CB4B17B7B2FCDD6BA60053">
        <enum>207.</enum>
        <header>Inspector General</header>
        <subsection id="id8f57ca7c623146ca8f11997bfa832caf">
          <enum>(a)</enum>
          <header>In general</header>
          <text>
            <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Inspector General Act of 1978/s:8G/ss:a">Section 8G(a) of the Inspector General Act of 1978</cato:entity-ref> (<cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc-appendix/5">5 U.S.C. App.</cato:entity-ref>)</cato:entity> is amended—</text>
          <paragraph id="id6AA2AB267A104C16B82B5F72AEAF0DE1">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <text>in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Inspector General Act of 1978/s:8G/ss:a/p:2">paragraph (2)</cato:entity-ref>, by inserting <quote>the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="7100" entity-type="federal-body">Overseas Private Investment Corporation</cato:entity-ref>,</quote> after <quote>the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="4900" entity-type="federal-body">National Science Foundation</cato:entity-ref>,</quote>; and</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="id42990EFA5F5A471098252464175365D8">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <text>in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Inspector General Act of 1978/s:8G/ss:a/p:4">paragraph (4)</cato:entity-ref>—</text>
            <subparagraph commented="no" id="id900eeff31ed24618853b6dc7fd7cfb8b">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Inspector General Act of 1978/s:8G/ss:a/p:4/sp:G">subparagraph (G)</cato:entity-ref>, by striking <quote>; and</quote> and inserting a semicolon;</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph commented="no" id="idc1359354e55a4611ad4da2ca31114a47">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Inspector General Act of 1978/s:8G/ss:a/p:4/sp:H">subparagraph (H)</cato:entity-ref>, by inserting <quote>and</quote> after the semicolon; and</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph commented="no" id="idc3460dbb304f471ebfc07e0a8519c497">
              <enum>(C)</enum>
              <text>by adding at the end the following:</text>
              <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2bb88f9f4cdf44509dbab6d33e5b860f" style="OLC">
                <subparagraph id="id48d627a2a0d64a248e8eb7422949c8a9">
                  <enum>(I)</enum>
                  <text>with respect to the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="7100" entity-type="federal-body">Overseas Private Investment Corporation</cato:entity-ref>, such term means the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Board of Directors" entity-parent-id="7100">Board of Directors
			 of the Overseas Private Investment Corporation</cato:entity-ref> (established under <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
                      <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Foreign Assistance Act of 1961/s:233/ss:b">section
			 233(b) of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2193">
                      <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/22/2193/b">22 U.S.C. 2193(b)</cato:entity-ref>
                    </external-xref>)</cato:entity>;</text>
                </subparagraph>
                <after-quoted-block>. </after-quoted-block>
              </quoted-block>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="idbd3fc2433b8a40a692ea3f5516049ebc">
          <enum>(b)</enum>
          <header>Conforming amendment</header>
          <text>
            <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Foreign Assistance Act of 1961/s:239">Section 239 of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2199">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/22/2199">22 U.S.C. 2199</cato:entity-ref>
            </external-xref>)</cato:entity> is amended by striking
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Foreign Assistance Act of 1961/s:239/ss:e">subsection (e)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
        </subsection>
      </section>
      <section id="id210dc1d4a6a74d76a77c350e4ab705ab">
        <enum>208.</enum>
        <header>Assessment of customer satisfaction</header>
        <text display-inline="no-display-inline">
          <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Foreign Assistance Act of 1961/s:239">Section 239 of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2199">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/22/2199">22 U.S.C. 2199</cato:entity-ref>
          </external-xref>)</cato:entity> is amended by adding at the end
			 the following:</text>
        <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2aaf5897dc834c5ea46e4f42cfc8f9f7" style="OLC">
          <subsection id="id601ec81b4c86405c8edd6302e9fee688">
            <enum>(l)</enum>
            <header>Assessment of customer satisfaction</header>
            <paragraph id="id7ce537232a6847bc8713cdb6840c4674">
              <enum>(1)</enum>
              <header>In general</header>
              <text>Each fiscal year, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7100">Corporation</cato:entity-ref> shall conduct a survey of a sample of its customers to assess the
			 satisfaction of those customers with the operation and procedures of the
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7100">Corporation</cato:entity-ref>, with particular attention to customers of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7100">Corporation</cato:entity-ref>
			 that are small businesses and cooperatives.</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="idca0d08cd16ef4a14b159b7070243d5ad">
              <enum>(2)</enum>
              <header>Report to congress</header>
              <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7100">Corporation</cato:entity-ref> shall include in its annual report required under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Foreign Assistance Act of 1961/s:240A">section 240A</cato:entity-ref> a report on the
			 survey conducted under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Foreign Assistance Act of 1961/s:239/ss:l/p:1" proposed="true">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref> that  includes, as appropriate,
			 summaries of recommendations made by customers of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7100">Corporation</cato:entity-ref> with
			 respect to ways
			 to improve the operations and procedures of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7100">Corporation</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
        </quoted-block>
      </section>
      <section id="id6734e35f7650434d8086fdc82305f8c0">
        <enum>209.</enum>
        <header>Schedule B hiring authority</header>
        <text display-inline="no-display-inline">In carrying out the purposes of this Act and its responsibilities under this Act, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="7100" entity-type="federal-body">Overseas
			 Private
			 Investment
			 Corporation</cato:entity-ref> may, in addition to other authorities available, employ not
			 more than 20 individuals, on a limited-appointment basis, pursuant to
			 schedule B of subpart C of part 213 of title 5, Code of Federal
			 Regulations, for the purpose of furthering specific efforts in sub-Saharan
			 Africa with respect to power production and generation and distribution,
			 including off-grid efforts.</text>
      </section>
      <section id="ide4125a555d9c4aadb65ac20e9c6b4512">
        <enum>210.</enum>
        <header>Sense of Congress on funding</header>
        <text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> that appropriations for the administrative expenses and activities
			 under <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Foreign Assistance of 1961/s:234/ss:g/p:5">section 234(g)(5) of the Foreign Assistance of 1961</cato:entity-ref> (<cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/22/2194/g/5">22 U.S.C.
			 2194(g)(5)</cato:entity-ref>)</cato:entity> of the
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7100">Corporation</cato:entity-ref> in each of the fiscal years 2015 through 2019 should be
			 adjusted to reflect the resources needed to carry out the purposes of this
			 Act, including enabling the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7100">Corporation</cato:entity-ref> to hire personnel and to upgrade
			 systems infrastructure, as appropriate, to implement the purposes of this
			 Act.</text>
      </section>
      <section commented="no" id="id264565cc743744a9bca7fed0e89457c3">
        <enum>211.</enum>
        <header>Report on equity authority</header>
        <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Inspector General" entity-parent-id="7100">Inspector General of the
			 Overseas Private
			 Investment Corporation</cato:entity-ref> (appointed pursuant to the amendments made by
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Energize Africa Act of 2014/s:207" proposed="true">section 207</cato:entity-ref>) shall submit to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> a report on the
			 authorities of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7100">Corporation</cato:entity-ref> to effectively meet its statutory
			 objectives, including as modified by this Act, that includes an assessment
			 of the
			 following:</text>
        <paragraph commented="no" id="id87AD0FDE04D2499EBB947BBD7AB5ED20">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The effectiveness of the existing authorities of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7100">Corporation</cato:entity-ref> in
			 promoting investment in energy and infrastructure projects.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph commented="no" id="id3646DA653A3B4E9BA321702E334C9A05">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The effect granting the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7100">Corporation</cato:entity-ref> the authority to
			 directly invest in projects would have on—</text>
          <subparagraph commented="no" id="id5F30668D78D54326A9CFAAB89136C2C6">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the ability of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7100">Corporation</cato:entity-ref> to support development projects, including
			 infrastructure and energy projects, that advance the foreign policy goals
			 of the United States;</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph commented="no" id="id418BE082B60D4159AD53C638C9F8A68C">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the risk profile of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7100">Corporation</cato:entity-ref>;</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph commented="no" id="idEFD50B14F11948E5B572E5BAFDCBEF72">
            <enum>(C)</enum>
            <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the budget of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7100">Corporation</cato:entity-ref>;</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph commented="no" id="id974B430F850F402AA6C926C2835D0CCF">
            <enum>(D)</enum>
            <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the success rate of projects, measured in terms of capacity to meet development
			 goals and financial targets;</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph commented="no" id="id679BA71C39EF4C9A98F84B35F64D2D8B">
            <enum>(E)</enum>
            <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">sectors or regions in which equity investment would be particularly beneficial or harmful to
			 furthering the
			 mission of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7100">Corporation</cato:entity-ref>; and</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph commented="no" id="idAAA1EF53D7AB492EA95AEC2F712842DD">
            <enum>(F)</enum>
            <text>the capability of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7100">Corporation</cato:entity-ref> to meet its statutory objectives, including as modified by this
			 Act, including whether granting such authority would limit the
			 effectiveness of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7100">Corporation</cato:entity-ref> in meeting its goals with respect to
			 stimulating United States private sector investment in such projects,
			 including investment by small- and medium-sized enterprises.</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph commented="no" id="id2A6DDD3DB6F44DAC871CFD0BD0CDC1A4">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The effect of any other financing instruments that may be better suited to energy or
			 infrastructure projects.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph commented="no" id="idBBF9A83FF0324347AF634904FE204F19">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The competitiveness of financing provided by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7100">Corporation</cato:entity-ref> relative to financing provided by
			 development finance institutions of other
			 major economies.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </section>
    </title>
  </legis-body>
  <official-title-amendment>Amend the title so as to read: <quote>A bill to establish a comprehensive United States Government policy to encourage the efforts of
			 countries in sub-Saharan Africa to improve access to and the
			 affordability, reliability, and
			 sustainability of power, and for other purposes. </quote>.</official-title-amendment>
  <endorsement>
    <action-date>July 24, 2014</action-date>
    <action-desc>Reported with amendments and an amendment to the title</action-desc>
  </endorsement>
</bill>
</doc>