<doc>
  <docmeta id="113sres447is">
    <bill congress="113" type="sres" number="447" version="is"/>
    <revision size="6889" annotations="0" status="complete" id="7" commit-time="2014-10-27T18:13:24Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113sres447is/7.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <resolution xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print">
	<metadata>
<dublinCore>
<dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">113 SRES 447 IS: Recognizing the threats to freedom of the press and expression around the world and reaffirming freedom of the press as a priority in the efforts of the United States Government to promote democracy and good governance. </dc:title>
<dc:publisher xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">2014-05-15</dc:date>
<dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">113th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session display="yes">2d Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. RES. 447</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20140515">May 15, 2014</action-date>
			<action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="S309">Mr. Casey</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S350">Mr. Rubio</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations</committee-name>
      </action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">Recognizing the threats to freedom of the press and expression around the world and reaffirming
			 freedom of the press as a priority in the efforts of the United States
			 Government to promote democracy and good governance. </official-title>
	</form>
	<preamble>
		<whereas>
      <text>Whereas Article 19 of the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="United Nations Universal Declaration of Human Rights">United Nations Universal Declaration of Human Rights</cato:entity-ref>, adopted at Paris
			 December 10, 1948, states that <quote>everyone has the right to freedom of opinion and expression; this right includes freedom to hold
			 opinions without interference and to seek, receive, and impart information
			 and ideas through any media and regardless of frontiers</quote>;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas, in 1993, the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" value="United Nations General Assembly" entity-parent-id="19UN">United Nations General Assembly</cato:entity-ref> proclaimed May 3 of each year as <quote>World Press Freedom Day</quote> to celebrate the fundamental principles of freedom of the press, to evaluate freedom of the press
			 around the world, to defend the media from attacks on its independence,
			 and to pay tribute to journalists who have lost their lives in the
			 exercise of their profession;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas, on December 18, 2013, the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" value="United Nations General Assembly" entity-parent-id="19UN">United Nations General Assembly</cato:entity-ref> adopted a resolution
			 (A/RES/68/163) on the safety of journalists and the issue of impunity,
			 which unequivocally condemns  all attacks and violence against journalists
			 and media workers, including torture, extrajudicial killings, enforced
			 disappearances, arbitrary detention, and intimidation and harassment in
			 both conflict and non-conflict situations;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas 2014 is the 21st anniversary of World Press Freedom Day, which focuses on the theme <quote>Media Freedom for a Better Future: Shaping the Post-2015 Development Agenda</quote>;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the <cato:entity entity-type="law-citation">
          <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Press Act of 2009">Daniel Pearl Freedom of the Press Act of 2009</cato:entity-ref> (<cato:entity-ref entity-type="public-law" value="public-law/111/16622">Public Law
			 111–16622</cato:entity-ref>; <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/note">U.S.C. 2151 note</cato:entity-ref>)</cato:entity>, which was passed by unanimous consent in the
			 <cato:entity-ref entity-id="0010" entity-type="federal-body">Senate</cato:entity-ref> and signed
			 into law by President Barack Obama in 2010, expanded the examination of
			 freedom of the press around the world in the annual human rights report of
			 the <cato:entity-ref entity-id="1900" entity-type="federal-body">Department of State</cato:entity-ref>;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas, according to Reporters Without Borders, 71 journalists and 39 citizen journalists were
			 killed in 2013 in connection with their collection and
			 dissemination of news and information;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas, according to the Committee to Protect Journalists, the 3 deadliest countries for
			 journalists on assignment in 2013 were Syria, Iraq, and Egypt, and in
			 Syria, the deadliest country for such journalists, an unprecedented number
			 of journalists were abducted;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas, according to the Committee to Protect Journalists, 617 journalists have been murdered
			 since
			 1992 without the perpetrators of such crimes facing punishment;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas, according to the Committee to Protect Journalists, the 5 countries with the highest number
			 of unsolved journalist murders are Iraq, the Philippines, Algeria,
			 Colombia, and Somalia;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas, according to Reporters Without Borders, 826 journalists and 127 citizen journalists were
			 arrested in 2013;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas, according to the Committee to Protect Journalists, 211 journalists worldwide were in
			 prison
			 on December 1, 2013;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas, according to Reporters Without Borders, the 5 countries with the highest number of
			 journalists in prison are Syria, China, Eritrea, Turkey, and Iran;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas, according to Reporters Without Borders, the Government of Syria and extremist rebel
			 militias have intentionally targeted journalists,
			 causing dramatic repercussions for the freedom of the press throughout the
			 region;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the Government of the Russian Federation has engaged in an unprecedented campaign to
			 silence the
			 independent press and undermine freedom of expression, including its
			 recent efforts to destabilize Ukraine;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas freedom of the press is a key component of democratic governance, the activism of civil
			 society, and socioeconomic development; and</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas freedom of the press enhances public accountability, transparency, and participation: Now,
			 therefore, be it</text>
		</whereas>
  </preamble>
	<resolution-body>
		<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="S1" section-type="undesignated-section">
      <enum/>
      <text>That the <cato:entity-ref entity-id="0010" entity-type="federal-body">Senate</cato:entity-ref>—</text>
      <paragraph id="id6ba2bb7c4de94785ae665b6cc9f07fae">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text>expresses concern about the threats to freedom of the press and expression around the world
			 following World Press Freedom Day, held on May 3, 2014;</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id2cdef068e1484410bf82c2e0ef49adfe">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text>commends journalists and media workers around the world for their essential role in promoting
			 government accountability, defending democratic activity, and
			 strengthening civil society, despite threats to their safety;</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id208722e13b6b4283a919777ba5beafe0">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <text>pays tribute to the journalists who have lost their lives carrying out their work;</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id4A7DA12C83464268AE1203C20F199C66">
        <enum>(4)</enum>
        <text>calls on governments abroad to implement United Nations General Assembly Resolution (A/RES/68/163),
			 by thoroughly investigating and seeking to resolve outstanding cases of
			 violence against journalists, including murders and kidnappings, while
			 ensuring the protection of witnesses;</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="ida54ffab646b74b77baea4ead64df990a">
        <enum>(5)</enum>
        <text>condemns all actions around the world that suppress freedom of the press, such as the recent
			 kidnappings of journalists and media workers in eastern Ukraine by
			 pro-Russian militant groups;</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id408ec30935b04de69a7fef245e3bbdc9">
        <enum>(6)</enum>
        <text>reaffirms the centrality of freedom of the press to efforts by the United States Government to
			 support democracy, mitigate conflict, and promote good governance
			 domestically and around the world; and</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="idbe4dec3f6d8b42309b8dea59a83ec4ac">
        <enum>(7)</enum>
        <text>calls on the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> and the <cato:entity-ref entity-id="1900" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref>—</text>
        <subparagraph id="id5fca428e3cae41ebab6e066ddd80e3c9">
          <enum>(A)</enum>
          <text>to improve the means by which the United States Government rapidly identifies, publicizes, and
			 responds to threats against freedom of the press around the world;</text>
        </subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="id9f2c9f0781c0492a9968bb643dfe8b67">
          <enum>(B)</enum>
          <text>to urge foreign governments to transparently investigate and bring to justice the perpetrators of
			 attacks against journalists; and</text>
        </subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="idb30d153546f849e88f45cf289abe3991">
          <enum>(C)</enum>
          <text>to highlight the issue of threats against freedom of the press year-round.</text>
				</subparagraph>
      </paragraph>
    </section>
  </resolution-body>
</resolution>
</doc>