<doc>
  <docmeta id="113sres226is">
    <bill congress="113" type="sres" number="226" version="is"/>
    <revision size="5116" annotations="0" status="complete" id="3" commit-time="2013-09-17T21:17:21Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113sres226is/3.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <resolution xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>113 SRES 226 IS: Celebrating the 100th anniversary of the birth of James Cleveland Jesse Owens and honoring him for his accomplishments and steadfast commitment to promoting the civil rights of all people. </dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2013-09-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">113th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session display="yes">1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. RES. 226</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20130912">September 12, 2013</action-date>
			<action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="S307">Mr. Brown</sponsor> (for himself,
			 <cosponsor name-id="S349">Mr. Portman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S253">Mr. Durbin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S339">Mr.
			 Kirk</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S258">Ms. Landrieu</cosponsor>, and
			 <cosponsor name-id="S261">Mr. Sessions</cosponsor>) submitted the following
			 resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>
      </action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">Celebrating the 100th anniversary of the
		  birth of James Cleveland <term>Jesse</term> Owens and honoring him for his
		  accomplishments and steadfast commitment to promoting the civil rights of all
		  people. </official-title>
	</form>
	<preamble>
		<whereas>
      <text>Whereas James Cleveland <term>Jesse</term> Owens was born
			 on September 12, 1913 in Oakville, Alabama;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas Jesse Owens, the youngest of 10 children of
			 sharecroppers and the grandson of a slave, moved with his family at the age of
			 9 to Cleveland, Ohio as part of the Great Migration;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas, as a student at Fairmount Junior High School,
			 Jesse Owens broke junior high school world records for the high jump and the
			 broad jump;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas Jesse Owens attended East Technical High School in
			 Cleveland, Ohio where, as a member of the track team, he placed first in 75 of
			 the 79 races he entered during his senior year, set the world record in the
			 220-yard dash, and tied the world record in the 100-yard dash;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas Jesse Owens, the <term>Buckeye Bullet</term>,
			 matriculated at the Ohio State University in 1933 after attracting national
			 attention as a high school athlete;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas, while attending classes, training, and breaking a
			 number of track and field records, Jesse Owens worked various jobs, including
			 as an elevator operator at the Ohio State Capitol, a waiter, a gas station
			 attendant, and a library employee;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas, due to his race, Jesse Owens was barred from
			 living on campus at the Ohio State University, denied service at restaurants
			 near the University, and forced to stay in segregated hotels;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas, on May 25, 1935, in a 45-minute period during the
			 Big Ten Track and Field Championships in Ann Arbor, Michigan, Jesse Owens,
			 competing with an injured back, tied the world record in the 100-yard dash and
			 set new world records in the long jump, the 220-yard dash, and the 220-yard low
			 hurdles;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas, as of the 2012 Summer Olympics, only two men had
			 surpassed the long jump record Jesse Owens set in 1935;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas, at the 1936 Summer Olympics, Jesse Owens won 4
			 gold medals, tied the world record in the 100-meter dash, and set new Olympic
			 records in the 200-meter race, the long jump, and the 400-meter relay;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas Jesse Owens’ resilience and heroic performance at
			 the 1936 Summer Olympics exposed the struggle against racial bigotry and
			 publicly defied Adolf Hitler’s intention of proving that ethnicity was a
			 predetermining factor for achievement;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the record-breaking performance by Jesse Owens at
			 the 1936 Summer Olympics was never recognized by President Franklin D.
			 Roosevelt or President Harry S. Truman, but was later recognized in 1955 by
			 President Dwight D. Eisenhower, who referred to Jesse Owens as an
			 <term>Ambassador of Sport</term>;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas, following his Olympic career, Jesse Owens resumed
			 his commitment to public service by spending much of his time working with
			 community groups such as the Boys Clubs of America, chronicling his personal
			 story to magnify the importance of equality and civil rights;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas, during the 1950s, Jesse Owens worked with the
			 <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Department of State</cato:entity-ref> to promote democracy abroad as an Ambassador of Goodwill
			 during the Cold War and advocated for socioeconomic equality, individuality,
			 freedom, and love of country;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas Jesse Owens was awarded the Presidential Medal of
			 Freedom by President Gerald R. Ford in 1976 and the Living Legend Award by
			 President Jimmy Carter in 1979, and was posthumously awarded the Congressional
			 Gold Medal by President George H.W. Bush in 1990; and</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the integrity, courage, and strength of character
			 that Jesse Owens demonstrated remain an example for all people of the United
			 States: Now, therefore, be it</text>
		</whereas>
  </preamble>
	<resolution-body>
		<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="S1" section-type="undesignated-section">
      <enum/>
      <text>That the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0010">Senate</cato:entity-ref>—</text>
			<paragraph id="ida4b3ead1f6a24bb29c2a4ab1939637c0">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text>honors and
			 celebrates the 100th anniversary of the birth of James Cleveland
			 <term>Jesse</term> Owens; and</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="idef9689bdf5214d939f927237e78803a5">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text>supports and
			 encourages the people of the United States to recognize the contributions of
			 Jesse Owens to the Olympic Games, collegiate athletics, international race
			 relations, and democracy.</text>
			</paragraph>
    </section>
  </resolution-body>
</resolution>
</doc>