<doc>
  <docmeta id="113s1104is">
    <bill congress="113" type="s" number="1104" version="is"/>
    <revision size="8777" annotations="0" status="complete" id="5" commit-time="2013-08-07T19:56:43Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113s1104is/5.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public">
	<metadata>
<dublinCore>
<title>113 S1104 IS: Assessing Progress in Haiti Act</title>
<publisher>U.S. Senate</publisher>
<date>2013-06-06</date>
<format>text/xml</format>
<language>EN</language>
<rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
		<congress>113th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. 1104</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20130606">June 6, 2013</action-date>
			<action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="S282">Mr. Nelson</sponsor> (for himself,
			 <cosponsor name-id="S258">Ms. Landrieu</cosponsor>, and
			 <cosponsor name-id="S308">Mr. Cardin</cosponsor>) introduced the following
			 bill; which was read twice and referred to the
			 <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign
			 Relations</committee-name>
      </action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To measure the progress of recovery and development
		  efforts in Haiti following the earthquake of January 12, 2010, and for other
		  purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body>
		<section id="S1" section-type="section-one">
      <enum>1.</enum>
      <header>Short
			 title</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as
			 the <quote>
          <short-title>Assessing Progress in Haiti
			 Act</short-title>
        </quote>.</text>
		</section>
    <section id="ide097121824e84ad58e98894a09383b51">
      <enum>2.</enum>
      <header>Findings</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">
        <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> makes the following
			 findings:</text>
			<paragraph id="idff6f96214d6f41ec8a5099caa8a874ad">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text>According to the
			 Government of Haiti, more than 316,000 people died as a result of the
			 earthquake that struck 15 miles southwest of Port-au-Prince on January 12,
			 2010, including 103 citizens of the United States and more than 100 United
			 Nations personnel.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="idaddd3c3645864d05858290a985db48b4">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text>According to the
			 United Nations and the International Organization for Migration, an estimated
			 3,000,000 people were directly affected by the disaster, and more than
			 2,100,000 people were displaced from their homes.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="idd08675a1c7874dd39cde06dd6121697a">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <text>The Post Disaster
			 Needs Assessment conducted by the Government of Haiti, the United Nations, the
			 World Bank, the Inter-American Development Bank, and others estimated that
			 damage and economic losses totaled $7,804,000,000, approximately 120 percent of
			 Haiti’s gross domestic product in 2009.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id7d807f8f19204f269d5373b1e8b6d244">
        <enum>(4)</enum>
        <text>The initial
			 emergency response of the men and women of the United States Government, led by
			 the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7200">United States Agency for International Development</cato:entity-ref> and the United States
			 Southern Command, as well as of cities, towns, individuals, businesses, and
			 philanthropic organizations across the United States, was swift and
			 resolute.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="ida0dc3f7596fb4ff7b821ebb5eace8ff9">
        <enum>(5)</enum>
        <text>According to the
			 Government of Haiti, numerous multilateral agencies such as the United Nations,
			 and international nongovernmental organizations, Haiti faces an ongoing food
			 crisis as a result of the earthquake and subsequent damage caused by tropical
			 storms and hurricanes, as well as long-term neglect of the agriculture
			 sector.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id99c4dd9aef90434986bb0b5e92c38832">
        <enum>(6)</enum>
        <text>According to the
			 International Organization for Migration, approximately 320,000 people remain
			 in spontaneous and organized camps in Haiti, and reports by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0500">General
			 Accountability Office</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Inspector General" entity-parent-id="7200">Inspector General for the United States Agency for
			 International Development</cato:entity-ref>, and civil society organizations indicate that the
			 pace of recovery and development has lagged significantly behind the emergency
			 relief phase.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id57c7964346e841888b914081e1350234">
        <enum>(7)</enum>
        <text>On October 21,
			 2010, an outbreak of cholera was detected and according to the Haitian Ministry
			 of Public Health and Population, as of February 17, 2013, more than 8,000
			 people had died from cholera and more than 647,500 had been infected with the
			 disease.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id39d82c71cce8499db664ea4854da8f8e">
        <enum>(8)</enum>
        <text>The United
			 Nations Office of the Special Envoy for Haiti estimates that, including donor
			 pledges and other support, approximately $6,400,000,000 has been disbursed,
			 with an additional amount of $3,800,000,000 committed, to assist in Haiti’s
			 recovery and development.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id5e2d590c1158490c8ce5f35c9277faf0">
        <enum>(9)</enum>
        <text>The United States
			 Government has appropriated approximately $3,600,000,000 for relief, recovery,
			 and development in Haiti since the earthquake, of which $2,600,000,000 had been
			 disbursed as of March 2013. The United States Government has also provided more
			 than $95,000,000 in aid to combat the cholera epidemic and care for the
			 victims.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="idf5fe2d828d7f4c3fa590a133c0341bec">
        <enum>(10)</enum>
        <text>Significant
			 challenges remain in Haiti, which will require continued recovery and
			 development aid from the international community for the foreseeable
			 future.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id35b9c01bba8248f38671edb2842a9f5d">
        <enum>(11)</enum>
        <text>The Haitian
			 diaspora has also played an essential role in Haiti’s reconstruction, and the
			 United States Government should take steps to increase outreach and encourage
			 participation by Haitian Americans in recovery and development activities in
			 Haiti.</text>
			</paragraph>
    </section>
    <section id="id13d04c23a6ff40c5b18c2f4f9e57db77">
      <enum>3.</enum>
      <header>Report</header>
			<subsection id="ida1c76d0c76cf4504aa7ab11deda836f8">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Report
			 required</header>
        <text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment
			 of this Act, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0500">Comptroller General of the United States</cato:entity-ref> shall submit to
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> a report on the status of post-earthquake recovery and development
			 efforts in Haiti, including efforts to prevent the spread of cholera and treat
			 persons infected with the disease.</text>
			</subsection>
      <subsection id="id9a4be44cb1aa40fd98c0d4d860a7502e">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Content</header>
        <text>The
			 report required by <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Assessing Progress in Haiti Act/s:3/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref> shall include the following elements:</text>
				<paragraph id="idc5a3c7ce4fda474086571881effafaff">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>An assessment of
			 the progress of recovery and development efforts, as embodied in the Haiti
			 Rebuilding and Development Strategy, compared to what remains to be achieved to
			 meet specific goals, including—</text>
					<subparagraph id="ida1e3b5e88d3f4b019cce9d2da1576d44">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>the amount of
			 funds disbursed and any significant changes to the Strategy since January 2010,
			 with an explanation of such changes;</text>
					</subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="idf2f1abf04dcf435a83d9b0b667976320">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>the amounts
			 obligated and expended on United States Government programs and activities
			 since January 2010 to implement the Strategy, including award data on the use
			 of implementing partners at the prime level and at the subprime level of
			 $25,000 and above, and disbursement data from prime implementing partners;
			 and</text>
					</subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="id2c751a68b3704fc7850087c8323d1166">
            <enum>(C)</enum>
            <text>a description of
			 goals and quantitative and qualitative indicators to evaluate the progress,
			 achievement, or lack of achievement of such goals, within specific time frames,
			 that comprise the Strategy at the program level.</text>
					</subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="id43033121c54f461285c33c24a8401ebb">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>An assessment of
			 the manner in which the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Department of State</cato:entity-ref> and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7200">United States Agency for
			 International Development</cato:entity-ref> are working with ministries and local authorities in
			 Haiti, including the extent to which the Government of Haiti has been consulted
			 on the establishment of goals and time frames and on the design and
			 implementation of new programs under the Strategy.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="idee546e727f3f4318a298806d24aa6c29">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <text>An assessment of
			 the extent to which civil society and grassroots organizations in Haiti have
			 been consulted on the establishment of goals and time frames and on the design
			 and implementation of new programs under the Strategy.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="idde79fba2e29344c180b3ae77a8076637">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
          <text>An assessment of
			 efforts to increase the involvement of the private sector in Haiti in recovery
			 and development activities.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="id50b215a30679432793cece4052c15944">
          <enum>(5)</enum>
          <text>An assessment of
			 how consideration for vulnerable populations, including internally displaced
			 persons, women, children, orphans, and persons with disabilities, have been
			 incorporated in the design and implementation of new programs and
			 infrastructure.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="id27f5c52c370b48ec9909d2e3359c6da5">
          <enum>(6)</enum>
          <text>An assessment of
			 how agriculture and infrastructure programs are impacting food security and the
			 livelihoods of smallholder farmers in Haiti.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="id9330754842d44b128adc90113fa121a1">
          <enum>(7)</enum>
          <text>An assessment of
			 recovery and development coordination among United States Government agencies
			 and between the United States Government and other donors.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="id13eda4c134a943a980b9e854f4520a77">
          <enum>(8)</enum>
          <text>A description of
			 the United States Government’s efforts, including diplomatic efforts, to help
			 abate the cholera epidemic in Haiti, in coordination with the Government of
			 Haiti, the United Nations, and other relevant entities.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="idfb7c2ab37f2a4ef78c97bf1cbc18b53e">
          <enum>(9)</enum>
          <text>A description of
			 mechanisms for communicating the progress of recovery and development efforts
			 to people in Haiti.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="ide20db75f5e8849a4a7bd12e2ea44ed06">
          <enum>(10)</enum>
          <text>An assessment of
			 the steps the Government of Haiti is taking to strengthen its capacity to
			 receive individuals who are removed, excluded, or deported from the United
			 States.</text>
				</paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="idfd581e2f941045a69a5665adddcfea38">
        <enum>(c)</enum>
        <header>Use of
			 previously appropriated funds</header>
        <text>Funding for the report required
			 under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Assessing Progress in Haiti Act/s:3/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref> shall be made available from existing funds appropriated
			 to the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Department of State</cato:entity-ref> and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7200">United States Agency for International
			 Development</cato:entity-ref> for assistance to Haiti, and shall not exceed $75,000.</text>
			</subsection>
    </section>
  </legis-body>
</bill>
</doc>