<doc>
  <docmeta id="113sres273ats">
    <bill congress="113" type="sres" number="273" version="ats"/>
    <revision size="2650" annotations="0" status="complete" id="3" commit-time="2013-10-18T21:54:06Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113sres273ats/3.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <resolution xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print">
  <metadata>
<dublinCore>
<title>113 SRES 273 ATS: Designating October 26, 2013, as Day of the Deployed.</title>
<publisher>U.S. Senate</publisher>
<date>2013-10-16</date>
<format>text/xml</format>
<language>EN</language>
<rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code>
    <congress display="yes">113th CONGRESS</congress>
    <session display="yes">1st Session</session>
    <legis-num>S. RES. 273</legis-num>
    <current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
    <action display="yes">
      <action-date date="20131016">October 16, 2013</action-date>
      <action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="S344">Mr. Hoeven</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S308">Mr. Cardin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S260">Mr. Roberts</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S342">Mr. Blunt</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S314">Mr. Tester</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S360">Ms. Heitkamp</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was considered and agreed to</action-desc>
    </action>
    <legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
    <official-title display="yes">Designating October 26, 2013, as <term>Day of the Deployed</term>.</official-title>
  </form>
  <preamble>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas more than 2,500,000 individuals serve as members of the United States Armed Forces;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas several hundred thousand members of the Armed Forces rotate each year through deployments to over 150 countries in every region of the world;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas more than 2,300,000 members of the Armed Forces have deployed to the area of operations of the United States Central Command since the September 11, 2001, terrorist attacks;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the United States is kept strong and free by the loyal military personnel from the active, National Guard, and Reserve components, who protect the precious heritage of the country through their positive declaration and actions;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas members of the Armed Forces serving at home and abroad have courageously answered the call to duty to defend the ideals of the United States and to preserve peace and freedom around the world;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas members of the Armed Forces personify the virtues of patriotism, service, duty, courage, and sacrifice;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the families of members of the Armed Forces make important and significant sacrifices for the United States;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0010">Senate</cato:entity-ref> designated October 26 as <term>Day of the Deployed</term> in 2011 and 2012; and</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas all 50 States designated October 26 as <term>Day of the Deployed</term> in 2012: Now, therefore, be it</text>
    </whereas>
  </preamble>
  <resolution-body>
    <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="S1" section-type="undesignated-section">
      <enum/>
      <text>That  the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0010">Senate</cato:entity-ref>—</text>
      <paragraph id="id5DE5EF7ED62C40FCB8824CD979108D3C">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text>designates October 26, 2013, as <term>Day of the Deployed</term>;</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id830F5B5509D04FDAB373B4295EF112D5">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text>honors the deployed members of the United States Armed Forces and their families;</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id17C6C6FAFC834A93937631A5CB284B4D">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <text>calls on the people of the United States to reflect on the service of those members of the Armed Forces, wherever they serve, past, present, and future; and</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id2AD0D86F571446B8948568FE6CEC7258">
        <enum>(4)</enum>
        <text>encourages the people of the United States to observe Day of the Deployed with appropriate ceremonies and activities.</text>
      </paragraph>
    </section>
  </resolution-body>
</resolution>
</doc>