<doc>
  <docmeta id="113sres184ats">
    <bill congress="113" type="sres" number="184" version="ats"/>
    <revision size="6119" annotations="0" status="complete" id="3" commit-time="2013-08-12T18:27:51Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113sres184ats/3.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <resolution xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print">
	<metadata>
<dublinCore>
<title>113 SRES 184 ATS: Recognizing refugee women and girls on World Refugee Day.</title>
<publisher>U.S. Senate</publisher>
<date>2013-06-24</date>
<format>text/xml</format>
<language>EN</language>
<rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">113th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session display="yes">1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. RES. 184</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20130624">June 24, 2013</action-date>
			<action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="S223">Mrs. Boxer</sponsor> (for herself,
			 <cosponsor name-id="S258">Ms. Landrieu</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S311">Ms. Klobuchar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S331">Mrs.
			 Gillibrand</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S229">Mrs. Murray</cosponsor>,
			 <cosponsor name-id="S324">Mrs. Shaheen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S182">Ms. Mikulski</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S366">Ms.
			 Warren</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S361">Ms. Hirono</cosponsor>,
			 <cosponsor name-id="S221">Mrs. Feinstein</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S360">Ms. Heitkamp</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S284">Ms.
			 Stabenow</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was considered
			 and agreed to</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">Recognizing refugee women and girls on
		  World Refugee Day.</official-title>
	</form>
	<preamble>
		<whereas>
      <text>Whereas June 20 was established by the United Nations as
			 World Refugee Day, a global day to honor the courage, strength, and
			 determination of women, men, and children who are forced to flee their homes
			 under threat of conflict, violence, and persecution;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas, according to the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" value="Office of the United Nations High Commissioner for Refugees" entity-parent-id="19UN">Office of the United Nations
			 High Commissioner for Refugees</cato:entity-ref> (in this preamble referred to as the
			 <term>UNHCR</term>), there are more than 43,000,000 displaced people worldwide,
			 including more than 15,000,000 refugees;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas, according to the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" value="Office of the United Nations High Commissioner for Refugees" entity-parent-id="19UN">UNHCR</cato:entity-ref>, women and girls make up
			 at least 50 percent of any refugee population;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas refugee women and girls work every day, often
			 under the most difficult circumstances, to care for their families, improve
			 their prospects and build a better future;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas refugee women and girls are often at greater risk
			 of sexual violence and exploitation, forced or early marriage, human
			 trafficking, and other forms of gender-based violence;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas refugee women and girls face barriers in accessing
			 education, healthcare, and economic opportunities in countries of
			 asylum;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas, according to the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" value="Office of the United Nations High Commissioner for Refugees" entity-parent-id="19UN">UNHCR</cato:entity-ref>, more than 1,600,000
			 refugees, ¾ of which are women and children, have fled the ongoing violence in
			 Syria;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas, according to the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" value="Office of the United Nations High Commissioner for Refugees">UNHCR</cato:entity-ref>, an estimated 2,700,000
			 people in the Democratic Republic of the Congo have been displaced, and an
			 additional nearly 500,000 Congolese refugees have crossed the border into
			 neighboring countries;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas refugee women and girls are frequently victims of
			 gender-based violence as their displaced status puts them at greater risk,
			 coupled with intense social and cultural stigmas that make actual statistics
			 extremely difficult to compile because underreporting is endemic;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas refugee women and girls have a right to safe and
			 equitable access to humanitarian assistance, including food and cooking fuel,
			 shelter, education, health care, and economic opportunity;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the full and meaningful participation of refugee
			 women and girls in community decision-making is critical to the stability,
			 security, and prosperity of entire communities;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the full participation of refugee women and girls
			 in the design and implementation of assistance programs is vital to ensuring
			 that those programs are equitable, efficient and successful;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the United States is a leader on protection of and
			 humanitarian assistance for refugees, including refugee women and girls;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the United States has recognized the threat that
			 gender-based violence can pose to refugee women and girls by working to
			 strengthen efforts to protect them through the United States National Action
			 Plan on Women, Peace, and Security;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the United States is a leading advocate for the
			 meaningful participation of refugee women in humanitarian programs, peace
			 processes, governance, and recovery programs;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the United States provides critical resources and
			 support to the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" value="Office of the United Nations High Commissioner for Refugees" entity-parent-id="19UN">UNHCR</cato:entity-ref> and other international and nongovernmental organizations
			 working with refugees around the world; and</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the United States has welcomed more than 3,000,000
			 refugees during the last 30 years, who are resettled in communities across the
			 country: Now, therefore, be it</text>
		</whereas>
  </preamble>
	<resolution-body>
		<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="S1" section-type="undesignated-section">
      <enum/>
      <text>That the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0010">Senate</cato:entity-ref>—</text>
			<paragraph id="id107658024d984fb687c2d096896ed162">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text>supports the
			 goals and ideals of World Refugee Day;</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id23acc9f1abd940dcb7843144ad79bdb6">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text>reaffirms its
			 commitment to the protection, well-being, and self-reliance of refugee women
			 and girls and their families in United States humanitarian policy, programs,
			 and diplomacy and recognizes the work of the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">United States Department of State</cato:entity-ref>
			 and the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7200">United States Agency for International Development</cato:entity-ref> to this end;</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id39fcc164309b447ab8f26f8303d73203">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <text>emphasizes the
			 importance of ensuring that humanitarian assistance programs supported by the
			 United States provide safe and equitable access for women and girls and are
			 designed and implemented with their full participation;</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="idf467a38b517a441ca49c339521c8ca8a">
        <enum>(4)</enum>
        <text>reiterates the
			 importance of targeted programs for refugee women and girls that prevent and
			 respond to gender-based violence, support self-reliance, and promote and
			 develop their participation and leadership skills;</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="idff15650df635411b903141d04b9353c7">
        <enum>(5)</enum>
        <text>recognizes the
			 work of the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1954">Bureau of Population, Refugees, and Migration of the Department of
			 State</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" value="Office of Refugee Resettlement" entity-parent-id="7500">Office of Refugee Resettlement of the Department of Health and Human
			 Services</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-parent-id="7003">U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services of the Department of
			 Homeland Security</cato:entity-ref>, nongovernmental organizations, advocacy groups, and
			 communities across the United States in welcoming and resettling refugees in
			 the United States;</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id8131763bb1cd4986a203e9a3c0126595">
        <enum>(6)</enum>
        <text>celebrates the
			 invaluable contributions that refugee women and girls make to their families
			 and communities; and</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="idb5bb985513784f6598955b97d9ac38d2">
        <enum>(7)</enum>
        <text>encourages the
			 people of the United States to observe World Refugee Day with appropriate
			 programs and activities.</text>
			</paragraph>
    </section>
  </resolution-body>
</resolution>
</doc>