<doc>
  <docmeta id="113sres324ats">
    <bill congress="113" type="sres" number="324" version="ats"/>
    <revision size="2790" annotations="0" status="complete" id="5" commit-time="2014-02-11T14:42:26Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113sres324ats/5.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <resolution xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print">
  <metadata>
<dublinCore>
<dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">113 SRES 324 ATS: Expressing the sense of the Senate with respect to the tragic shooting at Los Angeles International Airport on November 1, 2013, of employees of the Transportation Security Administration.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">2013-12-18</dc:date>
<dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code>
    <congress display="yes">113th CONGRESS</congress>
    <session display="yes">1st Session</session>
    <legis-num>S. RES. 324</legis-num>
    <current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
    <action display="yes">
      <action-date date="20131218">December 18, 2013</action-date>
      <action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="S176">Mr. Rockefeller</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S223">Mrs. Boxer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S221">Mrs. Feinstein</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S303">Mr. Thune</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S277">Mr. Carper</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S301">Mr. Coburn</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was considered and agreed to</action-desc>
    </action>
    <legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
    <official-title display="yes">Expressing the sense of the Senate with respect to the tragic shooting at Los Angeles International Airport on November 1, 2013, of employees of the Transportation Security Administration.</official-title>
  </form>
  <preamble>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas on November 1, 2013, a gunman entered Terminal 3 of the Los Angeles International Airport and opened fire at a security checkpoint, targeting the Transportation Security Officers who are charged with protecting our aviation system and the people of the United States;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas Gerardo Hernandez, a 39-year-old resident of Porter Ranch, California, a beloved husband and father of two, lost his life in the shooting and tragically became the first Transportation Security Officer to be killed in the performance of his duties;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas James Speer and Tony Grigsby, dedicated Transportation Security Officers and colleagues of the deceased officer, were wounded in the attack;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas a member of the traveling public, Brian Ludmer, a 29-year-old high school teacher  from Lake Forest, Illinois, was also injured; and</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas Transportation Security Officers, law enforcement personnel, first responders, and medical professionals acted courageously to subdue the gunman, secure the airport, help move passengers out of harm's way, and treat victims of the attack:</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Now, therefore, be it</text>
    </whereas>
  </preamble>
  <resolution-body>
    <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="S1" section-type="undesignated-section">
      <enum/>
      <text>That the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0010">Senate</cato:entity-ref>—</text>
      <paragraph id="idB8FAFE795AC24A3FBCDF02AD58687B6A">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text>strongly condemns the senseless and appalling act of violence carried out at Los Angeles International Airport on November 1, 2013;</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id11A34A54E52D4F02856513C107CBD38E">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text>offers its deepest condolences to the family, friends, and loved ones of Gerardo Hernandez;</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id244AD39F36AD48C9A28819FEF8117262">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <text>honors the dedicated public service of Gerardo Hernandez, James Speer, and Tony Grigsby;</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id58BAAEDABDD94D8FA3104F2A4E47E93B">
        <enum>(4)</enum>
        <text>sends its hope for a quick recovery to the other victims of the horrific attack; and</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id2DDCCCE19A1445F092A74A99F87A40BA">
        <enum>(5)</enum>
        <text>remains committed to preventing similar tragedies from happening again.</text>
      </paragraph>
    </section>
  </resolution-body>
</resolution>
</doc>