<doc>
  <docmeta id="113sres4is">
    <bill congress="113" type="sres" number="4" version="is"/>
    <revision size="7245" annotations="0" id="7" commit-time="2013-04-29T00:21:47+00:00" committer="favila" doc="113sres4is/7.xml" status="complete">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <resolution xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print"> 
<form> 
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code> 
<congress display="yes">113th CONGRESS</congress> 
<session display="yes">1st Session</session> 
<legis-num>S. RES. 4</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber> 
<action display="yes"> 
<action-date date="20130103">January 3, 2013</action-date> 
<action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="S326">Mr. Udall of New Mexico</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S322">Mr. Merkley</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S172">Mr. Harkin</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was ordered to lie over under the rule</action-desc> 
</action> 
<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type> 
<official-title display="yes">To limit certain uses of the filibuster in the Senate to improve the legislative process. </official-title> 
</form> 
<resolution-body> 
<section id="id98EA86D972E44B0C826C637270DC2EEB" section-type="section-one">
      <enum>1.</enum>
      <header>Motions to proceed</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Paragraph 1 of rule XXII of the Standing Rules of the Senate is amended by inserting at the end the following new paragraph:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id355F73A32B524994B65BB4269B64124A" style="OLC"> 
<subsection id="id6b8f1e47fcec463ba6dfa85a42d17281">
          <enum/>
          <text>Other than a motion made during the first 2 hours of a new legislative day as described in paragraph 2 of rule VIII, consideration of a motion to proceed to the consideration of any debatable matter, including debate on any debatable motion or appeal in connection therewith, shall be limited to not more than 2 hours, to be equally divided between, and controlled by, the Majority Leader and the Minority Leader or their designees. This paragraph shall not apply to motions considered nondebatable by the Senate pursuant to rule or precedent.</text> </subsection>
        <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
      </quoted-block> </section>
<section id="id8bb85e0be6524ea780a967bf02529133">
      <enum>2.</enum>
      <header> Extended debate</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Paragraph 2 of rule XXII of the Standing Rules of the Senate is amended by striking the second undesignated paragraph and inserting the following:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1FCC6FFBBB32425CAD0BEF52D4237D05" style="OLC"> 
<subsection id="id5bdb3096c1434d8c959ebf581675145e">
          <enum/>
          <text>Is it the sense of the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0010">Senate</cato:entity-ref> that the debate shall be brought to a close? And if that question shall be decided in the affirmative by three-fifths of the Senators duly chosen and sworn, except on a measure or motion to amend the Senate rules, in which case the necessary affirmative vote shall be two-thirds of the Senators voting, a quorum being present, then cloture has been invoked.</text> </subsection>
<subsection id="id10b129da9f954e40b71814c2cb58812f">
          <enum/>
          <text>If that question is on disposition of a bill or joint resolution, a resolution or concurrent resolution, a substitute amendment for a bill or resolution, a motion with respect to amendments between the Houses, a conference report, or advice and consent to a nomination or treaty, and if such question shall be decided in the affirmative by a majority of Senators voting, a quorum being present, but less than three-fifths of the Senators duly chosen and sworn (or less than two-thirds of the Senators voting, a quorum being present, in the case of a measure or motion to amend the Senate rules), then it shall be in order for the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" value="Majority Leader of the Senate" entity-parent-id="0010">Majority Leader</cato:entity-ref> (or his or her designee) to initiate a period of extended debate upon the measure, motion, or other matter pending before the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0010">Senate</cato:entity-ref>, or the unfinished business, in relation to which the motion to close debate was offered, in which case the period of extended debate shall begin one hour later.</text> </subsection>
<subsection id="id0ED3307F8B5943DF89B11B55161DF95F">
          <enum/>
          <text>During a period of extended debate, such measure, motion, or other matter pending before the Senate, or the unfinished business, shall be the unfinished business to the exclusion of all other business, except on action or motion by the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" value="Majority Leader of the Senate" entity-parent-id="0010">Majority Leader</cato:entity-ref> (or his or her designee).</text> </subsection>
<subsection id="id6ebea861b8b848d6a65195a45bd2ed60">
          <enum/>
          <text>During a period of extended debate it shall not be in order for a Senator other than the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" value="Majority Leader of the Senate" entity-parent-id="0010">Majority Leader</cato:entity-ref> (or his or her designee) to raise a question as to the presence of a quorum, except immediately prior to a vote or when it has been more than forty-eight hours since a quorum was demonstrated. If upon a roll call it shall be ascertained that a quorum is not present, then the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0010">Senate</cato:entity-ref> shall adjourn to a time previously decided by order of the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0010">Senate</cato:entity-ref> or, if no such time has been established, then to a time certain determined by the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" value="Majority Leader of the Senate" entity-parent-id="0010">Majority Leader</cato:entity-ref>, after consultation with the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" value="Minority Leader of the Senate" entity-parent-id="0010">Minority Leader</cato:entity-ref>.</text> </subsection>
<subsection id="id0609199682004536996b0ca28ee931e8">
          <enum/>
          <text>During a period of extended debate a motion to adjourn or recess shall not be in order, unless made by the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" value="Majority Leader of the Senate" entity-parent-id="0010">Majority Leader</cato:entity-ref> (or his or her designee) or if the absence of a quorum has been demonstrated. Notwithstanding paragraph 1 of rule XIX, there shall be no limit to the number of times a Senator may speak upon any question during a period of extended debate.</text> </subsection>
<subsection id="id29b2f0e1876341a09752b439459ae4d7">
          <enum/>
          <text>If, during the course of extended debate, the Presiding Officer puts any question to a vote, the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" value="Majority Leader of the Senate" entity-parent-id="0010">Majority Leader</cato:entity-ref> (or his or her designee) may postpone any such vote, which shall occur at a time determined by the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" value="Majority Leader of the Senate" entity-parent-id="0010">Majority Leader</cato:entity-ref>, after consultation with the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" value="Minority Leader of the Senate" entity-parent-id="0010">Minority Leader</cato:entity-ref>, but not later than the time at which a quorum is next demonstrated.</text> </subsection>
<subsection id="idbcfd14bed2ab4499b3d7f2bd8a38a26d">
          <enum/>
          <text>If at any time during a period of extended debate no Senator seeks recognition, then the Presiding Officer shall inquire as to whether any Senator seeks recognition. If no Senator seeks recognition, then the Presiding Officer shall again put the question as to bringing debate to a close (and the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" value="Majority Leader of the Senate" entity-parent-id="0010">Majority Leader</cato:entity-ref> or his or her designee may postpone such vote in accordance with the preceding paragraph), which shall be decided without further debate or intervening motion. If that question shall be decided in the affirmative by a majority of Senators voting, a quorum being present, then cloture has been invoked and the period of extended debate has ended. If that question shall be decided in the negative by a majority of Senators voting, a quorum being present, then the period of extended debate has ended.</text> </subsection>
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="iddd0d54a43bcc41ee8c54682df3c32c02">
          <enum/>
          <text>If cloture is invoked, then the measure, motion, other matter pending before the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0010">Senate</cato:entity-ref>, or the unfinished business, in relation to which the motion to close debate was offered, shall remain the unfinished business to the exclusion of all other business until disposed of.</text> </subsection>
        <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
      </quoted-block> </section>
<section id="id3213c92d4d294ef7b44115c99e0de037">
      <enum>3.</enum>
      <header>Post-cloture debate on nominations</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Paragraph 2 of rule XXII of the Standing Rules of the Senate is amended by striking <quote>After no more than thirty hours of consideration of the measure, motion, or other matter on which cloture has been invoked, the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0010">Senate</cato:entity-ref> shall proceed, without any further debate on any question, to vote on</quote> in the fourth undesignated paragraph and inserting <quote>After no more than 30 hours of consideration of the measure, motion, or other matter on which cloture has been invoked, except on the question of advice and consent to a nomination other than a nomination to a position as Justice of the Supreme Court in which case consideration shall be limited to 2 hours, the Senate shall proceed, without any further debate on any question, to vote on</quote>.</text> </section>
<section id="id3FC2B11B935849B09B19D56D02644CAC">
      <enum>4.</enum>
      <header>Conference motions</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Rule XXVIII of the Standing Rules of the Senate is amended by—</text> 
<paragraph id="id78A30360038548F8A982E0B9205BCA91">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">redesignating paragraphs 1 through 9 as paragraphs 2 through 10, respectively;</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="idC2935CD7453C4DB891BBCB647C9CD254">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">redesignating any reference to paragraphs 1 through 9 as paragraph 2 through 10, respectively; and</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="id5E874CE63A44488BA4B71BC2CEFBB27C">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">inserting before paragraph 2, as redesignated, the following:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idDF3C382E2DAE46D3B97D69964A59ADEF" style="OLC"> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6F798A68B4634CBD8F75963776E88A06">
            <enum>1.</enum>
            <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A nondivisible motion to disagree to a House amendment or insist upon a Senate amendment, to request a committee of conference with the House or to agree to a request by the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0050">House</cato:entity-ref> for a committee of conference, and to authorize the Presiding Officer to appoint conferees (or to appoint conferees), is in order and consideration of such a motion, including consideration of any debatable motion or appeal in connection therewith, shall be limited to not more than 2 hours.</text> </subsection>
          <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
        </quoted-block> </paragraph>
    </section>
</resolution-body> 
</resolution>
</doc>