<doc>
  <docmeta id="113s641is">
    <bill congress="113" type="s" number="641" version="is"/>
    <revision size="26890" annotations="0" id="4" commit-time="2013-06-05T22:37:41Z" status="complete" committer="mbohmer" doc="113s641is/4.xml">
      <description description="Markup copied from completed documents">Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>113 S641 IS: Palliative Care and Hospice Education and Training Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2013-03-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
		<congress>113th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. 641</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20130321">March 21, 2013</action-date>
			<action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="S247">Mr. Wyden</sponsor> (for himself
			 and <cosponsor name-id="S259">Mr. Reed</cosponsor>) introduced the following
			 bill; which was read twice and referred to the
			 <committee-name committee-id="SSHR00">Committee on Health, Education, Labor,
			 and Pensions</committee-name>
      </action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To amend the Public Health Service Act to increase the
		  number of permanent faculty in palliative care at accredited allopathic and
		  osteopathic medical schools, nursing schools, and other programs, to promote
		  education in palliative care and hospice, and to support the development of
		  faculty careers in academic palliative medicine.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="HD01873B9FE704740BFF77C62CDFCF7B6" style="OLC">
		<section id="H26963C518B6042B88AC06A9A3457F553" section-type="section-one">
      <enum>1.</enum>
      <header>Short title</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the
			 <quote>
          <short-title>Palliative Care and Hospice Education
			 and Training Act</short-title>
        </quote>.</text>
		</section>
    <section id="H9E97ED6D6E4D4C41A92EBA91DADC01B6">
      <enum>2.</enum>
      <header>Findings</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">
        <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> makes the following
			 findings:</text>
			<paragraph id="HB6B8A57736D34F97BCED2C2463733154">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text>Health care
			 providers need better education about pain management and palliative care.
			 Students graduating from medical school have very little, if any, training in
			 the core precepts of pain and symptom management, advance care planning,
			 communication skills, and care coordination for patients with serious,
			 life-threatening, or terminal illness.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H07BC4ADF0BA14C14BAE505FCD7679894">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text>Palliative care is
			 interdisciplinary, patient- and family-centered health care for people with
			 serious illnesses. This type of care is focused on providing patients with
			 relief from the symptoms, pain, and stress of a serious illness, whatever the
			 diagnosis. The goal of palliative care is to relieve suffering and improve
			 quality of life for both patients and their families. Palliative care is
			 provided by a team of doctors, nurses, social workers, chaplains, and other
			 specialists who work with a patient’s other health care providers to provide an
			 extra layer of support, including assistance with difficult medical
			 decisionmaking and coordination of care among specialists. Palliative care is
			 appropriate at any age and at any stage in a serious illness, and can be
			 provided together with curative treatment. Palliative care is not dependent on
			 a life-limiting prognosis and may actually help an individual recover from
			 illness by relieving symptoms, such as pain, anxiety, or loss of appetite,
			 while undergoing sometimes difficult medical treatments or procedures, such as
			 surgery or chemotherapy. There were 1,623 hospitals with palliative care
			 programs in 2012.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H1E3B378F3C404EE2A1FF9423E90492A6">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <text>Hospice is
			 palliative care for patients in their last year of life. Considered the model
			 for quality compassionate care for individuals facing a life-limiting illness,
			 hospice provides expert medical care, pain management, and emotional and
			 spiritual support expressly tailored to the patient’s needs and wishes. In most
			 cases, care is provided in the patient’s home but may also be provided in
			 freestanding hospice centers, hospitals, nursing homes, and other long-term
			 care facilities. In 2011, an estimated 1,650,000 patients received services
			 from hospice, and nearly 45 percent of all deaths in the United States occurred
			 under the care of a hospice program. Hospice is a covered benefit under the
			 Medicare program. There were 3,630 Medicare-certified hospices serving more
			 than 1,200,000 beneficiaries in 2011.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H28F1E1198D5C4EC5BDA759AD1887C2E9">
        <enum>(4)</enum>
        <text>A
			 2005 study at Michigan State University found that the formal training of
			 United States doctors in palliative care is <quote>grossly inadequate</quote>.
			 When the American Society of Clinical Oncology surveyed their members, 65
			 percent said they had received inadequate education in controlling symptoms
			 associated with cancer, and 81 percent felt they had inadequate mentoring in
			 discussing a poor prognosis with their patients and families. Training in
			 pediatric palliative care is also seriously lacking according to physicians,
			 residents, and medical students responding to a survey presented at a meeting
			 of American Federation for Medical Research.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H25F5EF16AC7C45BE9FAB66352FA50CE9">
        <enum>(5)</enum>
        <text>The American Board
			 of Medical Specialties (ABMS) and the Accreditation Council for Graduate
			 Medical Education (ACGME) provided formal subspecialty status for hospice and
			 palliative medicine (HPM) in 2006, and the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid
			 Services recognized hospice and palliative medicine as a medical subspecialty
			 in October of 2008.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H409BE8AD46694C06B0B75E01BB8A1EE9">
        <enum>(6)</enum>
        <text>As of February
			 2013, there were a total of 89 hospice and palliative medicine training
			 programs accredited by the Accreditation Council for Graduate Medical
			 Education. For the 2012–2013 academic year, these programs were training 206
			 physicians in hospice and palliative medicine. Some programs include an
			 additional track in research, geriatrics, or public health.</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H3682BB33E878493FBCF7C9741FFB53C4">
        <enum>(7)</enum>
        <text>There is a large
			 gap between those practicing in the palliative medicine field and the number of
			 physicians needed. A mid-range estimate by the American Academy of Hospice and
			 Palliative Medicine’s Workforce Task Force calls for 6,000 or more full time
			 equivalents to serve current needs in hospice and palliative care programs. At
			 maximum capacity, the current system would produce roughly 4,600 new hospice
			 and palliative medicine certified physicians over the next 20 years, during
			 which time some 70,000,000 new Medicare beneficiaries will enter the Medicare
			 program. At the same time, there is expected to be increasing acceptance of the
			 hospice and palliative approach to care among the general population and health
			 care providers.</text>
			</paragraph>
    </section>
    <section id="HFEA33E59FDAF43449B37D99F391E7AF7">
      <enum>3.</enum>
      <header>Palliative care
			 and hospice education and training</header>
			<subsection id="H86555030788D432BB5E5241ACDD9A673">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>In
			 general</header>
        <text>
          <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Public Health Service Act/t:VII/pt:D">Part D of title VII of the Public Health Service Act</cato:entity-ref> (<cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/42/294/etseq">42
			 U.S.C. 294 et seq.</cato:entity-ref>)</cato:entity> is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEA7927B69243476AB9CAB61DFE47A92E" style="OLC">
					<section id="H770F162784834F5DAB5066EE9D0E5F9E">
            <enum>759A.</enum>
            <header>Palliative
				care and hospice education and training</header>
						<subsection id="H14FA1F3F7B9C4CAB8F68FCFF2B99462B">
              <enum>(a)</enum>
              <header>Palliative care
				and hospice education centers</header>
							<paragraph id="HD28D6DA0B3CA4DF2B24A3AA35B9D3874">
                <enum>(1)</enum>
                <header>In
				general</header>
                <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall award grants or contracts under this
				section to entities described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Public Health Service Act/s:799B/p:1,3,4">paragraph (1), (3), or (4) of section 799B</cato:entity-ref>,
				and <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Public Health Service Act/s:801/p:2">section 801(2)</cato:entity-ref>, for the establishment or operation of Palliative Care and
				Hospice Education Centers that meet the requirements of <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Public Health Service Act/s:759A/ss:a/p:2" proposed="true">paragraph (2)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
							</paragraph>
              <paragraph id="HAB0477A9D28F4AF59B7B36A9F2ECDB97">
                <enum>(2)</enum>
                <header>Requirements</header>
                <text>A
				Palliative Care and Hospice Education Center meets the requirements of this
				paragraph if such Center—</text>
								<subparagraph id="H96E133253D584D8A9DC66719B645A33B">
                  <enum>(A)</enum>
                  <text>improves the
				training of health professionals in palliative care, including residencies,
				traineeships, or fellowships;</text>
								</subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="H570729411CEA4A62934A188702990F61">
                  <enum>(B)</enum>
                  <text>develops and
				disseminates curricula relating to the palliative treatment of the complex
				health problems of individuals with serious or life-threatening
				illnesses;</text>
								</subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="H8F2DA6588D6A4414A3FF4C0DC08A7284">
                  <enum>(C)</enum>
                  <text>supports the
				training and retraining of faculty to provide instruction in palliative
				care;</text>
								</subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="H94A39CA1BD154C998DA15F99A40C16FA">
                  <enum>(D)</enum>
                  <text>supports
				continuing education of health professionals who provide palliative care to
				patients with serious or life-threatening illness;</text>
								</subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="H8149C32D721743F3BC4BE5A47EFB5B2B">
                  <enum>(E)</enum>
                  <text>provides students
				(including residents, trainees, and fellows) with clinical training in
				palliative care in the home, long-term care facilities, home care, hospices,
				chronic and acute disease hospitals, and ambulatory care centers;</text>
								</subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="H4E25A3762D03464F93DC3D79CE3412BE">
                  <enum>(F)</enum>
                  <text>establishes
				traineeships for individuals who are preparing for advanced education nursing
				degrees in palliative care nursing, home care, hospice, in the home, long-term
				care, or other nursing areas that specialize in palliative care; and</text>
								</subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="H19EF0CB45CEE48F088F854A99D30BADD">
                  <enum>(G)</enum>
                  <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">does not duplicate the activities of
				existing education centers funded under this section or under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Public Health Service Act/s:753">section 753</cato:entity-ref> or
				<cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Public Health Service Act/s:865">865</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
								</subparagraph>
              </paragraph>
              <paragraph id="H693BE885028A4AA5957AF620C876B2BB">
                <enum>(3)</enum>
                <header>Expansion of
				existing centers</header>
                <text>Nothing in this section shall be construed
				to—</text>
								<subparagraph id="H0BD47F7B4CEE440E8BF97772F8C747BD">
                  <enum>(A)</enum>
                  <text>prevent the
				<cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> from providing grants to expand existing education centers, including
				geriatric education centers established under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Public Health Service Act/s:753">section 753</cato:entity-ref> or <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Public Health Service Act/s:865">865</cato:entity-ref>, to provide
				for education and training focused specifically on palliative care, including
				for non-geriatric populations; or</text>
								</subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="H1FFB7F2734494A8BB9DA6D1C3B65F1FF">
                  <enum>(B)</enum>
                  <text>limit the number
				of education centers that may be funded in a community.</text>
								</subparagraph>
              </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="H0B31A66B7AFF44C6AFA35F4B2F22276D">
              <enum>(b)</enum>
              <header>Palliative
				medicine physician training</header>
							<paragraph id="H44EE57D8C66544649BC9606A744413B8">
                <enum>(1)</enum>
                <header>In
				general</header>
                <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> may make grants to, and enter into
				contracts with, schools of medicine, schools of osteopathic medicine, teaching
				hospitals, and graduate medical education programs, for the purpose of
				providing support for projects that fund the training of physicians (including
				residents, trainees, and fellows) who plan to teach palliative medicine.</text>
							</paragraph>
              <paragraph id="HA0CFB9C8B15E432CA27543AEB3FC4CD2">
                <enum>(2)</enum>
                <header>Requirements</header>
                <text>Each
				project for which a grant or contract is made under this subsection
				shall—</text>
								<subparagraph id="H0778C007981941F39EC665C2C58B9719">
                  <enum>(A)</enum>
                  <text>be staffed by
				full-time teaching physicians who have experience or training in palliative
				medicine;</text>
								</subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="HB569590E3368471096CFB9780AE9C217">
                  <enum>(B)</enum>
                  <text>be based in a
				hospice and palliative medicine fellowship program accredited by the
				Accreditation Council for Graduate Medical Education;</text>
								</subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="H9EEC0E80C7C8461C9C45F9E3FDF4044F">
                  <enum>(C)</enum>
                  <text>provide training
				in palliative medicine through a variety of service rotations, such as
				consultation services, acute care services, extended care facilities,
				ambulatory care and comprehensive evaluation units, hospice, home health, and
				community care programs;</text>
								</subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="H5ED3951EF05045908E0EA0F782F18CC2">
                  <enum>(D)</enum>
                  <text>develop specific
				performance-based measures to evaluate the competency of trainees; and</text>
								</subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="HDDE36A1A1A4A4AADA6CBB6DA1A09B1D4">
                  <enum>(E)</enum>
                  <text>provide training
				in palliative medicine through one or both of the training options described in
				<cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Public Health Service Act/s:759A/ss:b/p:3/sp:A,B" proposed="true">subparagraphs (A) and (B) of paragraph (3)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
								</subparagraph>
              </paragraph>
              <paragraph id="H4C6C33724FB24E099530E6D25E19DE2C">
                <enum>(3)</enum>
                <header>Training
				options</header>
                <text>The training options referred to in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Public Health Service Act/s:759A/ss:b/p:2/sp:E" proposed="true">subparagraph (E) of
				paragraph (2)</cato:entity-ref> shall be as follows:</text>
								<subparagraph id="H420906694E02443E9693462C64891947">
                  <enum>(A)</enum>
                  <text>1-year retraining
				programs in hospice and palliative medicine for physicians who are faculty at
				schools of medicine and osteopathic medicine, or others determined appropriate
				by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
								</subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="H329B1668F4C54598A174055307BB5B13">
                  <enum>(B)</enum>
                  <text>1- or 2-year
				training programs that shall be designed to provide training in hospice and
				palliative medicine for physicians who have completed graduate medical
				education programs in any medical specialty leading to board eligibility in
				hospice and palliative medicine pursuant to the American Board of Medical
				Specialties.</text>
								</subparagraph>
              </paragraph>
              <paragraph id="H276FB00132D64B60B1FC43A85D525D32">
                <enum>(4)</enum>
                <header>Definitions</header>
                <text>For
				purposes of this subsection the term <term>graduate medical education</term>
				means a program sponsored by a school of medicine, a school of osteopathic
				medicine, a hospital, or a public or private institution that—</text>
								<subparagraph id="HEB8CE6ECBBC84CF89F16FAF259E1EB0D">
                  <enum>(A)</enum>
                  <text>offers
				postgraduate medical training in the specialties and subspecialties of
				medicine; and</text>
								</subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="HD2595CB800C545BDA92BC0B7244DF4D6">
                  <enum>(B)</enum>
                  <text>has been
				accredited by the Accreditation Council for Graduate Medical Education or the
				American Osteopathic Association through its Committee on Postdoctoral
				Training.</text>
								</subparagraph>
              </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="H2E2781F1B39A404AAD75067FAFDCBB51">
              <enum>(c)</enum>
              <header>Palliative
				medicine and hospice academic career awards</header>
							<paragraph id="HF9ABF2602A7D4925A4AC34AFEDB33B4E">
                <enum>(1)</enum>
                <header>Establishment of
				program</header>
                <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall establish a program to provide
				awards, to be known as the <term>Palliative Medicine and Hospice Academic
				Career Awards</term>, to eligible individuals to promote the career development
				of such individuals as academic hospice and palliative care physicians.</text>
							</paragraph>
              <paragraph id="H58A29D6A0FA140989448BEC2B6822206">
                <enum>(2)</enum>
                <header>Eligible
				individuals</header>
                <text>To be eligible to receive an award under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Public Health Service Act/s:795A/ss:c/p:1" proposed="true">paragraph
				(1)</cato:entity-ref>, an individual shall—</text>
								<subparagraph id="HA96BB3A7682D463397725E575BF71AF4">
                  <enum>(A)</enum>
                  <text>be board certified
				or board eligible in hospice and palliative medicine; and</text>
								</subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="H05B91A7148F7487385D165E92A12F1D0">
                  <enum>(B)</enum>
                  <text>have a junior
				(non-tenured) faculty appointment at an accredited (as determined by the
				<cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref>) school of medicine or osteopathic medicine.</text>
								</subparagraph>
              </paragraph>
              <paragraph id="H9B31C51AE7824210AE57207A7A26C7EA">
                <enum>(3)</enum>
                <header>Limitations</header>
                <text>No
				award under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Public Health Service Act/s:759A/ss:c/p:1" proposed="true">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref> may be made to an eligible individual unless the
				individual—</text>
								<subparagraph id="HAEBA7D48ACE44148BBF53D8C26D32150">
                  <enum>(A)</enum>
                  <text>has submitted to
				the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> an application, at such time, in such manner, and containing such
				information as the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> may require, and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> has approved such
				application;</text>
								</subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="HAC53D3940D2E41E3B2595F0F339B456E">
                  <enum>(B)</enum>
                  <text>provides, in such
				form and manner as the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> may require, assurances that the individual
				will meet the service requirement described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Public Health Service Act/s:759A/ss:c/p:6" proposed="true">paragraph (6)</cato:entity-ref>; and</text>
								</subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="H44121701E02B4CD4A6740CD07B9B784F">
                  <enum>(C)</enum>
                  <text>provides, in such
				form and manner as the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> may require, assurances that the individual
				has a full-time faculty appointment in a health professions institution and
				documented commitment from such institution to spend a majority of the total
				funded time of such individual on teaching and developing skills in
				interdisciplinary education in palliative care.</text>
								</subparagraph>
              </paragraph>
              <paragraph id="HA172EC84C3614B8EB20A5FC5DD0B053F">
                <enum>(4)</enum>
                <header>Maintenance of
				effort</header>
                <text>An eligible individual who receives an award under
				<cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Public Health Service Act/s:759A/ss:c/p:1" proposed="true">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref> shall provide assurances to the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> that funds provided to
				the eligible individual under this subsection will be used only to supplement,
				not to supplant, the amount of Federal, State, and local funds otherwise
				expended by the eligible individual.</text>
							</paragraph>
              <paragraph id="H0AB23011CFE54D069F5F3D82E3815452">
                <enum>(5)</enum>
                <header>Amount and
				term</header>
								<subparagraph id="H58F849983A224470AC565FD9F882B58C">
                  <enum>(A)</enum>
                  <header>Amount</header>
                  <text>The
				amount of an award under this subsection shall be equal to the award amount
				provided for under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Public Health Service Act/s:753/ss:c/p:5/sp:A">section 753(c)(5)(A)</cato:entity-ref> for the fiscal year involved.</text>
								</subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="HE5C0DDC3AE054DA6A2385036932A07CD">
                  <enum>(B)</enum>
                  <header>Term</header>
                  <text>The
				term of an award made under this subsection shall not exceed 5 years.</text>
								</subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="H5ABC90FD42D64DD49A19168C9CB94526">
                  <enum>(C)</enum>
                  <header>Payment to
				institution</header>
                  <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall make payments for awards under
				this subsection to institutions which include schools of medicine and
				osteopathic medicine.</text>
								</subparagraph>
              </paragraph>
              <paragraph id="H67B1BF0EAD92435C9B196C8CA37328A5">
                <enum>(6)</enum>
                <header>Service
				requirement</header>
                <text>An individual who receives an award under this
				subsection shall provide training in palliative care and hospice, including the
				training of interdisciplinary teams of health care professionals. The provision
				of such training shall constitute a majority of the total funded obligations of
				such individual under the award.</text>
							</paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="HA0BD82813A9D4E15825EED966F32685F">
              <enum>(d)</enum>
              <header>Palliative care
				workforce development</header>
							<paragraph id="HFC8CFF52D017463FA957E67B65695E36">
                <enum>(1)</enum>
                <header>In
				general</header>
                <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall award grants or contracts under this
				subsection to entities that operate a Palliative Care and Hospice Education
				Center pursuant to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Public Health Service Act/s:759A/ss:a/p:1" proposed="true">subsection (a)(1)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
							</paragraph>
              <paragraph id="HA959158FA2BB486BBAC44E8BB84A0FC5">
                <enum>(2)</enum>
                <header>Application</header>
                <text>To
				be eligible for an award under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Public Health Service Act/s:759A/ss:d/p:1" proposed="true">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref>, an entity described in such
				paragraph shall submit to the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> an application at such time, in such
				manner, and containing such information as the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> may require.</text>
							</paragraph>
              <paragraph id="HB5BA21D0029C452DB167FC42E6DEBE19">
                <enum>(3)</enum>
                <header>Use of
				funds</header>
                <text>Amounts awarded under a grant or contract under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Public Health Service Act/s:759A/ss:d/p:1" proposed="true">paragraph
				(1)</cato:entity-ref> shall be used to carry out the fellowship program described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Public Health Service Act/s:759A/ss:d/p:4" proposed="true">paragraph
				(4)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
							</paragraph>
              <paragraph id="HB4FBE2A947E84CC3BAB234DF7C82A0F5">
                <enum>(4)</enum>
                <header>Fellowship
				program</header>
								<subparagraph id="H7B91541E055740E9BA8B504B4A4557CD">
                  <enum>(A)</enum>
                  <header>In
				general</header>
                  <text>Pursuant to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Public Health Service Act/s:759A/ss:d/p:3" proposed="true">paragraph (3)</cato:entity-ref>, a Palliative Care and Hospice
				Education Center that receives an award under this subsection shall use such
				funds to offer short-term intensive courses (referred to in this subsection as
				a <term>fellowship</term>) that focus on palliative care that provide
				supplemental training for faculty members in medical schools and other health
				professions schools with programs in psychology, pharmacy, nursing, social
				work, chaplaincy, or other health disciplines, as approved by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref>.
				Such a fellowship shall be open to current faculty, and appropriately
				credentialed volunteer faculty and practitioners, who do not have formal
				training in palliative care, to upgrade their knowledge and clinical skills for
				the care of individuals with serious or life-threatening illness and to enhance
				their interdisciplinary teaching skills.</text>
								</subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="HD187EFA6E9A64CC7BB57148EE832631C">
                  <enum>(B)</enum>
                  <header>Location</header>
                  <text>A
				fellowship under this paragraph shall be offered either at the Palliative Care
				and Hospice Education Center that is sponsoring the course, in collaboration
				with other Palliative Care and Hospice Education Centers, or at medical
				schools, schools of nursing, schools of pharmacy, schools of social work,
				schools of chaplaincy or pastoral care education, graduate programs in
				psychology, or other health professions schools approved by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> with
				which the Centers are affiliated.</text>
								</subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="H5D82339D4910454BB22FECCEE140F619">
                  <enum>(C)</enum>
                  <header>CME
				credit</header>
                  <text>Participation in a fellowship under this paragraph shall
				be accepted with respect to complying with continuing health profession
				education requirements. As a condition of such acceptance, the recipient shall
				subsequently provide a minimum of 18 hours of voluntary instruction in
				palliative care content (that has been approved by a palliative care and
				hospice education center) to students or trainees in health-related
				educational, home, hospice, or long-term care settings.</text>
								</subparagraph>
              </paragraph>
              <paragraph id="HBDEDD542C6684EF38CFEC17556591DB7">
                <enum>(5)</enum>
                <header>Targets</header>
                <text>A
				Palliative Care and Hospice Education Center that receives an award under this
				subsection shall meet targets approved by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> for providing
				palliative care training to a certain number of faculty or practitioners during
				the term of the award, as well as other parameters established by the
				<cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
							</paragraph>
              <paragraph id="H744BCC8D045D46CD9D9A845A1540886D">
                <enum>(6)</enum>
                <header>Amount of
				award</header>
                <text>An award under this subsection shall be in an amount of
				$150,000. Not more than 24 Palliative Care and Hospice Education Centers may
				receive an award under this subsection.</text>
							</paragraph>
              <paragraph id="H9420FFB71BB74C79864E5D08C33BF1D0">
                <enum>(7)</enum>
                <header>Maintenance of
				effort</header>
                <text>A Palliative Care and Hospice Education Center that
				receives an award under this subsection shall provide assurances to the
				<cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> that funds provided to the Center under the award will be used only
				to supplement, not to supplant, the amount of Federal, State, and local funds
				otherwise expended by such Center.</text>
							</paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="H1D659859A6DA4EAC878FEEC1B1AF728B">
              <enum>(e)</enum>
              <header>Palliative care
				and hospice career incentive awards</header>
							<paragraph id="H8E6A94B0743D4B79A7EDCF335BB55946">
                <enum>(1)</enum>
                <header>In
				general</header>
                <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall award grants or contracts under this
				subsection to individuals described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Public Health Service Act/s:759A/ss:e/p:2" proposed="true">paragraph (2)</cato:entity-ref> to foster greater interest
				among a variety of health professionals in entering the field of palliative
				care.</text>
							</paragraph>
              <paragraph id="H731E849C873148A48119BDE2C63F5C78">
                <enum>(2)</enum>
                <header>Eligible
				individuals</header>
                <text>To be eligible to receive an award under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Public Health Service Act/s:759A/ss:e/p:1" proposed="true">paragraph
				(1)</cato:entity-ref>, an individual shall—</text>
								<subparagraph id="H67A68849CCC348D682AF556C4DC1F276">
                  <enum>(A)</enum>
                  <text>be an advanced
				practice nurse, a clinical social worker, a pharmacist, a chaplain, or student
				of psychology who is pursuing a doctorate or other advanced degree in
				palliative care or related fields in an accredited health professions school;
				and</text>
								</subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="H6FACC1642B4645EA8A1C397D5211007E">
                  <enum>(B)</enum>
                  <text>submit to the
				<cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such
				information as the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> may require.</text>
								</subparagraph>
              </paragraph>
              <paragraph id="HCEC81347AAF7403AAEE889E9AF39F30B">
                <enum>(3)</enum>
                <header>Conditions of
				award</header>
                <text>As a condition of receiving an award under this subsection,
				an individual shall agree that, following completion of the award period, the
				individual will teach or practice palliative care in health-related
				educational, home, hospice or long-term care settings for a minimum of 5 years
				under guidelines established by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
							</paragraph>
              <paragraph id="H5AF167D035DD4124BC4D3031AB40C50B">
                <enum>(4)</enum>
                <header>Payment to
				institution</header>
                <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall make payments for awards under
				this subsection to institutions which include schools of medicine, osteopathic
				medicine, nursing, social work, psychology, chaplaincy or pastoral care
				education, dentistry, and pharmacy, or other allied health discipline in an
				accredited health professions school that is approved by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
							</paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="HC7C12AAD055B40D382A9D951033DBC15">
              <enum>(f)</enum>
              <header>Authorization of
				appropriations</header>
              <text>
                <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="auth-auth-approp">There are authorized to be appropriated <cato:property name="purpose">to carry
				out <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Public Health Service Act/s:759A" proposed="true">this section</cato:entity-ref>
                  </cato:property>, <cato:funds-and-year amount="44100000" year="2014, 2015, 2016, 2017, 2018">$44,100,000 for each of the fiscal years 2014 through
				2018</cato:funds-and-year>.</cato:entity>
              </text>
						</subsection>
          </section>
          <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
        </quoted-block>
			</subsection>
      <subsection id="H16AF9FF2A80F424D99DD3ADAB68962A1">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Effective
			 date</header>
        <text>The amendment made by this section shall be effective
			 beginning on the date that is 90 days after the date of enactment of this
			 Act.</text>
			</subsection>
    </section>
    <section id="HA102BFF39AB84D06B32481E4222D4053">
      <enum>4.</enum>
      <header>Application to
			 advanced practice nurses</header>
			<subsection id="H0BEF96305F994866AE9508B03D70FF0F">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Advanced
			 education nursing grants</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">
          <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Public Health Service Act/s:811/ss:a">Section 811(a) of the Public Health Service
			 Act</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/296j">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/42/296j/a">42 U.S.C. 296j(a)</cato:entity-ref>
            </external-xref>)</cato:entity> is amended—</text>
				<paragraph id="H09A1789028444F30A92D6CAAE74B1982">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Public Health Service Act/s:811/ss:a/p:1">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref>, by striking
			 <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H585DA8D9FEC745208FC6AC0CC1C24D4A">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by redesignating <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Public Health Service Act/s:811/ss:a/p:2">paragraph (2)</cato:entity-ref> as <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Public Health Service Act/s:811/ss:a/p:3" proposed="true">paragraph
			 (3)</cato:entity-ref>; and</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H57F779F5AD7D4264A3362615FEF84C8C">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by inserting after <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Public Health Service Act/s:811/ss:a/p:1">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref>, the
			 following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB7F241B29E3A44F18323BBF5953BC014" style="OLC">
						<paragraph id="HB47629BB4CAF4F9D8000B4BC451FCCC7">
              <enum>(2)</enum>
              <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">palliative care and hospice career
				incentive awards authorized under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Public Health Service Act/s:759A/ss:e">section 759A(e)</cato:entity-ref>;
				and</text>
						</paragraph>
            <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
          </quoted-block>
				</paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="HB13DA9379C7D4E7B84A02989CFB6E42F">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>In
			 general</header>
        <text>
          <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Public Health Service Act/t:VIII/pt:D">Part D of title VIII of the Public Health Service Act</cato:entity-ref> (<cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/42/296p/etseq">42
			 U.S.C. 296p et seq.</cato:entity-ref>)</cato:entity> is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H59A35F3CEA7B42348AD1F7CD36331C5E" style="OLC">
					<section id="H5A7CB670196741F2B44D63C13C99053F">
            <enum>832.</enum>
            <header>Palliative care
				and hospice education and training</header>
						<subsection id="H20AF93DB812043B7993323AFC5BC8B4E">
              <enum>(a)</enum>
              <header>Program
				authorized</header>
              <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall award grants to eligible entities
				to develop and implement, in coordination with programs under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Public Health Service Act/s:759A">section 759A</cato:entity-ref>,
				programs and initiatives to train and educate individuals in providing
				palliative care in health-related educational, hospice, home, or long-term care
				settings.</text>
						</subsection>
            <subsection id="HFB0E79E4B31341888F06A38CBF36CFBD">
              <enum>(b)</enum>
              <header>Use of
				funds</header>
              <text>An eligible entity that receives a grant under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Public Health Service Act/s:832/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection
				(a)</cato:entity-ref> shall use funds under such grant to—</text>
							<paragraph id="HE0A8FD8786C84ECB8424A01E14D4910E">
                <enum>(1)</enum>
                <text>provide training
				to individuals who will provide palliative care in health-related educational,
				home, hospice, or long-term care settings;</text>
							</paragraph>
              <paragraph id="H192C998B300B4A469893B08904B43264">
                <enum>(2)</enum>
                <text>develop and
				disseminate curricula relating to palliative care in health-related
				educational, home, hospice, or long-term care settings;</text>
							</paragraph>
              <paragraph id="H3B1E06E896CD4BF39D8389A12AB306ED">
                <enum>(3)</enum>
                <text>train faculty
				members in palliative care in health-related educational, home, hospice, or
				long-term care settings; or</text>
							</paragraph>
              <paragraph id="H81EFF0247F6B4AEA8F63CC42F1B0EC71">
                <enum>(4)</enum>
                <text>provide continuing
				education to individuals who provide palliative care in health-related
				educational, home, hospice, or long-term care settings.</text>
							</paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="HD67D2A7AA5F941FAB55D657704CD6025">
              <enum>(c)</enum>
              <header>Application</header>
              <text>An
				eligible entity desiring a grant under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Public Health Service Act/s:832/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref> shall submit an
				application to the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> at such time, in such manner, and containing such
				information as the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> may reasonably require.</text>
						</subsection>
            <subsection id="H6EBBDDFED19548A2901EBA413723E6D4">
              <enum>(d)</enum>
              <header>Eligible
				entity</header>
              <text>For purposes of this section, the term <term>eligible
				entity</term> shall include a school of nursing, a health care facility, a
				program leading to certification as a certified nurse assistant, a partnership
				of such a school and facility, or a partnership of such a program and
				facility.</text>
						</subsection>
            <subsection id="H4C565CB2E4F849308D375A89D8F15EF0">
              <enum>(e)</enum>
              <header>Authorization of
				appropriations</header>
              <text>
                <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="auth-auth-approp">There are authorized to be appropriated <cato:property name="purpose">to carry
				out <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Public Health Service Act/s:832" proposed="true">this section</cato:entity-ref>
                  </cato:property> <cato:funds-and-year amount="5000000" year="2014, 2015, 2016, 2017, 2018">$5,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2014 through
				2018</cato:funds-and-year>.</cato:entity>
              </text>
						</subsection>
          </section>
          <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
        </quoted-block>
			</subsection>
    </section>
  </legis-body>
</bill>
</doc>