<doc>
  <docmeta id="113sres538ats">
    <bill congress="113" type="sres" number="538" version="ats"/>
    <revision size="3600" annotations="0" status="complete" id="4" commit-time="2014-10-03T18:30:14Z" committer="mnewby" doc="113sres538ats/4.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <resolution xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print">
	<metadata>
<dublinCore>
<dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">113 SRES 538 ATS: Expressing the condolences of the Senate to the families of James Foley and Steven Sotloff, and condemning the terrorist acts of the Islamic State of Iraq and the Levant. </dc:title>
<dc:publisher xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">2014-09-09</dc:date>
<dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">113th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session display="yes">2d Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. RES. 538</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20140909">September 9, 2014</action-date>
			<action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="S324">Mrs. Shaheen</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S340">Ms. Ayotte</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S282">Mr. Nelson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S350">Mr. Rubio</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S306">Mr. Menendez</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was considered and agreed to</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">Expressing the condolences of the Senate to the families of James Foley and Steven Sotloff, and
			 condemning the terrorist acts of the Islamic State of Iraq and the Levant. </official-title>
	</form>
	<preamble>
		<whereas>
      <text>Whereas James Foley and Steven Sotloff were highly respected journalists whose integrity and
			 dedication were a credit to their profession;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas James Foley and Steven Sotloff embodied the spirit of our Nation’s First Amendment
			 liberties, including the freedom of the press;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas James Foley and Steven Sotloff made significant contributions to our Nation through their
			 courageous reporting of events in Libya, Syria, and elsewhere;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the Islamic State of Iraq and the Levant (ISIL) is a terrorist organization responsible for
			 committing barbaric acts against United States citizens;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas ISIL continues to hold hostages in blatant contravention of international law;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas ISIL has committed despicable acts of violence against Iraqi Christians, forcing many to
			 flee their ancient homeland;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas ISIL has committed despicable acts of violence against Muslims who do not subscribe to
			 ISIL’s depraved, violent, and oppressive ideology;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas ISIL has threatened to decimate the ancient Yazidi population of Iraq while abducting
			 Yazidi women and children and subjecting them to rape, forced marriage,
			 and slavery;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas ISIL has targeted many other religious and ethnic minority groups, including Turkmen
			 populations; and</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas ISIL threatens to conduct terrorist attacks internationally: Now, therefore, be it</text>
		</whereas>
  </preamble>
	<resolution-body>
    <section id="id01A3D7A07E644EC596EB0BEBD1C6DCF2" section-type="section-one">
      <enum>1.</enum>
      <header>Sense of the Senate</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">The <cato:entity-ref entity-id="0010" entity-type="federal-body">Senate</cato:entity-ref>—</text>
			<paragraph id="id9acd28c488bb4e1ab6eb34e590be871d">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text>strongly condemns the terrorist acts of ISIL, including the barbaric and deplorable murders of
			 James Foley and Steven Sotloff;</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="idd3dbddbcb1ec4f368d44d8f5fd887dc3">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text>mourns the deaths of James Foley and Steven Sotloff and expresses its condolences to their
			 families;</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id23d1e63114a446a2b698bcd5a2f7e9f1">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <text>salutes James Foley and Steven Sotloff for their unwavering and courageous pursuit of journalistic
			 excellence under the most difficult and dangerous of conditions;</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id470b7b2b18c344cbb1a52c9a6a686a5c">
        <enum>(4)</enum>
        <text>supports efforts to vigorously pursue and bring to justice those responsible for the murders of
			 James Foley and Steven Sotloff;</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="ida487cedd220c4b7b9dca17d33498bb25">
        <enum>(5)</enum>
        <text>demands the immediate and unconditional release of all hostages being held by ISIL; and</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id1ceb206d9346434cace141511cb8d089">
        <enum>(6)</enum>
        <text>calls on the United States and the international community, working in partnership with the
			 governments and citizens of the Middle East, to address the threat posed
			 by ISIL.</text>
			</paragraph>
    </section>
    <section id="id8DBCCC59F35D46DF83D52E373165F7CE">
      <enum>2.</enum>
      <header>Rule of construction</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this resolution shall be construed as a declaration of war or authorization to use
			 force.</text>
    </section>
  </resolution-body>
</resolution>
</doc>