<doc>
  <docmeta id="113sres358ats">
    <bill congress="113" type="sres" number="358" version="ats"/>
    <revision size="4540" annotations="0" status="complete" id="4" commit-time="2014-08-11T17:59:01Z" committer="mnewby" doc="113sres358ats/4.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <resolution xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print">
	<metadata>
<dublinCore>
<dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">113 SRES 358 ATS: Commending the Seattle Seahawks for winning Super Bowl XLVIII and the 12th Man for their critical support.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">2014-02-12</dc:date>
<dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">113th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session display="yes">2d Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. RES. 358</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20140212">February 12, 2014</action-date>
			<action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="S275">Ms. Cantwell</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="S229">Mrs. Murray</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was considered and agreed to</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">Commending the Seattle Seahawks for winning Super Bowl XLVIII and the 12<superscript>th</superscript> Man for their critical support.</official-title>
	</form>
	<preamble>
		<whereas>
      <text>Whereas on February 2, 2014, the Seattle Seahawks won Super Bowl XLVIII with a commanding 43-8
			 victory over the Denver Broncos;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas Super Bowl XLVIII is the first Super Bowl Championship won by the Seahawks franchise;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas Seahawks coach Pete Carroll is only the third coach in the history of football to win both
			 a Super Bowl in the National Football League (NFL) and a National
			 Championship in college football;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas Seahawks quarterback Russell Wilson is the third-youngest starting quarterback to win the
			 Super Bowl;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the Seahawks had a 13-3 record for the 2013 regular season, giving the Seahawks the best
			 regular season record in the National Football Conference and tying them
			 with the Broncos for the best regular season record in the NFL;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas in December 1984, the Seahawks retired the number 12 in honor of their fan base, who are
			 among the
			 loudest, proudest, and most impactful group of fans in sports, which is
			 known as <quote>the 12<superscript>th</superscript> Man</quote>;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the 12<superscript>th</superscript> Man is critical to the home field advantage of the Seahawks at CenturyLink Field, holds a world
			 record
			 for crowd noise at 137.6 decibels, and has twice triggered measurable
			 earthquakes on the Richter Scale;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the Seahawks have the top-ranked defense in the NFL, led by an unstoppable defensive line
			 and cornerback Richard Sherman and the <quote>Legion of Boom</quote> secondary;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas Seattle linebacker Malcolm Smith was named Most Valuable Player (MVP) of Super Bowl XLVIII
			 after making several key plays, including a 69-yard interception return
			 for a touchdown in the second quarter;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas Smith is the first defensive player to be named Super Bowl MVP since Super Bowl XXXVII;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the Seahawks defense contributed to a Broncos safety that was the fastest score in Super
			 Bowl history and helped the Seahawks hold the lead throughout the game
			 despite the Broncos having the highest-scoring offense in NFL history;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas Super Bowl XLVIII was the most-watched television show in United States history, with an
			 average audience of 111,500,000 people tuning in;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas Seahawks owner Paul G. Allen and team coaches, staff, players, and all of their families
			 and supporters
			 should be commended for their dedication to supporting communities
			 throughout the State of Washington with generous charity and advocacy work
			 on behalf of those less fortunate; and</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas on February 5, 2014, 700,000 fans packed the streets of Seattle to celebrate the Seahawks
			 victory: Now, therefore, be it</text>
		</whereas>
  </preamble>
	<resolution-body>
		<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="S1" section-type="undesignated-section">
      <enum/>
      <text>That the <cato:entity-ref entity-id="0010" entity-type="federal-body">Senate</cato:entity-ref>—</text>
      <paragraph id="idc64db01d977d44cf9b8cf4712b6a88e2">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text>congratulates—</text>
        <subparagraph id="idbc3ca0e13e324123ac54f09b18e34926">
          <enum>(A)</enum>
          <text>the Seattle Seahawks for their victory in Super Bowl XLVIII, the first National Football League
			 championship brought home to the Pacific Northwest;</text>
        </subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="id71ba0bfc721c44259eb4d72e4edfed08">
          <enum>(B)</enum>
          <text>Seahawks owner Paul G. Allen and the Seahawks coaching, management, and support staff;</text>
        </subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="id65136e7ce4ec4dda92c00ac12a0334e7">
          <enum>(C)</enum>
          <text>the Seahawks 12<superscript>th</superscript> Man, for being among the most loyal and loudest sports fans in the world; and</text>
        </subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="id64c91cb8d2db48e4948a96ad10672ca2">
          <enum>(D)</enum>
          <text>the Denver Broncos and quarterback Peyton Manning on a historic season; and</text>
        </subparagraph>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id87c0d30de02d44298d58b318989c796b">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text>requests the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" value="Secretary of the Senate" entity-parent-id="0010">Secretary of the Senate</cato:entity-ref> to transmit an enrolled copy of this resolution to—</text>
        <subparagraph id="ideb18ee4bb57c4aaba24758a0a8d88443">
          <enum>(A)</enum>
          <text>Seahawks owner and Chairman Paul G. Allen;</text>
        </subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="idcf6450477ace482caaa0cca87a1a2d2a">
          <enum>(B)</enum>
          <text>Seahawks President Peter McLoughlin; and</text>
        </subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="id264d284e800f4c7996e108eb1dc0c658">
          <enum>(C)</enum>
          <text>Seahawks Executive Vice President of Football Operations and Head Coach Pete Carroll.</text>
				</subparagraph>
      </paragraph>
    </section>
  </resolution-body>
</resolution>
</doc>