<doc>
  <docmeta id="113sres326ats">
    <bill congress="113" type="sres" number="326" version="ats"/>
    <revision size="4724" annotations="0" status="complete" id="5" commit-time="2014-02-11T14:44:41Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113sres326ats/5.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <resolution xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print">
  <metadata>
<dublinCore>
<dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">113 SRES 326 ATS: Congratulating the 2013 Southern New Hampshire University men's soccer team on winning the National Collegiate Athletic Association Division II Men's Soccer Championship.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"/>
<dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code>
    <congress display="yes">113th CONGRESS</congress>
    <session display="yes">1st Session</session>
    <legis-num>S. RES. 326</legis-num>
    <current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
    <action display="yes">
      <action-date>December 20, 2013</action-date>
      <action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="S324">Mrs. Shaheen</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="S340">Ms. Ayotte</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was considered and agreed to</action-desc>
    </action>
    <legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
    <official-title display="yes">Congratulating the 2013 Southern New Hampshire University men's soccer team on winning the National Collegiate Athletic Association Division II Men's Soccer Championship.</official-title>
  </form>
  <preamble>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas, on December 7, 2013, the Southern New Hampshire University (SNHU) men’s soccer team, known as the Penmen, won the National Collegiate Athletic Association (NCAA) Division II national championship in Evans, Georgia, becoming the second men’s soccer team in the history of SNHU to win a national title;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas, with their victory over the Carson-Newman University Eagles, the Penman capped off a 23-game unbeaten streak as they ended their season with 22 wins, 1 loss, and 1 draw, tying the SNHU men's soccer program’s record for most wins in a season;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the State of New Hampshire and the City of Manchester are immensely proud of the SNHU men’s soccer team, and recognize the teamwork and dedication required to win a national championship;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the student-athletes of SNHU demonstrate the same dedication to their studies as they do to athletics, having previously received the USA Today NCAA Foundation Academic Achievement Award in recognition of the high graduation rate of SNHU student-athletes;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the SNHU men’s soccer team was honored in 2013 with the Northeast-10 Team Academic Excellence Award for having the highest team grade point average in the Northeast-10 Conference for men’s soccer, and SNHU sophomore Brad Campion received the Elite 89 award for the highest cumulative grade point average at the 2013 NCAA Division II Men’s Soccer Championship;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas SNHU men’s soccer head coach Marc Hubbard, a native of Durham, New Hampshire, has led the Penmen to NCAA tournament berths in each of his 6 seasons as a coach, in addition to 2 Northeast-10 regular season and tournament titles, and has twice been honored as the Northeast-10 Coach of the Year;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas assistant coaches Josh Taylor, Rich Weinrebe, Dave Williams, and Phil Tuttle leveraged their years of experience playing and coaching the game of soccer to support Coach Hubbard and the team;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the 2013 Southern New Hampshire University men’s soccer team is comprised of—</text>
      <paragraph id="id6C33E2D6AA78459AABC93974E7609DC1">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text>1 graduate student: Callum Williams;</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id1CF335CB54A3495F87A335E3FF10CB71">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text>4 seniors: Dom DiMaggio, Christian Rodriguez, Pierre Omanga, and Brian Francolini;</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="idCFA4275072A647DC8E6490E68C86092F">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <text>9 juniors: Yannick Kabala, Joe Mahr, Mohamed Toufik, Danillo Andrade, Kenny Doublette, Kyle Logan, Miguel Carneiro, Keegan Campbell, and Chris Pereira;</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="idC5896E8A90C84160A3F4B7B875514438">
        <enum>(4)</enum>
        <text>7 sophomores: Myles Groenloh, Jonathan Lupinelli, Brad Campion, Ryan Simpson, Sebastian Stezewski, Julian Omeally, and Dominic Samuel; and</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="idF90979F59BDC457093E06A6A6D26107A">
        <enum>(5)</enum>
        <text>5 freshmen: Andrew Pesci, Ryan Reynolds, Nate Fournier, Curtis Pereira, and Eddie Legg;</text>
      </paragraph>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas 4 members of the 2013 SNHU men’s soccer team hail from the State of New Hampshire; and</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the SNHU men’s soccer team should be recognized for both its athletic and scholastic accomplishments:  Now, therefore, be it</text>
    </whereas>
  </preamble>
  <resolution-body>
    <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="S1" section-type="undesignated-section">
      <enum/>
      <text>That the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0010">Senate</cato:entity-ref>—</text>
      <paragraph id="idEC78A4E5F90B4096871ACA516E1E1C49">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text>congratulates the Southern New Hampshire University men's soccer team on winning the National Collegiate Athletic Association Division II Men's Soccer Championship;</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="idB98946E8C1BE46BF8B32CF79FE47CEA8">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text>recognizes the positive environment of scholastic and athletic achievement fostered at Southern New Hampshire University; and</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id9D4983E1A7FF4BF684ED7E1008BF0532">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <text>requests the Secretary of the Senate to transmit an enrolled copy of this resolution for appropriate display to—</text>
        <subparagraph id="id0EB44447E4584ACA95A660CDE7077702">
          <enum>(A)</enum>
          <text>Southern New Hampshire University;</text>
        </subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="id390A8BFBD28B41B0B2A2D15DF6822309">
          <enum>(B)</enum>
          <text>Paul J. LeBlanc, the president of Southern New Hampshire University; and</text>
        </subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="id554F2F925BF84E56B056DF155F5AB8D6">
          <enum>(C)</enum>
          <text>Marc Hubbard, the head coach of the Southern New Hampshire University men's soccer team.</text>
        </subparagraph>
      </paragraph>
    </section>
  </resolution-body>
</resolution>
</doc>