<doc>
  <docmeta id="113sres349is">
    <bill congress="113" type="sres" number="349" version="is"/>
    <revision size="2290" annotations="0" status="complete" id="5" commit-time="2014-02-11T15:32:41Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113sres349is/5.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <resolution xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print">
  <form>
    <distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code>
    <congress display="yes">113th CONGRESS</congress>
    <session display="yes">2d Session</session>
    <legis-num>S. RES. 349</legis-num>
    <current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
    <action display="yes">
      <action-date date="20140206">February 6, 2014</action-date>
      <action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="S275">Ms. Cantwell</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="S229">Mrs. Murray</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>
      </action-desc>
    </action>
    <legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
    <official-title display="yes">Celebrating the 30<superscript>th</superscript> Anniversary of the Walla Walla Valley American Viticultural Area.</official-title>
  </form>
  <preamble>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the Walla Walla Valley American Viticultural Area was designated an American Viticultural
			 Area on February 6, 1984;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the Walla Walla Valley American Viticultural Area is considered one of the most awarded and
			 recognized of the American Viticultural Areas in the United States;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas in 2013, 4 Walla Walla Valley American Viticultural Area wines were selected by 3 leading
			 wine publications as among the top 100 wines in the world;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the wine industry contributes over $500 million annually to the economy of Walla Walla
			 County;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas jobs in the wine industry are steadily growing in Walla Walla County and are expected to
			 account for 20 percent of jobs in Walla Walla County by 2020;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the number of wineries in the Walla Walla Valley American Viticultural Area has grown from
			 4 in 1984 to approximately 130 today;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas agricultural land devoted to growing wine grapes in the Walla Walla Valley American
			 Viticultural Area has grown from 30 acres in 1984 to 1,800 acres in 2013;
			 and</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas Walla Walla Valley American Viticultural Area wines are consistently rated highly by
			 critics and enjoyed by wine connoisseurs around the world: Now, therefore,
			 be it</text>
    </whereas>
  </preamble>
  <resolution-body>
    <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="S1" section-type="undesignated-section">
      <enum/>
      <text>That the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0010">Senate</cato:entity-ref>—</text>
      <paragraph id="idb1bb94ad401840379764e9bd1a89a27b">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text>commends the Walla Walla Valley American Viticultural Area on the occasion of its 30 year
			 anniversary;</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="idcf52d8e32c604f659dec585ead090e7e">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text>recognizes the Walla Walla Valley American Viticultural Area as a pioneer in the wine industry of
			 Washington; and</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id19f6dce28bd54c6f9132c54b70698dd4">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <text>requests the Secretary of the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0010">Senate</cato:entity-ref> to transmit an enrolled copy of this resolution for
			 appropriate display to the Walla Walla Valley Wine Alliance.</text>
      </paragraph>
    </section>
  </resolution-body>
</resolution>
</doc>