<doc>
  <docmeta id="113s675rs">
    <bill congress="113" type="s" number="675" version="rs"/>
    <revision size="45039" annotations="0" status="complete" id="4" commit-time="2014-08-01T15:21:58Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113s675rs/4.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <bill bill-stage="Reported-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public">
  <metadata>
<dublinCore>
<dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">113 S675 RS: Never Contract With the Enemy Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">2013-04-09</dc:date>
<dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
    <calendar>Calendar No. 485</calendar>
    <congress>113th CONGRESS</congress>
    <session>2d Session</session>
    <legis-num>S. 675</legis-num>
    <associated-doc role="report">[Report No. 113–216]</associated-doc>
    <current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
    <action>
      <action-date date="20130409">April 9, 2013</action-date>
      <action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="S340">Ms. Ayotte</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S341">Mr. Blumenthal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S260">Mr. Roberts</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S290">Mr. Chambliss</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S347">Mr. Moran</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S338">Mr. Manchin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S343">Mr. Boozman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S300">Mr. Burr</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S324">Mrs. Shaheen</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S299">Mr. Vitter</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name added-display-style="italic" committee-id="SSGA00" deleted-display-style="strikethrough">Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs</committee-name>
      </action-desc>
    </action>
    <action stage="Reported-in-Senate">
      <action-date>July 23, 2014</action-date>
      <action-desc>Reported by <sponsor name-id="S277">Mr. Carper</sponsor>, with an amendment</action-desc>
      <action-instruction>Strike out all after the enacting clause and insert the part printed in italic</action-instruction>
    </action>
    <legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
    <official-title>To prohibit contracting with the enemy.</official-title>
  </form>
  <legis-body>
    <section changed="deleted" committee-id="SSGA00" id="S1" reported-display-style="strikethrough" section-type="section-one">
      <enum>1.</enum>
      <header>Short
			 title</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as
			 the <quote>
          <short-title>Never Contract With the Enemy
			 Act</short-title>
        </quote>.</text>
    </section>
    <section changed="deleted" committee-id="SSGA00" id="idE3319283BAEF4F25BF1F85CAACD0FA21" reported-display-style="strikethrough">
      <enum>2.</enum>
      <header>Prohibition on
			 contracting with the enemy</header>
      <subsection id="id6C9B4D61E7314753968E121AA76DD2D3">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Statement of
			 policy</header>
        <text>It shall be the policy of the United States that executive
			 agencies shall not contract with the enemy or with a person or entity that
			 has
			 been identified as providing funds received under a contract, grant, or
			 cooperative agreement directly or indirectly to an enemy of the United
			 States
			 or otherwise supporting those who are actively opposing the United States
			 or
			 coalition forces in a contingency operation.</text>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="idC6A4D234BD95459E977F18421A5ED09F">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Authority To
			 terminate or void contracts, grants, and cooperative agreements and To
			 restrict
			 future award</header>
        <paragraph id="idFEFCE7E49CC948E09670985587E74609">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>In
			 general</header>
          <text>Not later than 30 days after the date of the enactment of
			 this Act, the Federal Acquisition Regulation shall be revised to provide
			 that,
			 upon notice from a Senior Procurement Executive or the commander of a
			 geographic combatant command under subsection (e)(3), the head of
			 contracting
			 activity of an executive agency may do the following:</text>
          <subparagraph id="id593ADBC720E2429394F5D100A2DCF7C9">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>If the notice is
			 that a person or entity has been identified as providing funds received
			 under a
			 contract, grant, or cooperative agreement of the executive agency directly
			 or
			 indirectly to an enemy of the United States or a person or entity who is
			 actively supporting an enemy of the United States or otherwise supporting
			 those
			 who are actively opposing United States or coalition forces in a
			 contingency
			 operation—</text>
            <clause id="id84C693C7344B4BA68327835DC072CF1C">
              <enum>(i)</enum>
              <text>either—</text>
              <subclause id="idCEBC91B2794D47DE89CAC54B1497ABF7">
                <enum>(I)</enum>
                <text>terminate for
			 default the contract, grant, or cooperative agreement; or</text>
              </subclause>
              <subclause id="id19BDB2ECBD1B4EBE8B31A0F7AA5F4B1F">
                <enum>(II)</enum>
                <text>void the
			 contract, grant, or cooperative agreement in whole or in part; and</text>
              </subclause>
            </clause>
            <clause id="id78944DF89D1B47BC9104423C4FB42A33">
              <enum>(ii)</enum>
              <text>restrict the
			 future award to the person or entity so identified of contracts, grants,
			 or
			 cooperative agreements of the executive agency.</text>
            </clause>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="id29ef140334984d2796f4269dba411977">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>If the notice is
			 that the person or entity has failed to exercise due diligence to ensure
			 that
			 none of the funds received under a contract, grant, or cooperative
			 agreement of
			 the executive entity are provided directly or indirectly to an enemy of
			 the
			 United States or a person or entity who is actively supporting an enemy of
			 the
			 United States or otherwise supporting those who are actively opposing
			 United
			 States or coalition forces in a contingency operation, terminate for
			 default
			 the contract, grant, or cooperative agreement.</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="idA2677C062B624FC78F2772F239B8A13C">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Treatment as
			 void</header>
          <text>For purposes of this section:</text>
          <subparagraph id="id38861b388bed47e69fbbfa7df2eb06ec">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>A contract,
			 grant, or cooperative agreement that is void is unenforceable as contrary
			 to
			 public policy.</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="id5967ac510f1e4ccdbb701887d812d91c">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>A contract,
			 grant, or cooperative agreement that is void in part is unenforceable as
			 contrary to public policy with regard to a segregable task or effort under
			 the
			 contract, grant, or cooperative agreement.</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="id5EE6ED0DF34841CE920F765D238EA458">
        <enum>(c)</enum>
        <header>Contract
			 clause</header>
        <paragraph id="id66E1A913E8D84E83BC340C16817247B0">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>In
			 general</header>
          <text>Not later than 30 days after the date of the enactment of
			 this Act, the Federal Acquisition Regulation shall be revised to require
			 that—</text>
          <subparagraph id="idc3b9eea3591b4110a9963ec9f0dbeb70">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>the clause
			 described in paragraph (2) shall be included in each covered contract,
			 grant,
			 and cooperative agreement of an executive agency that is awarded on or
			 after
			 the date of the enactment of this Act; and</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="idcf796e4130984791b5f00948638f68df">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>to the maximum
			 extent practicable, each covered contract, grant, and cooperative
			 agreement of
			 an executive agency that is awarded before the date of the enactment of
			 this
			 Act shall be modified to include the clause described in paragraph (2),
			 other
			 than the matter provided for in subparagraph (A) of that paragraph.</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="id59D15F2BC0634A6F81E402EAB494441C">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Clause
			 described</header>
          <text>The clause described in this paragraph is a clause
			 that—</text>
          <subparagraph id="id627380BF9D784A5A9ABD4F6FCC2961ED">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>requires the
			 contractor, or the recipient of the grant or cooperative agreement, to
			 certify
			 in connection with entry into the contract, grant, or cooperative
			 agreement
			 that the contractor or recipient, as the case may be, has never knowingly
			 provided funds directly or indirectly to an enemy of the United States or
			 a
			 person or entity who is actively supporting an enemy of the United States
			 or
			 otherwise knowingly supported those who are actively opposing United
			 States or
			 coalition forces in a contingency operation;</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="idaf0e13aa9f43436c84536eb309720600">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>requires the
			 contractor, or the recipient of the grant or cooperative agreement, to
			 exercise
			 due diligence to ensure that none of the funds received under the
			 contract,
			 grant, or cooperative agreement are provided directly or indirectly to an
			 enemy
			 of the United States or a person or entity who is actively supporting an
			 enemy
			 of the United States or otherwise supporting those who are actively
			 opposing
			 United States or coalition forces in a contingency operation; and</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="id33a45f8046d647b48c57bc91f2a8543c">
            <enum>(C)</enum>
            <text>notifies the
			 contractor, or the recipient of the grant or cooperative agreement, of the
			 authority of the head of the contracting activity to terminate or void the
			 contract, grant, or cooperative agreement, in whole or in part, as
			 provided in
			 subsection (b).</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="idA76582F7B0564AC1B8097658BE73A4A1">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <header>Covered
			 contract, grant, or cooperative agreement</header>
          <text>In this subsection, the
			 term <quote>covered contract, grant, or cooperative agreement</quote> means a
			 contract, grant, or cooperative agreement with an estimated value in
			 excess of
			 $20,000.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="id00938977F5B949FE9ED7568EA0B66299">
        <enum>(d)</enum>
        <header>Requirements
			 following contract actions</header>
        <text>Not later than 30 days after the date
			 of the enactment of this Act, the Federal Acquisition Regulation shall be
			 revised as follows:</text>
        <paragraph id="idDD491F512C5445ACA54062965681DC11">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>To require that
			 any head of contracting activity taking an action under subsection (b) to
			 terminate, void, or restrict a contract, grant, or cooperative agreement
			 notify
			 in writing the contractor or recipient of the grant or cooperative
			 agreement,
			 as applicable, of the action.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="idAAC18DD77A5649C281A7711473FA7C7C">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>To permit, in
			 such manner as the Federal Acquisition Regulation as so revised shall
			 provide,
			 the contractor or recipient of a grant or cooperative agreement subject to
			 an
			 action taken under subsection (b) to terminate or void the contract,
			 grant, or
			 cooperative agreement, as the case may be, an opportunity to contest the
			 action
			 within 30 days of receipt of notice of the action.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="idC9358B9F2B6E4B248E6F9FFC36ADC908">
        <enum>(e)</enum>
        <header>Identification
			 of supporters of the enemy</header>
        <paragraph id="id1D732B966D3944D8A0527BD23C9098B8">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>Identification</header>
          <text>Not
			 later than 30 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the
			 Secretary
			 of Defense and each Senior Procurement Executive shall carry out a program
			 to
			 use available intelligence (including information made available pursuant
			 to
			 subsection (g)(1)) to—</text>
          <subparagraph id="id05FC7BD17F10496382A3F9263417F26F">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>either—</text>
            <clause id="id047028A68D4E45FF8F452E92A04BEA74">
              <enum>(i)</enum>
              <text>in
			 the case of the geographic combatant commands, review persons and entities
			 who
			 receive United States funds through contracts, grants, and cooperative
			 agreements performed for such commands in their areas of responsibility;
			 or</text>
            </clause>
            <clause id="idC9026EDDEFD84E0BBF17F80195E0BD74">
              <enum>(ii)</enum>
              <text>in
			 the case of the Senior Procurement Executives, review persons and entities
			 who
			 receive United States funds through contracts, grants, and cooperative
			 agreements performed for their agencies; and</text>
            </clause>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="idB4E8126278D14078BE31BC0B7538E4C7">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>identify any such
			 persons and entities who are providing funds received under a contract,
			 grant,
			 or cooperative agreement of an executive agency directly or indirectly to
			 an
			 enemy of the United States or a person or entity who is actively
			 supporting an
			 enemy of the United States or otherwise supporting those who are actively
			 opposing United States or coalition forces in a contingency operation.</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="idB4033DF1C7FA4251A4FB658831D271D2">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Discharge by
			 DoD through commanders of combatant commands</header>
          <text>The Secretary of
			 Defense shall carry out the program required by paragraph (1) through the
			 commanders of the geographic combatant commands.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="id787F7A44FA1948539564C6D19D8C0AB1">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <header>Notification of
			 contracting activities</header>
          <text>If a Senior Procurement Executive or the
			 commander of a geographic combatant command, acting pursuant to a program
			 required by paragraph (1), identifies a person or entity as actively
			 supporting
			 an enemy of the United States or otherwise supporting those who are
			 actively
			 opposing United States or coalition forces in a contingency operation, the
			 Senior Procurement Executive or commander, as the case may be, shall
			 notify the
			 heads of contracting activities of the executive agencies in writing of
			 such
			 identification. Any written notification pursuant to this paragraph shall
			 be
			 made in accordance with procedures established to implement the revisions
			 to
			 the Federal Acquisition Regulation required by this section.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="id1C0F931AA6D745C1AE5712F3310056A1">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
          <header>Annual
			 review</header>
          <text>As part of the programs required by paragraph (1), the
			 Senior Procurement Executives and the commanders of the geographic
			 combatant
			 commands shall, on an annual basis, review the lists of persons and
			 entities
			 previously covered by a notice under paragraph (3) as having been
			 identified
			 pursuant to paragraph (1)(B) in order to determine whether or not such
			 persons
			 and entities continue to warrant identification pursuant to paragraph
			 (1)(B).
			 If a Senior Procurement Executive or commander determines pursuant to such
			 a
			 review that a person or entity no longer warrants identification pursuant
			 to
			 paragraph (1)(B), the Senior Procurement Executive or commander, as the
			 case
			 may be, shall notify the heads of contracting activities of the executive
			 agencies in writing of such determination.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="idD86C933E2BB44102860CA19F0F502A14">
          <enum>(5)</enum>
          <header>Protection of
			 classified information</header>
          <text>Classified information relied upon to make
			 an identification in accordance with this subsection may not be disclosed
			 to a
			 contractor or a recipient of a grant or cooperative agreement with respect
			 to
			 which an action is taken pursuant to the authority provided in subsection
			 (b),
			 or to their representatives, in the absence of a protective order issued
			 by a
			 court of competent jurisdiction established under Article I or Article III
			 of
			 the Constitution of the United States that specifically addresses the
			 conditions upon which such classified information may be so disclosed.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="id14A7A2021F39449B8D02983F48237B2C">
        <enum>(f)</enum>
        <header>Delegation of
			 certain responsibilities</header>
        <paragraph id="id92C2F1BB040B4F9790363BCA27109BAD">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>Responsibility
			 to identify and provide notice</header>
          <text>A Senior Procurement Executive may
			 delegate the responsibilities in paragraphs (1), (3), and (4) of
			 subsection (e)
			 to the designated deputy of such Executive. The commander of a geographic
			 combatant command may delegate the responsibilities in such paragraphs to
			 the
			 deputy commander of that combatant command. Any delegation of
			 responsibilities
			 under this paragraph shall be made in writing.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="id1BA28401E28148A89E4E85ED08006105">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Nondelegation
			 of responsibility for contract actions</header>
          <text>The authority provided by
			 subsection (b) to terminate, void, or restrict contracts, grants, and
			 cooperative agreements may not be delegated below the level of head of
			 contracting activity.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="idEE22BEC9F8E2406883AB46D6BB9B61B1">
        <enum>(g)</enum>
        <header>Additional
			 responsibilities of executive agencies</header>
        <paragraph id="idA34CE6C382D2470599C85C6D0B46F7EA">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>Dissemination
			 of information on supporters of the enemy</header>
          <text>The Secretary of
			 Defense and the Administrator for Federal Procurement Policy shall jointly
			 carry out a program through which the contracting activities of the
			 executive
			 agencies may provide information to Senior Procurement Executives and the
			 commanders of the geographic combatant commands relating to persons or
			 entities
			 who may be providing funds received under contracts, grants, or
			 cooperative
			 agreements of the executive agencies directly or indirectly to an enemy of
			 the
			 United States or a person or entity who is actively supporting an enemy of
			 the
			 United States or otherwise supporting those who are actively opposing
			 United
			 States or coalition forces in a contingency operation. The program shall
			 be
			 designed to facilitate and encourage the sharing of information between
			 executive agencies and the geographic combatant commands.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="id71A4C06783614789AB4A98A00DFE8C5A">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Inclusion of
			 information on contract actions in FAPIIS</header>
          <text>Upon the termination,
			 voiding, or restriction of a contract, grant, or cooperative agreement of
			 an
			 executive agency under subsection (b), the head of contracting activity of
			 the
			 executive agency shall provide for the inclusion in the Federal Awardee
			 Performance and Integrity Information System (FAPIIS), or other formal
			 system
			 of records on contractors or entities, of appropriate information on the
			 termination, voiding, or restriction, as the case may be, of the contract,
			 grant, or cooperative agreement.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="idE6CB3CC6E65E42E1AE7B11FBDE96D78B">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <header>Reports</header>
          <text>The
			 head of contracting activity that receives a notice pursuant to subsection
			 (e)(3) shall submit to the Senior Procurement Executives and the
			 commanders of
			 the geographic combatant commands a report on the action, if any, taken by
			 the
			 head of contracting activity pursuant to subsection (b), including a
			 determination not to terminate, void, or restrict the contract, grant, or
			 cooperative agreement as otherwise authorized by subsection (b).</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="id8D6A72112DC548D283E864C7DE07B704">
        <enum>(h)</enum>
        <header>Reports</header>
        <paragraph id="id04D9D00D07234ECCB6573D9B0D9C823A">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>In
			 general</header>
          <text>Not later than March 1 each year, the Secretary of
			 Defense shall, in consultation with the heads of other executive agencies,
			 submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report on the use of
			 the
			 authorities in this section in the preceding calendar year, including the
			 following:</text>
          <subparagraph id="id7C1C1686DE254A6EA1BF327F344FA92E">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>For each instance
			 in which an executive agency exercised the authority to terminate, void,
			 or
			 restrict a contract, grant, and cooperative agreement pursuant to
			 subsection
			 (b), the following:</text>
            <clause id="id7880D15744A2451CA86A7501915C0B4E">
              <enum>(i)</enum>
              <text>The
			 executive agency taking such action.</text>
            </clause>
            <clause id="id50567C6CCEC4444C9471951E8D3E62F2">
              <enum>(ii)</enum>
              <text>An
			 explanation of the basis for the action taken.</text>
            </clause>
            <clause id="idA8693D9F91774F86968742D08CCDCFB3">
              <enum>(iii)</enum>
              <text>The value of
			 the contract, grant, or cooperative agreement voided or terminated.</text>
            </clause>
            <clause id="id5EADCD56A2F74EC997A2E5489ACDD614">
              <enum>(iv)</enum>
              <text>The value of all
			 contracts, grants, or cooperative agreements of the executive agency in
			 force
			 with the person or entity concerned at the time the contract, grant, or
			 cooperative agreement was terminated or voided.</text>
            </clause>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="id50F278338E264BC7B6523A79107C3312">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>For each instance
			 in which an executive agency did not exercise the authority to terminate,
			 void,
			 or restrict a contract, grant, and cooperative agreement pursuant to
			 subsection
			 (b) as requested pursuant to subsection (e)(3), the following:</text>
            <clause id="id08D2C7931759476799EFA3D01F230EF0">
              <enum>(i)</enum>
              <text>The
			 executive agency concerned.</text>
            </clause>
            <clause id="id9D94F25486A4457F9198B1A65793CF11">
              <enum>(ii)</enum>
              <text>An
			 explanation why the action was not taken.</text>
            </clause>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="id980206331D9649F0B5923E5444F381FD">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Form</header>
          <text>Any
			 report under this subsection may be submitted in classified form.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="id5AA5E0EBF822461893625D3E550E11BD">
        <enum>(i)</enum>
        <header>Other
			 definitions</header>
        <text>In this section:</text>
        <paragraph id="id2287F3F73F1643F5AFE40E09D120541C">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>The term
			 <term>appropriate committees of Congress</term> means—</text>
          <subparagraph id="idF3F79732A3444196808350AEB4F5ED0F">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>the Committee on
			 Armed Services, the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental
			 Affairs,
			 and the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate; and</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="id34B9EA25415346E29F69A9BCFBBF1DB6">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>the Committee on
			 Armed Services, the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, and the
			 Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives.</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="idFD191F81BA434DFD9221616E06E4F95A">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>The term
			 <term>combatant command</term> means a command established pursuant to chapter
			 6 of title 10, United States Code.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="idFF09A83555F04BF0B01B7A09F34EC449">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <text>The term
			 <term>contingency operation</term> has the meaning given that term in section
			 101(a)(13) of title 10, United States Code.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="idDB88ED1EBFBB4269A9E1434AEAFF376B">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
          <text>The term
			 <term>enemy of the United States</term> means any of the following:</text>
          <subparagraph id="id470BDAE78CCD438CA9BD803EDB9CDE1D">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>Any person or
			 organization determined by the Secretary of Defense or the Secretary of
			 State
			 to be hostile to United States forces or interests or providing support to
			 any
			 person or organization hostile to United States forces or interests during
			 the
			 time of a declared war, peacekeeping operation, or other military or
			 contingency operation.</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="id2792EBE04F564F70AE6C6ACBEB765493">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>Any organization
			 designated as a terrorist organization under section 219(a) of the
			 Immigration
			 and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1189">
                8 U.S.C. 1189(a)
              </external-xref>).</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="idC084933CE2B54CCF9C42A9626EAB0BC1">
          <enum>(5)</enum>
          <text>The term
			 <term>executive agency</term> has the meaning given that term in section 133 of
			 title 41, United States Code.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="id80BAD13DBC3947E69489449ED40E0776">
          <enum>(6)</enum>
          <text>The term
			 <term>head of contracting activity</term> has the meaning given that term in
			 subpart 601 of part 1 of the Federal Acquisition Regulation.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="id611B5251CAEF449AAA691BB73549DF97">
          <enum>(7)</enum>
          <text>The term
			 <term>Senior Procurement Executive</term> has the meaning given that term in
			 <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/41/1702">section 1702</external-xref> of title 41, United States Code.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="idE72BE1DD975547678AC9F7CE35CBC2F2">
        <enum>(j)</enum>
        <header>Coordination
			 with current authorities applicable to CENTCOM</header>
        <paragraph id="id38C3D15FA0944463BE3B274610AF32EE">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>Repeal of
			 superseded authority</header>
          <text>Effective 30 days after the date of the
			 enactment of this Act, section 841 of the National Defense Authorization
			 Act
			 for Fiscal Year 2012 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/112/81">
              Public Law 112–81
            </external-xref>; 125 Stat. 1510; 10 U.S.C. 2302
			 note)
			 is repealed.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="id541E7A6F573F4F0AA8B1BC8AA9432518">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Use of
			 superseded authorities in discharge of requirements</header>
          <text>In providing
			 for the discharge of the requirements of this section by the Department of
			 Defense, the Secretary of Defense may use and modify for that purpose
			 requirements and procedures established by the Secretary for purposes of
			 the
			 discharge of the requirements of section 841 of the National Defense
			 Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2012.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
    </section>
  </legis-body>
  <legis-body display-enacting-clause="no-display-enacting-clause">
    <section changed="added" committee-id="SSGA00" id="id12A40087F5EF42D7AB487FCA08F7C5B2" reported-display-style="italic" section-type="section-one">
      <enum>1.</enum>
      <header>Short title</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote>
          <short-title>
            <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Never Contract With the Enemy Act" proposed="true">Never Contract With the Enemy Act</cato:entity-ref>
          </short-title>
        </quote>.</text>
    </section>
    <section changed="added" committee-id="SSGA00" id="id1A21ED058E99499DB652B0C0501B9FFC" reported-display-style="italic" section-type="subsequent-section">
      <enum>2.</enum>
      <header>Prohibition on providing funds to the enemy</header>
      <subsection id="ida4e124381b234960854fdaf7df7d4393">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Identification of persons and entities</header>
        <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="9700" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of Defense</cato:entity-ref> shall, in conjunction with the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Director of National Intelligence">Director of National Intelligence</cato:entity-ref> and in
			 consultation with the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1900" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref>, establish in each covered
			 combatant command a program to identify persons and entities within the
			 area of responsibility of such command that—</text>
        <paragraph id="idd8431c8ebbef42a699b8e5e5584c623f">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>provide funds, including goods and services, received under a contract, grant, or cooperative
			 agreement of an executive agency directly or indirectly to a covered
			 person or entity; or</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="id6f2be56b1726487e985adc875171a9b6">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>fail to exercise due diligence to ensure that none of the funds, including goods and services,
			 received under a contract, grant, or cooperative agreement of an executive
			 agency are provided directly or indirectly to a covered person or entity.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="idD979F78FE0FC481984CB4EC8D161F490">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Notice of identified persons and entities</header>
        <paragraph id="id7D81474A991D4FF7967826F9CF8E548A">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>Notice</header>
          <text>Upon the identification of a person or entity as  being described by <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Never Contract With the Enemy Act/s:2/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref>, the head of an
			 executive agency (or the designee of such head) or the commander of a
			 covered  combatant command (or the specified deputies of the commander)
			 shall be notified, in writing, of such identification of the person or
			 entity.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="id21401FBB28024D71AA24C7FB218D50AB">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Responsive actions</header>
          <text>Upon receipt of a notice under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Never Contract With the Enemy Act/s:2/ss:b/p:1" proposed="true">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref>, the head of an executive agency (or the designee of
			 such head) or the commander of a covered combatant command (or the
			 specified deputies of the commander) may notify the heads of contracting
			 activities, or other appropriate officials of the agency or command, in
			 writing of such identification.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="id1F8FA1952DF642AFAEEA9C5BAEAA1041">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <header>Making of notifications</header>
          <text>Any written notification pursuant to this subsection shall be made in accordance with procedures
			 established to implement the revisions of regulations required by this
			 section.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="id4d180160d7db42e49b6e04dfe546675e">
        <enum>(c)</enum>
        <header>Authority to terminate or void contracts, grants, and cooperative agreements and to restrict future
			 award</header>
        <text>Not later than 270 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Federal Acquisition
			 Regulation, the Defense Federal Acquisition Regulation Supplement, and the
			 Uniform
			 Administrative Requirements, Cost Principles, and Account Requirements for
			 Federal Awards shall be revised to provide that, upon notice from the head
			 of an executive agency (or the designee of such head) or the commander of
			 a covered combatant command (or the specified deputies of the commander)
			 pursuant to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Never Contract With the Enemy Act/s:2/ss:b" proposed="true">subsection (b)</cato:entity-ref>, the head of contracting activity of an
			 executive agency, or other appropriate official, may do the following:</text>
        <paragraph id="id2B949C032ECB408F97720D378BBA9B62">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>Restrict the award of contracts, grants, or cooperative agreements of the executive agency
			 concerned upon a written determination by the head of contracting activity
			 or other appropriate official that the contract, grant, or cooperative
			 agreement would provide funds received under such contract, grant, or
			 cooperative agreement directly or indirectly to a covered person or
			 entity.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="id55171E09FB4841F99F8655DAB35AE5D0">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>Terminate for default any contract, grant, or cooperative agreement of the executive agency
			 concerned upon a written determination by the head of contracting activity
			 or other appropriate official that the contractor, or the recipient of the
			 grant or cooperative agreement, has failed to exercise due diligence to
			 ensure that none of the funds received under the contract, grant, or
			 cooperative agreement are provided directly or indirectly to a covered
			 person or entity.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="id3871F294662D4A5BAA9EFFE4163AED6D">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <text>Void in whole or in part any contract, grant, or cooperative agreement of the executive agency
			 concerned upon a written determination by the head of contracting activity
			 or other appropriate official that the contract, grant, or cooperative
			 agreement provides funds directly or indirectly to a covered person or
			 entity.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="id304795cf19ef43a5ac7f79001cf96964">
        <enum>(d)</enum>
        <header>Clause</header>
        <paragraph id="id4960447f7611412481bbde5e6afa5dbb">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>In general</header>
          <text>Not later than 270 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Federal Acquisition
			 Regulation, the Defense Federal Acquisition Regulation Supplement, and the
			 Uniform Administrative Requirements, Cost Principles, and Account
			 Requirements for Federal Awards shall be revised to require that—</text>
          <subparagraph id="idcc0131e6341444b18e888b38c974974f">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>the clause described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Never Contract With the Enemy Act/s:2/ss:d/p:2" proposed="true">paragraph (2)</cato:entity-ref> shall be included in each covered contract, grant, and
			 cooperative agreement of an executive agency that is awarded on or after
			 the date that is 270 days after the date of the enactment of this Act; and</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="idcf1afb38cc2c48eab1474d8eb8bd49ed">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>to the maximum extent practicable, each covered contract, grant, and cooperative agreement of an
			 executive agency that is awarded before the date of the enactment of this
			 Act shall be modified to include the clause described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Never Contract With the Enemy Act/s:2/ss:d/p:2" proposed="true">paragraph (2)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="id03acd0f8ab77449eb3909563f96656ec">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Clause described</header>
          <text>The clause described in this paragraph is a clause that—</text>
          <subparagraph id="id5d3d57e6c1fc402fa6c5515b66d7e52d">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>requires the contractor, or the recipient of the grant or cooperative agreement, to exercise due
			 diligence to ensure that none of the funds, including goods and services,
			 received under the contract, grant, or cooperative agreement are provided
			 directly or indirectly to a covered person or entity; and</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="id167e83808f0345319c596d55d7384c0d">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>notifies the contractor, or the recipient of the grant or cooperative agreement, of the authority
			 of the head of the contracting activity, or other appropriate official, to
			 terminate or void the contract, grant, or cooperative agreement, in whole
			 or in part, as provided in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Never Contract With the Enemy Act/s:2/ss:c" proposed="true">subsection (c)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="id24EA0D1CE9F845968DF5BD91637A7202">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <header>Treatment as void</header>
          <text>For purposes of this section:</text>
          <subparagraph id="id1F005CA4781B46C2993D1B8BE16E44EA">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>A contract, grant, or cooperative agreement that is void is unenforceable as contrary to public
			 policy.</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="idB308E940AAD14C8D8C46AF8446D7220C">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>A contract, grant, or cooperative agreement that is void in part is unenforceable as contrary to
			 public policy with regard to a segregable task or effort under the
			 contract, grant, or cooperative agreement.</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="id43f07f9f4977414f8213e434b6c79d80">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
          <header>Public comment</header>
          <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> shall ensure that the process for amending regulations required by <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Never Contract With the Enemy Act/s:2/ss:d/p:1" proposed="true">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref>
			 shall include an opportunity for public comment, including an opportunity
			 for comment on standards of due diligence required by this Act.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="id0b2542b5a6cd4a04baa5e37850339d6d">
        <enum>(e)</enum>
        <header>Requirements following contract actions</header>
        <text>Not later than 270 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Federal Acquisition
			 Regulation, the Defense Federal Acquisition Regulation Supplement, and the
			 Uniform Administrative Requirements, Cost Principles, and Account
			 Requirements for Federal Awards shall be revised as follows:</text>
        <paragraph id="id5511cd1c5ffb492381ec83fb10a5cee8">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>To require that any head of contracting activity, or other appropriate official, taking an action
			 under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Never Contract With the Enemy Act/s:2/ss:c" proposed="true">subsection (c)</cato:entity-ref> to terminate, void, or restrict a contract, grant, or
			 cooperative agreement notify in writing the contractor or recipient of the
			 grant or cooperative agreement, as applicable, of the action.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="id3296c0d275d447989d5aad17b65bbeed">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>To permit the contractor or recipient of a grant or cooperative agreement subject to an action
			 taken under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Never Contract With the Enemy Act/s:2/ss:c" proposed="true">subsection (c)</cato:entity-ref> to terminate or void the contract, grant, or
			 cooperative agreement, as the case may be, an opportunity to challenge the
			 action by requesting an administrative review of the action under the
			 procedures of the executive agency concerned not later than 30 days after
			 receipt of notice of the action.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="id9bf946ed52be4caa829966cfa9156e3e">
        <enum>(f)</enum>
        <header>Annual review; protection of classified information</header>
        <paragraph id="id263e7b804296442e814b60350286d605">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>Annual review</header>
          <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="9700" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of Defense</cato:entity-ref>, in conjunction with the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Director of National Intelligence">Director of National Intelligence</cato:entity-ref> and in
			 consultation with the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1900" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref> shall, on an annual basis, review
			 the lists of persons and entities previously covered by a notice under
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Never Contract With the Enemy Act/s:2/ss:b" proposed="true">subsection (b)</cato:entity-ref> as having been identified as described by <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Never Contract With the Enemy Act/s:2/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref> in
			 order to determine whether or not such persons and entities continue to
			 warrant identification as described by <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Never Contract With the Enemy Act/s:2/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref>. If  a determination
			 is made pursuant to such a review that a person or entity no longer
			 warrants identification as described by <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Never Contract With the Enemy Act/s:2/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="9700" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of
			 Defense</cato:entity-ref> shall notify the head of an executive agency (or designee) or
			 commander (or deputy), as the case may be, in writing of such
			 determination.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="idf9a82bce78b34bceb9eeab2967c7ddd0">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Protection of classified information</header>
          <text>Classified information relied upon to make an identification in accordance with <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Never Contract With the Enemy Act/s:2/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref> may
			 not be disclosed to a contractor or a recipient of a grant or cooperative
			 agreement with respect to which an action is taken pursuant to the
			 authority provided in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Never Contract With the Enemy Act/s:2/ss:c" proposed="true">subsection (c)</cato:entity-ref>, or to their representatives, in the
			 absence of a protective order issued by a court of competent jurisdiction
			 established under Article I or Article III of the Constitution of the
			 United States that specifically addresses the conditions upon which such
			 classified information may be so disclosed.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="id94a97518937a452ebd0bd85bc9da3dc0">
        <enum>(g)</enum>
        <header>Delegation of certain responsibilities</header>
        <paragraph id="id6db3546141af433dba46202369a897c1">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>Combatant command responsibilities</header>
          <text>The commander of a covered combatant command may delegate the responsibilities in this section to
			 any deputies of the commander	specified by the commander for purposes of
			 this section. Any delegation of responsibilities under this paragraph
			 shall be made in writing.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="idef97ad288c61462686752107a2a5d1a8">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Nondelegation of responsibility for certain actions</header>
          <text>The authority provided by <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Never Contract With the Enemy Act/s:2/ss:c" proposed="true">subsection (c)</cato:entity-ref> to terminate, void, or restrict contracts, grants, and
			 cooperative agreements, in whole or in part,  may not be delegated below
			 the level of head of contracting activity, or equivalent official for
			 purposes of grants or	cooperative agreements.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="idc45a6b7575f541eba871db898c3c4332">
        <enum>(h)</enum>
        <header>Additional responsibilities of executive agencies</header>
        <paragraph id="id6520d025732c45ae94c6395768e3e933">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>Sharing of information on supporters of the enemy</header>
          <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="9700" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of Defense</cato:entity-ref> shall, in consultation with the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1103" entity-type="federal-body">Director of the Office of Management and
			 Budget</cato:entity-ref>, carry out a program through which agency components may provide
			 information to heads of executive agencies (or the designees of such
			 heads) and the commanders of the covered  combatant commands (or the
			 specified deputies of the commanders) relating to persons or entities who
			 may be providing funds, including goods and services, received under
			 contracts, grants, or cooperative agreements of the executive agencies
			 directly or indirectly to a covered person or entity. The program shall be
			 designed to facilitate and encourage the sharing of risk and threat
			 information between executive agencies and the covered combatant commands.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="id70a63ff97bfd42b0b83d2f52c4c60912">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Inclusion of information on contract actions in fapiis and other systems</header>
          <text>Upon the termination, voiding, or restriction of a contract, grant, or cooperative agreement of an
			 executive agency under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Never Contract With the Enemy Act/s:2/ss:c" proposed="true">subsection (c)</cato:entity-ref>, the head of contracting activity of
			 the executive agency shall provide for the inclusion in the Federal
			 Awardee Performance and Integrity Information System (FAPIIS), or other
			 formal system of records on contractors or entities, of appropriate
			 information on the termination, voiding, or restriction, as the case may
			 be, of the contract, grant, or cooperative agreement.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="id1005f2640cd44e6e874818b8b4afd01f">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <header>Reports</header>
          <text>The head of contracting activity that receives a notice pursuant to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Never Contract With the Enemy Act/s:2/ss:b" proposed="true">subsection (b)</cato:entity-ref> shall submit to
			 the head of the executive agency (or designee) concerned or the
			 appropriate covered  combatant command, as the case may be, a report on
			 the action, if any, taken by the head of contracting activity pursuant to
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Never Contract With the Enemy Act/s:2/ss:c" proposed="true">subsection (c)</cato:entity-ref>, including a determination not to terminate, void, or
			 restrict the contract, grant, or cooperative agreement as otherwise
			 authorized by <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Never Contract With the Enemy Act/s:2/ss:c" proposed="true">subsection (c)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="id3704b3117a944a6fa9b89abc58258fdc">
        <enum>(i)</enum>
        <header>Reports</header>
        <paragraph id="id657ae6494fbd4748b4785e3835eb2910">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>In general</header>
          <text>Not later than March 1 of 2016, 2017, and 2018, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1103" entity-type="federal-body">Director of the Office of Management and Budget</cato:entity-ref>
			 shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report on the use
			 of the authorities in this section in the preceding calendar year,
			 including the following:</text>
          <subparagraph id="ida708cd1ef0f9402a9188430a54459834">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>For each instance in which an executive agency exercised the authority to terminate, void, or
			 restrict a contract, grant, and cooperative agreement pursuant to
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Never Contract With the Enemy Act/s:2/ss:c" proposed="true">subsection (c)</cato:entity-ref>, based on a notification under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Never Contract With the Enemy Act/s:2/ss:b" proposed="true">subsection (b)</cato:entity-ref>, the
			 following:</text>
            <clause id="idfddf212a41ab4dd8b14e9d3735a2966f">
              <enum>(i)</enum>
              <text>The executive agency taking such action.</text>
            </clause>
            <clause id="idf06155dab8b54317ac9d419a0f69c75b">
              <enum>(ii)</enum>
              <text>An explanation of the basis for the action taken.</text>
            </clause>
            <clause id="id036bcd526d114fa5af08351dea03d409">
              <enum>(iii)</enum>
              <text>The value of the contract, grant, or cooperative agreement voided or terminated.</text>
            </clause>
            <clause id="iddbb9677724574a1eb534ccdade9ac86b">
              <enum>(iv)</enum>
              <text>The value of all contracts, grants, or cooperative agreements of the executive agency in force with
			 the person or entity concerned at the time the contract, grant, or
			 cooperative agreement was terminated or voided.</text>
            </clause>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="idb34764418ede47a394f19faec3b3e1ce">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>For each instance in which an executive agency did not exercise the authority to terminate, void,
			 or restrict a contract, grant, and cooperative agreement pursuant to
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Never Contract With the Enemy Act/s:2/ss:c" proposed="true">subsection (c)</cato:entity-ref>, based on a notification under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Never Contract With the Enemy Act/s:2/ss:b" proposed="true">subsection (b)</cato:entity-ref>, the
			 following:</text>
            <clause id="id14267b63d43e4e3a80d21b5a6f619f1e">
              <enum>(i)</enum>
              <text>The executive agency concerned.</text>
            </clause>
            <clause id="id87edc303c1294e7cb55347a30a1c2623">
              <enum>(ii)</enum>
              <text>An explanation why the action was not taken.</text>
            </clause>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="id22e73745b2fb4eb4a5e93194da300047">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Form</header>
          <text>Any report under this subsection may, at the election of the Director—</text>
          <subparagraph id="id483AB252B9BA44F39200D76BD6D2A8D2">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>be submitted in unclassified form, but with a classified annex; or</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="id4B3EF8CEF20F44F5A2DA38661DC12924">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>be submitted in classified form.</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="idfc780653fabd478e8776e1993bdab6b2">
        <enum>(j)</enum>
        <header>National security exception</header>
        <text>Nothing in this section shall apply to the authorized intelligence or law enforcement activities of
			 the United States Government.</text>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="id137e6abadd5146b7807445a24e09bccc">
        <enum>(k)</enum>
        <header>Construction with other authorities</header>
        <text>Except as provided in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Never Contract With the Enemy Act/s:2/ss:l" proposed="true">subsection (l)</cato:entity-ref>, the authorities in this section shall be in addition to, and
			 not to the exclusion of, any other authorities available to executive
			 agencies to implement policies and purposes similar to those set forth in
			 this section.</text>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="id1282A10DDCC4445E854EBDB0F908D4F4">
        <enum>(l)</enum>
        <header>Coordination with current authorities</header>
        <paragraph id="id34060DBD2E08470FB51BF3E1EF51A00F">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>Repeal of superseded authority related to CENTCOM</header>
          <text>Effective 270 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2012/s:841">section 841 of the National Defense
			 Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2012</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/112/81">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="public-law" value="public-law/112/81">Public Law 112–81</cato:entity-ref>
            </external-xref>; <cato:entity-ref entity-type="statute-at-large" value="statute-at-large/125/1513">125 Stat. 1513</cato:entity-ref>;
			 <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/10/2313/note">
                <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/10/2313">
              10 U.S.C. 2313
            </external-xref> note</cato:entity-ref>)</cato:entity> is repealed.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="idFEEBE675742243BC82EC97DF3903EC2D">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Repeal of superseded authority related to Department of Defense</header>
          <text>Effective 270 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2014/s:831">section 831 of the National Defense
			 Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2014</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/113/66">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="public-law" value="public-law/113/66">Public Law 113–66</cato:entity-ref>
            </external-xref>; <cato:entity-ref entity-type="statute-at-large" value="statute-at-large/127/810">127 Stat. 810</cato:entity-ref>;
			 <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/10/2302/note">
                <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/10/2302">
              10 U.S.C. 2302
            </external-xref> note</cato:entity-ref>)</cato:entity> is repealed.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id14FFE6F4B8184B10B01795FC129EED4D">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Use of superseded authorities in discharge of requirements</header>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In providing for the discharge of the requirements of this section by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="9700" entity-type="federal-body">Department of Defense</cato:entity-ref>,
			 the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="9700" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of Defense</cato:entity-ref> may use and modify for that purpose the
			 regulations and procedures established for purposes of the discharge of
			 the requirements of <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2012/s:841">section 841 of the National Defense Authorization Act
			 for Fiscal Year 2012</cato:entity-ref> and <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2014/s:831">section 831 of the National Defense
			 Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2014</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="idE6B5C48FCBA7400D8758BF94F67B1965">
        <enum>(m)</enum>
        <header>Sunset</header>
        <text>The provisions of this section shall cease to be effective on	December 31, 2019.</text>
      </subsection>
    </section>
    <section changed="added" committee-id="SSGA00" id="idCDFF53F78F9A4F7C90273ACE789FE957" reported-display-style="italic">
      <enum>
        <added-phrase committee-id="SSGA00" reported-display-style="italic">3.</added-phrase>
      </enum>
      <header>Additional access to records</header>
      <subsection id="id9CEC850B45AD4D48B9ADA2C23D77DE83">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Contracts, grants, and cooperative agreements</header>
        <paragraph id="id69C71EAB26C8452F83BAAA370CDBE8D8">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>In general</header>
          <text>Not later than 270 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, applicable regulations shall
			 be revised to provide that the clause described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Never Contract With the Enemy Act/s:3/ss:a/p:2" proposed="true">paragraph (2)</cato:entity-ref> may, as
			 appropriate, be included in each covered contract, grant, and cooperative
			 agreement of an executive agency that is awarded on or after the date of
			 the enactment of this Act.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="id1B5D5E08EC17479988550378102AADDB">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Clause</header>
          <text>The clause described in this paragraph is a clause authorizing the head of the	executive agency
			 concerned, upon a written determination pursuant to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Never Contract With the Enemy Act/s:3/ss:a/p:3" proposed="true">paragraph (3)</cato:entity-ref>, to
			 examine any records of the contractor, the recipient of a grant or
			 cooperative agreement, or any subcontractor or subgrantee under such
			 contract, grant, or cooperative agreement to the extent necessary to
			 ensure that funds, including goods and services, available under the
			 contract, grant, or cooperative agreement are not provided directly or
			 indirectly to a covered person or entity.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="idAB4258D01D92458E8A5EFD7ABDAD701A">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <header>Written determination</header>
          <text>The authority to examine records pursuant to the contract clause described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Never Contract With the Enemy Act/s:3/ss:a/p:2" proposed="true">paragraph (2)</cato:entity-ref> may be
			 exercised only upon a written determination by the contracting officer or
			 comparable official responsible for a grant or cooperative agreement, upon
			 a finding by the commander of a covered combatant command (or the
			 specified deputies of the commander) or the head of an executive agency
			 (or the designee of such head) that there is reason to believe that funds,
			 including goods and services, available under the contract, grant, or
			 cooperative agreement concerned may have been provided directly or
			 indirectly to a covered person or entity.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="id2B1CAB15DF0B40D1ACA71955BEA03392">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
          <header>Flowdown</header>
          <text>A clause described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Never Contract With the Enemy Act/s:3/ss:a/p:2" proposed="true">paragraph (2)</cato:entity-ref> may  also be included in any subcontract or subgrant under a
			 covered contract, grant, or cooperative agreement if the subcontract or
			 subgrant has an estimated value in excess of $50,000.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="idAF5A050C42C84EF4AF1EC26FCB05D1E4">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Reports</header>
        <paragraph id="idA72D508C88984A2487917C79C0D79037">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>In general</header>
          <text>Not later than March 1 of 2016, 2017, and 2018, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1103" entity-type="federal-body">Director of the Office of Management and Budget</cato:entity-ref>
			 shall submit to the appropriate committees of <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> a report on the use
			 of the authority provided by this section in the preceding calendar year.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="idC0AB678DCDF849EA8FD9F2779D773B80">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Elements</header>
          <text>Each report under this subsection  shall identify, for the calendar year covered by such report,
			 each instance in which an executive agency exercised the authority
			 provided under this section to examine records, explain the basis for the
			 action taken, and summarize the results of any examination of records so
			 undertaken.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="id1947FF3439BC448FA11230DEB358C27A">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <header>Form</header>
          <text>Any report under this subsection may be submitted in classified form.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="id4dda48d887b1474f9c71bc3bfcab02c9">
        <enum>(c)</enum>
        <header>Coordination with current authorities applicable to CENTCOM</header>
        <paragraph id="idba7dff7b904747a5b088aaacf9014931">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>Repeal of superseded authority</header>
          <text>Effective 270 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2012/s:842">section 842 of the National Defense
			 Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2012</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/112/81">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="public-law" value="public-law/112/81">Public Law 112–81</cato:entity-ref>
            </external-xref>; <cato:entity-ref entity-type="statute-at-large" value="statute-at-large/125/1510">125 Stat. 1510</cato:entity-ref>;
			 <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/10/2302/note">
                <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/10/2302">
              10 U.S.C. 2302
            </external-xref> note</cato:entity-ref>)</cato:entity> is repealed.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6B6CF2B8CEC745429BCF03D2CEA0ACA7">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Use of superseded authorities in discharge of requirements</header>
          <text>In providing for the discharge of the requirements of this section by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="9700" entity-type="federal-body">Department of Defense</cato:entity-ref>,
			 the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="9700" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of Defense</cato:entity-ref> may use and modify for that purpose requirements
			 and procedures established by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="9700">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> for purposes of the discharge
			 of the requirements of <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2012/s:842">section 842 of the National Defense Authorization
			 Act for Fiscal Year 2012</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
    </section>
    <section changed="added" committee-id="SSGA00" id="id8f0efeb7b4f242709b78653eff4a979a" reported-display-style="italic">
      <enum>
        <added-phrase committee-id="SSGA00" reported-display-style="italic">4.</added-phrase>
      </enum>
      <header>Definitions</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text>
      <paragraph id="id93C338B2C9B04027B8247AC1C8D29F1E">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <header>Appropriate committees of Congress</header>
        <text>The term <term>appropriate committees of Congress</term> means—</text>
        <subparagraph id="id673E0FF4F11B4347B52ABB79310B5AEC">
          <enum>(A)</enum>
          <text>the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="committee" entity-id="SSAS00">Committee on Armed Services</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="SSGA00" entity-type="committee">Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs</cato:entity-ref>, the
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="SSFR00" entity-type="committee">Committee on Foreign Relations</cato:entity-ref>, and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="SSAP00" entity-type="committee">Committee on Appropriations of the
			 Senate</cato:entity-ref>; and</text>
        </subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="id55991D37D0FC42FA9C5945DEF13C24DA">
          <enum>(B)</enum>
          <text>the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="committee" entity-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="HGO00" entity-type="committee">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="HFA00" entity-type="committee">Committee on
			 Foreign Affairs</cato:entity-ref>, and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="HAP00" entity-type="committee">Committee on Appropriations of the House of
			 Representatives</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
        </subparagraph>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="idB3045F3C3FE14F8682F2A19770167E0A">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <header>Contingency operation</header>
        <text>The term <term>contingency operation</term> has the meaning given that term in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc/10/101/a/13">
            <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/10/101">section 101(a)(13)</external-xref> of title 10, United States Code</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="idE98DF30F6940458BA995A020101016B6">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <header>Contract</header>
        <text>The term <term>contract</term> includes a contract for commercial items but is not limited to a contract for commercial items.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="idB7CAB101E8AD4A6EB793457CDC2D38F8">
        <enum>(4)</enum>
        <header>Covered combatant command</header>
        <text>The term <term>covered combatant command</term> means the following:</text>
        <subparagraph id="id03BF0C43D7B84B6191F68AB2157CAE6B">
          <enum>(A)</enum>
          <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="United States Africa Command" entity-parent-id="9700">United States Africa Command</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
        </subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="id4E740B35A42F48369C47971AB1EEDD20">
          <enum>(B)</enum>
          <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="United States Central Command" entity-parent-id="9700">United States Central Command</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
        </subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="idAE687313CDE841C9AEA5CF7A08E8B20D">
          <enum>(C)</enum>
          <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="United States European Command" entity-parent-id="9700">United States European Command</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
        </subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="idCE02E6ABF228458D86AF56B500A6CFD8">
          <enum>(D)</enum>
          <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="United States Pacific Command" entity-parent-id="9700">United States Pacific Command</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
        </subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="idE1700DE6F8594B3D92D070D773DE1C9F">
          <enum>(E)</enum>
          <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-parent-id="9700" value="United States Southern Command">United States Southern Command</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
        </subparagraph>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id2f822ebc8ae343ae8837ecfc0fd602b6">
        <enum>(5)</enum>
        <header>Covered contract, grant, or cooperative agreement defined</header>
        <text>The term <term>covered contract, grant, or cooperative agreement</term> means a contract, grant, or cooperative agreement with an estimated value in excess of $50,000
			 that is performed outside the United States, including its possessions and
			 territories.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="idF2984EF19FDA4B7680F6BEF6C07A2FD7">
        <enum>(6)</enum>
        <header>Covered person or entity</header>
        <text>The term <term>covered person or entity</term> means a person or entity that is actively opposing United States or coalition forces involved in a
			 contingency operation in which members of the Armed Forces are actively
			 engaged in hostilities.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id50BEAD607C2A4ADE910EFCDEA8BA4BF3">
        <enum>(7)</enum>
        <header>Executive agency</header>
        <text>The term <term>executive agency</term> has the meaning given that term in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc/41/133">
            <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/41/133">section 133</external-xref> of title 41, United States Code</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc29c3055c7ed4a62a4aa2b56da48f86b">
        <enum>(8)</enum>
        <header>Head of contracting activity</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>head of contracting activity</term> has the meaning given that term in subpart 601 of part 1 of the Federal Acquisition Regulation.</text>
      </paragraph>
    </section>
  </legis-body>
  <endorsement>
    <action-date>July 23, 2014</action-date>
    <action-desc>Reported with an amendment</action-desc>
  </endorsement>
</bill>
</doc>