<doc>
  <docmeta id="113sres347is">
    <bill congress="113" type="sres" number="347" version="is"/>
    <revision size="3041" annotations="0" status="complete" id="3" commit-time="2014-02-11T15:39:43Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113sres347is/3.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <resolution xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution">
  <form>
    <distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code>
    <congress>113th CONGRESS</congress>
    <session>2d Session</session>
    <legis-num>S. RES. 347</legis-num>
    <current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
    <action>
      <action-date date="20140206">February 6, 2014</action-date>
      <action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="S322">Mr. Merkley</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S346">Mr. Lee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S338">Mr. Manchin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S348">Mr. Paul</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S172">Mr. Harkin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S057">Mr. Leahy</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S316">Mr. Whitehouse</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S319">Mr. Begich</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S247">Mr. Wyden</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations</committee-name>
      </action-desc>
    </action>
    <legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
    <official-title>Providing for completion of the accelerated transition of United States combat and military and security operations to the Government of Afghanistan.</official-title>
  </form>
  <preamble>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas in June 2013, the Government of Afghanistan assumed the lead for combat operations in all regions of Afghanistan consistent with the schedule agreed to by <cato:entity-ref entity-type="person" entity-id="O000167">President Barack Obama</cato:entity-ref> and President of Afghanistan  Hamid Karzai: Now, therefore, be it</text>
    </whereas>
  </preamble>
  <resolution-body>
    <section id="idd5599fc72d2b4251a11bed99411ef0f6" section-type="section-one">
      <enum>1.</enum>
      <header>Completion of accelerated transition of United States combat and military and security operations to the Government of Afghanistan</header>
      <subsection id="idea065d47eaf84fc0804bc74c15391a18">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Statement of policy</header>
        <text>It is the policy of the United States—</text>
        <paragraph id="idACECA0DB3C9E4CD9BD1A9C071B107C3A">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>that, in coordination with the Government of Afghanistan, <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="19RN">North Atlantic Treaty Organization</cato:entity-ref> (NATO) member countries, and other allies in Afghanistan, the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> shall complete the accelerated transition of United States military and security operations to the Government of Afghanistan and redeploy United States Armed Forces from Afghanistan (including operations involving military and security-related contractors) by not later than December 31, 2014; and</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="id5BBF3F17F75D45B3A77BFDA7E4A23D8C">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>to pursue diplomatic efforts leading to a political settlement and reconciliation of the internal conflict in Afghanistan.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="id7BE4F0D3264E47D3AE10D1397EB6B976">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Sense of the Senate</header>
        <text>It is the sense of the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0010">Senate</cato:entity-ref> that, should the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> determine the necessity to maintain United States troops in Afghanistan to carry out missions after December 31, 2014, any such presence and missions should be authorized by a separate vote of <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> not later than June 1, 2014.</text>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="idcb91b9330252435e98f1ff9803561e57">
        <enum>(c)</enum>
        <header>Rule of construction</header>
        <text>Nothing in this section shall be construed as limiting or prohibiting any authority of the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> to—</text>
        <paragraph id="idde283b1702ec489784e1da64aa1770de">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>modify the military strategy, tactics, and operations of United States Armed Forces as such Armed Forces redeploy from Afghanistan;</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="idae8d7fa70d284f48a4991924f721a565">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>attack al Qaeda forces wherever such forces are located;</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="idba52823844754ed3b22174f68c84be49">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <text>provide financial support and equipment to the Government of Afghanistan for the training and supply of Afghanistan military and security forces;</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="idf8fb2048daf74f919bb85917804de6e9">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
          <text>gather, provide, and share intelligence with United States allies operating in Afghanistan and Pakistan; or</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="id1356E3901C4C464DA176141C7CE51982">
          <enum>(5)</enum>
          <text>provide security after December 31, 2014, to United States facilities or diplomatic personnel located in Afghanistan.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
    </section>
  </resolution-body>
</resolution>
</doc>