<doc>
  <docmeta id="113s1530is">
    <bill congress="113" type="s" number="1530" version="is"/>
    <revision size="103134" annotations="0" status="complete" id="10" commit-time="2013-09-27T14:54:15Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113s1530is/10.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public">
  <metadata>
<dublinCore>
<title>113 S1530 IS: Children in Families First Act of 2013</title>
<publisher>U.S. Senate</publisher>
<date>2013-09-19</date>
<format>text/xml</format>
<language>EN</language>
<rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
    <congress>113th CONGRESS</congress>
    <session>1st Session</session>
    <legis-num>S. 1530</legis-num>
    <current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
    <action>
      <action-date date="20130919">September 19, 2013</action-date>
      <action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="S258">Ms. Landrieu</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S342">Mr. Blunt</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S300">Mr. Burr</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S236">Mr. Inhofe</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S339">Mr. Kirk</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S311">Ms. Klobuchar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S324">Mrs. Shaheen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S366">Ms. Warren</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S318">Mr. Wicker</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S331">Mrs. Gillibrand</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations</committee-name>
      </action-desc>
    </action>
    <legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
    <official-title>To realign structures and reallocate resources in the
		  Federal Government, in keeping with the core American belief that families are
		  the best protection for children and the bedrock of any society, to bolster
		  United States diplomacy and assistance targeted at ensuring that every child
		  can grow up in a permanent, safe, nurturing, and loving family, and to
		  strengthen intercountry adoption to the United States and around the world and
		  ensure that it becomes a viable and fully developed option for providing
		  families for children in need, and for other purposes. </official-title>
  </form>
  <legis-body>
    <section id="S1" section-type="section-one">
      <enum>1.</enum>
      <header>Short
			 title; table of contents</header>
      <subsection id="id6C46C943CBEB4F379F860ECF51333310">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Short
			 title</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act may be cited
			 as the <quote>
            <short-title>Children in Families First Act
			 of 2013</short-title>
          </quote>.</text>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="id4B0DF9B0A93F4909B7DDA3C1A95FF91A">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Table of
			 contents</header>
        <text>The table of contents is as follows:</text>
        <toc>
          <toc-entry idref="S1" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title; table of contents.</toc-entry>
          <toc-entry idref="id7E0EBFD2C9BE49CF9467286015FE82F7" level="section">Sec. 2. Findings; purposes.</toc-entry>
          <toc-entry idref="idb8f499eadacb4ba696feca4a84f92a69" level="section">Sec. 3. Definitions.</toc-entry>
          <toc-entry idref="idD46BC2A40652463C9CA85447B8F125C4" level="title">TITLE I—Realignment of certain international child welfare responsibilities and functions</toc-entry>
          <toc-entry idref="id4E3BE82E65784E4795CCD6B5E89833D0" level="section">Sec. 101. Establishment of Bureau of Vulnerable Children and Family Security in the Department of State.</toc-entry>
          <toc-entry idref="id3E5D4661B9DC42248E56E6C185F66B2B" level="section">Sec. 102. Responsibilities of U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services for accreditation of adoption service providers.</toc-entry>
          <toc-entry idref="id5c129f1553ce46d5aff36c4cb427089f" level="section">Sec. 103. Transfer of functions and savings provisions.</toc-entry>
          <toc-entry idref="id7E0CAD9FC1DB4CAE89C0165E9C4A7456" level="section">Sec. 104. Responsibilities of U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services for adoption-related case processing.</toc-entry>
          <toc-entry idref="idB3BD7FF5F90744A888012A98DD261E81" level="title">TITLE II—Annual reporting</toc-entry>
          <toc-entry idref="idfc32de0c78514a8788f1a2337f0f101e" level="section">Sec. 201. Annual report on children living without families.</toc-entry>
          <toc-entry idref="id9E7FEFD27CE248EFBEB1536E2AD39AD6" level="section">Sec. 202. Country reports regarding severe forms of trafficking.</toc-entry>
          <toc-entry idref="id2C39851689E24499AA3F05BF4FC91E63" level="title">TITLE III—Promotion of a comprehensive approach for children in adversity</toc-entry>
          <toc-entry idref="id5C3F67EFFF104358A542756AFE65A703" level="section">Sec. 301. Establishment of a USAID Center for Excellence for Children in Adversity.</toc-entry>
          <toc-entry idref="idCF03F2474E794FF197467FBAB3A3FC8F" level="title">TITLE IV—Funding and effective dates</toc-entry>
          <toc-entry idref="id0B79761145C94CE59E6FBB16C6F98990" level="section">Sec. 401. Authorization of appropriations.</toc-entry>
          <toc-entry idref="idAA01F188A054418891CB55021ADD0B88" level="section">Sec. 402. Effective dates.</toc-entry>
        </toc>
      </subsection>
    </section>
    <section id="id7E0EBFD2C9BE49CF9467286015FE82F7">
      <enum>2.</enum>
      <header>Findings;
			 purposes</header>
      <subsection id="idFEFB0D4A1A9B41869BB527E47E8F2A0D">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Findings</header>
        <text>
          <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref>
			 makes the following findings:</text>
        <paragraph id="idf0d1adaf963843aba9eb9d84922fe76d">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>The people of the
			 United States recognize and believe that children must grow up in permanent,
			 safe, and nurturing families in order to develop and thrive.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="id9645ac638c004a8e967b509000476496">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>Science now
			 proves conclusively that children suffer immediate, lasting, and in many cases
			 irreversible damage from time spent living in institutions or outside of
			 families, including reduced brain activity, reduced IQ, smaller brain size, and
			 inability to form emotional bonds with others.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="id591a771fdaeb426699cbe63899911324">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <text>Governments in other countries seek models that promote the placement of children who are living outside family care in permanent, safe, and nurturing families, rather than in foster care or institutions, but many governments lack the resources or infrastructure to adequately address this need.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="idc56edf41dd7f41059c10847ab6ba4f51">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
          <text>Despite the good
			 efforts of countless governments and nongovernmental organizations, millions of
			 children remain uncounted and outside of the protection, nurturing care,
			 permanence, safety, and love of a family. Without the care of a family, these
			 children are forced to live on the streets, in institutions, in paid foster
			 care, in child-headed households, in group homes, or as household
			 servants.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="id8e18b4073e8d4d44b1bf67fc05210e75">
          <enum>(5)</enum>
          <text>No reliable data
			 currently exists to define and document the number and needs of children in the
			 world currently living without families, but available evidence demonstrates
			 that there are millions of children in this situation needing immediate
			 help.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="idfe08f12332e1457d99ea6b9ff771ff25">
          <enum>(6)</enum>
          <text>The December 2012 Action Plan for Children in Adversity commits the United States Government to achieving a world in which all children grow up within protective family care and free from deprivation, exploitation, and danger.  To effectively and efficiently accomplish this goal, it is necessary to realign the United States Government’s current operational system for assisting orphans and vulnerable children, and processing intercountry adoptions.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="id74b69343e24a41c99e6f53d4f5be5c63">
          <enum>(7)</enum>
          <text>All options for
			 providing appropriate, protective, and permanent family care to children living
			 without families must be considered concurrently and permanent solutions must
			 be put in place as quickly as possible. Solutions include family preservation
			 and reunification, kinship care, guardianship, domestic and intercountry
			 adoption, and other culturally acceptable forms of care that will result in
			 appropriate, protective, and permanent family care. Preference should be given
			 to options that optimize child best interests, which generally means options
			 which provide children with fully protected legal status and parents with full
			 legal status as parents, including full parental rights and responsibilities.
			 The principle of subsidiarity, which gives preference to in-country solutions,
			 should be implemented within the context of a concurrent planning strategy,
			 exploring in- and out-of-country options simultaneously. If an in-country
			 placement serving the child’s best interest and providing appropriate,
			 protective, and permanent care is not quickly available, and such an
			 international home is available, the child should be placed in that
			 international home without delay.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="id8443a53fb0cc4fe2b262bfff9c8c8561">
          <enum>(8)</enum>
          <text>Significant
			 resources are already dedicated to international assistance for orphans and
			 vulnerable children, and a relatively small portion of these resources can be
			 reallocated to achieve more timely, effective, nurturing, and permanent
			 familial solutions for children living without families, resulting in fewer
			 children worldwide living in institutions or on the streets, more families
			 preserved or reunified, and increased domestic and international
			 adoptions.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="id3DEDD55230584D6F9AA5B8F95CC4DC89">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Purposes</header>
        <text>The
			 purposes of this Act are—</text>
        <paragraph id="iddc0bfbb0c3a5428bb1337da0647af27d">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>to support the
			 core American value that families are the bedrock of any society;</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="idE7C262291A5A448AA557B597DD7BF04B">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>to protect the
			 fundamental human right of all children to grow up within the loving care of
			 permanent, safe, and nurturing families;</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="id9a61cca061004920b60bc240517d1163">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <text>to address a
			 critical gap in United States foreign policy implementation by adjusting the
			 Federal Government’s international policy and operational structures so that
			 seeking permanent families for children living without families receives more
			 prominence, focus, and resources (through the reallocation of existing
			 personnel and resources);</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="idde0ad4285ac8439e9d6230d5c273dd0d">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
          <text>to harness the
			 diplomatic and operational power of the United States Government in the
			 international sphere by helping to identify and implement timely, permanent,
			 safe, and nurturing familial solutions for children living without families,
			 including refugee or stateless children;</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="ida646b9bac2f243fab4edc3cbd0b5fcf5">
          <enum>(5)</enum>
          <text>to ensure that
			 intercountry adoption by United States citizens becomes a
			 viable and fully developed option for creating permanent families for children
			 who need them;</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="id9AC473F8713F444791B9DCFF7D957BAE">
          <enum>(6)</enum>
          <text>to protect
			 against abuses of children, birth families, and adoptive parents involved in
			 intercountry adoptions, and to ensure that such adoptions are in the individual
			 child’s best interests; and</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="id027c3fe5312f4dde95ff9f78f3c3fb03">
          <enum>(7)</enum>
          <text>to harmonize and
			 strengthen existing intercountry adoption processes under United States
			 law—</text>
          <subparagraph id="id5003FAABA7F04267ACF98F1A20A74BD1">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>by ensuring that
			 the same set of procedures and criteria govern suitability and eligibility
			 determinations for prospective adoptive parents seeking to complete
			 intercountry adoptions, whether or not the child is from a foreign state that
			 is a party to the Hague Adoption Convention; and</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="id5E95176197B64A649BE4748FA0642C7C">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>by aligning the
			 definitions of eligible child for Convention adoptions and non-Convention
			 adoptions to the maximum extent possible.</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
    </section>
    <section id="idb8f499eadacb4ba696feca4a84f92a69">
      <enum>3.</enum>
      <header>Definitions</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text>
      <paragraph id="id54e3816b7f6b4d3bac62f340d0095722">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <header>Action plan for
			 children in adversity</header>
        <text>The term <term>Action Plan for Children in
			 Adversity</term> means the policy document entitled <term>United States
			 Government Action Plan on Children in Adversity: A Framework for International
			 Assistance: 2012–2017</term>, released on December 19, 2012.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="idBCCE66CA115540E1B784798792F21055">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <header>Appropriate,
			 protective, and permanent family care</header>
        <text>The term <term>appropriate,
			 protective, and permanent family care</term> means a nurturing, lifelong,
			 commitment to a child by an adult, or adults with parental roles and
			 responsibilities that—</text>
        <subparagraph id="idA9030EA4AAF8448B990356C298A37AE9">
          <enum>(A)</enum>
          <text>provides physical
			 and emotional support;</text>
        </subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="idEEDCEA6128D54F2CA6847DA16796F58E">
          <enum>(B)</enum>
          <text>provides the
			 child with a sense of belonging; and</text>
        </subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="id62085F605EF049099BD276D7B23DD0A8">
          <enum>(C)</enum>
          <text>generally
			 involves full legal recognition of the child’s status as child of the parents
			 and of the parents’ rights and responsibilities regarding the child.</text>
        </subparagraph>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id8b914db8ab034e7eb2c6328ec9a60501">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <header>Central
			 authority</header>
        <text>The term <term>central authority</term> has the meaning
			 given the term in <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000/s:3">section 3 of the Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000</cato:entity-ref> (<cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/42/14902">42 U.S.C.
			 14902</cato:entity-ref>)</cato:entity>.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id63da0871d0dc4403b264fa42dfd6b436">
        <enum>(4)</enum>
        <header>Children in
			 adversity</header>
        <text>The term <term>children in adversity</term> means
			 children living inside or outside of family care who are deprived, excluded,
			 vulnerable, or at risk for violence, abuse, exploitation, or neglect.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="idf95b41e310bd4f57a4b913524c0497e2">
        <enum>(5)</enum>
        <header>Convention
			 adoption</header>
        <text>The term <term>Convention
			 adoption</term> has the meaning given the term in <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000/s:3">section 3 of the Intercountry
			 Adoption Act of 2000</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/14902">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/42/14902">42 U.S.C. 14902</cato:entity-ref>
            </external-xref>)</cato:entity>.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="idaae145c574af455b8962cacca6720425">
        <enum>(6)</enum>
        <header>Convention
			 country</header>
        <text>The term <term>Convention country</term> has the meaning
			 given the term in <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000/s:3">section 3 of the Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000</cato:entity-ref> (<cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/42/14902">42 U.S.C.
			 14902</cato:entity-ref>)</cato:entity> and for which the Hague Adoption Convention has entered into
			 force.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="idf868f95fecc244f993b9da74956532e5">
        <enum>(7)</enum>
        <header>Guardianship</header>
        <text>The
			 term <term>guardianship</term> means a permanent legal relationship between an
			 adult and a child, whereby the adult is lawfully invested with the power, and
			 charged with the duty, of taking care of the child. While some forms of
			 guardianship are not truly permanent, the form of guardianship referred to and
			 supported under this Act is permanent guardianship. A Kefala order issued by a
			 country that follows traditional Islamic law does not qualify as an adoption
			 under United States law, but may be a form of guardianship in some
			 circumstances.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="idfac45fae827f45dd99eaace2d62739f6">
        <enum>(8)</enum>
        <header>Habitual
			 residence determination</header>
        <text>The term <term>habitual residence
			 determination</term> means a factual determination of where a prospective
			 adoptive parent (or parents) resides and where the child resides for purposes
			 of an intercountry adoption case.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id97d78cde4d1a4e3abc9caae89458e17b">
        <enum>(9)</enum>
        <header>Hague adoption
			 convention</header>
        <text>The term <term>Hague Adoption Convention</term> means
			 the Convention of Protection of Children and Cooperation in Respect of
			 Intercountry Adoption, concluded at the Hague May 29, 1993.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id956d3569692e47d68ba69bcbf759bf7b">
        <enum>(10)</enum>
        <header>Kinship
			 care</header>
        <text>The term <term>kinship care</term> means the full time care,
			 nurturing, and protection of children by relatives, members of their tribes or
			 clans, godparents, stepparents, or any adult who has a kinship bond with a
			 child, so long as those persons have the capacity and commitment to function as
			 true parents for the child on a permanent basis. It does not include paid
			 kinship foster care.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="idd0168c3963574352b59dd9f6fc4f8ccd">
        <enum>(11)</enum>
        <header>Non-convention
			 adoption</header>
        <text>The term <term>non-Convention adoption</term>
			 means—</text>
        <subparagraph id="id6F1E3E032451454D9E9B14A8CEDC47A4">
          <enum>(A)</enum>
          <text>an adoption by
			 United States parents of a child from a non-Convention country in accordance
			 with <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Immigration and Nationality Act/s:101/ss:b/p:1/sp:F">subparagraph (F) of section 101(b)(1) of the Immigration and Nationality
			 Act</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/8/1101/b/1">8 U.S.C. 1101(b)(1)</cato:entity-ref>
              </external-xref>)</cato:entity>;</text>
        </subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="id74508a64d2df469f99834d73e4b50661">
          <enum>(B)</enum>
          <text>an adoption by
			 United States parents of a child under the laws of the child’s country of
			 origin (generally when the parents are living in the child’s country of origin
			 and therefore able legally to complete a domestic adoption); or</text>
        </subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="id13E4F0953DD04D69B087448CF9E5C6BE">
          <enum>(C)</enum>
          <text>in certain
			 circumstances (generally with respect to relative adoptions or adoptions by
			 dual national parents), an adoption by United States parents of a child from a
			 Convention country if that country allows legal and valid adoptions to take
			 place outside the scope of the Convention.</text>
        </subparagraph>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id3461391777814ef19c71d4401a8924b9">
        <enum>(12)</enum>
        <header>Non-convention
			 country</header>
        <text>The term <term>non-Convention country</term> means a
			 country in which the Hague Adoption Convention has not entered into force,
			 regardless of whether or not that country has signed the Convention.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id84f4da3e2ee94b00b8fbcfa98eaa0b7c">
        <enum>(13)</enum>
        <header>Unparented
			 children</header>
        <text>The term <term>unparented children</term> means children
			 lacking the legal, permanent, safe, and nurturing care of a parental figure or
			 figures, either inside their country of origin, in the country of their
			 habitual residence, or elsewhere, regardless of their lawful or unlawful
			 immigration status in their current country of residence.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id94b4260deb174a8fb699276d301f1cd0">
        <enum>(14)</enum>
        <header>Vulnerable
			 children</header>
        <text>The term <term>vulnerable children</term>, consistent
			 with the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7200">United States Agency for International Development's</cato:entity-ref> definition, means
			 children and youth who are under 18 years whose safety, well-being, growth, and
			 development are at significant risk due to inadequate care, protection, or
			 access to essential services.</text>
      </paragraph>
    </section>
    <title id="idD46BC2A40652463C9CA85447B8F125C4">
      <enum>I</enum>
      <header>Realignment of
			 certain international child welfare responsibilities and functions</header>
      <section id="id4E3BE82E65784E4795CCD6B5E89833D0">
        <enum>101.</enum>
        <header>Establishment
			 of Bureau of Vulnerable Children and Family Security in the Department of
			 State</header>
        <subsection id="id1dda90bb5ee04233a112495c712d2252">
          <enum>(a)</enum>
          <header>Establishment</header>
          <text>There
			 is established within the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Department of State</cato:entity-ref> the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Bureau of Vulnerable Children and Family Security" entity-parent-id="1900" proposed="true">Bureau of Vulnerable Children
			 and Family Security</cato:entity-ref> (referred to in this Act as the <term>VCFS</term>), which
			 shall be located in the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-parent-id="1900" value="Civilian Security, Democracy and Human Rights">Secretariat for Civilian Security, Democracy and Human
			 Rights</cato:entity-ref> and shall promote and support the following activities:</text>
          <paragraph id="id1cd9a4fb2fdf43999cdc19c26f7fd423">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <text>The development
			 and implementation in foreign countries of child welfare laws, regulations,
			 policies, best practices, and procedures in keeping with the goals articulated
			 in the Action Plan for Children in Adversity, including—</text>
            <subparagraph id="id7885e1471b2d448397e3e86b202fc533">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>the sound
			 development of children through the integration of health, nutrition, and
			 family support;</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="idc7bf8ae8938b4153a755998df5b599ab">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>supporting and
			 enabling families to care for children through family preservation,
			 reunification, and support of kinship care, guardianship, and domestic and
			 intercountry adoption; and</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="idd2349c8e83a84df2bdf3444b606be5b7">
              <enum>(C)</enum>
              <text>facilitating the
			 efforts of national governments and partners to prevent, respond to, and
			 protect children from violence, exploitation, abuse, and neglect.</text>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="id8214d22d916743f08db4699f1f30d15b">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <text>Addressing the
			 gap in United States Government diplomacy, policy, and operations with respect
			 to promoting appropriate, protective, and permanent family care for children
			 living without families by establishing within the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Bureau of Vulnerable Children and Family Security" entity-parent-id="1900" proposed="true">VCFS</cato:entity-ref> a <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Bureau of Vulnerable Children and Family Security" entity-parent-id="1900" proposed="true">Senior Coordinator
			 for Permanence</cato:entity-ref>, who—</text>
            <subparagraph id="id0912AA60890B49C59B92215A5C885DC8">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>shall occupy at least a Deputy Assistant Secretary-level position in the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Bureau of Vulnerable Children and Family Security" entity-parent-id="1900" proposed="true">VCFS</cato:entity-ref>;
			 and</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="idFE5B5F9E885344308B6D4B6D6D208295">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>shall lead the
			 development and implementation of policies that will ensure the timely
			 provision of appropriate, protective, and permanent family care for children
			 living without families, including refugee and stateless children, through the
			 full continuum of permanence solutions, including family preservation and
			 reunification, kinship care, guardianship, and domestic and intercountry
			 adoption.</text>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="idCA2BA802A615419B880579DA5E1318AC">
          <enum>(b)</enum>
          <header>Assistant
			 Secretary</header>
          <paragraph id="id404F073379BF48BA8B8EF27B95DE8859">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <header>Appointment</header>
            <text>The
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Bureau of Vulnerable Children and Family Security" entity-parent-id="1900" proposed="true">VCFS</cato:entity-ref> shall be headed by an <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Bureau of Vulnerable Children and Family Security" entity-parent-id="1900" proposed="true">Assistant Secretary</cato:entity-ref>, who shall be appointed by the
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> by and with the consent of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0010">Senate</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="id270753AD72684FDBA9D3D62272B53114">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <header>Qualifications</header>
            <text>The
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Bureau of Vulnerable Children and Family Security" entity-parent-id="1900" proposed="true">Assistant Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall—</text>
            <subparagraph id="id005E397C23704D3D8CE42FB745EAA937">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>have experience
			 in the development of policies and systems and the implementation of programs
			 that promote the goals of the Action Plan for Children in Adversity;</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="id5EDFB98ED6424233A1CB991A5A4DAA17">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>be knowledgeable
			 of international child welfare, family permanence, and family creation through
			 domestic and intercountry adoption; and</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="id309FF87B91734658A3BE8361E815622A">
              <enum>(C)</enum>
              <text>be committed to
			 developing an integrated United States Government approach to international
			 child welfare that places equal emphasis on—</text>
              <clause id="id9212AD84F87B49DD90CE8D5F16A2FDDB">
                <enum>(i)</enum>
                <text>early childhood
			 survival and development;</text>
              </clause>
              <clause id="idCA2925378F674F36B93ADA1494CF0423">
                <enum>(ii)</enum>
                <text>family
			 permanence; and</text>
              </clause>
              <clause id="idD3AACF9CFA6F4779AB6F525AC46B6938">
                <enum>(iii)</enum>
                <text>protection from
			 abuse and exploitation.</text>
              </clause>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="id73E59710FF82449B90ADF7AFE803AE59">
            <enum>(3)</enum>
            <header>Authority</header>
            <text>The
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Bureau of Vulnerable Children and Family Security" entity-parent-id="1900" proposed="true">Assistant Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall report to the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Civilian Security, Democracy and Human Rights" entity-parent-id="1936">Under Secretary for Civilian Security,
			 Democracy and Human Rights</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="id76bb4779701e4c6c8565d141348a0004">
            <enum>(4)</enum>
            <header>Increase in
			 authorized assistant secretary positions</header>
            <subparagraph id="id7AD73AD714F94B188617FC4442D11872">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <header>Amendment to
			 State Department Basic Authorities Act of 1956</header>
              <text>
                <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
                  <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="State Department Basic Authorities Act of 1956/s:1/ss:c/p:1">Section 1(c)(1) of
			 the State Department Basic Authorities Act of 1956</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2651a">
                    <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/22/2651a/c/1">22 U.S.C. 2651a(c)(1)</cato:entity-ref>
                  </external-xref>)</cato:entity> is
			 amended by striking <quote>not more than 24 Assistant Secretaries</quote> and
			 inserting <quote>not more than 25 Assistant Secretaries</quote>.</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="id1210786dcb1a4b66a92a68fc8cd8875c">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <header>Amendment to
			 title 5, United States Code</header>
              <text>
            <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" value="usc/5/5315" entity-type="uscode">
              <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/5/5315">Section 5315</external-xref> of title 5, United
			 States Code</cato:entity-ref>, is amended by striking <quote>Assistant Secretaries of State
			 (24)</quote> and inserting <quote>Assistant Secretaries of State
			 (25)</quote>.</text>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="id81D43E3C663842C59F025D703FABB9D4">
          <enum>(c)</enum>
          <header>Functions</header>
          <paragraph id="id9F9C21AEF53B44B5BB3C4999A62B417E">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <header>Advisory</header>
            <text>The
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Bureau of Vulnerable Children and Family Security" entity-parent-id="1900" proposed="true">Assistant Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall serve as a primary advisor to the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref>
			 and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> in all matters related to vulnerable children and family
			 security in foreign countries.</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="idB6164254F3BF4C1989960A3BDE6FA685">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <header>Diplomatic
			 representation</header>
            <text>Subject to the direction of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> and the
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref>, and in consultation and coordination with the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Senior Coordinator for Children in Adversity" entity-parent-id="7200">Senior
			 Coordinator for Children in Adversity of the United States Agency for
			 International Development</cato:entity-ref>, and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7000">Secretary of Homeland Security</cato:entity-ref>, the
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Bureau of Vulnerable Children and Family Security" entity-parent-id="1900" proposed="true">Assistant Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall represent the United States in matters relevant to
			 international child welfare, family preservation and reunification, and
			 provision of permanent, safe parental care through kinship, domestic and intercountry
			 adoption in—</text>
            <subparagraph id="id84e0818c53f74abdbe86f3b87672ea39">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>contacts with
			 foreign governments, nongovernmental organizations, intergovernmental agencies,
			 and specialized agencies of the United Nations and other international
			 organizations of which the United States is a member;</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="idddb0bd0af8404c65b02503a29ce0d198">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>multilateral
			 conferences and meetings relevant to family preservation, reunification, and
			 creating appropriate, protective, and permanent care for unparented children;
			 and</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="id63d4c1c67c5b49bc8c79cf5f6437216c">
              <enum>(C)</enum>
              <text>fulfillment of
			 the diplomatic responsibilities designated to the central authority under <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
                  <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000/t:I">title
			 I of the Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/14911">
                    <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/42/14911/etseq">42 U.S.C. 14911 et seq.</cato:entity-ref>
                  </external-xref>)</cato:entity>, as
			 amended by this Act.</text>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="idBE17EEC4D5BE4D19ABAF998BC7D95605">
            <enum>(3)</enum>
            <header>Policy
			 development with respect to permanence for unparented children</header>
            <subparagraph id="iddaebd02d5a3e4388b03f92dbe171d708">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <header>In
			 general</header>
              <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Bureau of Vulnerable Children and Family Security" entity-parent-id="1900" proposed="true">Assistant Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall—</text>
              <clause id="id13E127716AD14F67B118BBF3DDE7B431">
                <enum>(i)</enum>
                <text>develop and
			 advocate for policies and practices to ensure that children in foreign
			 countries who are living without families find appropriate, protective, and
			 permanent family care which is in the best interest of each child;</text>
              </clause>
              <clause id="id298406EECC7845979C6FDD9CFB8FE875">
                <enum>(ii)</enum>
                <text>give
			 consideration to family preservation and reunification, kinship care,
			 guardianship, and domestic and intercountry adoption; and</text>
              </clause>
              <clause id="id7457A18742404F2C8ABA203E93DEB895">
                <enum>(iii)</enum>
                <text>seek to develop
			 and implement policies that lead to the use of all options for providing
			 appropriate, protective, and permanent family care to children living without
			 families as quickly as possible.</text>
              </clause>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="id29A2EFFABADF4088B3EB9111796786B6">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <header>Best interest
			 determination</header>
              <text>In carrying out <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Children in Families First Act of 2013/s:101/ss:c/p:3/sp:A" proposed="true">subparagraph (A)</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Bureau of Vulnerable Children and Family Security" entity-parent-id="1900" proposed="true">Assistant
			 Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall give preference to options that optimize the best interests of
			 children, including options which provide children with fully protected legal
			 status as children and parents with full legal status as parents, including
			 full parental rights and responsibilities.</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="id3A0FB173500A49C9BA6F5C7287F2046B">
              <enum>(C)</enum>
              <header>Subsidiarity</header>
              <text>The
			 principle of subsidiarity, which gives preference to in-country solutions,
			 should be implemented within the context of a concurrent planning strategy,
			 exploring in- and out-of-country options simultaneously. If an in-country
			 placement serving the child’s best interests and providing appropriate,
			 protective, and permanent care is not quickly available, and such an
			 international home is available, the child should be placed in that
			 international home without delay.</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="id0C7C894E46314763AB157C314ECC1BA9">
              <enum>(D)</enum>
              <header>Best
			 practices</header>
              <text>In developing policies and programs under this Act, the
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Bureau of Vulnerable Children and Family Security" entity-parent-id="1900" proposed="true">Assistant Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall identify and utilize evidence-based programs and best
			 practices in family preservation and reunification and provision of permanent
			 parental care through guardianship, kinship care, and domestic and intercountry
			 adoption as derived from a wide variety of domestic, foreign, and global
			 policies and practices.</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="idb304194012f3441ca9ad098bacfd5889">
              <enum>(E)</enum>
              <header>Technical
			 assistance</header>
              <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Bureau of Vulnerable Children and Family Security" entity-parent-id="1900" proposed="true">Assistant Secretary</cato:entity-ref>, in consultation with other
			 appropriate Federal agencies, shall provide technical assistance to governments
			 of foreign countries to help build their child welfare capacities and to
			 strengthen appropriate family preservation and reunification and the provision
			 of appropriate, protective, and permanent family care through kinship care,
			 guardianship, and domestic and intercountry adoption, including assistance
			 with—</text>
              <clause id="id8d4282202e4749728606901e2c2543ec">
                <enum>(i)</enum>
                <text>the
			 drafting, disseminating, and implementing of legislation;</text>
              </clause>
              <clause id="id31b8e1b3070e459986fb634ce57b22ad">
                <enum>(ii)</enum>
                <text>the development
			 of implementing systems and procedures;</text>
              </clause>
              <clause id="id9ed52b510ec742cba86f6d930ccb3892">
                <enum>(iii)</enum>
                <text>the
			 establishment of public, private, and faith- and community-based
			 partnerships;</text>
              </clause>
              <clause id="id9d5ad202e4d447709ee062b80f4e0e41">
                <enum>(iv)</enum>
                <text>the development
			 of workforce training for governmental and nongovernmental staff; and</text>
              </clause>
              <clause id="idf5da19fe1f5d408e96304d7230bd8338">
                <enum>(v)</enum>
                <text>infrastructure
			 development and data collection techniques necessary to identify and document
			 the number and needs of children living without appropriate, protective, and
			 permanent family care.</text>
              </clause>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="id59d4e073eee644dabcfd47edb8f54278">
            <enum>(4)</enum>
            <header>Responsibilities
			 with respect to intercountry adoption</header>
            <subparagraph id="ide6664c2c1b1649ba9841cc356bf4e682">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <header>In
			 general</header>
              <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Bureau of Vulnerable Children and Family Security" entity-parent-id="1900" proposed="true">VCFS</cato:entity-ref>, in coordination with other offices of the
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Department of State</cato:entity-ref> and <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7003">U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services</cato:entity-ref>, shall have
			 lead responsibility for representing the United States Government in
			 discussions, negotiations, and diplomatic contacts pertaining to intercountry
			 adoptions.</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="id521697D61F8A4199AA4C50DA4E2F6F1C">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <header>Central
			 authority responsibility under the intercountry adoption act of
			 2000</header>
              <text>
                <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
                  <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000/s:101/ss:b/p:2">Section 101(b)(2) of the Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000</cato:entity-ref>
			 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/14911">
                    <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/42/14911/b/2">42 U.S.C. 14911(b)(2)</cato:entity-ref>
                  </external-xref>)</cato:entity> is amended by striking <quote>Office of Children's
			 Issues</quote> and inserting <quote>
                  <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Bureau of Vulnerable Children and Family Security" entity-parent-id="1900" proposed="true">Bureau of Vulnerable Children and Family
			 Security</cato:entity-ref>
                </quote>.</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="id1F6A0E009A95433ABE9247994A63F5FA">
              <enum>(C)</enum>
              <header>Determinations
			 of hague adoption convention compliance</header>
              <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Bureau of Vulnerable Children and Family Security" entity-parent-id="1900" proposed="true">VCFS</cato:entity-ref>, in consultation
			 with other offices of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Department of State</cato:entity-ref>, and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7000">Department of Homeland Security</cato:entity-ref>, shall have lead responsibility for determining whether a
			 Convention partner country has met its obligations under the Hague Adoption
			 Convention and is eligible to participate in intercountry adoptions in
			 accordance with United States law. Such determinations shall be documented in
			 writing, based on standardized criteria, and available for public review and
			 comment.</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="id71c31a575d2a4a7ea4735d5201910e5b">
              <enum>(D)</enum>
              <header>Negotiation of
			 bilateral agreements</header>
              <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Bureau of Vulnerable Children and Family Security" entity-parent-id="1900" proposed="true">VCFS</cato:entity-ref>, in consultation with the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7000">Secretary
			 of Homeland Security</cato:entity-ref>, shall have lead responsibility for the negotiation of
			 bilateral agreements with other countries pertaining to intercountry adoption
			 and in conformity with the provisions of the Hague Adoption Convention when the
			 other country is a Convention partner.</text>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="id8F80D93E3BE849FC8762FD0995AEEF9C">
            <enum>(5)</enum>
            <header>Policy
			 coordination</header>
            <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Bureau of Vulnerable Children and Family Security" entity-parent-id="1900" proposed="true">Assistant Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall coordinate with the
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7000">Secretary of Homeland Security</cato:entity-ref> and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7200">Administrator of the United States
			 Agency for International Development</cato:entity-ref> to maintain consistency in United States
			 foreign and domestic policy and operations with respect to children living
			 outside family care in foreign countries, particularly those living without
			 families.</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="id5D61FAED9EFA45E99A96837F6FA7AFFE">
            <enum>(6)</enum>
            <header>Information
			 coordination</header>
            <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Bureau of Vulnerable Children and Family Security" entity-parent-id="1900" proposed="true">Assistant Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall transmit—</text>
            <subparagraph id="idBB722691118244ED8E4188EE5A7B32CF">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>any intercountry
			 adoption related case information received from the Central Authority of
			 another Convention country to the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7000">Secretary of Homeland Security</cato:entity-ref>; and</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="idC1188965E6D440939169109AAFC9B465">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>any intercountry
			 adoption related case information that the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7000">Secretary of Homeland Security</cato:entity-ref>
			 requests to the Central Authority of another Convention country.</text>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
      </section>
      <section id="id3E5D4661B9DC42248E56E6C185F66B2B">
        <enum>102.</enum>
        <header>Responsibilities
			 of U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services for accreditation of adoption
			 service providers</header>
        <subsection id="id5C7B6DE93BC9467484F21C1506C7F907">
          <enum>(a)</enum>
          <header>General
			 responsibilities under the Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000</header>
          <paragraph id="idC3DB9214B77D4801A4CBAD3572413B7F">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <header>In
			 general</header>
            <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000">Intercountry
			 Adoption Act of 2000</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/106/279">
                  <cato:entity-ref entity-type="public-law" value="public-law/106/279">Public Law 106–279</cato:entity-ref>
                </external-xref>; <cato:entity-ref entity-type="statute-at-large" value="statute-at-large/114/825">114 Stat. 825</cato:entity-ref>)</cato:entity> is amended by
			 inserting after <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000/s:103">section 103</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/14913">
                  <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/42/14913">42 U.S.C. 14913</cato:entity-ref>
                </external-xref>)</cato:entity> the following:</text>
            <quoted-block act-name="" id="id4076E967EEED421A94475702B3BE4243" style="OLC">
              <section id="idC588BA4062BE44DC95F0AFD25523746D">
                <enum>103A.</enum>
                <header>Responsibilities
				of the Department of Homeland Security</header>
                <subsection id="id950B49EEC9244000ADAA79E08934E6FB">
                  <enum>(a)</enum>
                  <header>Accreditation
				and approval responsibilities</header>
                  <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7000">Secretary of Homeland Security</cato:entity-ref>,
				working through the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7003">Director of U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services</cato:entity-ref>,
				shall carry out the functions prescribed by the Convention with respect to the
				accreditation of agencies and the approval of persons to provide adoption
				services in the United States in cases subject to the Convention as provided in
				title II. Such functions may not be delegated to any other Federal
				agency.</text>
                </subsection>
                <subsection id="id1FC4BE8138934D4C8B05C3DF091E9984">
                  <enum>(b)</enum>
                  <header>Investigations</header>
                  <text>The
				<cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7000">Secretary of Homeland Security</cato:entity-ref> shall be responsible for managing and overseeing
				investigations related to the operation and services of adoption service
				providers, whether directly or indirectly.</text>
                </subsection>
                <subsection id="idEF56AE99E2ED44E89852D24619533A01">
                  <enum>(c)</enum>
                  <header>Liaison with
				foreign governments on post-Placement reports and certain adoption
				cases</header>
                  <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7000">Secretary of Homeland Security</cato:entity-ref> shall serve as the
				liaison with foreign governments with respect to queries about required
				post-placement reports and about specific intercountry adoption cases once the
				adopted children are living in the United States, including queries about the
				status of adopted children who are living in the United States in cases
				involving allegations of abuse, neglect, abandonment, or
				death.</text>
                </subsection>
              </section>
              <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
            </quoted-block>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="idCEBBA315DF574588A67CE5C653DB4284">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <header>Clerical
			 amendment</header>
            <text>
              <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000/s:1">Section 1 of such Act</cato:entity-ref> is amended by inserting after the
			 item relating to section 103 the following:</text>
            <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6B8872068613450B8E10C83FD702BD43" style="OLC">
              <toc>
                <toc-entry bold="off" level="section">Sec. 103A. Responsibilities of
				the Department of Homeland
				Security.</toc-entry>
              </toc>
              <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
            </quoted-block>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="idCBDD37E0371544E19ECB879B6AD40940">
            <enum>(3)</enum>
            <header>Conforming
			 amendments</header>
            <text>
              <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000/s:102">Section 102 of such Act</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/14912">
                  <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/42/14912">42 U.S.C. 14912</cato:entity-ref>
                </external-xref>)</cato:entity> is
			 amended—</text>
            <subparagraph id="idC2A55D52386442048B1347C823D82AD2">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000/s:102/ss:a">subsection
			 (a)</cato:entity-ref>, by striking <quote>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Secretary</cato:entity-ref>
                </quote> and inserting <quote>Except as
			 provided for under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000/s:103A" proposed="true">section 103A</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Secretary</cato:entity-ref>
                </quote>;</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="idA100A12717DA4DD2A5CD438518EC783B">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000/s:102/ss:b">subsection
			 (b)</cato:entity-ref>, by inserting <quote>, in coordination with the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7000">Secretary of Homeland
			 Security</cato:entity-ref>,</quote> after <quote>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Secretary</cato:entity-ref>
                </quote>;</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="id6783D97D2C514F00AC526B71C8C52AAE">
              <enum>(C)</enum>
              <text>by striking
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000/s:102/ss:c">subsection (c)</cato:entity-ref>;</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="id76F5DAF73D744710848579E8A7B0083D">
              <enum>(D)</enum>
              <text>by redesignating
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000/s:102/ss:d">subsections (d)</cato:entity-ref> and <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000/s:102/ss:f">(f)</cato:entity-ref> as <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000/s:102/ss:c" proposed="true">subsections (c)</cato:entity-ref> and <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000/s:102/ss:d" proposed="true">(d)</cato:entity-ref>, respectively; and</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="id2C22F2B05CED4296AAE6EDDC604B48C3">
              <enum>(E)</enum>
              <text>by striking
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000/s:102/ss:e">subsection (e)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="id3F474E273F344E1BB300083F7FB1E852">
          <enum>(b)</enum>
          <header>Accreditation
			 responsibilities under the Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000</header>
          <paragraph id="idC36BCABF43014735A394D6D30886DFC3">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <header>Designation of
			 accrediting agencies</header>
            <text>
              <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000/s:202">Section 202 of the Intercountry Adoption Act
			 of 2000</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/14922">
                  <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/42/14922">42 U.S.C. 14922</cato:entity-ref>
                </external-xref>)</cato:entity> is amended by inserting <quote>
                <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7000">of Homeland
			 Security</cato:entity-ref>
              </quote> after <quote>Secretary</quote> each place it appears.</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="idC122A767DCEF458689EA77A2CA13C999">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <header>Standards and
			 procedures for providing accreditation or approval</header>
            <text>
              <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000/s:203">Section 203 of
			 the Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/14923">
                  <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/42/14923">42 U.S.C. 14923</cato:entity-ref>
                </external-xref>)</cato:entity> is amended by inserting
			 <quote>
                <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7000">of Homeland Security</cato:entity-ref>
              </quote> after <quote>Secretary</quote> each place
			 it appears in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000/s:203/ss:a">subsections (a)</cato:entity-ref> and <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000/s:203/ss:b">(b)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="id07D0B3465EA140ECA065F79028890976">
            <enum>(3)</enum>
            <header>Oversight of
			 accreditation and approval</header>
            <text>
              <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000/s:204">Section 204 of the Intercountry
			 Adoption Act of 2000</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/14924">
                  <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/42/14924">42 U.S.C. 14924</cato:entity-ref>
                </external-xref>)</cato:entity> is amended—</text>
            <subparagraph id="id8AA379CB5E924A558058861747B9C790">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>by inserting
			 <quote>of Homeland Security</quote> after <quote>Secretary</quote> each place
			 it appears; and</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="id94E1538609FB4E1B93C340BAD8A91E3D">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000/s:204/ss:c">subsection
			 (c)</cato:entity-ref>—</text>
              <clause id="idEFF2E95FBF9D4BEA977F9850F33B39FB">
                <enum>(i)</enum>
                <text>in
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000/s:204/ss:c/p:1">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref>, by amending the paragraph heading to read as follows:</text>
                <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5B5062C117B2421092ADD6FD51DC4D51" style="OLC">
                  <paragraph id="id169B513C259C48298A3DFA576A46FEB8">
                    <enum>(4)</enum>
                    <header>Authority of
				the secretary of homeland security</header>
                  </paragraph>
                  <after-quoted-block>;
				and</after-quoted-block>
                </quoted-block>
              </clause>
              <clause id="idBA6E8A0BAC6C442786D045A20364B2CD">
                <enum>(ii)</enum>
                <text>in
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000/s:204/ss:c/p:2">paragraph (2)</cato:entity-ref>, by striking <quote>Secretary's debarment order</quote> and
			 inserting <quote>debarment order of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7000">Secretary of Homeland
			 Security</cato:entity-ref>
                  </quote>.</text>
              </clause>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="id604B78A3859743DAA2218040D5A5B375">
            <enum>(4)</enum>
            <header>Administrative
			 provisions</header>
            <subparagraph id="id4DC1BC5F20F74791AF56CED4597FBFB5">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <header>Access to
			 convention records</header>
              <text>
                <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
                  <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000/s:401/ss:b">Section 401(b) of the Intercountry Adoption
			 Act of 2000</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/14941">
                    <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/42/14941/b">42 U.S.C. 14941(b)</cato:entity-ref>
                  </external-xref>)</cato:entity> is amended—</text>
              <clause id="id53D2F82664E84D1B89F4D682B1BB325C">
                <enum>(i)</enum>
                <text>in
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000/s:401/ss:b/p:1">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref>, by inserting <quote>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7003">Director of U.S. Citizenship and
			 Immigration Services</cato:entity-ref>,</quote> after <quote>
                    <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Secretary</cato:entity-ref>
                  </quote>; and</text>
              </clause>
              <clause id="id9F5BD14977C44E2B93840597884D83BB">
                <enum>(ii)</enum>
                <text>in
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000/s:401/ss:b/p:2">paragraph (2)</cato:entity-ref>, by inserting <quote>the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7003">Director of U.S. Citizenship and
			 Immigration Services</cato:entity-ref>,</quote> after <quote>
                    <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Secretary</cato:entity-ref>,</quote>.</text>
              </clause>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="id2AEB5286E34A49FFABF9838D1885071F">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <header>Assessment of
			 fees</header>
              <text>
                <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
                  <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000/s:403/ss:b">Section 403(b) of the Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000</cato:entity-ref> (<cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/42/14943/b">42
			 U.S.C. 14943(b)</cato:entity-ref>)</cato:entity> is amended—</text>
              <clause id="idE80B2814168C476FAF8C9D71BE0DCE07">
                <enum>(i)</enum>
                <text>in
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000/s:403/ss:b/p:1">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref>—</text>
                <subclause id="idFF97DCE429EF418895A7198C1CE6258E">
                  <enum>(I)</enum>
                  <text>by inserting
			 <quote>or the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7003">Director of U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services</cato:entity-ref>
                    </quote>
			 after <quote>
                      <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Secretary</cato:entity-ref>
                    </quote>; and</text>
                </subclause>
                <subclause id="idA18EC812985A47B8845FB7284CD30FDD">
                  <enum>(II)</enum>
                  <text>by inserting
			 <quote>or <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7003">U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services</cato:entity-ref>, respectively,</quote>
			 after <quote>
                      <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Department of State</cato:entity-ref>
                    </quote>; and</text>
                </subclause>
              </clause>
              <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id33A31A6E4FE4496FBB583311F9574327">
                <enum>(ii)</enum>
                <text>in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000/s:403/ss:b/p:2">paragraph
			 (2)</cato:entity-ref>, by inserting <quote>or <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7003">U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services</cato:entity-ref>
			 appropriation, as the case may be,</quote> after <quote>
                    <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Department of State</cato:entity-ref>
			 appropriation</quote>.</text>
              </clause>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="id1c63fdb753c54a8a9ab296ce8743e5f2">
          <enum>(c)</enum>
          <header>Intercountry
			 adoption functions of U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services</header>
          <paragraph id="id5f709f7d5179465d92b6d6d293254f97">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <header>Definitions</header>
            <text>In
			 this subsection and in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Children in Families First Act of 2013/s:103" proposed="true">section 103</cato:entity-ref>:</text>
            <subparagraph id="id8cc16f973212404bbf32509584a0ed67">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <header>Adoption
			 service</header>
              <text>The term <term>adoption service</term> has the meaning
			 given the term in <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
                  <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000/s:3">section 3 of the Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000</cato:entity-ref> (<cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/42/14902">42 U.S.C.
			 14902</cato:entity-ref>)</cato:entity>.</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="id2dee1d0dc3d34ab0be3b826ee46485e2">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <header>Associate
			 director</header>
              <text>The term <term>Associate Director</term> means the
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-parent-id="7003" value="Associate Director of the Field Operations Directorate">Associate Director of the Directorate</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="id30643eb5cea64c64950b85a46f470266">
              <enum>(C)</enum>
              <header>Directorate</header>
              <text>Except
			 as otherwise provided in this subsection, the term <term>Directorate</term>
			 means the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Field Operations Directorate" entity-parent-id="7003">Field Operations Directorate of U.S. Citizenship and Immigration
			 Services</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="ide5a6907f97c6438ea6a4894224f115c1">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <header>Intercountry
			 adoption functions</header>
            <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Associate Director of the Field Operations Directorate" entity-parent-id="7003">Associate Director</cato:entity-ref> shall carry out—</text>
            <subparagraph id="idfa9f34af14334da0849af5de4dc23510">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>the functions
			 described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000/s:103A/ss:a" proposed="true">section 103A(a) of the Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000</cato:entity-ref>, relating
			 to accreditation of agencies and approval of persons to provide adoption
			 services;</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="idaecb2f6db1bb40dfb3758451ea97837d">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>the functions
			 described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000/s:103A/ss:b" proposed="true">section 103A(b) of such Act</cato:entity-ref>, relating to management and oversight
			 of investigations related to the operation of such providers; and</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="idcea8be6852d34fc2a6b58b86fb321637">
              <enum>(C)</enum>
              <text>the functions
			 described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000/s:103A/ss:c" proposed="true">section 103A(c) of such Act</cato:entity-ref>, relating to liaison responsibilities
			 regarding post-placement reports and certain adoption cases.</text>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="id95a0eb67337847739d19d905e6623451">
            <enum>(3)</enum>
            <header>Informational
			 responsibilities</header>
            <subparagraph id="idc951fb1c29824a1a829f79dd1c89ab63">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <header>Database on
			 adoption service providers</header>
              <clause id="id4655584cb4fb4d8697e62ac42e95be3a">
                <enum>(i)</enum>
                <header>In
			 general</header>
                <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Associate Director of the Field Operations Directorate" entity-parent-id="7003">Associate Director</cato:entity-ref> shall establish and operate, in
			 conjunction with the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref>, a publicly accessible database of
			 adoption service providers.</text>
              </clause>
              <clause id="idb50de9d30d694da0876b3e7978599c17">
                <enum>(ii)</enum>
                <header>Agreement</header>
                <text>The
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Associate Director of the Field Operations Directorate" entity-parent-id="7003">Associate Director</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7003">Director</cato:entity-ref>, and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref> shall enter into
			 an agreement under which the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7003">Director</cato:entity-ref> and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall provide, for the
			 database, data on intercountry adoption cases relating to adoption service
			 providers.</text>
              </clause>
              <clause id="id8d9140824cf54a3199c0ae97501b7ed1">
                <enum>(iii)</enum>
                <header>Contents</header>
                <text>The
			 database shall include, with respect to each accredited agency and approved
			 person, who is an adoption service provider individually, and to the aggregate
			 of all adoption service providers—</text>
                <subclause id="id4a3f4d9daed0457a8669b3928bda8652">
                  <enum>(I)</enum>
                  <text>information
			 identifying such a provider;</text>
                </subclause>
                <subclause id="id328cc4a54f6d465c88b7a920811bc73b">
                  <enum>(II)</enum>
                  <text>information on
			 the accreditation status of an agency, or the approval status of a person, as
			 an adoption service provider;</text>
                </subclause>
                <subclause id="id4F3AE45077BE4F62A501EC21820F2EFA">
                  <enum>(III)</enum>
                  <text>information on
			 the number of applications or petitions filed respecting adoption and the
			 numbers of approvals and denials of the applications or petitions;</text>
                </subclause>
                <subclause id="idc81bd0dc3e1e485fb94b2a0d6882f528">
                  <enum>(IV)</enum>
                  <text>the number of
			 substantiated grievances filed with respect to an adoption service provider;
			 and</text>
                </subclause>
                <subclause id="idf35ce6844a704a87af94a4335b79788c">
                  <enum>(V)</enum>
                  <text>a description of
			 any sanctions an adoption service provider, or corrective actions that the
			 provider is required to take to maintain accreditation or approval described in
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Children in Families First Act of 2013/s:102/ss:c/p:3/sp:A/cl:iii/scl:II" proposed="true">subclause (II)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
                </subclause>
              </clause>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="ide000a699c5fe4c4e9d7ad6058afacb8d">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <header>Database on
			 internationally adopted children</header>
              <clause id="id69432949ec4646e8b83b17be5c9a308f">
                <enum>(i)</enum>
                <header>In
			 general</header>
                <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Associate Director of the Field Operations Directorate" entity-parent-id="7003">Associate Director</cato:entity-ref>, in conjunction with the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Secretary
			 of State</cato:entity-ref>, shall establish and operate a database containing data respecting
			 children involved in intercountry adoption cases who have immigrated to the
			 United States.</text>
              </clause>
              <clause id="idC66A8DB1A1474B269C8C5FE9198C43EF">
                <enum>(ii)</enum>
                <header>Information
			 tracking</header>
                <text>Although the data available for adoptions finalized
			 before the date of the enactment of this Act will likely be incomplete, the
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Associate Director of the Field Operations Directorate" entity-parent-id="7003">Associate Director</cato:entity-ref> should seek to import available data on all adoptions
			 involving children who are younger than 18 years of age on the date of the
			 enactment of this Act. In operating the database established under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Children in Families First Act of 2013/s:102/ss:c/p:3/sp:B/cl:i" proposed="true">clause (i)</cato:entity-ref>,
			 the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Associate Director of the Field Operations Directorate" entity-parent-id="7003">Associate Director</cato:entity-ref> shall track information about each such child before
			 attaining United States citizenship, including—</text>
                <subclause id="id80031E41F17F49979D743B699D034C3A">
                  <enum>(I)</enum>
                  <text>information
			 identifying a child and the adoptive or prospective adoptive parents,
			 including—</text>
                  <item id="id84742118791545F395C04055296E2B6C">
                    <enum>(aa)</enum>
                    <text>the
			 full name of the child in the country of origin and the full name of the child
			 after the adoption is finalized;</text>
                  </item>
                  <item id="id815F5701989D4B84A4ED7E7D759843FC">
                    <enum>(bb)</enum>
                    <text>the
			 gender, date of birth, nationality, and citizenship of the child;</text>
                  </item>
                  <item id="id1FEC7362B33A4AFC9F50B50087CF1101">
                    <enum>(cc)</enum>
                    <text>the
			 physical address of the child at the time of the adoption; the type of visa
			 issued to the child; and</text>
                  </item>
                  <item id="id33F8BF528D2449899484745198F74FA7">
                    <enum>(dd)</enum>
                    <text>the
			 date on which the child entered the United States;</text>
                  </item>
                </subclause>
                <subclause id="id5B71B426347C4751A81C6C854D8CBF37">
                  <enum>(II)</enum>
                  <text>information on
			 the particular adoption service provider, if any, providing services in the
			 particular case; and</text>
                </subclause>
                <subclause id="id02E6646FD7E64B3B907014E879D68E6D">
                  <enum>(III)</enum>
                  <text>information on
			 immigration or citizenship status of the child.</text>
                </subclause>
              </clause>
              <clause id="idb505fba702bc423fa5785036cc3aa1a5">
                <enum>(iii)</enum>
                <header>Interagency
			 agreement</header>
                <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Associate Director of the Field Operations Directorate" entity-parent-id="7003">Associate Director</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7003">Director</cato:entity-ref>, and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Secretary
			 of State</cato:entity-ref> shall enter into an agreement under which the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref> shall
			 provide, for the database, data on intercountry adoption cases concerning the
			 adopted children, and the adoption service providers.</text>
              </clause>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
      </section>
      <section id="id5c129f1553ce46d5aff36c4cb427089f">
        <enum>103.</enum>
        <header>Transfer of
			 functions and savings provisions</header>
        <subsection id="idc8f260ff76224440846898c12d5c2d69">
          <enum>(a)</enum>
          <header>Definitions</header>
          <text>In
			 this section, unless otherwise provided or contextually indicated—</text>
          <paragraph id="id08886b7363c2457fab00529e194c7cb1">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <text>the term
			 <term>Federal agency</term> has the meaning given to the term
			 <term>agency</term> under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc/5/551//1">
                <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/5/551">section 551(1)</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code</cato:entity-ref>;</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="id1f6f7e9203f74fc0a93b788b264d5262">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <text>the term
			 <term>function</term> means any duty, obligation, power, authority,
			 responsibility, right, privilege, activity, or program; and</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="id6efbe9c5afff422db847b85fe46b6b05">
            <enum>(3)</enum>
            <text>the term
			 <term>office</term> includes any office, administration, agency, institute,
			 unit, organizational entity, or component thereof.</text>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="id6f663648ffef4557a51e0460aa79dd18">
          <enum>(b)</enum>
          <header>Transfer of
			 functions</header>
          <text>There are transferred to the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Field Operations Directorate" entity-parent-id="7003">Directorate</cato:entity-ref>, all functions
			 described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000/s:103A/ss:a" proposed="true">section 103A(a) of the Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000</cato:entity-ref>, as added
			 by <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Children in Families First Act of 2013/s:102/ss:a" proposed="true">section 102(a) of this Act</cato:entity-ref>, which were exercised by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref>
			 before the date of the enactment of this Act (including all related functions
			 of any officer or employee of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Department of State</cato:entity-ref>), including functions
			 relating to—</text>
          <paragraph id="id6b53acc55b004ab08b20eb00d050909c">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <text>the accreditation
			 of agencies and approval of persons to provide adoption services;</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="iddae84db63aac4f24b2f995d10d3385d6">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <text>the management
			 and oversight of investigations related to the operation of such providers;
			 and</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="idA4AAEAD68E5E497FA31ECB110CDA8E70">
            <enum>(3)</enum>
            <text>liaison
			 responsibilities with respect to required post-placement reports.</text>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="id528fddf02a4e434181183a79bb01a1ea">
          <enum>(c)</enum>
          <header>Determinations
			 of certain functions by the Office of Management and Budget</header>
          <text>If
			 necessary, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1103">Director of the Office of Management and Budget</cato:entity-ref> shall make any
			 determination with respect to the transfer of functions under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Children in Families First Act of 2013/s:103/ss:b" proposed="true">subsection
			 (b)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="id0dcdcd8c3c8c433eb6a41ffbf48fcb91">
          <enum>(d)</enum>
          <header>Personnel
			 provisions</header>
          <paragraph id="id81a590f03baa4dce9dcd626efdb44d5f">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <header>Appointments</header>
            <text>The
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Associate Director of the Field Operations Directorate" entity-parent-id="7003">Associate Director</cato:entity-ref> may appoint and fix the compensation of such officers and
			 employees, including investigators, attorneys, and administrative law judges,
			 as may be necessary to carry out the respective functions transferred under
			 this section. Except as otherwise provided by law, such officers and employees
			 shall be appointed in accordance with the civil service laws and their
			 compensation fixed in accordance with <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc/5">title 5, United States Code</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="id3b95dd485d7642cd9230f0d033f1aa8c">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <header>Experts and
			 consultants</header>
            <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Associate Director of the Field Operations Directorate" entity-parent-id="7003">Associate Director</cato:entity-ref> may obtain the services of
			 experts and consultants in accordance with <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc/5/3109">
                <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/5/3109">section 3109</external-xref> of title 5, United
			 States Code</cato:entity-ref>, and compensate such experts and consultants for each day
			 (including travel time) at rates not in excess of the rate of pay for level IV
			 of the Executive Schedule under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc/5/5315">section 5315 of such title</cato:entity-ref>. The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Associate Director of the Field Operations Directorate">Associate
			 Director</cato:entity-ref> may pay experts and consultants who are serving away from their homes
			 or regular place of business travel expenses and per diem in lieu of
			 subsistence at rates authorized by <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc/5/5702">sections 5702</cato:entity-ref> and <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc/5/5703">5703</cato:entity-ref> of such title for
			 persons in Government service employed intermittently.</text>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="id177adcbc81c04811a9d96c6615e06662">
          <enum>(e)</enum>
          <header>Delegation and
			 assignment</header>
          <text>Except where otherwise expressly prohibited by law or
			 otherwise provided under this section—</text>
          <paragraph id="id669BE680F2354944BB28BEF696A364B7">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <text>the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Associate Director of the Field Operations Directorate" entity-parent-id="7003">Associate
			 Director</cato:entity-ref> may—</text>
            <subparagraph id="id4CC8A6A32F7948899A7F8B956D6E276B">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>delegate any of
			 the functions transferred to the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Associate Director of the Field Operations Directorate" entity-parent-id="7003">Associate Director</cato:entity-ref> under this section and any
			 function transferred or granted to the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Associate Director of the Field Operations Directorate" entity-parent-id="7003">Associate Director</cato:entity-ref> after the date of the
			 enactment of this Act to such officers and employees of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Field Operations Directorate" entity-parent-id="7003">Directorate</cato:entity-ref> as the
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Associate Director of the Field Operations Directorate" entity-parent-id="7003">Associate Director</cato:entity-ref> may designate; and</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="id04E5075ED3CB4F9EB9D4D18B27E4B80C">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>authorize
			 successive redelegations of such functions as may be necessary or appropriate;
			 and</text>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="id0F60D530B2E64DF493CB692B481E0783">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <text>no delegation of
			 functions by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Associate Director of the Field Operations Directorate" entity-parent-id="7003">Associate Director</cato:entity-ref> under this subsection or under any other
			 provision of this section shall relieve such <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Associate Director of the Field Operations Directorate" entity-parent-id="7003">Associate Director</cato:entity-ref> of
			 responsibility for the administration of such functions.</text>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="id156867e4293444168ba286f50ac85b55">
          <enum>(f)</enum>
          <header>Reorganization</header>
          <text>The
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Associate Director of the Field Operations Directorate" entity-parent-id="7003">Associate Director</cato:entity-ref> is authorized—</text>
          <paragraph id="id3A9ADAEDC39E433DB3BE743555AA3C72">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <text>to allocate or
			 reallocate any function transferred under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Children in Families First Act of 2013/s:103/ss:b" proposed="true">subsection (b)</cato:entity-ref> among the officers of
			 the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Field Operations Directorate" entity-parent-id="7003">Directorate</cato:entity-ref>; and</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="id9158CFB4D03D476E9DD45846058DAE68">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <text>to establish,
			 consolidate, alter, or discontinue such organizational entities in the
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Field Operations Directorate" entity-parent-id="7003">Directorate</cato:entity-ref> as may be necessary or appropriate.</text>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="idde136ce6f5464ee59ec1779a7af329c9">
          <enum>(g)</enum>
          <header>Rules</header>
          <text>The
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Associate Director of the Field Operations Directorate" entity-parent-id="7003">Associate Director</cato:entity-ref> is authorized to prescribe, in accordance with the
			 provisions of <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc-chapter/5/5">chapters 5</cato:entity-ref> and <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc-chapter/5/6">6 of title 5, United States Code</cato:entity-ref>, such rules and
			 regulations as the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Associate Director of the Field Operations Directorate" entity-parent-id="7003">Associate Director</cato:entity-ref> determines necessary or appropriate to
			 administer and manage the functions of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Field Operations Directorate" entity-parent-id="7003">Directorate</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="id7ac8f625be224b2b84f1255687ec4d76">
          <enum>(h)</enum>
          <header>Transfer and
			 allocations of appropriations and personnel</header>
          <text>Except as otherwise
			 provided under this section and subject to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc/31/1531">
              <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/31/1531">section 1531</external-xref> of title 31, United
			 States Code</cato:entity-ref>, the personnel employed in connection with, and the assets,
			 liabilities, contracts, property, records, and unexpended balances of
			 appropriations, authorizations, allocations, and other funds employed, used,
			 held, arising from, available to, or to be made available in connection with
			 the functions transferred under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Children in Families First Act of 2013/s:103/ss:b" proposed="true">subsection (b)</cato:entity-ref>, shall be transferred to the
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Field Operations Directorate" entity-parent-id="7003">Directorate</cato:entity-ref>. Unexpended funds transferred pursuant to this subsection may only
			 be used for the purposes for which the funds were originally authorized and
			 appropriated.</text>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="id37524fcbb35f4c8c8d2a59962782adaa">
          <enum>(i)</enum>
          <header>Incidental
			 transfers</header>
          <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1103">Director of the Office of Management and
			 Budget</cato:entity-ref>—</text>
          <paragraph id="id0D4AD8DF49DA4CAEA544E09380649329">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <text>may, at such time
			 or times as the Director may prescribe—</text>
            <subparagraph id="id952FB8BC66304F7EAD7E0469D5BF51F6">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>make such
			 determinations as may be necessary with regard to the functions transferred
			 under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Children in Families First Act of 2013/s:103/ss:b" proposed="true">subsection (b)</cato:entity-ref>; and</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="id896A47F8E0D34EE5840201F4B05681A1">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>make such
			 additional incidental dispositions of personnel, assets, liabilities, grants,
			 contracts, property, records, and unexpended balances of appropriations,
			 authorizations, allocations, and other funds held, used, arising from,
			 available to, or to be made available in connection with such functions, as may
			 be necessary to carry out the provisions of this section; and</text>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="idD024BB21618245A19F0899015A26676D">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <text>shall provide
			 for—</text>
            <subparagraph id="id88A4C788A8584B1EAA6AFE4CA64290AA">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>the termination
			 of the affairs of all entities terminated under this section; and</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="idE66B02CB434F4705A2C74AF2FA49898F">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>such further
			 measures and dispositions as may be necessary to carry out the purposes of this
			 section.</text>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="id181f07e7660844d38ce2e8bc458369d8">
          <enum>(j)</enum>
          <header>Effect on
			 personnel</header>
          <paragraph id="id261699c9662c485f8501727da0ff1ff9">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <header>In
			 general</header>
            <text>Except as otherwise provided under this section, the
			 transfer under this section of full-time personnel (except special Government
			 employees) and part-time personnel holding permanent positions shall not cause
			 any such employee to be separated or reduced in grade or compensation during
			 the 1-year period beginning on the date of such transfer.</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="id9fd4a809b87b4cef9ab455c3d659efdf">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <header>Executive
			 schedule positions</header>
            <text>Except as otherwise provided under this
			 section, any person who, on the day preceding the date of the enactment of this
			 Act, held a position compensated in accordance with the Executive Schedule
			 prescribed in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc-chapter/5/53">
                <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/53">chapter 53</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code</cato:entity-ref>, and who, without a
			 break in service, is appointed in the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Field Operations Directorate" entity-parent-id="7003">Directorate</cato:entity-ref> to a position having duties
			 comparable to the duties performed immediately preceding such appointment shall
			 continue to be compensated in such new position at not less than the rate
			 provided for such previous position, for the duration of the service of such
			 person in such new position.</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="id9303a4c49b9849fca876865e5b3b8a9d">
            <enum>(3)</enum>
            <header>Termination of
			 certain positions</header>
            <text>All positions whose functions are transferred
			 under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Children in Families First Act of 2013/s:103/ss:b" proposed="true">subsection (b)</cato:entity-ref> and whose incumbents have been appointed by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref>,
			 by and with the advice and consent of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0010">Senate</cato:entity-ref>, shall terminate on the date
			 of the enactment of this Act.</text>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="id038b39d75547405b9764c4f60a3a0641">
          <enum>(k)</enum>
          <header>Savings
			 provisions</header>
          <paragraph id="id6a602bb022ce461a9bb87a7efcaff5cf">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <header>Continuing
			 effect of legal documents</header>
            <text>All orders, determinations, rules,
			 regulations, permits, agreements, grants, contracts, certificates, licenses,
			 registrations, privileges, and other administrative actions which—</text>
            <subparagraph id="idd6d1e29294064f729196f55aea156f4d">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>have been issued,
			 made, granted, or allowed to become effective by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref>, any Federal
			 agency or official thereof, or by a court of competent jurisdiction, in the
			 performance of functions which are transferred under this section; and</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="id0df3717c04a749f49153418448e34b6a">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>are in effect on
			 the date of the enactment of this Act, or were final before such date of
			 enactment and are to become effective on or after the date of the enactment of
			 this Act,</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph">shall
			 continue in effect according to their terms until modified, terminated,
			 superseded, set aside, or revoked in accordance with law by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref>, the
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Associate Director of the Field Operations Directorate" entity-parent-id="7003">Associate Director</cato:entity-ref> or other authorized official, a court of competent
			 jurisdiction, or by operation of law.</continuation-text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="id2553290856cd43baa8c7200ef725494d">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <header>Proceedings not
			 affected</header>
            <text>Nothing in this section may be construed to affect any
			 proceeding, including a notice of proposed rulemaking, or any application for
			 any license, permit, certificate, or financial assistance pending before the
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Department of State</cato:entity-ref> on the effective date of this section, with respect to
			 functions transferred under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Children in Families First Act of 2013/s:103/ss:b" proposed="true">subsection (b)</cato:entity-ref>. Orders shall be issued in such
			 proceedings, appeals shall be taken therefrom, and payments shall be made
			 pursuant to such orders, as if this section had not been enacted. Orders issued
			 in any such proceedings shall continue in effect until modified, terminated,
			 superseded, or revoked by a duly authorized official, by a court of competent
			 jurisdiction, or by operation of law. Nothing in this paragraph may be
			 construed to prohibit the discontinuance or modification of any such proceeding
			 under the same terms and conditions and to the same extent that such proceeding
			 could have been discontinued or modified if this section had not been
			 enacted.</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="ide55ad225942d4e3f8fc5197ee499cf86">
            <enum>(3)</enum>
            <header>Suits not
			 affected</header>
            <text>Nothing in this section may be construed to affect suits
			 commenced before the date of the enactment of this Act. In all such suits,
			 proceedings shall be had, appeals taken, and judgments rendered in the same
			 manner and with the same effect as if this section had not been enacted.</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="id2ec33e95a982452f9f6abae2c66054a0">
            <enum>(4)</enum>
            <header>Nonabatement of
			 actions</header>
            <text>No suit, action, or other proceeding commenced by or
			 against the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Department of State</cato:entity-ref>, or by or against any individual in the
			 official capacity of such individual as an officer of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Department of State</cato:entity-ref>,
			 shall abate by reason of the enactment of this section.</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="idc52ed8a827df43dd87bedeb4c8ecac23">
            <enum>(5)</enum>
            <header>Administrative
			 actions relating to promulgation of regulations</header>
            <text>Any
			 administrative action relating to the preparation or promulgation of a
			 regulation by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Department of State</cato:entity-ref> relating to a function transferred under
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Children in Families First Act of 2013/s:103/ss:b" proposed="true">subsection (b)</cato:entity-ref> may be continued by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Field Operations Directorate" entity-parent-id="7003">Directorate</cato:entity-ref> with the same effect as if
			 this section had not been enacted.</text>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="id611a84e6895246d8b633c41bca23955d">
          <enum>(l)</enum>
          <header>Separability</header>
          <text>If
			 a provision of this section or its application to any person or circumstance is
			 held invalid, neither the remainder of this section nor the application of the
			 provision to other persons or circumstances shall be affected.</text>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="id4ee2548a580a4c57986d2ccc3bab4143">
          <enum>(m)</enum>
          <header>Transition</header>
          <text>The
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Associate Director of the Field Operations Directorate" entity-parent-id="7003">Associate Director</cato:entity-ref> is authorized to utilize—</text>
          <paragraph id="id5d03234a348c4b5ebdd5efe12b892b94">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <text>the services of
			 such officers, employees, and other personnel of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Department of State</cato:entity-ref> with
			 respect to functions transferred to the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Field Operations Directorate" entity-parent-id="7003">Directorate</cato:entity-ref> by this section; and</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="id4d250ecadd6f4ee294025e40b6a7964d">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <text>funds
			 appropriated to such functions for such period of time as may reasonably be
			 needed to facilitate the orderly implementation of this section.</text>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="idffab633a4cb245ef8a1e1d8111d6c6d0">
          <enum>(n)</enum>
          <header>References</header>
          <text>Reference
			 in any other Federal law, Executive order, rule, regulation, or delegation of
			 authority, or any document of or relating to—</text>
          <paragraph id="iddb6a8aadc3704567935c7b462fdfc0e9">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <text>the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Secretary of
			 State</cato:entity-ref> with regard to functions transferred under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Children in Families First Act of 2013/s:103/ss:b" proposed="true">subsection (b)</cato:entity-ref>, shall be
			 deemed to refer to the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Associate Director of the Field Operations Directorate" entity-parent-id="7003">Associate Director</cato:entity-ref>; and</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="id9d4f5d38594647bdbe15026910b1b369">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <text>the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Department of
			 State</cato:entity-ref> with regard to functions transferred under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Children in Families First Act of 2013/s:103/ss:b" proposed="true">subsection (b)</cato:entity-ref>, shall be
			 deemed to refer to the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Field Operations Directorate" entity-parent-id="7003">Directorate</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="id77cd065b0dd74d989253363e9971e40e">
          <enum>(o)</enum>
          <header>Additional
			 conforming amendments</header>
          <paragraph id="id2901b4cbf80c4e8fb46fe5288d3ed6cc">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <header>Recommended
			 legislation</header>
            <text>After consultation with the appropriate committees of
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1103">Director of the Office of Management and Budget</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Associate Director of the Field Operations Directorate" entity-parent-id="7003">Associate
			 Director</cato:entity-ref> shall prepare and submit to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> recommended legislation
			 containing technical and conforming amendments to reflect the changes made by
			 this section.</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8ea58626cdd9411dae906c23e6a144ad">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <header>Submission to
			 congress</header>
            <text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment
			 of this Act, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Associate Director of the Field Operations Directorate" entity-parent-id="7003">Associate Director</cato:entity-ref> shall submit the recommended legislation
			 referred to under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Children in Families First Act of 2013/s:103/ss:o/p:1" proposed="true">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref> to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
      </section>
      <section id="id7E0CAD9FC1DB4CAE89C0165E9C4A7456">
        <enum>104.</enum>
        <header>Responsibilities
			 of U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services for adoption-related case
			 processing</header>
        <subsection id="idEEDF94BFECB14259B39B77AAE6D2D5FA">
          <enum>(a)</enum>
          <header>In
			 general</header>
          <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7000">Secretary of Homeland Security</cato:entity-ref>, acting through the
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7003">Director of U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services</cato:entity-ref>—</text>
          <paragraph id="idBB271EBDB2EE4EBF9E07AE24B0E44EF5">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <text>shall be
			 responsible for processing and case-specific decisionmaking on all
			 intercountry adoption cases (up to the point of application for an immigrant
			 visa on behalf of the adopted child), including cases being processed pursuant
			 to the <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000">Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/14901">
                  <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/42/14901/etseq">42 U.S.C. 14901 et seq.</cato:entity-ref>
                </external-xref>)</cato:entity> and <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Intercountry Adoption Universal Accreditation Act of 2012/s:2">section
			 2 of the Intercountry Adoption Universal Accreditation Act of 2012</cato:entity-ref> (<cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/42/14925">42 U.S.C.
			 14925</cato:entity-ref>)</cato:entity>;</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="idA51E9292EF254172B1463CDF84A51B92">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <text>shall ensure that
			 all intercountry adoption suitability and eligibility determinations of
			 prospective adoptive parents required under <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Immigration and Nationality Act/s:101/ss:b/p:1/sp:F">subparagraph (F)</cato:entity-ref> or <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Immigration and Nationality Act/s:101/ss:b/p:1/sp:G">(G) of section
			 101(b)(1) of the Immigration and Nationality Act</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">
                  <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/8/1101/b/1">8 U.S.C. 1101(b)(1)</cato:entity-ref>
                </external-xref>)</cato:entity> are made
			 in accordance with standard criteria that comply with the Hague Adoption
			 Convention so that any such determination justifies a Convention adoption or a
			 non-Convention adoption;</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="idC6F0103DEC49446CB417F3FF6BA4C367">
            <enum>(3)</enum>
            <text>to the maximum
			 extent possible, and to the extent permitted by the country in which the child
			 resides, shall ensure that all non-Convention adoption cases undergo
			 preprocessing, including—</text>
            <subparagraph id="id6597D4C49EAD4D6D96ED265635BAFAAF">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>the filing of a
			 petition and the review of a child’s eligibility to immigrate to the United
			 States before the adoption or grant of legal custody (for purposes of
			 emigration and adoption in the United States) of that child is completed in the
			 country of origin; and</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="idB89C85C0EB0A479799630CDC576D30AB">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>the completion of
			 all necessary and relevant investigations associated with the petition before
			 the country of origin finalizes the adoption or grants legal custody for
			 purposes of emigration and adoption in the United States;</text>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="idD5FE511129D340DE8DE7760C955D110E">
            <enum>(4)</enum>
            <text>except as
			 provided in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Children in Families First Act of 2013/s:104/ss:a/p:5" proposed="true">paragraph (5)</cato:entity-ref>, shall be responsible for all case processing steps
			 in Convention and non-Convention adoption petitions on behalf of children whom
			 United States parents propose to immigrate to the United States (except for the
			 processing of immigrant visas), including processing of all necessary Hague
			 Adoption Convention certifications and the final adjudication of the
			 immigration petitions; and</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="id3E03D993C1504C84A60365C6FCCBEE81">
            <enum>(5)</enum>
            <text>may delegate the
			 responsibility for completing certain elements of case adjudication to the
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref> if the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7000">Department of Homeland Security</cato:entity-ref>—</text>
            <subparagraph id="id06DCBBAB29044E69AEA3A75299B40AE7">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>cannot adequately
			 complete such elements due to the need for physical presence in the country of
			 origin or other processing-related circumstances; and</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="id69BC72343B2346849B044D4DBDF5E67B">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>defines and
			 monitors the parameters for the elements delegated to the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref>
			 and retains final decisionmaking authority.</text>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="id3AEC6DA9F7C444D2BBEA4EF5237CB306">
          <enum>(b)</enum>
          <header>Foreign
			 adoption decrees</header>
          <paragraph id="ide63f23024a5e4ba19be6f4d2cc6f0ea9">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <header>Convention
			 countries</header>
            <text>The 2-year legal custody and joint residence
			 requirements set forth in <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Immigration and Nationality Act/s:101/ss:b/p:1/sp:E">section 101(b)(1)(E) of the Immigration and
			 Nationality Act</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">
                  <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/8/1101/b/1/E">8 U.S.C. 1101(b)(1)(E)</cato:entity-ref>
                </external-xref>)</cato:entity> shall not apply if the documentation
			 submitted on behalf of a child includes—</text>
            <subparagraph id="id08e7e087564645dcb86f843de56b40ac">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>an adoption
			 decree issued by a competent authority (as such term is used in the Hague
			 Adoption Convention) of the child’s country of origin and evidence that the
			 adoption was granted in compliance with the Hague Adoption Convention;
			 or</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="idc9997262230c4a0684a0fa02c63a9795">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>a custody or
			 guardianship decree issued by the competent authority of the child’s country of
			 origin to the adoptive parents, and a final adoption decree, verifying that the
			 adoption of the child was later finalized outside the United States by the
			 adoptive parents, in addition to evidence that the custody or guardianship was
			 granted in compliance with the Hague Adoption Convention.</text>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="id1F0FC57074754697845F3AA967B7CC44">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <header>Substantial
			 compliance with hague adoption convention</header>
            <text>
              <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Children in Families First Act of 2013/s:104/ss:b/p:1" proposed="true">Paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref> shall not
			 apply unless—</text>
            <subparagraph id="id4686882B179B48B794782336C0573BD0">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>on the date on
			 which the underlying adoption, custody, or guardianship decree was issued by
			 the child’s country of origin—</text>
              <clause id="id7BDE8F61FE854BF997C90CFF6D1E25CD">
                <enum>(i)</enum>
                <text>that country’s
			 adoption procedures complied with the requirements of the Hague Adoption
			 Convention (as determined by the United States central authority); and</text>
              </clause>
              <clause id="id9D260344D3C747C5B09DACB73234E0D3">
                <enum>(ii)</enum>
                <text>the competent
			 authority of the country of origin certified that the adoption is consistent
			 with Article 23 of the Hague Adoption Convention; and</text>
              </clause>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="id2d6c29fe1a244263a67ae38e2201ebe0">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>the adoption was
			 a Convention adoption that was completed between 2 Convention countries other
			 than the United States.</text>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="id22EFF9E19E84448081BDD65B20C0FDA2">
            <enum>(3)</enum>
            <header>Non-convention
			 countries</header>
            <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7000">Secretary of Homeland Security</cato:entity-ref> may accept the
			 filing of petitions on behalf of children living in non-Convention countries in
			 the absence of a final adoption decree.</text>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="idBABE83B3188348D59BE4516E00167140">
          <enum>(c)</enum>
          <header>Cooperation
			 with foreign governments</header>
          <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7000">Secretary of Homeland Security</cato:entity-ref> may
			 interact directly with the central authority of a Convention country or a
			 competent authority of a non-Convention country, as appropriate—</text>
          <paragraph id="id219BC0BC89094B0784EC7DBD42064814">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <text>to facilitate the
			 processing of intercountry adoption cases, including making habitual residence
			 determinations relevant to children and prospective adoptive parents in
			 adoption proceedings; and</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="id1F2B9E6A91F742BEB3783B61E164ED07">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <text>to negotiate, in
			 coordination with the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Department of State</cato:entity-ref>, and to implement bilateral
			 agreements with respect to intercountry adoptions.</text>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="id953A4A3D3AC04427B41D4BB2925CA945">
          <enum>(d)</enum>
          <header>Amendments to
			 the Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000</header>
          <paragraph id="id0724587893AD48A4BF51879DAC1CFF77">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <header>Transfer of
			 responsibilities to the Secretary of Homeland Security</header>
            <text>The
			 <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000">Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/14901">
                  <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/42/14901/etseq">42 U.S.C. 14901 et seq.</cato:entity-ref>
                </external-xref>)</cato:entity> is amended—</text>
            <subparagraph id="id498744C330614434A9C9B05AF3D80F48">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>by striking
			 <quote>
                  <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1500">Attorney General</cato:entity-ref>
                </quote> each place it appears and inserting
			 <quote>
                  <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7000">Secretary of Homeland Security</cato:entity-ref>
                </quote>; and</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="idDF46006E8EC14B0084AB4A1E5280EF3A">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>in the heading of
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000/s:103">section 103</cato:entity-ref>, by striking <quote>
                  <header-in-text level="section" style="OLC">
                    <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1500">Attorney General</cato:entity-ref>
                  </header-in-text>
                </quote> and inserting
			 <quote>
                  <header-in-text level="section" style="OLC">
                    <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7000">Secretary of Homeland
			 Security</cato:entity-ref>
                  </header-in-text>
                </quote>.</text>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="id7F0F80F59B5C42C49CF1AC8C58E0B491">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <header>Hague
			 convention certificates</header>
            <text>
              <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000/s:301">Section 301 of such Act</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/14931">
                  <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/42/14931">42 U.S.C. 14931</cato:entity-ref>
                </external-xref>)</cato:entity>
			 is amended—</text>
            <subparagraph id="id58E208BFD5864F98BBC69BE0697F860A">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000/s:301/ss:a">subsection
			 (a)</cato:entity-ref>—</text>
              <clause id="idB8A583D16FCA46C5B0B3CB78D1F57E50">
                <enum>(i)</enum>
                <text>in
			 the subsection heading, by striking <quote>
                    <header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">
                      <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref>
                    </header-in-text>
                  </quote> and inserting
			 <quote>
                    <header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">
                      <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7000">Secretary of Homeland
			 Security</cato:entity-ref>
                    </header-in-text>
                  </quote>; and</text>
              </clause>
              <clause id="idDE9905198F4447AA81EF1169EDCC1011">
                <enum>(ii)</enum>
                <text>in
			 the heading to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000/s:301/ss:a/p:1">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref>, by striking <quote>
                    <header-in-text level="paragraph" style="OLC">
                      <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref>
                    </header-in-text>
                  </quote> and
			 inserting <quote>
                    <header-in-text level="paragraph" style="OLC">
                      <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7000">Secretary of
			 Homeland Security</cato:entity-ref>
                    </header-in-text>
                  </quote>; and</text>
              </clause>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="idE016D6823EB640C8B2C7373E9D1693F5">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>by striking
			 <quote>
                  <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref>
                </quote> each place it appears and inserting
			 <quote>
                  <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7000">Secretary of Homeland Security</cato:entity-ref>
                </quote>.</text>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="id7BB6DB3F655F495586D6E013CE44ACA0">
            <enum>(3)</enum>
            <header>Clerical
			 amendment</header>
            <text>The table of contents of such Act is amended by
			 striking the item relating to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Children in Families First Act of 2013/s:103" proposed="true">section 103</cato:entity-ref> and inserting the following:</text>
            <quoted-block id="id730B1675FC3F462A8B1F268BD717C963" style="OLC">
              <toc>
                <toc-entry level="section">Sec. 103. Responsibilities of the
				Secretary of Homeland
				Security.</toc-entry>
              </toc>
              <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
            </quoted-block>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="id8CFCB9E8BB87497698B17499912DBC62">
          <enum>(e)</enum>
          <header>Definition of
			 child</header>
          <text>
            <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Immigration and Nationality Act/s:101/ss:b/p:1">Section 101(b)(1) of the Immigration and Nationality Act</cato:entity-ref> (<cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/8/1101/b/1">8
			 U.S.C. 1101(b)(1)</cato:entity-ref>)</cato:entity> is amended—</text>
          <paragraph id="id99BC07E6C9F74B8AAA4A196435A44142">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <text>in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Immigration and Nationality Act/s:101/ss:b/p:1/sp:E">subparagraph
			 (E)</cato:entity-ref>—</text>
            <subparagraph id="idA36BD928B7E946A39E92620D75E00319">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Immigration and Nationality Act/s:101/ss:b/p:1/sp:E/cl:i">clause (i)</cato:entity-ref>, by
			 striking <quote>(i) a child adopted while under the age of sixteen
			 years</quote> and inserting <quote>a child adopted while younger than 18 years
			 of age</quote>; and</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="idF1CDEF2C69BE447F97D0BB8920DCF2FD">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>by striking
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Immigration and Nationality Act/s:101/ss:b/p:1/sp:E/cl:ii">clause (ii)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="idA2A7A1CCE4134E89842A51F35100223C">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <text>by amending
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Immigration and Nationality Act/s:101/ss:b/p:1/sp:F">subparagraph (F)</cato:entity-ref> to read as follows:</text>
            <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5BA70979259F4D90B1DD10E90FF8A019" style="OLC">
              <subparagraph id="id9D953FA32DAD4731A226E79A0B2787C9">
                <enum>(F)</enum>
                <clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id69D29DC9DC544F40AB9C12C395641AEF">
                  <enum>(i)</enum>
                  <text>a child, younger than
				18 years of age at the time a petition is filed on the child's behalf to accord
				a classification as an immediate relative under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Immigration and Nationality Act/s:201/ss:b">section 201(b)</cato:entity-ref>, and who has
				been adopted in a foreign state that is not a party to the Convention on
				Protection of Children and Co-operation in Respect of Intercountry Adoption,
				done at the Hague May 29, 1993, or who is emigrating from such a foreign state
				to be adopted in the United States by a United States citizen and spouse
				jointly, or by an unmarried United States citizen who is at least 25 years of
				age, if—</text>
                  <subclause id="idE983ADDAD2BD48EC8BCB06CE1B2A8997" indent="up1">
                    <enum>(I)</enum>
                    <text>the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7000">Secretary of Homeland Security</cato:entity-ref> is
				satisfied that proper care will be furnished the child if admitted to the
				United States;</text>
                  </subclause>
                  <subclause id="idC976C538654C4F7595416C1D7E9D6705" indent="up1">
                    <enum>(II)</enum>
                    <text>the child’s natural parents (or parent,
				in the case of a child who has 1 sole or surviving parent), or other persons or
				institutions that retain legal custody of the child, have freely given their
				written irrevocable consent to the termination of their legal relationship with
				the child, and to the child's emigration and adoption;</text>
                  </subclause>
                  <subclause id="idCE0DCFC4DAC840A28DC222D8FAA54B10" indent="up1">
                    <enum>(III)</enum>
                    <text>the child has a living parent or
				parents who has or have relinquished, or will relinquish, the child voluntarily
				for the purposes of intercountry adoption, and the parent or parents are
				incapable of providing proper care for the child;</text>
                  </subclause>
                  <subclause id="id80CF49D910804FB2B5E61483569D98BA" indent="up1">
                    <enum>(IV)</enum>
                    <text>the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7000">Secretary of Homeland Security</cato:entity-ref>,
				after considering whether there is a petition pending to confer immigrant
				status on one or both natural parents, is satisfied that the purpose of the
				adoption is to form a bona fide parent-child relationship, and the parent-child
				relationship of the child and the natural parents has been terminated;
				and</text>
                  </subclause>
                  <subclause id="id8D259864AFF942E0B186121043B2F1AB" indent="up1">
                    <enum>(V)</enum>
                    <text>in the case of a child who has not been
				adopted—</text>
                    <item id="id6DE58FA9D552412485844E2FE1B7D8D1">
                      <enum>(aa)</enum>
                      <text>the competent authority of the
				foreign state has approved the child’s emigration to the United States for the
				purpose of adoption by the prospective adoptive parent or parents; and</text>
                    </item>
                    <item id="id70CCF7B7755649B7841395BFB5F177DF">
                      <enum>(bb)</enum>
                      <text>the prospective adoptive parent or
				parents has or have complied with any preadoption requirements of the child’s
				proposed residence; and</text>
                    </item>
                  </subclause>
                </clause>
                <clause id="id8F032FD97E2F43A29C179394C3373A65" indent="up1">
                  <enum>(ii)</enum>
                  <text>except that no natural parent or
				prior adoptive parent of any such child shall thereafter, by virtue of such
				parentage, be accorded any right, privilege, or status under this
				chapter;</text>
                </clause>
              </subparagraph>
              <after-quoted-block>;
				and</after-quoted-block>
            </quoted-block>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="idBA925AA32213462DA5E5FE5D2574BAB0">
            <enum>(3)</enum>
            <text>in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Immigration and Nationality Act/s:101/ss:b/p:1/sp:G">subparagraph
			 (G)</cato:entity-ref>—</text>
            <subparagraph id="idFF8FC386FB294805BAEC909C11A0F2E0">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>in the matter
			 preceding <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Immigration and Nationality Act/s:101/ss:b/p:1/sp:G/cl:i">clause (i)</cato:entity-ref>, by striking <quote>16</quote> and inserting
			 <quote>18</quote>;</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="idD5B313907B3342079E22161072560654">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Immigration and Nationality Act/s:101/ss:b/p:1/sp:G/cl:i">clause
			 (i)</cato:entity-ref>—</text>
              <clause id="id63C6031E6972444AA6275534860D7EFD">
                <enum>(i)</enum>
                <text>in
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Immigration and Nationality Act/s:101/ss:b/p:1/sp:G/cl:i/scl:II">subclause (II)</cato:entity-ref>, by striking <quote>because of the death or disappearance of,
			 abandonment or desertion by, the other parent</quote>; and</text>
              </clause>
              <clause id="idCF2F1530A68A43C6B55C1C02E7133119">
                <enum>(ii)</enum>
                <text>in
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Immigration and Nationality Act/s:101/ss:b/p:1/sp:G/cl:i/scl:III">subclause (III)</cato:entity-ref>, by striking <quote>two living natural parents, the natural
			 parents are</quote> and inserting <quote>a living parent or parents, who have
			 relinquished or will relinquish the child voluntarily for the purposes of
			 intercountry adoption, the parent or parents are</quote>;</text>
              </clause>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="id14421DBF2F404639A23AB504F2936786">
              <enum>(C)</enum>
              <text>in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Immigration and Nationality Act/s:101/ss:b/p:1/sp:G/cl:ii">clause (ii)</cato:entity-ref>,
			 by striking <quote>; or</quote> and inserting a period; and</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="idF4E2B9BAE83E415CB7F0EBEC3DCE3E46">
              <enum>(D)</enum>
              <text>by striking
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Immigration and Nationality Act/s:101/ss:b/p:1/sp:G/cl:iii">clause (iii)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="idfa6463a18aab4566b7c4a9ef691559d2">
          <enum>(f)</enum>
          <header>Relative
			 adoptions; waiver authority</header>
          <text>
            <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Intercountry Adoption Act/s:502">Section 502 of the Intercountry
			 Adoption Act</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/14952">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/42/14952">42 U.S.C. 14952</cato:entity-ref>
              </external-xref>)</cato:entity> is amended to read as follows:</text>
          <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida66ce4a684114d06a7aaf4b14c21e7d9" style="OLC">
            <subsection id="id25fc3348242f40b39d7ed580179c0ae9">
              <enum>(a)</enum>
              <header>Authority To
				establish alternative procedures for adoption of children by
				relatives</header>
              <text>Not later than 2 years after the date of the enactment
				of the <short-title>
                  <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Children in Families First Act of 2013" proposed="true">Children in Families First Act of
				2013</cato:entity-ref>
                </short-title>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7000">Secretary of Homeland Security</cato:entity-ref> shall establish, by
				regulation, alternative procedures for completing the intercountry adoption of
				children by United States citizens who are related to such children by blood,
				marriage, or adoption.</text>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="id885EC68257404983977D9A433BE98803">
              <enum>(b)</enum>
              <header>Waiver
				authority</header>
              <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7000">Secretary of Homeland Security</cato:entity-ref>, acting through the
				<cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7003">Director of U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services</cato:entity-ref>, may waive, on a
				case-by-case basis, applicable requirements for meeting the definition of a
				child under <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
                  <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Immigration and Nationality Act/s:101/ss:b/p:1/sp:E">subparagraph (E)</cato:entity-ref>, <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Immigration and Nationality Act/s:101/ss:b/p:1/sp:F">(F)</cato:entity-ref>, or <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Immigration and Nationality Act/s:101/ss:b/p:1/sp:G">(G) of section 101(b)(1) of the
				Immigration and Nationality Act</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">
                    <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/8/1101/b/1">8 U.S.C. 1101(b)(1)</cato:entity-ref>
                  </external-xref>)</cato:entity>, or regulations issued
				with respect to such definitions, in the interests of justice or to prevent or
				respond to the threat of grave physical or emotional harm to the child if the
				petitioner establishes that—</text>
              <paragraph id="idEC3D981D566940EA93414582C1A6763C">
                <enum>(1)</enum>
                <text>the child
				substantially complies with the requirements under one of such subparagraphs;
				and</text>
              </paragraph>
              <paragraph id="idBAEF9D5FFF7B4199B297738C2D43CEF6">
                <enum>(2)</enum>
                <text>such a waiver
				would be in the child’s best
				interests.</text>
              </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
          </quoted-block>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="id35c491901f1847379e72f1e265abef7a">
          <enum>(g)</enum>
          <header>Determination
			 of applicability of the Hague Adoption Convention in certain
			 cases</header>
          <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7000">Secretary of Homeland Security</cato:entity-ref>, acting through the
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7003">Director of U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services</cato:entity-ref>, may determine, on a
			 case-by-case basis, that a specific intercountry adoption case may proceed as a
			 non-Convention adoption if—</text>
          <paragraph id="id301bfc324fa2432aa9cb9bb3480bb143">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <text>the child’s
			 country of origin or habitual residence is a Convention country;</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="id7f7e5fbff54b4cafb6d15aecee847bc9">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <text>the central
			 authority of the child’s country of origin or habitual residence has issued, or
			 will issue, an adoption decree which that country considers to be legal and
			 valid under that country’s laws to the United States adoptive or prospective
			 adoptive parents; and</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="id5610ea680f104faeb9a96ce2ee1da97b">
            <enum>(3)</enum>
            <text>the central
			 authority of the child’s country of origin or habitual residence has informed
			 the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7000">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> or the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7003">Director</cato:entity-ref> that it does not consider the specific case to
			 fall within the scope of the Hague Adoption Convention.</text>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="iddf7a9240f95e4b5786bf4bcfd0c8c335">
          <enum>(h)</enum>
          <header>Special use of
			 parole authority</header>
          <paragraph id="idda912ccedd574f0caa31aea394eae38d">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <header>In
			 general</header>
            <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7000">Secretary of Homeland Security</cato:entity-ref>, acting through the
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7003">Director of U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services</cato:entity-ref>, may grant parole to a
			 child if the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7000">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> or the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7003">Director</cato:entity-ref> determines that—</text>
            <subparagraph id="idc0ed2aa83e38404a92135fb3b8893331">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>the child’s
			 circumstances indicate that immediate unification with the parties seeking
			 parole is in the child’s best interests;</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="id0A3ADE967FE443E081A00F8011888DB6">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>waiting to
			 complete other, more time consuming immigration processing could be
			 significantly harmful to the child’s well-being;</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="id44d8017d540744eca00d18a30d2021c3">
              <enum>(C)</enum>
              <text>the party or
			 parties seeking parole on behalf of the child—</text>
              <clause id="idC381FE7EFBA14EFDB319ECB1C8F10861">
                <enum>(i)</enum>
                <text>have a
			 pre-existing legal relationship with the child, as evidenced by an adoption
			 decree or a custody order; or</text>
              </clause>
              <clause id="idDE7EAF59E6C54C6183B78D34BC952512">
                <enum>(ii)</enum>
                <text>demonstrate a
			 pre-existing relationship with the child and an intent to establish a legal
			 relationship with the child, which may be evidenced by—</text>
                <subclause id="id0f33bffe759a4868b4bddabdb8f7f6ce">
                  <enum>(I)</enum>
                  <text>a familial
			 relationship with the child;</text>
                </subclause>
                <subclause id="id129b984f0de840bd8f322b92df77ae9c">
                  <enum>(II)</enum>
                  <text>a close personal
			 relationship with the child, such as—</text>
                  <item id="id4C165570BD2341C589169CE8CE4DD032">
                    <enum>(aa)</enum>
                    <text>being matched
			 with the child for an international adoption by an adoption service provider or
			 the competent authority of the child’s country of origin; or</text>
                  </item>
                  <item id="id2FC8DD9520324CCABD61943E3582BD30">
                    <enum>(bb)</enum>
                    <text>documentation
			 showing that the child’s parents, if deceased or otherwise incapacitated and
			 unable to provide proper care for the child, intended for the parties seeking
			 parole to take custody of the child; or</text>
                  </item>
                </subclause>
                <subclause id="id567e36db8aad4061868f328c289ea210">
                  <enum>(III)</enum>
                  <text>the filing of
			 adoption-related applications or petitions related to the adoption of the
			 child; and</text>
                </subclause>
              </clause>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="ida4f693745327457faef3bddc4bce3c38">
              <enum>(D)</enum>
              <text>the child will
			 receive proper care in the United States by the party or parties who seek
			 parole on behalf of the child, based on a review of the suitability of the
			 party or parties, which may include background check or completion of a home
			 study conducted by a competent authority.</text>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="ideafb5e0803d843579d743026a7e919d0">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <header>Meeting the
			 2-year periods for the purposes of filing an immediate relative petition on
			 behalf of an adopted child</header>
            <text>If a child is granted parole under
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Children in Families First Act of 2013/s:104/ss:h/p:1" proposed="true">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref>, is subsequently adopted by the parties who sought parole, and
			 such parties seek permanent immigration status for the child under <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Immigration and Nationality Act/s:101/ss:b/p:1/sp:E">section
			 101(b)(1)(E) of the Immigration and Nationality Act</cato:entity-ref> (<cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/8/1101/b/1/E">8 U.S.C.
			 1101(b)(1)(E)</cato:entity-ref>)</cato:entity>—</text>
            <subparagraph id="id1f3a278791fb46fc852f93ab5c8da3c1">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>the 2-year period
			 for legal custody of the child shall begin to accrue on the effective date of a
			 grant of custody in the child’s country of origin or habitual residence or in
			 the United States;</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="id3c9584e59d214691a1656058fd14a650">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>the 2-year period
			 for physical custody of the child shall begin to accrue on the date on which
			 the party or parties seeking parole for the child begin joint residence with
			 the child, in the child’s country of origin or habitual residence or in the
			 United States; and</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="id90c5aa4e208541fb8ede54dd6333bd1f">
              <enum>(C)</enum>
              <text>the 2-year
			 periods of joint residence and legal custody may accrue within or outside the
			 United States.</text>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0EC9B9878B35404DAF2F76E794395AD2">
          <enum>(i)</enum>
          <header>Rulemaking</header>
          <text>The
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7000">Secretary of Homeland Security</cato:entity-ref>, in consultation with the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref> and
			 the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7003">Director of U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services</cato:entity-ref>, shall issue
			 regulations to carry out this section and the amendments made by this
			 section.</text>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </title>
    <title id="idB3BD7FF5F90744A888012A98DD261E81">
      <enum>II</enum>
      <header>Annual
			 reporting</header>
      <section id="idfc32de0c78514a8788f1a2337f0f101e">
        <enum>201.</enum>
        <header>Annual report
			 on children living without families</header>
        <subsection id="ide52a92efa6404550806f071d64d15a10">
          <enum>(a)</enum>
          <header>In
			 general</header>
          <text>Not later than September 30, 2014, and annually
			 thereafter, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref>, in consultation with the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7200">Director of the
			 United States Agency for International Development</cato:entity-ref> and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref>,
			 shall submit a report to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">
              <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="committee" entity-id="SSFR00">Committee on
			 Foreign Relations of the Senate</cato:entity-ref>
            </committee-name> and the
			 <committee-name committee-id="">
              <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="committee" entity-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of
			 Representatives</cato:entity-ref>
            </committee-name> that—</text>
          <paragraph id="id061DC8E1B4D1490A8AD6A14516069CE6">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <text>identifies the
			 number of children living without families; and</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="idC6EABA17C4754354A1F0C15EC295A02E">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <text>describes the
			 degree to which the various family permanence solutions are being
			 utilized.</text>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="ide119dd0530cd45e1aeb1247db46e6f06">
          <enum>(b)</enum>
          <header>Content</header>
          <text>The
			 report required under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Children in Families First Act of 2013/s:201/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref> shall include—</text>
          <paragraph id="id9c186fb44e894f42bd0f129e31eab63b">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <text>a description of
			 the world’s unparented children, including—</text>
            <subparagraph id="id265c7dbbf274412f805b4d840a63329c">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>a description and
			 quantitative analysis of the world’s unparented children by country,
			 identifying the nationality of the children physically present in each country
			 and distinguishing among children who are citizens of the country, noncitizen
			 children lawfully present in the country, and noncitizen children unlawfully in
			 the country, irrespective of a child’s particular immigration status;</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="idb201381ba97e43779fbbffb233d91837">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>available data
			 about such children broken into detailed categories and including—</text>
              <clause id="id0ca69d2ad330418e873994c653a61a3b">
                <enum>(i)</enum>
                <text>information on
			 their nationality, age, gender, and status;</text>
              </clause>
              <clause id="idfb13f44ff91445e1920f8d6c2d7db8ac">
                <enum>(ii)</enum>
                <text>whether they
			 have a living parent or parents and the status of those parents;</text>
              </clause>
              <clause id="id86cbe0345e384dae83ea54e8cdcf3c13">
                <enum>(iii)</enum>
                <text>whether the
			 unparented children are considered abandoned, separated, relinquished, or have
			 some other status;</text>
              </clause>
              <clause id="id9ab65964681e4c53989bc6a7713ae7e0">
                <enum>(iv)</enum>
                <text>whether they are
			 institutionalized or homeless;</text>
              </clause>
              <clause id="idf9da7181b6be4800997d4a074bfa6b1c">
                <enum>(v)</enum>
                <text>information on
			 how they are documented, including through birth registries, orphanage
			 registries, United Nations High Commissioner for Refugees registration, or
			 identity cards; and</text>
              </clause>
              <clause id="id6533204527364ff397f0aabc0472c257">
                <enum>(vi)</enum>
                <text>an
			 assessment of their living conditions based on indicators such as crude
			 mortality rate, malnutrition rate, or other similar indicators;</text>
              </clause>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="id5a34ee1d823743889320e9a019e47a44">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <text>a review of the
			 previous fiscal year’s programming in support of appropriate, protective, and
			 permanent family care solutions, including project descriptions for each
			 project by country, goals of each project, amount awarded for each project, and
			 evaluation of outcomes during the fiscal year;</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="idc37f851e2a914afe886771e944875d52">
            <enum>(3)</enum>
            <text>an action plan
			 covering proposed programming and activities for the next fiscal year in
			 support of family permanency solutions, including goals for each country in
			 which programming will occur, proposed allocations of resources by country,
			 types of projects proposed by country, amounts of awards proposed for each
			 project, and desired outcomes for each country;</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="id81aea6d18bb743d0993681311730101a">
            <enum>(4)</enum>
            <text>a review of
			 trends over the last five years, including changes in the numbers and locations
			 of unparented children and the reasons for the changes, such as new refugee
			 arrivals, growing numbers of children abandoned at birth, and decreases in
			 number of children in institutions;</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="id048d22236ac641c29d984c9763f6496f">
            <enum>(5)</enum>
            <text>an overall
			 analysis of highest priority situations of concern for unparented children,
			 including analysis of whether the children are in a location that provides a
			 cooperative environment for assistance programming and intercountry
			 adoptions;</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="id13439a5f35f74346815e84723e0f0667">
            <enum>(6)</enum>
            <text>a description of
			 how intercountry adoption and refugee resettlement for unparented refugee
			 children has played a role in each country over the last 10 years and the
			 current status of such programs, including analysis of the situation with
			 respect to the Hague Adoption Convention and how the Convention has affected
			 intercountry adoptions from the country;</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="idd6107b991efc43d5a1a7fa70270482e8">
            <enum>(7)</enum>
            <text>aggregate
			 reporting on intercountry adoptions to the United States, distinguishing
			 between Convention adoptions and non-Convention adoptions and including—</text>
            <subparagraph id="ida0cfeb709244408daf61ee4a6e457b42">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>the total number
			 of intercountry adoptions involving immigration to the United States by year
			 over the past 10 years and projected data for the next fiscal year,
			 distinguishing between Convention and non-Convention adoptions, including
			 aggregate data on the country from which each child emigrated, the State of
			 residence of the adoptive parents, and the country in which the adoption was
			 finalized;</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="idcfd55c06eec247a58c2e8092f0816df5">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>the number of
			 intercountry adoptions involving emigration from the United States, regardless
			 of whether the adoption occurred under the Convention and distinguishing
			 between Convention and non-Convention adoptions, including the country to which
			 each child immigrated and the State from which each child emigrated;</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="id86d64703101b40a5ab563ac06a9b7f55">
              <enum>(C)</enum>
              <text>the average time
			 required for completion of the immigration portion of intercountry adoptions,
			 distinguishing between Convention and non-Convention adoptions, calculated as
			 the time between filing of the initial immigration-related adoption petition on
			 behalf of a child and the approval of that child’s immigrant visa; and</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="ide922734b5b584ad6a70b0ac087a7edf0">
              <enum>(D)</enum>
              <text>the range of
			 adoption fees charged in connection with intercountry adoptions involving
			 immigration to the United States and the median of such fees; and</text>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="idb592c2ddf9364e739c1dd5b5123da739">
            <enum>(8)</enum>
            <text>such additional
			 information as may be requested by members of the
			 <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">
                <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="committee" entity-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations of the
			 Senate</cato:entity-ref>
              </committee-name> and the <committee-name committee-id="">
                <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="committee" entity-id="HFA00">Committee on
			 Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives</cato:entity-ref>
              </committee-name>.</text>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="id3c8495fdf859443ab1192bc6385d90b3">
          <enum>(c)</enum>
          <header>Consultations</header>
          <text>To
			 the extent possible, designated representatives of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> should meet
			 with members of the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">
              <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="committee" entity-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign
			 Relations of the Senate</cato:entity-ref>
            </committee-name> and the
			 <committee-name committee-id="">
              <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="committee" entity-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of
			 Representatives</cato:entity-ref>
            </committee-name> not later than 2 weeks before the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Secretary of
			 State</cato:entity-ref> submits the report required under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Children in Families First Act of 2013/s:201/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref> to discuss the
			 information described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Children in Families First Act of 2013/s:201/ss:b" proposed="true">subsection (b)</cato:entity-ref>. The substance of such consultations
			 should be printed in the Congressional Record.</text>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="id9C44D5D52F794065BD59A7B2185ECC84">
          <enum>(d)</enum>
          <header>Repeal</header>
          <text>
            <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Intercountry Adoption Act/s:104">Section
			 104 of the Intercountry Adoption Act</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/14914">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/42/14914">42 U.S.C. 14914</cato:entity-ref>
              </external-xref>)</cato:entity> is repealed.</text>
        </subsection>
      </section>
      <section id="id9E7FEFD27CE248EFBEB1536E2AD39AD6">
        <enum>202.</enum>
        <header>Country
			 reports regarding severe forms of trafficking</header>
        <text display-inline="no-display-inline">
          <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Foreign Assistance Act of 1961/s:502B/ss:h/p:1/sp:B">Section 502B(h)(1)(B) of the Foreign
			 Assistance Act of 1961</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2304">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/22/2304/h/1/B">22 U.S.C. 2304(h)(1)(B)</cato:entity-ref>
            </external-xref>)</cato:entity> is amended by adding at the
			 end the following:</text>
        <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7C594BDEE3514214BCFF65E938EE84A0" style="OLC">
          <clause id="id52b00351b0b747baad555c60e90a9c22" indent="up1">
            <enum>(x)</enum>
            <text>What steps the government of that
				country has taken to reduce the number of children living outside of family
				care.</text>
          </clause>
          <clause id="id810841c03a174a18ba658aac380c2ad9" indent="up1">
            <enum>(xi)</enum>
            <text>What steps the government of that
				country has taken to reduce the number of children abused, neglected, or
				exploited.</text>
          </clause>
          <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
        </quoted-block>
      </section>
    </title>
    <title id="id2C39851689E24499AA3F05BF4FC91E63">
      <enum>III</enum>
      <header>Promotion of a
			 comprehensive approach for children in adversity</header>
      <section id="id5C3F67EFFF104358A542756AFE65A703">
        <enum>301.</enum>
        <header>Establishment
			 of a USAID Center for Excellence for Children in Adversity</header>
        <subsection id="id1102dfa79c6e4e0283568f31d4afb874">
          <enum>(a)</enum>
          <header>Center for
			 Excellence for Children in Adversity</header>
          <paragraph id="id40592f463d9a4a378c4877783b02f7a6">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <header>In
			 general</header>
            <text>There is established within the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7200">United States Agency for
			 International Development</cato:entity-ref> a <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Center of Excellence on Children in Adversity" entity-parent-id="7200" proposed="true">Center of Excellence on Children in
			 Adversity</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="id2dae54cab2a0460080f05748c629ce07">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <header>Coordinator</header>
            <text>The
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Center of Excellence on Children in Adversity" entity-parent-id="7200" proposed="true">Center for Excellence</cato:entity-ref> shall be headed by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Children in Adversity Coordinator" entity-parent-id="7200" proposed="true">Children in Adversity Coordinator</cato:entity-ref>,
			 who shall be appointed by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref>, in consultation with the
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7200">Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="id1dd7570e4fa0420f959f8aa1412ecd3f">
            <enum>(3)</enum>
            <header>Objectives</header>
            <text>The
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Center of Excellence on Children in Adversity" entity-parent-id="7200" proposed="true">Center of Excellence on Children in Adversity</cato:entity-ref> shall work in consultation with
			 the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Bureau of Vulnerable Children and Family Security" entity-parent-id="1900" proposed="true">Assistant Secretary of the Bureau of Vulnerable Children and Family
			 Security</cato:entity-ref> of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Department of State</cato:entity-ref> to promote greater United States Government
			 coherence and accountability for whole-of-government assistance to children in
			 adversity and ensure that United States foreign assistance and development
			 programs are focused on the following objectives:</text>
            <subparagraph id="idad4d84b42c814757a3ac0b2e6f607e0f">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>The sound
			 development of children through the integration of health, nutrition, and
			 family support.</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="id7a46236e65ba470f998660f25ad27749">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>Supporting and
			 enabling families to care for children through family preservation,
			 reunification, and support of kinship care, guardianship, and domestic and
			 intercountry adoption.</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="idc2ee52cedb354c66804ad326f6e493a6">
              <enum>(C)</enum>
              <text>Facilitating the
			 efforts of national governments and partners to prevent, respond to, and
			 protect children from violence, exploitation, abuse, and neglect.</text>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="id4fae951f3dc24b03b84c9c3cc7fa73c8">
            <enum>(4)</enum>
            <header>Authorities</header>
            <text>The
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Children in Adversity Coordinator" entity-parent-id="7200" proposed="true">Children in Adversity Coordinator</cato:entity-ref>, acting through nongovernmental organizations
			 (including faith-based and community-based organizations), partner country
			 finance, health, education, social welfare, and other ministries, and relevant
			 executive branch agencies, is authorized to—</text>
            <subparagraph id="ida9ac085571d94f4ebff7843c3d26e165">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>operate
			 internationally to carry out the programs and activities outlined in the Action
			 Plan for Children in Adversity;</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="id455302f5581545eabb055e52cb4c007f">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>provide grants
			 to, and enter into contracts and cooperative agreements with, nongovernmental
			 organizations (including faith-based organizations) to carry out this section;
			 and</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="id7c87f4d54cd146449f028d3ff1a37d74">
              <enum>(C)</enum>
              <text>transfer and
			 allocate <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7200">United States Agency for International Development</cato:entity-ref> funds that have
			 been appropriated for the purposes described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Children in Families First Act of 2013/s:301/ss:a/p:4/sp:A" proposed="true">subparagraphs (A)</cato:entity-ref> and
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Children in Families First Act of 2013/s:301/ss:a/p:4/sp:B" proposed="true">(B)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="idab9fb19f08d647f389dc0a5c81474253">
            <enum>(5)</enum>
            <header>Functions</header>
            <text>In
			 consultation with the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Assistant Secretary of the Bureau of Children's Affairs" entity-parent-id="1900">Assistant Secretary of the Bureau of Children's Affairs</cato:entity-ref> in
			 the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Department of State</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Children in Adversity Coordinator" entity-parent-id="7200" proposed="true">Children in Adversity Coordinator</cato:entity-ref> shall, through
			 the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Center of Excellence on Children in Adversity" entity-parent-id="7200" proposed="true">Center of Excellence</cato:entity-ref>—</text>
            <subparagraph id="id0ca721bc3b244a789a94a094afac55ad">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>facilitate
			 program and policy coordination related to the goals and objectives of the
			 Action Plan for Children in Adversity among relevant executive branch agencies
			 and nongovernmental organizations by auditing, monitoring, and evaluating such
			 programs;</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="id97c96ca1835749ca83817d66529007be">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>ensure that each
			 relevant executive branch agency undertakes responsibility for activities
			 related primarily to those areas in which the agency has the greatest
			 expertise, technical capability, and potential for success;</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="id722baf1e1b8a412a8ba1fa8b65efad2e">
              <enum>(C)</enum>
              <text>coordinate
			 relevant executive branch agency activities related to the Action Plan for
			 Children in Adversity;</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="id62a2a2f45bc74cb68430de9e76041577">
              <enum>(D)</enum>
              <text>establish due
			 diligence criteria for all recipients of funds appropriated by the United
			 States Government for assistance to children in adversity; and</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="idedf3f57a13c749d3bd733a7ecd9d6af0">
              <enum>(E)</enum>
              <text>oversee the
			 administration of the priority country demonstration program as described in
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Children in Families First Act of 2013/s:301/ss:f" proposed="true">subsection (f)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="id96c57581bf96425eab4f9319e62c21e2">
            <enum>(6)</enum>
            <header>Assistance</header>
            <text>The
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> is authorized to provide assistance, including through international,
			 nongovernmental, or faith-based organizations, for programs in developing
			 countries—</text>
            <subparagraph id="id29df2e0601524421ab2705aa63ed805d">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>to increase the
			 percentage of children achieving age-appropriate growth and developmental
			 milestones;</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="id885448db2e7a43e4afaa181cdbc6289f">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>to increase the
			 percentage of children under 5 years of age demonstrating secure attachment
			 with a primary caregiver;</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="id2675a6544f9446fd8461ff9d49a7eb2b">
              <enum>(C)</enum>
              <text>to integrate
			 health, nutrition, developmental protections, and caregiving support for
			 vulnerable children and their families;</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="idd0c8f7bad6134be9a8869ada17fae293">
              <enum>(D)</enum>
              <text>to increase the
			 percentage of children living within appropriate, permanent, safe, and
			 protective family care, through family preservation and reunification, and
			 through kinship care, guardianship, and domestic and intercountry adoption, and
			 to reduce the percentage of children living in institutions;</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="id0bcda7247d59447f83f5b8484e8efc65">
              <enum>(E)</enum>
              <text>to increase the
			 percentage of families providing adequate nutrition, education opportunities,
			 care, and protection for their children;</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="ide6a9d31c660f4465a61f1aa1ce0f4abb">
              <enum>(F)</enum>
              <text>to reduce the
			 percentage of children who experience violence, exploitation, abuse, and
			 neglect;</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="ide889d41810c949a18f727e5acfa68630">
              <enum>(G)</enum>
              <text>to increase the
			 percentage of children who receive appropriate care and protection after
			 experiencing violence, exploitation, abuse, or neglect;</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="iddbeeefe43f0942f897eda6967090f35e">
              <enum>(H)</enum>
              <text>to increase
			 public awareness that violence, exploitation, abuse, or neglect of children as
			 unacceptable;</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="ide4f00e7e78854beaa362cda023e14bd8">
              <enum>(I)</enum>
              <text>to increase the
			 percentage of countries that ratify and implement relevant conventions or
			 formally adopt internationally recognized principles, standards, and procedural
			 safeguards to protect children from violence, exploitation, abuse, and
			 neglect;</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="id0dacb34ffb3845219c4b0c5d6356cd2c">
              <enum>(J)</enum>
              <text>to increase the
			 percentage of children who have legal documentation and birth
			 registration;</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="id93dec51adb38455589f5a0909349f680">
              <enum>(K)</enum>
              <text>to increase the
			 number of laws, policies, and practices in partner states that promote and
			 strengthen child welfare and protection at household, community, and national
			 levels is increased;</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="id876bdae53b7a4de089d9b85db514c557">
              <enum>(L)</enum>
              <text>to increase
			 national and local human resource capacity for child welfare and
			 protection;</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="id0dfef6b85996468083ea7f026de406fd">
              <enum>(M)</enum>
              <text>to increase the
			 number of national and community systems effectively monitoring child welfare
			 and protection concerns, programs, and outcomes;</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="idb92db3d57129448ea5897ce781f0f523">
              <enum>(N)</enum>
              <text>to encourage and
			 assist in the collection of data related to children outside of family
			 care;</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="id610cfd1a52c64ecdb0b455571b3d7de9">
              <enum>(O)</enum>
              <text>to increase the
			 number of prevalence studies that measure and track trends in children’s
			 exposure to violence, exploitation, abuse, and neglect;</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="id5b3a80fc53204e54b60132184c2bc2b9">
              <enum>(P)</enum>
              <text>to increase the
			 number of published outcome/impact evaluations on interventions to assist
			 children outside of family care or minimize exposure to violence, exploitation,
			 abuse, and neglect that can be generalized to larger target groups;</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="id02ac957ed81e48338b7c1d2e0aa453a9">
              <enum>(Q)</enum>
              <text>to increase the
			 number of national governments and universities leading rigorous data
			 collection, research, and monitoring and evaluation studies related to child
			 welfare and protection; and</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="idf16a5778584e4b8e821edc4041d33b50">
              <enum>(R)</enum>
              <text>to increase the
			 number of United States Government-supported interventions for children in
			 adversity designed using data from rigorous research methodologies.</text>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="idddc21420b3e6476d8facd1b96f9a6790">
          <enum>(b)</enum>
          <header>Monitoring and
			 evaluation</header>
          <paragraph id="id52ddd7cb4691492b99334e8ea6feedc3">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <header>Establishment
			 of system</header>
            <text>To maximize the sustainable development impact of
			 assistance authorized under this section, and pursuant to the primary objective
			 of the Action Plan for Children in Adversity, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> shall establish a
			 monitoring and evaluation system to measure the effectiveness of United States
			 assistance to children in adversity.</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="id60ba80921a934fadadc44a4d0c842c43">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <header>Requirements</header>
            <text>The
			 monitoring and evaluation system shall—</text>
            <subparagraph id="id082279ae18ce425d93944d014056d701">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>be aligned with
			 the objectives and outcomes outlined by the Action Plan for Children in
			 Adversity; and</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="id3252adb0b36648dbb830a3b19b4fe3b9">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>provide a basis
			 for recommendations for adjustments to the assistance provided under this
			 part.</text>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="idd00ec1f2ea3a4466a1158652131d31ab">
          <enum>(c)</enum>
          <header>Priority
			 Country Demonstration Program</header>
          <paragraph id="idc4d4779c24e04047a74d6b4ed972a9ff">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <header>In
			 general</header>
            <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7200">Administrator of the United States Agency for
			 International Development</cato:entity-ref>, in consultation with the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref>, shall
			 establish and carry out a priority country demonstration program implementing
			 the Action Plan for Children in Adversity over a period of 5 years in at least
			 6 countries.</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="idf7aaed8cd0f44fbe8f8d829e7a9b1ea2">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <header>Purposes</header>
            <text>The
			 purposes of the programs established under sub<cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Children in Families First Act of 2013/s:301/ss:c/p:1" proposed="true">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref> shall be—</text>
            <subparagraph id="idc734870e6b7349b3bbe30aab12585b79">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>to demonstrate
			 how research-based policies and programs to achieve the core objectives of the
			 Action Plan for Children in Adversity can be successfully implemented on a
			 national level;</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="id42e16feae8b94e9cac561052944b4aaa">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>to establish
			 model programs that, once tested for efficacy, will be available for
			 replication on a global basis;</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="id09faf35adf3d4e9ebcd740010e20c6f9">
              <enum>(C)</enum>
              <text>to identify a
			 comprehensive series of interventions which result in meeting the outcomes and
			 objectives of the Action Plan for Children in Adversity; and</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="id3a3aba32181a45bea8c67a94c6ea5c8b">
              <enum>(D)</enum>
              <text>to determine
			 which in-country factors advance or negate the successful achievement of the
			 outcomes and objectives of the action plan.</text>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="idf31f5979146f4447a098d51ba34bec5a">
            <enum>(3)</enum>
            <header>Criteria for
			 selection of countries</header>
            <text>The criteria for selection of countries
			 shall include—</text>
            <subparagraph id="idd033b4cc6585476da85cfe75e490eb5a">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>magnitude and
			 severity of the problems to be addressed;</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="id022c9467ce7943efb7a1abd317c9975c">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>partner country
			 interest in participation in a comprehensive implementation of all 3 goals of
			 the Action Plan for Children in Adversity, including, with respect to the
			 second objective (Families First), expressed willingness to support the full
			 complement of permanence solutions (including family preservation,
			 reunification, kinship care, guardianship, and domestic and intercountry
			 adoption), and commitments to support and allow monitoring and evaluation, as
			 well as transparent reporting;</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="id30c47d1681b14aab8e8f54254e461289">
              <enum>(C)</enum>
              <text>potential to
			 leverage bilateral, multilateral, and foundation investments;</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="idc49a8d0e25cc44f1b40da1a431e9489c">
              <enum>(D)</enum>
              <text>potential to
			 leverage other United States development investments;</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="idc1c07f37283c48428bc7f02975074d94">
              <enum>(E)</enum>
              <text>regional
			 diversity to maximize learning opportunities; and</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="id6cdbe0559e0243b7aec666e3d76e8969">
              <enum>(F)</enum>
              <text>level of economic
			 development, with a focus on low- and middle-income countries.</text>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="id8A6A6DD3F05845DC856BD0680EE2B0F4">
          <enum>(d)</enum>
          <header>Repeals</header>
          <paragraph id="idA2E32FCBA0FD4B44BC46B9C606A15E9E">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <header>Assistance to
			 orphans and other vulnerable children</header>
            <text>
              <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Foreign Assistance Act of 1961/s:135">Section 135 of the Foreign
			 Assistance Act of 1961</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2152f">
                  <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/22/2152f">22 U.S.C. 2152f</cato:entity-ref>
                </external-xref>)</cato:entity> is repealed.</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="idC3B2B7F67625483FB25417D082BC86E6">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <header>Annual
			 report</header>
            <text>
              <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Assistance for Orphans and Other Vulnerable Children in Developing Countries Act of 2005/s:5">Section 5 of the Assistance for Orphans and Other
			 Vulnerable Children in Developing Countries Act of 2005</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2152g">
                  <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/22/2152g">22 U.S.C. 2152g</cato:entity-ref>
                </external-xref>)</cato:entity> is
			 hereby repealed.</text>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </title>
    <title id="idCF03F2474E794FF197467FBAB3A3FC8F">
      <enum>IV</enum>
      <header>Funding and effective dates</header>
      <section id="id0B79761145C94CE59E6FBB16C6F98990">
        <enum>401.</enum>
        <header>Authorization
			 of appropriations</header>
        <subsection id="idfa61c10c5a734d6ba644bd8692958c29">
          <enum>(a)</enum>
          <header>Realignment of
			 certain international child welfare responsibilities and functions</header>
          <paragraph id="id902783173655472CA3AFE66A613040CF">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <header>In general</header>
            <text>
              <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="auth-auth-approp">Subject to <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Children in Families First Act of 2013/s:401/ss:c" proposed="true">subsection (c)</cato:entity-ref>, there are authorized to be appropriated <cato:funds-and-year amount="30000000" year="2014..2018">$30,000,000 for each of the fiscal years 2014 through 2018</cato:funds-and-year> <cato:property name="purpose">to carry out <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Children in Families First Act of 2013/t:I" proposed="true">title I</cato:entity-ref>
                </cato:property>.</cato:entity>
            </text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="id0978DDC6754A45909DE7DC680C403FE9">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <header>Availability of funds</header>
            <text>Amounts appropriated pursuant to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Children in Families First Act of 2013/s:401/ss:a/p:1" proposed="true">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref> shall remain available until
			 expended.</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="idC1C025B9358B44E7BC0B6D784C6D2E78">
            <enum>(3)</enum>
            <header>Use of
			 funds</header>
            <text>Amounts appropriated pursuant to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Children in Families First Act of 2013/s:401/ss:a/p:1" proposed="true">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref> may be
			 used—</text>
            <subparagraph id="id73ABB85FAED84C2ABBDAF16FB585ECDC">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <text>to carry out <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Children in Families First Act of 2013/t:I" proposed="true">title I</cato:entity-ref>; and</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idB341DAE1058F4560B0C3A3728D49CBAC">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <text>for contributions
			 to the activities of international organizations, nongovernmental
			 organizations, and faith-based organizations for assistance to or on behalf of
			 children in adversity who are outside the United States.</text>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="id17031a27ace9492ab4278bf31cff64ee">
          <enum>(b)</enum>
          <header>Center for
			 Excellence for Children in Adversity</header>
          <text>
            <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="auth-auth-approp">Subject to <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Children in Families First Act of 2013/s:401/ss:c" proposed="true">subsection (c)</cato:entity-ref>, there are authorized to be appropriated to the
			 <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7200">Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development</cato:entity-ref> <cato:funds-and-year amount="30000000" year="2014..2018">$30,000,000 for each of the fiscal years 2014 through 2018</cato:funds-and-year> <cato:property name="purpose">to carry out <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Children in Families First Act of 2013/s:301" proposed="true">section 301</cato:entity-ref>
              </cato:property>.</cato:entity>
          </text>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="id6576178a2edf4b80b4c3dc4344dbcb4d">
          <enum>(c)</enum>
          <header>Limitations on use of funds</header>
          <text>None of the amounts appropriated pursuant to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Children in Families First Act of 2013/s:401/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref> or <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Children in Families First Act of 2013/s:401/ss:b" proposed="true">(b)</cato:entity-ref> may be awarded to the United Nations or any of its subsidiaries. Not more than 2 percent of such amounts may be used for administrative expenses.</text>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="id876FAAB8E6224DC78E98B197D55943C2">
          <enum>(d)</enum>
          <header>Availability of
			 other funds</header>
          <text>Unobligated balances of funds made available to carry
			 out activities under the <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Foreign Assistance Act of 1961">Foreign Assistance Act of 1961</cato:entity-ref> (<cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/22/2151/etseq">22 U.S.C. 2151 et
			 seq.</cato:entity-ref>)</cato:entity>—</text>
          <paragraph id="id707E51A1D1294174A27A1360861614C2">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <text>may be made
			 available for the purposes set forth in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Children in Families First Act of 2013/s:401/ss:a/p:2" proposed="true">subsection (a)(2)</cato:entity-ref>; and</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="id859B88AFA97D43C2B13A00C87FE2C139">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <text>may be
			 consolidated with appropriations appropriated pursuant to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Children in Families First Act of 2013/s:401/ss:a/p:1" proposed="true">subsection
			 (a)(1)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="idb107a10fc98648d38e9cb05ca7f296e2">
          <enum>(e)</enum>
          <header>Focus of
			 assistance</header>
          <text>Assistance provided under this Act—</text>
          <paragraph id="idAABB6102CA1E4D3C98C0B47E4F46EB5F">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <text>shall focus
			 primarily on promoting international child welfare, as set forth in this Act,
			 for all children in adversity; and</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="idDDC878492AFA43EAA7A98AB67B04750B">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <text>may be provided
			 on such terms and conditions as the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> determines appropriate.</text>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
      </section>
      <section id="idAA01F188A054418891CB55021ADD0B88">
        <enum>402.</enum>
        <header>Effective dates</header>
        <subsection id="id265B224E5E92454EB2288256C5894186">
          <enum>(a)</enum>
          <header>Effective upon enactment</header>
          <text>
            <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Children in Families First Act of 2013/s:104" proposed="true">Sections 104</cato:entity-ref> and <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Children in Families First Act of 2013/s:202" proposed="true">202</cato:entity-ref> and <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Children in Families First Act of 2013/t:III" proposed="true">title III</cato:entity-ref> and <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Children in Families First Act of 2013/t:IV" proposed="true">IV</cato:entity-ref> shall take effect on the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="id62AA6533041640CA82C57C5FDAAB0E27">
          <enum>(b)</enum>
          <header>Delayed effective date</header>
          <text>
            <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Children in Families First Act of 2013/s:101" proposed="true">Sections 101</cato:entity-ref>, <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Children in Families First Act of 2013/s:102" proposed="true">102</cato:entity-ref>, <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Children in Families First Act of 2013/s:103" proposed="true">103</cato:entity-ref>, and <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Children in Families First Act of 2013/s:201" proposed="true">201</cato:entity-ref> shall take effect on the date that is 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </title>
  </legis-body>
</bill>
</doc>