<doc>
  <docmeta id="113s2472is">
    <bill congress="113" type="s" number="2472" version="is"/>
    <revision size="21647" annotations="0" status="complete" id="7" commit-time="2014-07-02T23:20:59Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113s2472is/7.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public">
	<metadata>
<dublinCore>
<dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">113 S2472 IS: International Human Rights Defense Act of 2014</dc:title>
<dc:publisher xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">2014-06-12</dc:date>
<dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
		<congress>113th CONGRESS</congress>
    <session>2d Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. 2472</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20140612">June 12, 2014</action-date>
			<action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="S369">Mr. Markey</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S270">Mr. Schumer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S229">Mrs. Murray</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S223">Mrs. Boxer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S308">Mr. Cardin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S364">Mr. Murphy</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S354">Ms. Baldwin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S366">Ms. Warren</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S322">Mr. Merkley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S331">Mrs. Gillibrand</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S275">Ms. Cantwell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S341">Mr. Blumenthal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S316">Mr. Whitehouse</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S361">Ms. Hirono</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S253">Mr. Durbin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S307">Mr. Brown</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S057">Mr. Leahy</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S353">Mr. Schatz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S247">Mr. Wyden</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S370">Mr. Booker</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S337">Mr. Coons</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S221">Mrs. Feinstein</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S182">Ms. Mikulski</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S332">Mr. Franken</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S324">Mrs. Shaheen</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations</committee-name>
      </action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To establish in the Bureau of Democracy, Human Rights, and Labor of the Department of State a
			 Special Envoy for the Human Rights of LGBT Peoples.  </official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body>
		<section id="S1" section-type="section-one">
      <enum>1.</enum>
      <header>Short title</header>
			<text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the
		  <quote>
          <short-title>
            <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" proposed="true" value="International Human Rights Defense Act of 2014" entity-type="act">International Human Rights Defense Act of 2014</cato:entity-ref>
          </short-title>
        </quote>.</text>
		</section>
    <section id="id19E82EF74B034CB7A06189FF87891F1C">
      <enum>2.</enum>
      <header>Definitions</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text>
      <paragraph id="idB5241836FB364291A655DCF7FC058AAC">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <header>Appropriate congressional committees</header>
        <text>The term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text>
        <subparagraph id="idC31E495F7B0446FFA18F1DA1FC7AEDFE">
          <enum>(A)</enum>
          <text>the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="SSFR00" entity-type="committee">Committee on Foreign Relations</cato:entity-ref> and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="SSAP00" entity-type="committee">Committee on Appropriations of the Senate</cato:entity-ref>; and</text>
        </subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="idE87E8C80082B4C47866809553AD0BB26">
          <enum>(B)</enum>
          <text>the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="HFA00" entity-type="committee">Committee on Foreign Affairs</cato:entity-ref> and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="HAP00" entity-type="committee">Committee on Appropriations of the House of
			 Representatives</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
        </subparagraph>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id780533ecbb46498ca491193db7dd4f89">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <header>Gender identity</header>
        <text>The term <term>gender identity</term> means the gender-related identity, appearance, or mannerisms or other gender-related
			 characteristics of an individual, with or without regard to the
			 individual’s designated sex at birth.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8664a3e49a464e2cb79ef889572ffc12">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <header>LGBT</header>
        <text>The term <term>LGBT</term> means lesbian, gay, bisexual, or transgender.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id32eb2088e65944fa8b62f8d75ebf5292">
        <enum>(4)</enum>
        <header>Sexual orientation</header>
        <text>The term <term>sexual orientation</term> means homosexuality, heterosexuality, or bisexuality.</text>
      </paragraph>
    </section>
    <section id="idA2057B3EE9204EE28F59DD779CF4A8BE">
      <enum>3.</enum>
      <header>Findings</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">
        <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="0001" entity-type="federal-body">Congress</cato:entity-ref> makes the following findings:</text>
      <paragraph id="idff0f0f9be3f14a6f84ebf22064569e91">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text>Eighty-two countries prohibit the public support of
			 the
			 LGBT community, promote homophobia across society, or criminalize
			 homosexuality. That is equal to
			 more than 40 percent of United Nations Member States.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id300dfb689ee44ff499367c07881e697f">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text>In seven countries, homosexuality is a crime that is punishable by death.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id788016c21d2f49049edf353e25186109">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <text>Around the world, LGBT people face discrimination, hatred, violence, and bigotry.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id01d8955bad9b46398d65e373a4c08c9f">
        <enum>(4)</enum>
        <text>Violence and discrimination based on sexual orientation and gender identity are documented in the
			 Department of State’s annual Human Rights Report to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="0001" entity-type="federal-body">Congress</cato:entity-ref>. The 2013
			 report
			 continues to show a clear pattern of increased human rights violations in
			 every region of the world based on sexual orientation and gender identity.
			 These violations include murder, rape, torture, death threats, extortion,
			 imprisonment, as well as loss of employment, housing, access to health
			 care, and other forms of societal stigma and discrimination. The report
			 further documents growing LGBT-specific restrictions on basic freedoms of
			 assembly, press, and speech in every region of the world.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id5e5b81cc57dc4074b3c44000513e9158">
        <enum>(5)</enum>
        <text>In Jamaica and other countries, discrimination against LGBT people, including <quote>corrective rape</quote> of lesbian women, occurs all too frequently and with relative impunity.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="idee59cd8057014e1bbcab077f30ac6173">
        <enum>(6)</enum>
        <text>In 2013, the Government of the Russian Federation and others in the region	passed laws banning <quote>Homosexual Propaganda</quote>, which effectively makes it a crime to publically support LGBT equality.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id36a9dcff520d416e9934f10eb2b2afbb">
        <enum>(7)</enum>
        <text>In February 2014, the Government of Uganda adopted a law that makes <quote>aggravated homosexuality</quote> a crime
			 punishable with life
			 imprisonment and endangers any individual arbitrarily found to support
			 LGBT people.  Concurrently, the Government of Uganda also passed laws
			 severely limiting the basic freedoms of speech and assembly for LGBT
			 citizens.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="idb71a855680f34018bc19f24941405da4">
        <enum>(8)</enum>
        <text>In December 2013, the Government of Nigeria adopted a law further criminalizing homosexuality. The
			 law also
			 criminalizes
			 supporting LGBT people in any way, endangering the neighbors, friends,
			 doctors, and landlords of LGBT people.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id1863922aaada461bbe62be05c53584a2">
        <enum>(9)</enum>
        <text>The anti-homosexuality laws in Nigeria and Uganda potentially endanger all LGBT individuals in
			 those countries. In addition, international HIV workers could be at risk
			 since the study and treatment of at-risk populations may constitute
			 support
			 for LGBT people.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id1dcca75f36b842ce9457e9077a2fd982">
        <enum>(10)</enum>
        <text>On December 6, 2011, President <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="O000167" entity-type="person">Barack Obama</cato:entity-ref> released the Presidential Memorandum—International
			 Initiatives to Advance the Human Rights of Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual, and
			 Transgender Persons. The memorandum directed all Federal agencies engaged
			 abroad
			 to ensure that United States diplomacy and foreign assistance promote and
			 protect the human rights of LGBT persons.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id7635d1cf6efb4eb39d12eb0891c21e69">
        <enum>(11)</enum>
        <text>
          Secretary of State John Kerry has announced that the United States Government  will review United
			 States diplomatic
			 relationships with Nigeria and Uganda in light of passage of their recent
			 anti-LGBT laws. On
			 March 23, 2014, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1900" entity-type="federal-body">Department of State</cato:entity-ref>  announced that the United States
			 Government
			 would cut $6,400,000 in funding for the Interreligious Council of Uganda
			 because of its support for the Anti-Homosexuality Act, halt a survey
			 designed to minimize the spread of HIV/AIDS because of potential harm to
			 respondents, impose short-term travel bans on Ugandan military
			 officials, and halt some joint military exercises with the
			 military of  Uganda.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id01ace5f8e4524924b34139d040d296b7">
        <enum>(12)</enum>
        <text>In December 2013, the Supreme Court of India reversed a lower court ruling and reinstated the
			 criminalization of homosexuality in the second most populous nation on
			 Earth. In April 2014, India’s Supreme Court recognized transgender people
			 as a third gender, improving the legal rights of transgender people in
			 that country. Given these two court decisions, the degree of human rights
			 protections for LGBT persons in India is uncertain.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id5f17bec512824bd29a061b0b3bdab5b4">
        <enum>(13)</enum>
        <text>Removing institutionalized discrimination and targeted persecution against LGBT people around the
			 world is a
			 critical step in the promotion of human rights and global health
			 internationally.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id66115A87A6ED475F8A0F028424B3B1A4">
        <enum>(14)</enum>
        <text>According to the Trans Murder Monitoring Project, which monitors homicides of transgender
			 individuals, 238 transgender persons were killed between November 2012 and
			 November 2013 worldwide.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id718B33CE69D249D0B8CA9C8B1D2E9BB7">
        <enum>(15)</enum>
        <text>According to the International Guidelines on HIV/AIDS and Human Rights, as published by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-parent-id="19UN" entity-type="federal-body" value="High Commissioner for Human Rights">United
			 Nations High Commissioner for Human Rights</cato:entity-ref>, countries should review and
			 reform criminal laws and correctional systems to ensure that they are
			 consistent with international human rights obligations and are not misused
			 in the context of HIV or targeted against vulnerable groups.</text>
      </paragraph>
    </section>
    <section id="id9E531967A12B4E23A42C1C4754D8D401">
      <enum>4.</enum>
      <header>Statement of policy</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the policy of the United States—</text>
      <paragraph id="id7e78be72db2041f0a24240f0b5656dcf">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text>to take effective action to prevent and respond to discrimination and violence against all people
			 on any basis internationally, including sexual orientation and gender
			 identity, and that
			 human rights policy include attention to hate crimes and other
			 discrimination against LGBT people;</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="idbab720b4fabc47ae983a8d24f961b710">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text>to systematically integrate and coordinate efforts to prevent and respond to discrimination and
			 violence against LGBT people internationally into United States foreign
			 policy;</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="ida3e80172019a472fa66439ed33d28edc">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <text>to support and build local capacity in countries  around the world, including of governments at all
			 levels and nongovernmental organizations, to prevent and respond to
			 discrimination and violence against LGBT people internationally;</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id668799041c944aa2b109ba2cac7810cb">
        <enum>(4)</enum>
        <text>to consult, cooperate, coordinate, and collaborate with a wide variety of nongovernmental partners
			 with demonstrated experience in preventing and responding to
			 discrimination and violence against LGBT people internationally, including
			 faith-based organizations and LGBT-led organizations;</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="idb0feca0a33fd42368ca23140a426e32d">
        <enum>(5)</enum>
        <text>to employ a multisectoral approach to preventing and responding to discrimination and violence
			 against LGBT people internationally, including activities in the
			 economic, education, health, nutrition, legal, and judicial sectors;</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id4aaee8caffde4c17b4502afafbf054ed">
        <enum>(6)</enum>
        <text>to work at all levels, from the individual to the family, community, local, national, and
			 international levels, to prevent and respond to discrimination and
			 violence against LGBT people internationally;</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id0abf85647f794faa91d5ecb9699e93da">
        <enum>(7)</enum>
        <text>to enhance training by United States personnel of professional foreign military and police forces
			 and judicial officials to include appropriate and thorough LGBT-specific 
			 instruction on preventing and responding to discrimination and violence
			 based on sexual orientation and gender identity;</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id5e74f5034ec8434b99654578e3f760a5">
        <enum>(8)</enum>
        <text>to engage non-LGBT people as allies and partners, as an essential element of making sustained
			 reductions in discrimination and violence against LGBT people;</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id8aeeb7103c224ea29e11b0bf92323ccb">
        <enum>(9)</enum>
        <text>to require that all Federal contractors and grant recipients in the United States Government's
			 international programs establish appropriate policies and
			 take effective measures to ensure the protection and safety of their staff
			 and workplace, including from discrimination and violence directed
			 against LGBT people and those who provide services to them;</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id4ed0efb95bc248aaa4b9ba4c473d5ec9">
        <enum>(10)</enum>
        <text>to exert sustained international leadership to prevent and respond to discrimination and violence
			 against LGBT persons, including  in bilateral and multilateral fora;</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="idf07c2993c5ab405a9b6e5af851c0240a">
        <enum>(11)</enum>
        <text>to fully implement and expand upon the policies outlined in the Presidential
			 Memorandum—International Initiatives to Advance the Human Rights of
			 Lesbian, Gay,
			 Bisexual, and Transgender Persons;</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id0d24786306c247e28bc795d9d42b48d8">
        <enum>(12)</enum>
        <text>to ensure that international efforts to combat HIV/AIDS take all appropriate measures to support
			 at-risk communities, including LGBT persons, and to create enabling legal
			 environments for these communities;</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id3AB4626829FD410C945270459B150240">
        <enum>(13)</enum>
        <text>to work with governments and nongovernmental partners around the world to develop and implement
			 regional strategies to decriminalize homosexuality and to counteract the
			 prohibition of public support of the LGBT community; and</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="idDDFE4BEBFB4B40BC89A280C003D934F3">
        <enum>(14)</enum>
        <text>to ensure that those who have a well-founded fear of persecution on account of being LGBT or
			 supporting LGBT rights have the opportunity to seek protection in the
			 United States.</text>
      </paragraph>
    </section>
    <section id="id0ab70893513042a59bc20954ff818a7b">
      <enum>5.</enum>
      <header>Special Envoy for the human rights of LGBT people</header>
      <subsection id="id43972ff892bf45dabbccafd389533bb3">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Establishment</header>
        <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1900" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref> shall establish in the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1936">Bureau of Democracy, Human Rights, and Labor (DRL) of
			 the Department of State</cato:entity-ref> a <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" value="Special Envoy for the Human Rights of LGBT Peoples" entity-parent-id="1936" proposed="true" entity-type="federal-body">Special Envoy for the Human Rights of LGBT
			 Peoples</cato:entity-ref> (in this section referred to as the <quote>
            <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" proposed="true" entity-parent-id="1936" value="Special Envoy for the Human Rights of LGBT Peoples" entity-type="federal-body">Special Envoy</cato:entity-ref>
          </quote>), who shall be appointed by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1100" entity-type="federal-body">President</cato:entity-ref>.  The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Special Envoy for the Human Rights of LGBT Peoples" entity-parent-id="1936" proposed="true">Special Envoy</cato:entity-ref> shall report directly to the
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1936">Assistant Secretary for DRL</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="id60e5ab46e3ab438a8672a953db2cc8d7">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Purpose</header>
        <text>In addition to the duties described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" proposed="true" value="International Human Rights Defense Act of 2014/s:5/ss:c" entity-type="act">subsection (c)</cato:entity-ref> and those duties determined by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1900" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary
			 of State</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Special Envoy for the Human Rights of LGBT Peoples" entity-parent-id="1936" proposed="true">Special Envoy</cato:entity-ref> shall direct efforts of the United States
			 Government as directed by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> regarding human rights abuses
			 against the LGBT community internationally and the advancement of human
			 rights for LGBT people in United States foreign policy, and shall
			 represent
			 the United States internationally in bilateral and multilateral engagement
			 on these matters.</text>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="id2a052437d43a4825bc3912a444a2d8c6">
        <enum>(c)</enum>
        <header>Duties</header>
        <paragraph id="id82b84600df2843eba27a4517a5863ceb">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>In general</header>
          <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Special Envoy for the Human Rights of LGBT Peoples" entity-parent-id="1936" proposed="true">Special Envoy</cato:entity-ref>—</text>
          <subparagraph id="id034da742bd7c488faf21ba9e3a5a2567">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>shall direct activities, policies, programs, and funding relating to the human rights of LGBT
			 people and the advancement of LGBT equality initiatives internationally,
			 for all bureaus and offices of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1900" entity-type="federal-body">Department of State</cato:entity-ref> and shall lead the
			 coordination of relevant 
			 international programs for all other Federal agencies;</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="id9c7c3c1f6a2b4d35975554da70b354c8">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>shall represent the United States in diplomatic matters relevant to the human rights of LGBT
			 people, including discrimination and violence against LGBT people
			 internationally;</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="id474ea77de593484898bc66157316354d">
            <enum>(C)</enum>
            <text>shall direct, as appropriate, United States Government resources to respond to needs for
			 protection, integration, resettlement, and empowerment of LGBT people in
			 United States Government policies and international programs, including to
			 prevent and respond to discrimination and violence against LGBT people
			 internationally;</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="id04d91cc8e0d541d7b2081a6b1e0db2b3">
            <enum>(D)</enum>
            <text>shall design, support, and implement activities regarding support, education, resettlement, and
			 empowerment of LGBT people internationally, including for the prevention
			 and response to discrimination and violence against LGBT people
			 internationally;</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="id5e7a924a5152400fa29b8094200d2111">
            <enum>(E)</enum>
            <text>shall lead interagency coordination between the foreign policy priorities related to the human
			 rights of LGBT
			 people and the development assistance priorities of the LGBT Coordinator
			 of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="7200" entity-type="federal-body">United States Agency for International Development</cato:entity-ref>;</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="id77a2d7aebd014780a1dbea27b7645a13">
            <enum>(F)</enum>
            <text>shall conduct regular consultation with civil society organizations working to prevent and respond
			 to discrimination and violence against LGBT people internationally;</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="id99de035075af4fa6a42700b0557bbb66">
            <enum>(G)</enum>
            <text>shall ensure that programs, projects, and activities designed to prevent and respond to
			 discrimination and violence against LGBT people are subject to rigorous
			 monitoring and evaluation, and that there is a uniform set of indicators
			 and standards for such monitoring and evaluation that is used across
			 international programs in Federal agencies;</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="id2591c98d74124d97a2c87a25dc71b69c">
            <enum>(H)</enum>
            <text>shall serve as the principal advisor to the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1900" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref> regarding human rights for LGBT
			 people internationally; and</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="id77e999ee0cfa4f5eae753dfb07a1aace">
            <enum>(I)</enum>
            <text>is authorized to represent the United States in diplomatic and multilateral situations on matters
			 relevant to the human rights of LGBT people, including discrimination and
			 violence against LGBT people internationally.</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="id068a85e5cef645139747f5e992fd5878">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Data repository</header>
          <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1936" entity-type="federal-body">Bureau of Democracy, Human Rights, and Labor</cato:entity-ref> shall—</text>
          <subparagraph id="id227547C3E35C4B4B9A20734D0EF66D38">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>be the central repository of data on all United States programs, projects, and
			 activities that relate to prevention and response to discrimination and
			 violence against LGBT people; and</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="idA965C67DDD74411CB9CE2D565B68E69D">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>produce—</text>
            <clause id="id7E5F27534E7148D691AAA247258B4D02">
              <enum>(i)</enum>
              <text>a full accounting of
			 United States Government spending on such programs, projects, and
			 activities; and</text>
            </clause>
            <clause id="idFCC4E57FCC3841BC841C9001C89D5D24">
              <enum>(ii)</enum>
              <text>evaluations of the effectiveness of implemented programs.</text>
            </clause>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
    </section>
    <section id="idc3e638444d5a409b94e6b7afa873daf2">
      <enum>6.</enum>
      <header>Briefings and assessments</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Special Envoy for the Human Rights of LGBT Peoples" entity-parent-id="1936" proposed="true">Special Envoy</cato:entity-ref> shall brief the appropriate congressional committees on the
			 status of the human rights of LGBT people internationally, as well as the
			 status of
			 programs and response strategies to address LGBT discrimination and
			 violence against LGBT people internationally, and shall submit to the
			 appropriate congressional committees an assessment of human and financial
			 resources necessary to fulfill the purposes and duties of this Act.</text>
    </section>
    <section id="ide2dbb2de6a4848eeb8bf54c390d79d6f">
      <enum>7.</enum>
      <header>United States policy to prevent and respond to discrimination and violence against LGBT people
			 globally</header>
      <subsection id="iddac4c8d0ee6b4b94b46a4dee66a872a0">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Global strategy requirement</header>
        <text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter for
			 five years, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Special Envoy for the Human Rights of LGBT Peoples" entity-parent-id="1936" proposed="true">Special Envoy</cato:entity-ref>	shall develop or update a United States
			 global
			 strategy to prevent and respond to discrimination and violence against
			 LGBT people globally. The strategy shall be transmitted to the
			 appropriate congressional committees and, if practicable, made available
			 to the public.</text>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="idef5bd97ebfc34826a69c9f3a70bbe52a">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Initial strategy</header>
        <text>For the purposes of this section, the Presidential Memorandum—International Initiatives to
			 Advance the Human Rights of Lesbian, Gay,
			 Bisexual, and Transgender Persons, issued December 6, 2011, shall be
			 deemed to fulfill the initial requirement of <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="International Human Rights Defense Act of 2014/s:7/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="id4d1d15fd61ee403e95edb3004a5f8341">
        <enum>(c)</enum>
        <header>Reporting</header>
        <text>In accordance with <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Foreign Assistance Act of 1961/s:116/ss:d/p:13" proposed="true">paragraph (13) of  section 116(d) of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961</cato:entity-ref> (<cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/22/2151n/d">22
			 U.S.C. 2151n(d)</cato:entity-ref>)</cato:entity>, as added by <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="International Human Rights Defense Act of 2014/s:9/ss:b" proposed="true">section 9(b)</cato:entity-ref>, the Annual Report on Human
			 Rights Practices shall include detailed descriptions of nations that
			 have adopted laws or constitutions that discriminate against LGBT people.</text>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="id1c6cc463c70344558062408c406d147f">
        <enum>(d)</enum>
        <header>Collaboration and coordination</header>
        <text>In developing the strategy under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="International Human Rights Defense Act of 2014/s:7/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Special Envoy for the Human Rights of LGBT Peoples" entity-parent-id="1936" proposed="true">Special Envoy</cato:entity-ref> shall consult with—</text>
        <paragraph id="idbe5ea8fe016a48079a924dcbe0bf6ac4">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>the heads of relevant Federal agencies; and</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="idab03f2a01ab24f33971cdc7634e6e490">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>representatives of civil society, multilateral, and private sector organizations with demonstrated
			 experience in addressing discrimination and violence against LGBT people
			 or promoting equal rights for LGBT people internationally.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
    </section>
    <section id="id8fd60b6ae9ab4429a581b31ca2cfa75d">
      <enum>8.</enum>
      <header>Implementation of the United States strategy to prevent and respond to LGBT discrimination and
			 violence against the LGBT community globally</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1900" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref> and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="7200" entity-type="federal-body">Administrator of the United States Agency for International
			 Development</cato:entity-ref> are authorized to
			 provide assistance to prevent and respond to discrimination and violence
			 against LGBT people internationally, including the following activities:</text>
      <paragraph id="id8d1f11744c714917aa68c34e371778f1">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text>Development and implementation of programs, such as the Global Equality Fund,	that respond to
			 human rights abuses and economic
			 exclusion of LGBT people in the workplace and in public.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id7ece03eaa21640ef84e4f8a3ec4e0136">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text>Development and enforcement of civil and criminal legal and judicial sanctions, protection,
			 training, and capacity.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="idae23b6387d6e4e949af5e6cf4de84d01">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <text>Enhancement of the health sector capacity to detect, prevent, and respond to violence against the
			 LGBT community and to combat HIV/AIDS in the LGBT community
			 internationally, in close coordination with the Office of the Global AIDS
			 Coordinator.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="idA447D723255F4E23A1B36B23A617951C">
        <enum>(4)</enum>
        <text>Development of a leadership program for international LGBT activists that will foster collaboration
			 and knowledge sharing across the world.</text>
      </paragraph>
    </section>
    <section id="idd885268148254e0b9788d206aadeb317">
      <enum>9.</enum>
      <header>Monitoring the United States strategy to prevent and respond to discrimination and violence against
			 the LGBT community globally</header>
      <subsection id="idb16f2f70c8d44db7a19399a708adfd9f">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>In general</header>
        <text>In each strategy submitted under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="International Human Rights Defense Act of 2014/s:7/ss:a" proposed="true">section 7(a)</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Special Envoy for the Human Rights of LGBT Peoples" proposed="true" entity-parent-id="1936">Special Envoy</cato:entity-ref> shall include an analysis
			 of best practices for preventing and addressing discrimination and
			 violence against LGBT people internationally, which shall include—</text>
        <paragraph id="idb6d8639b3c03452b8c220191ad8f2e53">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>a description of successful efforts by foreign governments, multilateral institutions,
			 nongovernmental organizations, educational organizations, and faith-based
			 organizations in preventing and responding to discrimination and violence
			 against LGBT people;</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="id439e72c95e9745c49139c595f14678c5">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>recommendations related to best practices, effective strategies, and improvements to enhance the
			 impact of prevention and response efforts; and</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="id1c11be0916304b0e94a2e6262b34478f">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <text>the impact of activities funded by the strategy in preventing and reducing discrimination and
			 violence against LGBT people internationally.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="idbacf68d6a2b647bca37b61be667df70b">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Information required To be included in human rights practices report</header>
        <text>
          <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Foreign Assistance Act of 1961/s:116/ss:d">Section 116(d)</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2151n">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/22/2151n/d">22 U.S.C. 2151n(d)</cato:entity-ref>
          </external-xref>)</cato:entity> of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 is amended—</text>
        <paragraph id="id33d3ae8967d74cd58ca93574b33520bf">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Foreign Assistance Act of 1961/s:116/ss:d/p:11/sp:C">paragraph (11)(C)</cato:entity-ref>, by striking <quote>; and</quote>  and inserting a semicolon;</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="id553d8e3b1d7e47c3a763a8a656f47fb3">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Foreign Assistance Act of 1961/s:116/ss:d/p:12/sp:C/cl:ii">paragraph (12)(C)(ii)</cato:entity-ref>, by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="id7a24ea407a824155821788dded9de218">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <text>by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text>
          <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id602b478ff72c4480baabf4be367c8752" style="OLC">
            <paragraph id="idd239a8ae5d224b648a7e815a1e5325d9">
              <enum>(13)</enum>
              <text>wherever applicable, the nature and extent of discrimination and violence based on sexual
			 orientation and gender identity.</text>
            </paragraph>
            <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
          </quoted-block>
				</paragraph>
      </subsection>
    </section>
  </legis-body>
</bill>
</doc>