<doc>
  <docmeta id="113sres528ats">
    <bill congress="113" type="sres" number="528" version="ats"/>
    <revision size="4238" annotations="0" status="complete" id="4" commit-time="2014-08-27T19:17:57Z" committer="mnewby" doc="113sres528ats/4.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <resolution xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print">
	<metadata>
<dublinCore>
<dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">113 SRES 528 ATS: Commemorating the 125th anniversary of North Dakota’s Statehood.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">2014-07-29</dc:date>
<dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">113th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session display="yes">2d Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. RES. 528</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20140729">July 29, 2014</action-date>
			<action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="S344">Mr. Hoeven</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S360">Ms. Heitkamp</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was  considered and agreed to</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">Commemorating the 125th anniversary of North Dakota’s Statehood.</official-title>
	</form>
	<preamble>
		<whereas>
      <text>Whereas the Dakota Territory was incorporated in 1861;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas President Theodore Roosevelt came to the Dakota Territory in 1883 to hunt and begin cattle
			 ranching near Medora, North Dakota;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas President Theodore Roosevelt credited the fact he was elected <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> to the time he
			 spent and the experiences he had  in North Dakota;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas North Dakota was admitted to the Union on November 2, 1889;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the population of North Dakota grew from 2,000 in 1870 to 680,000 in 1930, and	 reached a
			 State record of 730,000 people in 2014;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the battleship USS NORTH DAKOTA, the first turbine-powered ship in the <cato:entity-ref entity-id="1700" entity-type="federal-body">United States Navy</cato:entity-ref>,
			 was launched in 1908;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the North Dakota State flag, the regimental flag carried by the North Dakota Infantry in
			 the Spanish-American War in 1898 and Philippine Island Insurrection in
			 1899, was designated in 1911;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the Bank of North Dakota was established in 1919 and the State mill and elevator began
			 operating in 1922;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas, in 1932, the International Peace Garden was established on the border between North Dakota
			 and the Canadian province of Manitoba, a symbol of peace between the
			 governments of the United States and Canada;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas, in 1949, the Theodore Roosevelt National Memorial Park was dedicated, covering 3 areas of
			 the badlands in western North Dakota;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas, in 1953, President Eisenhower dedicated the Garrison Dam, the fifth-largest earthen dam in
			 the world, which created Lake Sakakawea, the third-largest man-made lake
			 in the United States;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas North Dakota has a world-class system of higher education, which supports student
			 development across a variety of fields, including aerospace, agriculture,
			 architecture, education, engineering, law, medicine, and nursing;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the USS NORTH DAKOTA, a Virginia-class submarine was christened in November 2013;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas North Dakota has had the lowest unemployment rate in the United States for over 5 years;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas, in 2013, North Dakota was either 1st or 2nd  in the United States in total agriculture
			 production for 16 different commodities;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas North Dakota is the second largest producer of oil and gas in the United States;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas North Dakota produces over 1,000,000 barrels of oil each day;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the economy of North Dakota has grown faster than the economy of all other States of the
			 United States for 4 consecutive years;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the personal income of people in North Dakota is nearly 30 percent above the national
			 average;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas, in 2012, exports from North Dakota topped $4,000,000,000; and</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the economy and communities of North Dakota has experienced unprecedented development,
			 resulting in national recognition: Now, therefore, be it</text>
		</whereas>
  </preamble>
	<resolution-body>
		<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="S1" section-type="undesignated-section">
      <enum/>
      <text>That the <cato:entity-ref entity-id="0010" entity-type="federal-body">Senate</cato:entity-ref>—</text>
			<paragraph id="idc4166a41ef5846368208e487bf84c4a0">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text>congratulates—</text>
        <subparagraph id="id9eb7b32688884116bd627da3e89182e5">
          <enum>(A)</enum>
          <text>the State of North Dakota on its 125th anniversary; and</text>
        </subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="iddb473f18e85b441b9e01d0cd9397cb25">
          <enum>(B)</enum>
          <text>the people of North Dakota for their tremendous work and success in building the prosperity of
			 current and future generations living in the State; and</text>
        </subparagraph>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id46b34f94506843079ccbcf9894a666dc">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text>respectfully requests that the <cato:entity-ref entity-id="0010" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of the Senate</cato:entity-ref> transmit an enrolled copy of this resolution
			 to the Governor of North Dakota.</text>
			</paragraph>
    </section>
  </resolution-body>
</resolution>
</doc>