<doc>
  <docmeta id="113s1668is">
    <bill congress="113" type="s" number="1668" version="is"/>
    <revision size="3350" annotations="0" status="complete" id="5" commit-time="2013-11-15T21:39:21Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113s1668is/5.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public">
  <metadata>
<dublinCore>
<dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">113 S1668 IS: To require a Comptroller General of the United States report on the impact of certain mental and physical trauma on the discharge of members of the Armed Forces for misconduct.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">2013-11-07</dc:date>
<dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
    <congress>113th CONGRESS</congress>
    <session>1st Session</session>
    <legis-num>S. 1668</legis-num>
    <current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
    <action>
      <action-date date="20131107">November 7, 2013</action-date>
      <action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="S330">Mr. Bennet</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name>
      </action-desc>
    </action>
    <legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
    <official-title>To require a Comptroller General of the United States report on the impact of certain mental and physical trauma on the discharge of members of the Armed Forces for misconduct.</official-title>
  </form>
  <legis-body>
    <section id="idB5F3B30B69A647F18D3FB6CC9EEDC87C" section-type="section-one">
      <enum>1.</enum>
      <header>Comptroller General of the United States report on impact of certain mental and physical trauma on discharges from military service for misconduct</header>
      <subsection id="id9ACB62E686BA43A4884F9D229AE76F43">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Report required</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0500">Comptroller General of the United States</cato:entity-ref> shall submit to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> a report on the impact of mental and physical trauma relating to Post Traumatic Stress Disorder (PTSD), Traumatic Brain Injury (TBI), behavioral health matters not related to Post Traumatic Stress Disorder, and other neurological combat traumas (in this section referred to as <quote>covered traumas</quote>) on the discharge of members of the Armed Forces from the Armed Forces for misconduct.</text>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="id065F5731AB76409AA3D9FC7466BBF2E8">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Elements</header>
        <text>The report required by <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="113 S 1668/s:1/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref> shall include the following:</text>
        <paragraph id="idaf309aa954a845b298b06ce0198570f4">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>An assessment of the extent to which the Armed Forces have in place processes for the consideration of  the impact of mental and physical trauma relating to covered traumas on  members of the Armed Forces who are being considered for discharge from the Armed Forces for misconduct, including the compliance of the Armed Forces with such processes and mechanisms in the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="9700">Department of Defense</cato:entity-ref> for ensuring the compliance of the Armed Forces with such processes.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="idcd638a263cfc494b950c8236d25453d6">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>An assessment of the extent to which  the Armed Forces provide members of the Armed Forces, including commanding officers, junior officers, and noncommissioned officers, training on the symptoms of covered traumas and the identification of the presence of such conditions in members of the Armed Forces.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="id90f57e05b302410bb7ef3d30c52b4ce0">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <text>An assessment of the extent to which members of the Armed Forces who receive treatment for a covered trauma before discharge from the Armed Forces are later discharged from the Armed Forces for misconduct.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="idE72CE3B8B0C94B8BBE685849996729BF">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
          <text>An identification of the number of members of the Armed Forces discharged as described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="113 S 1668/s:1/ss:b/p:3" proposed="true">paragraph (3)</cato:entity-ref> who are ineligible for benefits from the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="3600">Department of Veterans Affairs</cato:entity-ref> based on characterization of discharge.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="idc9514d2a09244c4c8ea1f65bca92c003">
          <enum>(5)</enum>
          <text>An assessment of the extent to which members of the Armed Forces who accept a discharge from the Armed Forces for misconduct in lieu of trial by court-martial are counseled on the potential for ineligibility for benefits from the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="3600">Department of Veterans Affairs</cato:entity-ref> as a result of such discharge before acceptance of such discharge.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
    </section>
  </legis-body>
</bill>
</doc>