<doc>
  <docmeta id="113sres527ats">
    <bill congress="113" type="sres" number="527" version="ats"/>
    <revision size="4536" annotations="0" status="complete" id="4" commit-time="2014-08-27T19:48:12Z" committer="mnewby" doc="113sres527ats/4.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <resolution xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print">
	<metadata>
<dublinCore>
<dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">113 SRES 527 ATS: Congratulating the members of Phi Beta Sigma Fraternity, Inc. for 100 years of service throughout the United States and the world, and commending Phi Beta Sigma Fraternity, Inc. for exemplifying the ideals of brotherhood, scholarship, and service while upholding the motto “Culture for Service and Service for Humanity”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">2014-07-29</dc:date>
<dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">113th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session display="yes">2d Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. RES. 527</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20140729">July 29, 2014</action-date>
			<action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="S258">Ms. Landrieu</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S365">Mr. Scott</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S308">Mr. Cardin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S307">Mr. Brown</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S282">Mr. Nelson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S320">Mrs. Hagan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S131">Mr. Levin</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S354">Ms. Baldwin</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was considered and agreed to</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">Congratulating the members of Phi Beta Sigma Fraternity, Inc. for 100 years of service throughout
			 the United States and the world, and commending Phi Beta Sigma Fraternity,
			 Inc. for exemplifying the ideals of brotherhood, scholarship, and service
			 while upholding the motto <quote>Culture for Service and Service for Humanity</quote>.</official-title>
	</form>
	<preamble>
		<whereas>
      <text>Whereas Phi Beta Sigma Fraternity, Inc. was founded on the campus of <cato:entity-ref entity-id="9193" entity-type="federal-body">Howard University</cato:entity-ref> in the
			 District of Columbia on January 9, 1914, by A. Langston Taylor, Leonard F.
			 Morse, and Charles I. Brown;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas since the formation of Phi Beta Sigma Fraternity, Inc., the members of Phi Beta Sigma
			 Fraternity, Inc. have maintained a strong commitment to brotherhood,
			 community involvement, and service to all people;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas Phi Beta Sigma Fraternity, Inc. has implemented a number of initiatives encouraging
			 diversity, business opportunities, and advocacy;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas Phi Beta Sigma Fraternity, Inc. has established the Sigma Wellness, Sigma Cares,  and
			 Living Well Brother to Brother programs;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas Phi Beta Sigma Fraternity, Inc. was the first African-American fraternity to establish
			 alumni chapters and youth mentoring clubs and is the only fraternity to
			 form an African-American sorority counterpart, Zeta Phi Beta;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the men of Phi Beta Sigma Fraternity, Inc. have dedicated themselves to the promotion of
			 civil rights, and the members of Phi Beta Sigma Fraternity, Inc. include
			 influential leaders and activists such as  Hosea
			 Williams,  A. Phillip Randolph, and Lafayette
			 Mckeene Hershaw;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas members belonging to chapters of  Phi Beta Sigma Fraternity, Inc. across the United States
			 responded to a call for support of the war efforts  of the United States
			 during World War I;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas members of Phi Beta Sigma Fraternity, Inc., such as Alain LeRoy Locke, Weldon Johnson, and
			 A. Phillip Randolph, made significant contributions to the Harlem
			 Renaissance;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas Phi Beta Sigma Fraternity, Inc. has over 700 chapters in the United States, Africa, Europe,
			 Asia, and the Caribbean;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the men of Phi Beta Sigma Fraternity, Inc. have distinguished themselves as public
			 servants, including members such as—</text>
      <paragraph id="idd2467e288bd047a6a7bfd803f4a3e79a">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text>a United States Congressman, civil rights activist, and chairman of the Student
			 Nonviolent Coordinating Committee;</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id2d16e4c7190e41fa94114df49b3ddfbc">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text>the  first African-American Speaker of the Colorado House of Representatives;</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id1f45c76c56f14a76bd5476d6a9cf3e0f">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <text>the first African-American Democrat elected to the <cato:entity-ref entity-id="0001" entity-type="federal-body">Congress of the United
			 States</cato:entity-ref>;</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id071657f34df04e65a73517f61e45befb">
        <enum>(4)</enum>
        <text>Demetrius C. Newton, Sr., elected in 1986 as the first African-American Speaker Pro Tempore of the
			 Alabama House of Representatives; and</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id5c5cc2b36c4a4a01b6fbf6322f328927">
        <enum>(5)</enum>
        <text>Fleming Jones, Jr., the first African-American Democratic member of the West Virginia House of
			 Delegates; and</text>
			</paragraph>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas Phi Beta Sigma Fraternity, Inc. commemorated its history and promoted service during the
			 Phi Beta Sigma centennial celebration on January 9, 2014, in the District
			 of Columbia: Now, therefore, be it</text>
		</whereas>
  </preamble>
	<resolution-body>
		<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="S1" section-type="undesignated-section">
      <enum/>
      <text>That the <cato:entity-ref entity-id="0010" entity-type="federal-body">Senate</cato:entity-ref>—</text>
      <paragraph id="idB9BA7BFFDD4145408C193245760D5968">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text>congratulates Phi Beta Sigma Fraternity, Inc. for 100 years of service to communities throughout
			 the United States and the world; and</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id245D44AD2FC24301A393CA877BC4892A">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text>commends Phi Beta Sigma Fraternity, Inc. for a continued commitment to the ideals of brotherhood,
			 scholarship, and service.</text>
			</paragraph>
    </section>
  </resolution-body>
</resolution>
</doc>