<doc>
  <docmeta id="113s579is">
    <bill congress="113" type="s" number="579" version="is"/>
    <revision size="9896" annotations="0" id="4" commit-time="2013-05-16T18:35:14Z" status="complete" committer="mbohmer" doc="113s579is/4.xml">
      <description description="Markup copied from completed documents">Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public">
  <metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dublinCore>
      <dc:title>113 S579 IS: To direct the Secretary of State to develop a strategy to obtain observer status for Taiwan at the triennial International Civil Aviation Organization Assembly, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
      <dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
      <dc:date>2013-03-14</dc:date>
      <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
      <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
      <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    </dublinCore>
  </metadata>
  <form>
    <distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
    <congress>113th CONGRESS</congress>
    <session>1st Session</session>
    <legis-num>S. 579</legis-num>
    <current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
    <action>
      <action-date date="20130314">March 14, 2013</action-date>
      <action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="S306">Mr. Menendez</sponsor>(for
			 himself,<cosponsor name-id="S236">Mr. Inhofe</cosponsor>, and<cosponsor name-id="S212">Mr. Coats</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill;
			 which was read twice and referred to the<committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign
			 Relations</committee-name>
      </action-desc>
    </action>
    <legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
    <official-title>To direct the Secretary of State to develop a strategy to
		  obtain observer status for Taiwan at the triennial International Civil Aviation
		  Organization Assembly, and for other purposes.</official-title>
  </form>
  <legis-body>
    <section id="idC287D906BC664A87AAC6CD5F5A99E94C" section-type="section-one">
      <enum>1.</enum>
      <header>Concerning the participation
			 of Taiwan in the International Civil Aviation Organization</header>
      <subsection id="iddee8f83e03514e6d89af62c630dd2492">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Findings</header>
        <text>
          <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref>makes the following findings:</text>
        <paragraph id="id29462aa6554f41d09e553f84a9b7133e">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>Safe, secure, and
			 economical international air navigation and transport is important to every
			 citizen of the world, and safe skies are ensured through uniform aviation
			 standards, harmonization of security protocols, and expeditious dissemination
			 of information regarding new regulations and other relevant matters.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="id7f1a60b53515437788a5bb3b3458c35b">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>Direct and
			 unobstructed participation in international civil aviation forums and programs
			 is beneficial for all nations and their civil aviation authorities. Civil
			 aviation is vital to all due to the international transit and commerce it makes
			 possible, but must also be closely regulated due to the possible use of
			 aircraft as weapons of mass destruction or to transport biological, chemical,
			 and nuclear weapons or other dangerous materials.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="id7d20c6d551174cbf9597aec6c00fddfb">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <text>The Convention on
			 International Civil Aviation, signed at Chicago, Illinois, December 7, 1944,
			 and entered into force April 4, 1947, established the<cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="19UA">International Civil
			 Aviation Organization</cato:entity-ref>(ICAO), stating that<quote>[t]he aims and objectives of
			 the Organization are to develop the principles and techniques of international
			 air navigation and to foster the planning and development of international air
			 transport so as to … [m]eet the needs of the peoples of the world for safe,
			 regular, efficient and economical air transport</quote>.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="id7535057f82124161817c821c6092884c">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
          <text>The terrorist
			 attacks of September 11, 2001, demonstrated that the global civil aviation
			 network is subject to vulnerabilities that can be exploited in one country to
			 harm another. The ability of civil aviation authorities to coordinate, preempt,
			 and act swiftly and in unison is an essential element of crisis prevention and
			 response.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="id683fda14b308441f81b5b8ebc4f879a0">
          <enum>(5)</enum>
          <text>Following the
			 terrorist attacks of September 11, 2001, the<cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="19UA">ICAO</cato:entity-ref>convened a high-level
			 Ministerial Conference on Aviation Security that endorsed a global strategy for
			 strengthening aviation security worldwide and issued a public declaration that<quote>a uniform approach in a global system is essential to ensure aviation
			 security throughout the world and that deficiencies in any part of the system
			 constitute a threat to the entire global system,</quote>and that there should
			 be a commitment to<quote>foster international cooperation in the field of
			 aviation security and harmonize the implementation of security
			 measures</quote>.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="id217e10d50ff84a78b2ada973bd967a1b">
          <enum>(6)</enum>
          <text>The Taipei Flight
			 Information Region, under the jurisdiction of Taiwan, covers an airspace of
			 180,000 square nautical miles and provides air traffic control services to over
			 1,200,000 flights annually, with the Taiwan Taoyuan International Airport
			 recognized as the 10th and 19th largest airport by international cargo volume
			 and number of international passengers, respectively, in 2011.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="id29f217324f2f4223ba200d945a5ff77a">
          <enum>(7)</enum>
          <text>Despite the
			 established international consensus regarding a uniform approach to aviation
			 security that fosters international cooperation, exclusion from the<cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="19UA">ICAO</cato:entity-ref>since
			 1971 has impeded the efforts of the Government of Taiwan to maintain civil
			 aviation practices that comport with evolving international standards, due to
			 its inability to contact the<cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="19UA">ICAO</cato:entity-ref>for up-to-date information on aviation
			 standards and norms, secure amendments to the organization’s regulations in a
			 timely manner, obtain sufficient and timely information needed to prepare for
			 the implementation of new systems and procedures set forth by the<cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="19UA">ICAO</cato:entity-ref>, receive
			 technical assistance in implementing new regulations, and participate in
			 technical and academic seminars hosted by the<cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="19UA">ICAO</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="id320d8b4253ba4ab6a5b6c3435056d58f">
          <enum>(8)</enum>
          <text>On October 8,
			 2010, the<cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Department of State</cato:entity-ref>praised the 37th<cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="19UA">ICAO</cato:entity-ref>Assembly on its adoption of
			 a Declaration on Aviation Security, but noted that<quote>because every airport
			 offers a potential entry point into this global system, every nation faces the
			 threat from gaps in aviation security throughout the world—and all nations must
			 share the responsibility for securing that system</quote>.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="id23bcccd06a174281b62442fb7a905c4d">
          <enum>(9)</enum>
          <text>On October 2,
			 2012, Taiwan became the 37th participant to join the United States Visa Waiver
			 program, which is expected to stimulate tourism and commerce that will rely
			 increasingly on international commercial aviation.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="id56fafc3f35444017836618f7e51be80b">
          <enum>(10)</enum>
          <text>The Government of
			 Taiwan’s exclusion from the<cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="19UA">ICAO</cato:entity-ref>constitutes a serious gap in global standards
			 that should be addressed at the earliest opportunity in advance of the 38th<cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="19UA">ICAO</cato:entity-ref>Assembly in September 2013.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="id27cc3c5befe2494faa42753c163976d6">
          <enum>(11)</enum>
          <text>The<cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="6920">Federal
			 Aviation Administration</cato:entity-ref>and its counterpart agencies in Taiwan have enjoyed
			 close collaboration on a wide range of issues related to innovation and
			 technology, civil engineering, safety and security, and navigation.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="id1f5b264c44af4e0ab9f44def3824293d">
          <enum>(12)</enum>
          <text>The<cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="19UA">ICAO</cato:entity-ref>has
			 allowed a wide range of observers to participate in the activities of the
			 organization.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="id8667e5436f7345ca9b8b826c04c1a0e8">
          <enum>(13)</enum>
          <text>The United
			 States, in the 1994 Taiwan Policy Review, declared its intention to support
			 Taiwan’s participation in appropriate international organizations and has
			 consistently reiterated that support.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="id2663a44fc28140829d20fab2918e3bbd">
          <enum>(14)</enum>
          <text>Senate
			 Concurrent Resolution 17, 112th Congress, agreed to September 11, 2012,
			 affirmed the sense of Congress that—</text>
          <subparagraph id="id38ca44eceeef46cfb290fe4993386bbb">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>meaningful
			 participation by the Government of Taiwan as an observer in the meetings and
			 activities of the<cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="19UA">ICAO</cato:entity-ref>will contribute both to the fulfillment of the<cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="19UA">ICAO’s</cato:entity-ref>overarching mission and to the success of a global strategy to address aviation
			 security threats based on effective international cooperation; and</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="idcd2411c1342045db9d2358f1977d9801">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>the United States
			 Government should take a leading role in garnering international support for
			 the granting of observer status to Taiwan in the<cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="19UA">ICAO</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="id91e7c5936f4f449d85f7b646b0759706">
          <enum>(15)</enum>
          <text>Following the
			 enactment of<cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
              <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/108/235">Public Law 108–235</external-xref>(<cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/22/290/note">
                <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/290">22 U.S.C. 290</external-xref>note</cato:entity-ref>)</cato:entity>, a law authorizing the<cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref>to initiate and implement a plan to endorse and obtain
			 observer status for Taiwan at the annual summit of the World Health Assembly
			 and subsequent advocacy by the United States, Taiwan was granted observer
			 status to the World Health Assembly for four consecutive years since 2009. Both
			 prior to, and in its capacity as an observer, Taiwan has contributed
			 significantly to the international community’s collective efforts in pandemic
			 control, monitoring, early warning, and other related matters.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="id04de76ed4ac445c29152c0edd6c4b7be">
          <enum>(16)</enum>
          <text>
            <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="19UA">ICAO</cato:entity-ref>rules and
			 existing practices allow for the meaningful participation of noncontracting
			 countries as well as other bodies in its meetings and activities through
			 granting of observer status.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="iddf54d39c650a4061a3e7574fa0ea5886">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Taiwan's
			 participation at ICAO</header>
        <text>The Secretary of State shall—</text>
        <paragraph id="id081fb154f4bd4e9ea6923e4eebdfe6a1">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>develop a
			 strategy to obtain observer status for Taiwan, at the triennial ICAO Assembly
			 next held in September 2013 in Montreal, Canada, and other related meetings,
			 activities, and mechanisms thereafter; and</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="idd3c44acd008d45189d9a1bd5537ada48">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>instruct the United States Mission to the<cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="19UA">ICAO</cato:entity-ref>to officially request observer status for Taiwan at the triennial ICAO
			 Assembly and other related meetings, activities, and mechanisms thereafter and
			 to actively urge<cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="19UA">ICAO</cato:entity-ref>member states to support such observer status and
			 participation for Taiwan.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="idf4e6f8ce54504b75b9c5974d119b9b85">
        <enum>(c)</enum>
        <header>Report
			 Concerning Observer Status for Taiwan at the ICAO Assembly</header>
        <text>Not later than 30 days after the date of
			 the enactment of this Act, the<cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref>shall submit to<cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref>a
			 report, in unclassified form, describing the United States strategy to endorse
			 and obtain observer status for Taiwan at the triennial<cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="19UA">ICAO</cato:entity-ref>Assembly and at
			 subsequent ICAO Assemblies and at other related meetings, activities, and
			 mechanisms thereafter. The report shall include the following:</text>
        <paragraph id="id9B66799A54D8447B979A1106FECB6941">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>A
			 description of the efforts the<cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref>has made to encourage<cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="19UA">ICAO</cato:entity-ref>member states to promote Taiwan’s bid to obtain observer status.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="idc5c448a03e864a268cf62bd3a628552e">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>The steps the<cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1900">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref>will take to endorse and obtain observer status for Taiwan
			 in<cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="19UA">ICAO</cato:entity-ref>at the triennial ICAO Assembly and at other related meetings,
			 activities, and mechanisms thereafter.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
    </section>
  </legis-body>
</bill>
</doc>