<doc>
  <docmeta id="113s2687is">
    <bill congress="113" type="s" number="2687" version="is"/>
    <revision size="21623" annotations="0" status="complete" id="4" commit-time="2014-08-11T22:39:13Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113s2687is/4.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public">
	<metadata>
<dublinCore>
<dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">113 S2687 IS: Access to Contraception for Women Servicemembers and Dependents Act of 2014</dc:title>
<dc:publisher xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">2014-07-30</dc:date>
<dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
		<congress>113th CONGRESS</congress>
    <session>2d Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. 2687</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20140730">July 30, 2014</action-date>
			<action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="S324">Mrs. Shaheen</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S198">Mr. Reid</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S229">Mrs. Murray</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S307">Mr. Brown</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S331">Mrs. Gillibrand</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S223">Mrs. Boxer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S253">Mr. Durbin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S354">Ms. Baldwin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S341">Mr. Blumenthal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S284">Ms. Stabenow</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S221">Mrs. Feinstein</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S361">Ms. Hirono</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S332">Mr. Franken</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S353">Mr. Schatz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S314">Mr. Tester</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S247">Mr. Wyden</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S366">Ms. Warren</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S319">Mr. Begich</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name>
      </action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To amend title 10, United States Code, to ensure that women members of the Armed Forces and their
			 families have access to the contraception they need in order to promote
			 the health and readiness of all members of the Armed Forces, and for other
			 purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body>
    <section id="idA61DAEEBED2543C59047536862D7EC3A" section-type="section-one">
      <enum>1.</enum>
      <header>Short title</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote>
          <short-title>
            <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Access to Contraception for Women Servicemembers and Dependents Act of 2014" proposed="true">Access to Contraception for Women Servicemembers and Dependents Act of 2014</cato:entity-ref>
          </short-title>
        </quote>.</text>
    </section>
    <section id="id4B448AC0F70B4297A82E8520E95D3E1F" section-type="subsequent-section">
      <enum>2.</enum>
      <header>Findings</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress makes the following findings:</text>
      <paragraph id="idb88f4f12af034bbcb46d08542e03724a">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text>Women are serving in the Armed Forces at increasing rates, playing a critical role in the national
			 security of the United States.    More than 350,000 women serve on active
			 duty in the Armed Forces or in the Selected Reserve.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id54560839dff841d3971d5875c923c41e">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text>Nearly 10,000,000 members of the Armed Forces (including members of the National Guard and
			 Reserves), military retirees, their families, their survivors, and certain
			 former spouses, including nearly 5,000,000 female beneficiaries, are
			 eligible for health care through the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="9700" entity-type="federal-body">Department of Defense</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id6b75c15da3034280be5468fb3b9f2512">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <text>Contraception is critical for women's health and is highly effective at reducing unintended
			 pregnancy. The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="7523" entity-type="federal-body">Centers for Disease Control and Prevention</cato:entity-ref> describe
			 contraception as one
			 of the 10 greatest public health achievements of the twentieth century.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id88e1234cf21a4e309ce2f534beac7967">
        <enum>(4)</enum>
        <text>Contraception has played a direct role in the greater participation of women in education and
			 employment. Increased wages and increased control over
			 reproductive decisions provide women with educational and professional
			 opportunities that have increased gender equality over the decades since
			 contraception was introduced.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="ide4e8625a47d94c37a72bb61a5109ed8a">
        <enum>(5)</enum>
        <text>Studies have shown that when cost barriers to the full range of methods of contraception are
			 eliminated, and women receive comprehensive counseling on the various
			 methods  of contraception (including highly effective Long-Acting
			 Reversible Contraceptives
			 (LARCs)), rates of unintended pregnancy decline dramatically.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id8c8d604937db41d3b1fc099930808e26">
        <enum>(6)</enum>
        <text>Research has also shown that investments in effective contraception save public and private
			 dollars.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="idd5cc14c0336d484ca855b7cba7baa82b">
        <enum>(7)</enum>
        <text>The 2011 recommendations of the Institute of Medicine on women’s preventive health services include
			 recommendations that health insurance plans cover all methods of
			 contraception approved by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="7524" entity-type="federal-body">Food and Drug Administration</cato:entity-ref>, sterilization
			 procedures, and patient education and counseling for all women with
			 reproductive capacity without any cost-sharing requirements.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id9931b69de806408eade3f5bcc709cb69">
        <enum>(8)</enum>
        <text>The recommendations described in paragraph (7) are reflected in provisions of the <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act">Patient
			 Protection and Affordable Care Act</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/148">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="public-law" value="public-law/111/148">Public Law 111–148</cato:entity-ref>
          </external-xref>)</cato:entity>, and thus group
			 and individual health insurance plans must provide such coverage. The
			 recommendations have also been adopted by the
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="2400" entity-type="federal-body">Office
			 of Personnel Management</cato:entity-ref>, and thus all health insurance plans that are part
			 of the Federal Employees Health Benefits Program must provide such
			 coverage.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id008009b25cb842d2b08f40e0b56b3b2a">
        <enum>(9)</enum>
        <text>Under the TRICARE program, servicewomen on active duty have full coverage of
			 all prescription drugs, including contraception, without cost-sharing
			 requirements. However, servicewomen not on active
			 duty, and female dependents of members of the Armed Forces, who receive
			 health care 
			 through the TRICARE program do not have similar coverage of all
			 prescription
			 methods of contraception approved by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="7524" entity-type="federal-body">Food and Drug Administration</cato:entity-ref>
			 without cost-sharing.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id927642e262c14175894b41f6b2768edc">
        <enum>(10)</enum>
        <text>Studies indicate that servicewomen need comprehensive counseling for pregnancy prevention,
			 particularly in their predeployment preparations, and the lack thereof is
			 contributing to unintended pregnancies among servicewomen.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id03aacfb753a24cbb9526c785ee3a6e72">
        <enum>(11)</enum>
        <text>An analysis by Ibis Reproductive Health of the 2008 Survey of Health Related Behaviors among Active
			 Duty Military Personnel found a high unintended pregnancy rate among
			 servicewomen.
			 Adjusting for the difference between age distribution in the Armed Forces
			 and the general population, the rate of unintended pregnancy among
			 servicewomen is higher than for the general
			 population.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id9F57EE79DEA94940B5D917CFA2E6DFAB">
        <enum>(12)</enum>
        <text>With the integrated use of electronic medical records throughout the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="9700" entity-type="federal-body">Department of Defense</cato:entity-ref>, the
			 technological infrastructure exists to develop clinical decision support
			 tools.  These tools, which are incorporated into the electronic medical
			 record, allow for a point-of-care feedback loop that can be used to
			 enhance patient decisionmaking, case and patient management, and care
			 coordination. Benefits of clinical decision support tools include
			 increased quality of care and enhanced health outcomes, improved
			 efficiency, and provider and patient satisfaction.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="idd12dc9baa9124c73b73a6e5af2a14b11">
        <enum>(13)</enum>
        <text>The Defense Advisory Committee on Women in the Services (DACOWITS) has recommended that all the
			 Armed Forces, to the extent that they have not already,  implement
			 initiatives that inform servicemembers of the importance of family
			 planning, educate them on methods of contraception, and make various
			 methods of contraception available, based on the finding that family
			 planning can increase the overall readiness and quality of life of all
			 members of the military.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id1756a7d219494a0a832051a450093ac5">
        <enum>(14)</enum>
        <text>Health care, including family planning for survivors  of sexual assault in the Armed Forces is a
			 critical issue. Servicewomen on active duty  report
			 rates of unwanted sexual contact at approximately 16 times those of the
			 comparable general population of women in the United States.  Through
			 regulations, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="9700" entity-type="federal-body">Department of Defense</cato:entity-ref> already supports a policy of
			 ensuring that servicewomen who are sexually assaulted
			 have access to emergency contraception.</text>
      </paragraph>
    </section>
    <section id="id22AC0608F7E048DDA5496D8408457394">
      <enum>3.</enum>
      <header>Contraception coverage parity under the TRICARE program</header>
      <subsection id="idE78F10A244234DF39C7188D29E75131C">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>In general</header>
        <text>
          <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc/10/1074d">
            <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/10/1074d">Section 1074d</external-xref> of title 10, United States Code</cato:entity-ref>, is amended—</text>
        <paragraph id="idEF370181BDE34D88BDC80C7B8005B3C5">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>in subsection (a), by inserting <quote>
              <header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">for members and former members</header-in-text>
            </quote> after <quote>
              <header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">Services available</header-in-text>
            </quote>;</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="id09883860AB6542B6B06EC9120A5404FD">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>by redesignating subsection (b) as subsection (d); and</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="id90072CA95108467C96EAD5B45DEA0582">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <text>by inserting after subsection (a) the following new subsections:</text>
          <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id99C42D8EED504F6586CE225A9EF47726" style="OLC">
            <subsection id="idF08DF47C59664F47AD0919C5150E4F39">
              <enum>(b)</enum>
              <header>Care related to prevention of pregnancy</header>
              <text>Female covered beneficiaries shall
			 be entitled to care related to the prevention of pregnancy described by
			 subsection (d)(3).</text>
						</subsection>
            <subsection id="id210BF8E504D14B5AB5E66560379F3D70">
              <enum>(c)</enum>
              <header>Prohibition on cost-Sharing for certain services</header>
              <text>Notwithstanding <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc/10/1074g/a/6">section 1074g(a)(6) of this title</cato:entity-ref> or any other provision of law, cost-sharing may
			 not be imposed or collected for care related to the prevention of
			 pregnancy provided pursuant
			 to subsection (a) or (b), including for any method of contraception
			 provided, whether provided through a facility of the uniformed services,
			 the TRICARE retail pharmacy program, or the national mail-order pharmacy
			 program.</text>
            </subsection>
            <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
          </quoted-block>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="id2F9C24EBA6D04F7587BEC7BC7A540769">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Care related to prevention of pregnancy</header>
        <text>Subsection (d)(3) of such section, as redesignated by subsection (a)(2) of this section, is further
			 amended by inserting before the period at the end the following: <quote>(including all methods of contraception approved by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="7524" entity-type="federal-body">Food and Drug Administration</cato:entity-ref>, sterilization
			 procedures, and patient education and counseling in connection therewith)</quote>.</text>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="id751D4C3DE80741D5B2A00FAB4E3B0E3D">
        <enum>(c)</enum>
        <header>Conforming amendment</header>
        <text>
          <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc/10/1077/a/13">Section 1077(a)(13) of such title</cato:entity-ref> is amended by striking <quote>section 1074d(b)</quote> and inserting <quote>
            <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc/10/1074d/d" proposed="true">section 1074d(d)</cato:entity-ref>
          </quote>.</text>
      </subsection>
    </section>
    <section id="id652DC8F7E925467D86B56EAABE100EC4">
      <enum>4.</enum>
      <header>Access to broad range of methods of contraception approved by the Food and Drug Administration for
			 members of
			 the
			 Armed Forces and military dependents at military treatment facilities</header>
      <subsection id="id7dc64ad42ca3409093e3198415d67093">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>In general</header>
        <text>Commencing not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="9700" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of
			 Defense</cato:entity-ref> shall ensure that every military treatment facility has a
			 sufficient stock of a broad range of methods of contraception approved by
			 the
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="7524" entity-type="federal-body">Food and Drug Administration</cato:entity-ref>, as recommended by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="7523" entity-type="federal-body">Centers for Disease
			 Control and Prevention</cato:entity-ref> and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Office of Population Affairs" entity-parent-id="7500">Office of Population Affairs of the
			 Department of Health and Human Services</cato:entity-ref>, to be able to dispense at
			 any time any such method of contraception to any women members of the
			 Armed Forces and female covered beneficiaries who receive care through
			 such facility.</text>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="id48DD67BEBAFE4112A0787E3DC7249A6F">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Covered beneficiary defined</header>
        <text>In this section, the term <term>covered beneficiary</term> has the meaning given that term in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc/10/1072//5">
            <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/10/1072">section 1072(5)</external-xref> of title 10, United States Code</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
      </subsection>
    </section>
    <section id="id4B340C70A35A4CD5AE304A114EEE22AA">
      <enum>5.</enum>
      <header>Comprehensive standards and access to contraception counseling for members of the Armed Forces</header>
      <subsection id="idF0834F62C1E340AD968BBB2959146884">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Purpose</header>
        <text>The purpose of this section is to ensure that all health care providers employed by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="9700" entity-type="federal-body">Department
			 of
			 Defense</cato:entity-ref> who provide care for women members of the Armed Forces, including
			 general practitioners,
			 are provided, through clinical practice guidelines, the most current
			 evidence-based and evidence-informed
			 standards of care with respect to methods of contraception and counseling
			 on methods of contraception.</text>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="id83d8ad537d68412f9ee25a31cb0eab7c">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Clinical practice guidelines</header>
        <paragraph id="idD04E84C0C31A4B49B8F872617546A540">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>In general</header>
          <text>Not later than one year after the date of the  enactment of this Act, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="9700" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of Defense</cato:entity-ref>
			 shall compile clinical practice guidelines for health care providers
			 described in subsection (a) on standards of care with respect to methods
			 of contraception and counseling
			 on methods of contraception for women members of the Armed Forces.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="idD23AE08C25334FE0A77DFB93806318EF">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Sources</header>
          <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="9700">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall compile clinical practice guidelines under this subsection from among clinical
			 practice guidelines established by appropriate health agencies and
			 professional organizations, including the following:</text>
          <subparagraph id="id84683217a6164f36badc2310eba4a8f8">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>The United States Preventive Services Task Force.</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="id25adb73b54a94326ac2846fbba434dfc">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="7523" entity-type="federal-body">Centers for Disease Control and Prevention</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="id4e3d0ab0ec33478b87385f0f5616fde2">
            <enum>(C)</enum>
            <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Office of Population Affairs" entity-parent-id="7500">Office of Population Affairs of the Department of Health and Human Services</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="id2c3aa1100ccc4f40871bea119229ee83">
            <enum>(D)</enum>
            <text>The American College of Obstetricians and Gynecologists.</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="ide600bf2e0f7b4a21b99950c061ce4d78">
            <enum>(E)</enum>
            <text>The Association of Reproductive Health Professionals.</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="idc7ff4192c38143c5b499ec16d7f9b496">
            <enum>(F)</enum>
            <text>The American Academy of Family Physicians.</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="idd7354e64258a4b97bbeefd850c0166e5">
            <enum>(G)</enum>
            <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="7528" entity-type="federal-body">Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="idBBB1D80410F44C9F8480564F392C7F23">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <header>Updates</header>
          <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="9700">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall from time to time update the list of  clinical practice guidelines compiled
			 under this
			 subsection to incorporate into such guidelines new or updated standards of
			 care with respect to methods of contraception and counseling
			 on methods of contraception.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="id73b2eea7cf2f467192a2bb4dc0db3574">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
          <header>Dissemination</header>
          <subparagraph id="id5518042411CE4030948F77D39A9EB177">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <header>Initial dissemination</header>
            <text>As soon as practicable after the compilation of clinical practice guidelines pursuant to paragraph
			 (1), but commencing not later than one year after the date of the
			 enactment of this Act, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="9700">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall provide for rapid dissemination
			 of the clinical practice guidelines to health care providers described in
			 subsection (a).</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="idDD1BD2CEE2C84E65A1D50A93894A2254">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <header>Updates</header>
            <text>As soon as practicable after the adoption under paragraph (3) of any update   to the clinical
			 practice guidelines compiled pursuant to this subsection, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="9700">Secretary</cato:entity-ref>
			 shall provide for the rapid dissemination of such clinical practice
			 guidelines, as so updated, to health care providers described in
			 subsection (a).</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="idE8165005604E41B89A0B9198BA195AF8">
            <enum>(C)</enum>
            <header>Protocols</header>
            <text>Clinical practice guidelines, and any updates to such guidelines, shall be disseminated under this
			 paragraph  in accordance with administrative protocols developed by the
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="9700">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> for that purpose.</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="iddab1fce2b0d54fe79654ece1dc352507">
        <enum>(c)</enum>
        <header>Clinical decision support tools</header>
        <paragraph id="id4efa8de7b31c43d99d80eb271156e1db">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>In general</header>
          <text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="9700">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall, in order
			 to assist health care providers described in subsection (a),  develop and
			 implement clinical decision support tools that reflect, through the
			 clinical practice guidelines compiled pursuant to subsection (b), the most
			 current evidence-based and evidence-informed standards of care with
			 respect to methods of contraception and counseling on methods of
			 contraception.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="id9ed74af9708c49fa8fd5d726f8da5ef6">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Updates</header>
          <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="9700">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall from time to time update the clinical decision support tools developed under
			 this subsection to incorporate into such tools new or updated	guidelines
			 on methods of contraception and counseling on methods of contraception.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="idFA3CBEFA3A644888A5FF6E5DB8B5AF42">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <header>Dissemination</header>
          <text>Clinical decision support tools, and any updates to such tools, shall be disseminated under this
			 subsection   in accordance with administrative protocols developed by the
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="9700">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> for that purpose. Such protocols shall be similar to the
			 administrative protocols developed under subsection (b)(4)(C).</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="id83797aa3642c41f28d8e048280100b23">
        <enum>(d)</enum>
        <header>Access to contraception counseling</header>
        <text>As soon as practicable after the date of the enactment of this Act, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="9700">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall ensure that
			 women members of the Armed Forces
			 have access to counseling on the full range of methods of contraception
			 provided by health care providers described in subsection (a) during
			 health care visits, including, but not limited to, visits as follows:</text>
        <paragraph id="id001f5e40d1794482b1bd1753a1bdd338">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>During predeployment health care visits, with the counseling to be provided during such visits
			 emphasizing the interaction between anticipated deployment conditions and
			 various methods of contraception.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="id8439137aaab14a808f76512c6af7c84e">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>During health care visits during deployment.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="id90b4ad03918e48aaab789476040a97c4">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <text>During annual physical examinations.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="id663bf69b5ebc499d9a9fc08b2481bf85">
        <enum>(e)</enum>
        <header>Incorporation into surveys of questions on servicewomen experiences with family planning services
			 and counseling</header>
        <paragraph id="idcab1a89551014fa59b345ec976f9b4bd">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>In general</header>
          <text>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="9700">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> shall integrate
			 into the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="9700" entity-type="federal-body">Department of Defense</cato:entity-ref> surveys specified in paragraph (2)
			 questions designed
			 to obtain information on the experiences of  women members of the Armed
			 Forces—</text>
          <subparagraph id="id0BE2C55A7D5A4CF9B08AB361205DF6A8">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>in accessing family planning services and counseling;</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="id8F6E7EE5BA334FE28B0796651034F9C4">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>in using family planning methods, which method was preferred and whether deployment conditions
			 affected the decision on which family planning method or methods to be
			 used; and</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="id2C6E5DD3B86240969CC9321C90395258">
            <enum>(C)</enum>
            <text>if pregnant, whether the pregnancy was intended.</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="id5d14c92f506541c5bd47eb06cff2afe0">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Covered surveys</header>
          <text>The surveys into which questions shall be integrated as described in paragraph (1) are the
			 following:</text>
          <subparagraph id="idaf754466f1b34a0abe4dbbe8648621e4">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>The Health Related Behavior Survey of Active Duty Military Personnel.</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="idc0d77b1af411414daf2c87278cce0cd8">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>The Health Care Survey of <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="9700" entity-type="federal-body">Department of Defense</cato:entity-ref> Beneficiaries.</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
    </section>
    <section id="id1A73CACF9A7A424D9241F0E5452DC6B0">
      <enum>6.</enum>
      <header>Education on family planning for members of the Armed Forces</header>
      <subsection id="id27BB09E35E6546979B860D45D3502E4E">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Education program</header>
        <paragraph id="idB437F949A737452788E2EB993A42ED5A">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>In general</header>
          <text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="9700" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of Defense</cato:entity-ref> shall
			 establish
			 an education program for all members of the Armed Forces, including both
			 men and women members, consisting of
			 a uniform standard curriculum on family planning.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="idB0A5DC13CB9848F9A985BC2DADF92399">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Sense of Congress</header>
          <text>It is the sense of Congress that the standard curriculum should
			 use the latest technology available to efficiently and effectively deliver
			 information to members of the Armed Forces.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="id3f584745d01041fc9fa5b9caf1545d22">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Elements</header>
        <text>The standard curriculum under subsection (a) shall include the following:</text>
        <paragraph id="id59e6bc8b23bf49e99350fa1ce5cb3637">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>Information on the importance of providing comprehensive family planning for members of the Armed
			 Forces, and their commanding officers, and on the positive impact family
			 planning can have on the health and readiness of the Armed Forces.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="ida0c55b74faf7495f8e2203c445934cc5">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>Current, medically accurate information.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="id56483c149e944bca8cf1e31f5f9bbd52">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <text>Clear, user-friendly information on the full range of methods of contraception and where members of
			 the Armed Forces can access their chosen
			 method of
			 contraception.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="idb8d1a4167561444086319eb447290bce">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
          <text>Information on all applicable laws and policies so that members are informed of their rights and
			 obligations.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="id8f46e53ff48043cea70e50403823847a">
          <enum>(5)</enum>
          <text>Information on patients’ rights to confidentiality.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="idf7c8a594d7f5485296709ac19b2c8c57">
          <enum>(6)</enum>
          <text>Information on the unique circumstances encountered by members of the Armed Forces, and the effects
			 of such circumstances on the use of contraception.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
    </section>
    <section id="id06B749FC81644AF38003A8B88DDFEB66">
      <enum>7.</enum>
      <header>Pregnancy prevention assistance at military treatment facilities for women who are sexual
			 assault survivors</header>
      <subsection id="id81179D0F81644B36B87129A1B6460EBD">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Purpose</header>
        <text>The purpose of this section is to provide in statute, and to enhance, existing regulations that
			 require health care providers at military treatment facilities to consult
			 with survivors of sexual assault once clinically stable regarding options
			 for emergency contraception and any necessary follow-up care, including
			 the provision of the emergency contraception.</text>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="idC5E8863F77B8479B9D408D963018A60C">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>In general</header>
        <text>The assistance specified in subsection (c) shall be provided at every military treatment facility
			 to the following:</text>
        <paragraph id="id3BEBC4B9EB98463687847E30BFE389E6">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>Any woman who presents at a military treatment facility  and states to personnel of the facility
			 that she is a victim of sexual assault or is accompanied by another
			 individual who states that the woman is a victim of sexual assault.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id442651F0A4014125A063C75331E758A6">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>Any woman who presents at a military treatment facility and is reasonably believed by personnel of
			 such
			 facility to be a survivor of sexual assault.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="idCF6EA41313054C41AFE1F828D972DD83">
        <enum>(c)</enum>
        <header>Assistance</header>
        <paragraph id="id49db1dede42644a88c03bd8d7ddd1874">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>In general</header>
          <text>The assistance specified in this subsection shall include the following:</text>
          <subparagraph id="idB361136A6ADF4F21AC55E22DA4A10A8A">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>The prompt provision by appropriate staff
			 of the military treatment facility of comprehensive, medically and
			 factually accurate, and unbiased written and oral information about all
			 methods of emergency contraception approved by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="7524" entity-type="federal-body">Food and Drug
			 Administration</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="id9E98B9D7E1234849AA3A11B4F2B18A14">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>The prompt provision by such staff of emergency contraception to
			 a woman upon her request.</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="id8EC81E7A8E3244CA92627FA217BD4E9D">
            <enum>(C)</enum>
            <text>Notification to the woman of her right
			 to confidentiality in the receipt of care and services pursuant to this
			 section.</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="id83203416F1484C12BE51668FBFDA3079">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Nature of information</header>
          <text>The information provided pursuant to paragraph (1)(A) shall be provided in language that is clear
			 and
			 concise, is readily comprehensible, and meets such conditions (including
			 conditions regarding the provision of information in languages other than
			 English) as the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="9700">Secretary</cato:entity-ref> may provide in the regulations under this
			 section.</text>
				</paragraph>
      </subsection>
    </section>
  </legis-body>
</bill>
</doc>