<doc>
  <docmeta id="113sres502ats">
    <bill congress="113" type="sres" number="502" version="ats"/>
    <revision size="5686" annotations="0" status="complete" id="4" commit-time="2014-08-29T18:20:22Z" committer="mnewby" doc="113sres502ats/4.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <resolution xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution">
  <metadata>
<dublinCore>
<dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">113 SRES 502 ATS: Concerning the suspension of exit permit issuance by the Government of the Democratic Republic of Congo for adopted Congolese children seeking to depart the country with their adoptive parents.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">2014-07-15</dc:date>
<dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code>
    <congress>113th CONGRESS</congress>
    <session>2d Session</session>
    <legis-num>S. RES. 502</legis-num>
    <current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
    <action>
      <action-date date="20140715">July 15, 2014</action-date>
      <action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="S349">Mr. Portman</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S258">Ms. Landrieu</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S289">Mr. Alexander</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S340">Ms. Ayotte</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S354">Ms. Baldwin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S317">Mr. Barrasso</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S341">Mr. Blumenthal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S342">Mr. Blunt</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S343">Mr. Boozman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S223">Mrs. Boxer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S307">Mr. Brown</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S300">Mr. Burr</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S275">Ms. Cantwell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S290">Mr. Chambliss</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S212">Mr. Coats</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S252">Ms. Collins</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S310">Mr. Corker</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S287">Mr. Cornyn</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S266">Mr. Crapo</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S355">Mr. Cruz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S356">Mr. Donnelly</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S253">Mr. Durbin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S254">Mr. Enzi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S221">Mrs. Feinstein</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S357">Mrs. Fischer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S332">Mr. Franken</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S331">Mrs. Gillibrand</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S153">Mr. Grassley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S320">Mrs. Hagan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S172">Mr. Harkin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S236">Mr. Inhofe</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S321">Mr. Johanns</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S345">Mr. Johnson of Wisconsin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S363">Mr. King</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S339">Mr. Kirk</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S311">Ms. Klobuchar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S131">Mr. Levin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S369">Mr. Markey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S312">Mrs. McCaskill</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S197">Mr. McCain</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S174">Mr. McConnell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S182">Ms. Mikulski</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S347">Mr. Moran</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S288">Ms. Murkowski</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S364">Mr. Murphy</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S348">Mr. Paul</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S350">Mr. Rubio</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S284">Ms. Stabenow</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S314">Mr. Tester</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S303">Mr. Thune</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S299">Mr. Vitter</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S371">Mr. Walsh</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S327">Mr. Warner</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S366">Ms. Warren</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S318">Mr. Wicker</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S360">Ms. Heitkamp</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S344">Mr. Hoeven</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S229">Mrs. Murray</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S351">Mr. Toomey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S118">Mr. Hatch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S136">Mr. Cochran</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S324">Mrs. Shaheen</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations</committee-name>
      </action-desc>
    </action>
    <action stage="Reported-in-Senate">
      <action-date>July 29, 2014</action-date>
      <action-desc>Reported by <sponsor name-id="S306">Mr. Menendez</sponsor>, with an amendment and an amendment to the preamble</action-desc>
      <action-instruction>Strike out all after the resolving clause and insert the part printed in italic</action-instruction>
      <action-instruction>Strike the preamble and insert the part printed in italic</action-instruction>
    </action>
    <action>
      <action-date>July 31, 2014</action-date>
      <action-desc>Considered, amended, and agreed to with an amended preamble</action-desc>
    </action>
    <legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
    <official-title display="yes">Concerning the suspension of exit permit issuance by the Government of the Democratic Republic of
			 Congo for adopted Congolese children seeking to depart the country with
			 their adoptive parents.</official-title>
  </form>
  <preamble>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas according to UNICEF, over 4,000,000 orphans are estimated to be living in the Democratic
			 Republic of Congo;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas cyclical and violent conflict has plagued the Democratic Republic of Congo since the
			 mid-1990s;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the United States has made significant financial investments in the Democratic Republic of
			 Congo, providing an estimated $274,000,000 bilateral aid to the Democratic
			 Republic of Congo in fiscal year 2013 and an additional $165,000,000 in
			 emergency humanitarian assistance;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the policy of the United States Government toward the Democratic Republic of Congo is <quote>focused on helping the country become a nation that … provides for the basic needs of its citizens</quote>;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the <cato:entity-ref entity-id="19UN" entity-type="federal-body">United Nations</cato:entity-ref>, the Hague Conference on Private International Law, and other
			 international organizations have recognized that a child should grow up in
			 a family environment;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas adoption, both domestic and international, is an important child protection tool and an
			 integral part of child welfare best practices around the world, along with
			 family reunification and prevention of abandonment;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas, on September 27, 2013, the Congolese Ministry of Interior and Security, General
			 Directorate
			 of Migration, informed the United States Embassy in Kinshasa that
			 effective September 25, 2013, they had suspended issuance of exit permits
			 to adopted Congolese children seeking to depart the country with their
			 adoptive parents;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas there are United States families with finalized adoptions in the Democratic Republic of the
			 Congo and the necessary legal paperwork and visas ready to travel home
			 with these children but are currently unable to do so; and</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas, on December 19, 2013, the Congolese Minister of Justice, Minister of Interior and
			 Security,
			 and the General Directorate of Migration confirmed to members of the
			 <cato:entity-ref entity-id="1900" entity-type="federal-body">United
			 States Department of State</cato:entity-ref> that the current suspension on the issuance of
			 exit permits continues: Now, therefore, be it</text>
    </whereas>
  </preamble>
  <resolution-body>
    <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="S1" section-type="undesignated-section">
      <enum/>
      <text>That the <cato:entity-ref entity-id="0010" entity-type="federal-body">Senate</cato:entity-ref>—</text>
      <paragraph id="id43e1f386-5939-471e-b398-e40e8e7b2a7b">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">affirms that all children deserve a safe, loving, and permanent family;</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="ideb58a3ab-6515-4330-a741-1a2badcfb749">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recognizes the importance of ensuring that international adoptions of all children are conducted in
			 an ethical and transparent manner;</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="idf0e80697-db28-4366-b32f-4c80f600d686">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <text>expresses concern over the impact on children and families caused by the current suspension of exit
			 permit issuance within the Democratic Republic of Congo;</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id17c423c8-2c5d-4e12-967f-34da723e1059">
        <enum>(4)</enum>
        <text>respectfully requests that the Government of the Democratic Republic of Congo—</text>
        <subparagraph id="idb408dfa4-456f-46d2-b2fc-7250c017c4b4">
          <enum>(A)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">resume processing adoption cases and issuing exit permits via the Ministry of Gender and Family’s
			 Interministerial Adoption Committee and General Directorate of Migration;</text>
        </subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="id88d900b0-6208-436f-8123-ecb031d7d0a5">
          <enum>(B)</enum>
          <text>prioritize the processing of intercountry adoptions which were initiated before the suspension; and</text>
        </subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="id67d8236e-326b-42de-874f-e4dc0abbe9ab">
          <enum>(C)</enum>
          <text>expedite the processing of those adoptions which involve medically fragile children; and</text>
        </subparagraph>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idca4169ea-045b-4b56-a9df-fce5db5025f7">
        <enum>(5)</enum>
        <text>encourages continued dialogue and cooperation between the <cato:entity-ref entity-id="1900" entity-type="federal-body">United States Department of State</cato:entity-ref> and the
			 Democratic Republic of the Congo's Ministry of Foreign Affairs to improve
			 the intercountry adoption process and ensure the welfare of all children
			 adopted from the Democratic Republic of Congo.</text>
      </paragraph>
    </section>
  </resolution-body>
</resolution>
</doc>