<doc>
  <docmeta id="113s2142is">
    <bill congress="113" type="s" number="2142" version="is"/>
    <revision size="17181" annotations="0" status="complete" id="4" commit-time="2014-04-11T17:47:50Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113s2142is/4.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public">
	<metadata>
<dublinCore>
<dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">113 S2142 IS: Venezuela Defense of Human Rights and Civil Society Act of 2014</dc:title>
<dc:publisher xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">2014-03-13</dc:date>
<dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
		<congress>113th CONGRESS</congress>
    <session>2d Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. 2142</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20140313">March 13, 2014</action-date>
			<action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="S306">Mr. Menendez</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S350">Mr. Rubio</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S282">Mr. Nelson</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S339">Mr. Kirk</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations</committee-name>
      </action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To impose targeted sanctions on persons responsible for violations of human rights of
			 antigovernment protesters in Venezuela, to strengthen civil society in
			 Venezuela, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body>
		<section id="S1" section-type="section-one">
      <enum>1.</enum>
      <header>Short title</header>
			<text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the
		  <quote>
          <short-title>
            <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Venezuela Defense of Human Rights and Civil Society Act of 2014" proposed="true">Venezuela Defense of Human Rights and Civil Society Act of 2014</cato:entity-ref>
          </short-title>
        </quote>.</text>
    </section>
    <section id="idf153a885ce3b4f3eb031fbab71653886">
      <enum>2.</enum>
      <header>Findings</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">
        <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> makes the following findings:</text>
      <paragraph id="id1f818340005047ff85c69902bbc3a79b">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text>The Central Bank of Venezuela and the National Statistical Institute of Venezuela have stated that
			 the inflation rate in Venezuela was 56.30 percent in 2013, the  highest
			 level of inflation in the Western Hemisphere and the third highest level
			 of inflation in the world behind South Sudan and Syria.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id78c754b30a7b4c08b00c51d2980972ba">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text>The Central Bank of Venezuela and the Government of Venezuela have imposed  a series of currency
			 controls that has exacerbated economic problems and, according to the
			 World Economic Forum, has become the most problematic factor for doing
			 business in Venezuela.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id8d8646ec00b3470c905ec6eaccba8468">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <text>The Central Bank of Venezuela and the National Statistical Institute of Venezuela have declared
			 that the scarcity index of Venezuela reached 28 percent in December 2013,
			 which signifies that one in 4 basic goods is  unavailable at any given
			 time.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id89789339fb9a4618b688b0a613ddb8e4">
        <enum>(4)</enum>
        <text>Since 1999, violent crime in Venezuela has risen sharply and the Venezuelan Violence Observatory,
			 an independent nongovernmental organization, found the national per capita
			 murder rate to be 79 per 100,000 people in 2013.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id0cb2f43746b440e69ae61e143c5ff071">
        <enum>(5)</enum>
        <text>The international nongovernmental organization Human Rights Watch recently stated, <quote>Under the leadership of President Chàvez and now President Maduro, the accumulation of power in the
			 executive branch and the erosion of human rights guarantees have enabled
			 the government to intimidate, censor, and prosecute its critics.</quote>.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="iddea4ed324a0b42c28e0bdb58b02f79b5">
        <enum>(6)</enum>
        <text>The Country Reports on Human Rights Practices for 2013 of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1900" entity-type="federal-body">Department of State</cato:entity-ref> maintained that
			 in Venezuela <quote>the government did not respect judicial independence or permit judges to act according to the law
			 without fear of retaliation</quote> and <quote>the government used the judiciary to intimidate and selectively prosecute political, union,
			 business, and civil society leaders who were critical of government
			 policies or actions</quote>.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id1757fbbd659a44329cb72fe8311c874e">
        <enum>(7)</enum>
        <text>The Government of Venezuela has detained foreign journalists and threatened and expelled
			 international media outlets operating in Venezuela, and the international
			 nongovernmental organization Freedom House declared that Venezuela’s <quote>media climate is permeated by intimidation, sometimes including physical attacks, and strong
			 antimedia rhetoric by the government is common</quote>.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="idbeeab76a90684215902f0ec1d943481c">
        <enum>(8)</enum>
        <text>Since February 4, 2014, the Government of Venezuela has responded to antigovernment protests with
			 violence and killings perpetrated by public security forces, and by
			 arresting and unjustly charging opposition leader Leopoldo Lopes with
			 criminal incitement, conspiracy, arson, and intent to damage property.</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="idca6fe86848314564a3cb2bc82fb9b14d">
        <enum>(9)</enum>
        <text>As of March 13, 2014, 23 people had been killed, more than 100 people had been injured, and dozens
			 had been unjustly detained as a result of antigovernment demonstrations
			 throughout Venezuela.</text>
      </paragraph>
    </section>
    <section id="idcfb290ad288747a68e58020a163a47ea">
      <enum>3.</enum>
      <header>Sense of Congress regarding antigovernment protests in Venezuela and the need to prevent further
			 violence in Venezuela</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> that—</text>
      <paragraph id="id67932a1c54cb4272942b5ecd23d6149c">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text>the United States aspires to a mutually beneficial relationship with Venezuela based on respect for
			 human rights and the rule of law and  a functional and productive
			 relationship on issues of public security, including counternarcotics and
			 counterterrorism;</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id61CE8CFAC21349E89296DFCD48DF0D4D">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text>the United States
			 supports the people of Venezuela in their efforts to realize their full
			 economic potential and to advance representative democracy, human rights,
			 and the rule of law within their country;</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="idea0b684dd7a24c25b101401d7f7340dc">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <text>the chronic mismanagement by the Government of Venezuela of its economy has produced conditions of
			 economic hardship and scarcity of basic goods and foodstuffs for the
			 people of Venezuela;</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="ide1cb074a8b8d47d8930e3cb972d9fc2e">
        <enum>(4)</enum>
        <text>the failure of the Government of Venezuela to guarantee minimal standards of public security for
			 its citizens has led the country to become one of the most violent in the
			 world;</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id0e5a69b4a4524ed79376f956e0d7762a">
        <enum>(5)</enum>
        <text>the Government of Venezuela continues to take steps to remove checks and balances on the
			 executive, politicize the judiciary, undermine the independence of the
			 legislature through use of executive decree powers, persecute and
			 prosecute its political opponents, curtail freedom of the press, and limit
			 the free expression of its citizens;</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id755715e4660946668d41baee026fb7e8">
        <enum>(6)</enum>
        <text>the people of Venezuela, responding to ongoing economic hardship, high levels of crime and
			 violence, and the lack of basic political rights and individual freedoms,
			 have turned out in demonstrations in Caracas and throughout the country to
			 protest the inability of the Government of Venezuela to ensure the
			 political and economic well-being of its citizens; and</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id8c12ec5750a94ad2a61ca42fa03cb125">
        <enum>(7)</enum>
        <text>the repeated use of violence perpetrated by the National Guard and security personnel of Venezuela,
			 as well as persons acting on behalf of the Government of Venezuela, in
			 relation to the antigovernment protests that began on February 4, 2014, is
			 intolerable and the use of unprovoked violence by protesters is also a
			 matter of serious concern.</text>
      </paragraph>
    </section>
    <section id="id76a7a3f812994ca7b133fae0ab4693aa">
      <enum>4.</enum>
      <header>United States policy toward Venezuela</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the policy of the United States—</text>
      <paragraph id="id6838f660373549608e4ac262e9b9ceba">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text>to support the people of Venezuela in their aspiration to live under conditions of peace and
			 representative democracy as defined by the Inter-American Democratic
			 Charter of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="19AS" entity-type="federal-body">Organization of American States</cato:entity-ref>;</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id2c9bae5f1019413fb9db4aed795b4b0b">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text>to work in concert with the other member states within the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="19AS" entity-type="federal-body">Organization of American States</cato:entity-ref>, as
			 well as the countries of the European Union, to ensure the peaceful
			 resolution of the current situation in Venezuela and the immediate
			 cessation of violence against antigovernment protestors;</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="idf4fc81e7dff7494f84c9be51dd9859c0">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <text>to hold accountable government and security officials in Venezuela responsible for or complicit in
			 the use of force in relation
			 to the antigovernment protests that began on February 4, 2014, and similar
			 future acts of violence; and</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="idb95722d22fab4e8bbcadc8ffac387ac5">
        <enum>(4)</enum>
        <text>to continue to support the development of democratic political processes and independent civil
			 society
			 in Venezuela.</text>
      </paragraph>
    </section>
    <section id="id25d5241c633b48eea8fbb7d29bc585b0">
      <enum>5.</enum>
      <header>Sanctions on persons responsible for violence in Venezuela</header>
      <subsection id="id1ce0a2ce035e40ddb1cfbe4c8e6ffbf1">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>In general</header>
        <text>The President shall impose the sanctions described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Venezuela Defense of Human Rights and Civil Society Act of 2014/s:5/ss:b" proposed="true">subsection (b)</cato:entity-ref> with respect to any person,
			 including a current or former official of the Government of Venezuela or a
			 person acting on behalf of that Government, that the President determines—</text>
        <paragraph id="id85059a16d5094474b327d394939dde8d">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>has perpetrated, or is responsible for ordering, controlling, or otherwise directing, significant
			 acts of violence or serious human rights abuses in Venezuela against
			 persons associated
			 with the antigovernment protests in Venezuela that began on February 4,
			 2014;</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="ide134cd9196a840799e00650db0e08392">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>has directed or ordered the arrest or prosecution of a person primarily because of the person's
			 legitimate
			 exercise of freedom of expression or assembly; or</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="ide4b0a03dcc6848bb8a852e020a486357">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <text>has materially assisted, sponsored, or provided significant financial, material, or
			 technological support for, or goods or services in support of, the
			 commission of acts described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Venezuela Defense of Human Rights and Civil Society Act of 2014/s:5/ss:a/p:1" proposed="true">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref> or <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Venezuela Defense of Human Rights and Civil Society Act of 2014/s:5/ss:a/p:2" proposed="true">(2)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="id3cf2f55d6ba648e9b3616308eefdb144">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Sanctions described</header>
        <paragraph id="id2c8c8b0b9737439fa42d54e07879112f">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>In general</header>
          <text>The sanctions described in this subsection are the following:</text>
          <subparagraph id="iddf3a0aa3fde0473a80379a39206c3b6e">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <header>Asset blocking</header>
            <text>The exercise of all powers granted to the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> by the <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="International Emergency Economic Powers Act">International Emergency Economic Powers
			 Act</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/50/1701/etseq">50 U.S.C. 1701 et seq</cato:entity-ref>.</external-xref>)</cato:entity> to the extent necessary to block and prohibit
			 all transactions in all property and interests in property of a person
			 determined by the President to be subject to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Venezuela Defense of Human Rights and Civil Society Act of 2014/s:5/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref> if such
			 property and interests in property are in the United States, come within
			 the United States, or are or come within the possession or control of a
			 United States person.</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="id0a1c532fabd2412bb76cd4c305a48a7d">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <header>Exclusion from the United States and revocation of visa or other documentation</header>
            <text>In the case of an alien determined by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> to be subject to subsection (a), denial of a
			 visa to, and exclusion from the United States of, the alien, and
			 revocation in accordance with <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Immigration and Nationality Act/s:221/ss:i">section 221(i) of the Immigration and
			 Nationality Act</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1201">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/8/1201/i">8 U.S.C. 1201(i)</cato:entity-ref>
              </external-xref>)</cato:entity>, of any visa or other documentation of
			 the alien.</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="id93b3e8e2906d4967a0944ba7ece3bc49">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Penalties</header>
          <text>A person that violates, attempts to violate, conspires to violate, or causes a violation of
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Venezuela Defense of Human Rights and Civil Society Act of 2014/s:5/ss:b/p:1/sp:A" proposed="true">paragraph (1)(A)</cato:entity-ref> or any regulation, license, or order issued to carry out
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Venezuela Defense of Human Rights and Civil Society Act of 2014/s:5/ss:b/p:1/sp:A" proposed="true">paragraph (1)(A)</cato:entity-ref> shall be subject to the penalties set forth in
			 <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="International Emergency Economic Powers Act/s:206/ss:b">subsections (b)</cato:entity-ref> and <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="International Emergency Economic Powers Act/s:206/ss:c">(c) of section 206 of the International Emergency
			 Economic Powers Act</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1705">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/50/1705">50 U.S.C. 1705</cato:entity-ref>
            </external-xref>)</cato:entity> to the same extent as a person that
			 commits an unlawful act described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="International Emergency Economic Powers Act/s:206/ss:a">subsection (a) of that section</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="idcba6207f8218472097d937e06607504c">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <header>Exception to comply with united nations headquarters agreement</header>
          <text>Sanctions under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Venezuela Defense of Human Rights and Civil Society Act of 2014/s:5/ss:b/p:1/sp:B" proposed="true">paragraph (1)(B)</cato:entity-ref> shall not apply to an alien if admitting the alien into the United
			 States is necessary to permit the United States to comply with the
			 Agreement regarding the Headquarters of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="19UN" entity-type="federal-body">United Nations</cato:entity-ref>, signed at Lake
			 Success June 26, 1947, and entered into force November 21, 1947, between
			 the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="19UN" entity-type="federal-body">United Nations</cato:entity-ref> and the United States, or other applicable
			 international obligations.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="id6f240cecc4dc4a5ea303553053a1bd32">
        <enum>(c)</enum>
        <header>Waiver</header>
        <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> may waive the application of sanctions under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Venezuela Defense of Human Rights and Civil Society Act of 2014/s:5/ss:b" proposed="true">subsection (b)</cato:entity-ref> with respect to a person
			 if the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref>—</text>
        <paragraph id="id47386cd358c347129276db896348e97e">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>determines that such a waiver is in the national security interests of the United States; and</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="idc16a07b1b7bb40c2a24dbaf397cca587">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>on or before the date on which the waiver takes effect, submits to the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="committee" entity-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign
			 Relations</cato:entity-ref> and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="committee" entity-id="SSBK00">Committee on Banking Housing, and Urban Affairs of the
			 Senate</cato:entity-ref> and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="committee" entity-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</cato:entity-ref> and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="committee" entity-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial
			 Services of the House of Representatives</cato:entity-ref> a notice  of and justification
			 for the waiver.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="id80a42232eea84d15abab54224a565c2e">
        <enum>(d)</enum>
        <header>Regulatory authority</header>
        <text>The President shall issue such regulations, licenses, and orders as are necessary to carry out this
			 section.</text>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="id1554c47c0dd942589364924018faba8b">
        <enum>(e)</enum>
        <header>Definitions</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text>
        <paragraph id="id36a125992bbf42199f526d1ce1f09e90">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>Admitted; alien</header>
          <text>The terms <term>admitted</term> and <term>alien</term> have the meanings given those terms in <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Immigration and Nationality Act/s:101">section 101 of the Immigration and Nationality Act</cato:entity-ref> (<cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/8/1101">8
			 U.S.C. 1101</cato:entity-ref>)</cato:entity>.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="id5b4269eb9c524016bca041f6ee4f8377">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Financial institution</header>
          <text>The term <term>financial institution</term> has the meaning given that term in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc/31/5312">
              <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/31/5312">section 5312</external-xref> of title 31, United States Code</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="id154078bbeab3487fb9fcbbb39616d8b4">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <header>Materially assisted</header>
          <text>The term <term>materially assisted</term> means the provision of assistance that is significant and of a kind directly relevant to acts
			 described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Venezuela Defense of Human Rights and Civil Society Act of 2014/s:5/ss:a/p:1" proposed="true">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref> or <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Venezuela Defense of Human Rights and Civil Society Act of 2014/s:5/ss:a/p:2" proposed="true">(2) of subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="ide969c32cb13e413a8cc072c6c701d190">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
          <header>United states person</header>
          <text>The term <term>United States person</term> means—</text>
          <subparagraph id="iddc3d42a94fb04f94a10d019d55eb8434">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>a United States citizen or an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence to the United States;
			 or</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide47704df168640b5a06d0f02fa85a580">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>an entity organized under the laws of the United States or of any jurisdiction within the United
			 States, including a foreign branch of such an entity.</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
    </section>
    <section id="idf6ded5ae26234a6facc75193af7fad0f">
      <enum>6.</enum>
      <header>Support for civil society in Venezuela</header>
      <subsection id="idf413f60d57144e93bf6e540f6468d08f">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>In general</header>
        <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1900" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref>	shall, subject to the availability of appropriations, directly or through 
			 nongovernmental organizations—</text>
        <paragraph id="id61af59d30f304d2ea2ad1ac345e4f59e">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>defend internationally recognized human rights for the people of Venezuela;</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="id5B758BEAAF4F4496A8DCE228E82305C1">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>build the organizational and operational capacity of democratic civil society activists and
			 organizations in
			 Venezuela at the national and	regional level;</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="id6c70216a68e04f19b5f6bd171c4b537b">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <text>support the efforts of independent media outlets to broadcast, distribute, and share information
			 beyond the limited channels made available by the Government of Venezuela;</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="id2816814a787943d3bda88d9830d74872">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
          <text>facilitate open and uncensored access to the Internet for the people of Venezuela;</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="id84bc18c3a4714a358973c51346db05f6">
          <enum>(5)</enum>
          <text>improve transparency and accountability of institutions that are part of the Government of
			 Venezuela;</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="id7b9676f38fb4484ab1785e773da979ed">
          <enum>(6)</enum>
          <text>provide support to civil society organizations, activists, and peaceful demonstrators in Venezuela
			 that have been targeted for exercising internationally recognized civil
			 and political rights, as well as journalists targeted for activities
			 related to the work of a free press; and</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="idbb5bf28f86d84892bc5923c2a1b5b9db">
          <enum>(7)</enum>
          <text>provide support for democratic political organizing and election monitoring in Venezuela.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="id32f0d104c4734f1da56af0f890a53f02">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Strategy requirement</header>
        <text>Not later than 60 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> shall submit a
			 strategy to carry out the activities described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Venezuela Defense of Human Rights and Civil Society Act of 2014/s:6/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref> to—</text>
        <paragraph id="idDE63AD8D376F4F68A9D830C750B45D33">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="committee" entity-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate</cato:entity-ref> and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="committee" entity-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House
			 of Representatives</cato:entity-ref>; and</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id032DE581C54F4803991042B8DC6745D2">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="committee" entity-id="SSAP00">Committee on Appropriations of the Senate</cato:entity-ref> and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="committee" entity-id="HAP00">Committee on Appropriations of the House of
			 Representatives</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="id301f689f179b497a8a0ea567e2e6a876">
        <enum>(c)</enum>
        <header>Authorization of appropriations</header>
        <paragraph id="id51032588214a42719c8007b33c968e3b">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>In general</header>
          <text>
            <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="auth-auth-approp">There is  authorized to be appropriated to the <cato:entity-ref entity-id="1900" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref> <cato:funds-and-year amount="15000000" year="2015">$15,000,000 for fiscal year 2015</cato:funds-and-year>
			 <cato:property name="purpose">to carry out <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Venezuela Defense of Human Rights and Civil Society Act of 2014/s:6/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref>
              </cato:property>.  Amounts appropriated for the activities set
			 forth in <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Venezuela Defense of Human Rights and Civil Society Act of 2014/s:6/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref> shall be used pursuant to the authorization and
			 requirements contained in this section.  Additional amounts may be
			 authorized to be appropriated under provisions of law.</cato:entity>
          </text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="id5e7e389d80d649dc849a73d7228420cb">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Notification requirement</header>
          <subparagraph id="id80faff48c28f453fa097a770703b3baa">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <header>In general</header>
            <text>Funds appropriated or otherwise made available pursuant to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Venezuela Defense of Human Rights and Civil Society Act of 2014/s:6/ss:c/p:1" proposed="true">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref> may not be obligated
			 until	until 15 days after the date on which the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> has provided
			 notice of intent to obligate such funds to—</text>
            <clause id="idb9a1ee5757f04e24913814813f6d8875">
              <enum>(i)</enum>
              <text>the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="committee" entity-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate</cato:entity-ref> and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="committee" entity-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House
			 of Representatives</cato:entity-ref>; and</text>
            </clause>
            <clause id="id5aab973af1b94f999930982fdd4a2fe4">
              <enum>(ii)</enum>
              <text>the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="committee" entity-id="SSAP00">Committee on Appropriations of the Senate</cato:entity-ref> and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="committee" entity-id="HAP00">Committee on Appropriations of the House of
			 Representatives</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
            </clause>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="id74e3aabde16149afbc942e25a3b29520">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <header>Waiver</header>
            <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> may waive the requirement under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Venezuela Defense of Human Rights and Civil Society Act of 2014/s:6/ss:c/p:2/sp:A" proposed="true">subparagraph (A)</cato:entity-ref>	if the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> determines that
			 failure to waive that requirement would pose a substantial risk to human
			 health or welfare, in which case notification shall be provided as early
			 as practicable, but in no event later than 3 days after taking the action
			 to which such notification requirement was applicable in the context of
			 the circumstances necessitating such waiver.</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
    </section>
  </legis-body>
</bill>
</doc>