<doc>
  <docmeta id="113sres32ats">
    <bill congress="113" type="sres" number="32" version="ats"/>
    <revision size="2752" annotations="0" status="complete" id="3" commit-time="2013-08-10T23:06:01Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113sres32ats/3.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <resolution xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution">
	<metadata>
<dublinCore>
<title>113 SRES 32 ATS: Congratulating the North Dakota State University football team for winning the 2012 National Collegiate Athletic Association Division I Football Championship Subdivision title.</title>
<publisher>U.S. Senate</publisher>
<date>2013-02-13</date>
<format>text/xml</format>
<language>EN</language>
<rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code>
		<congress>113th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. RES. 32</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20130213">February 13, 2013</action-date>
			<action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="S344">Mr. Hoeven</sponsor> (for himself
			 and <cosponsor name-id="S360">Ms. Heitkamp</cosponsor>) submitted the following
			 resolution; which was considered and agreed to</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">Congratulating the North Dakota State
		  University football team for winning the 2012 National Collegiate Athletic
		  Association Division I Football Championship Subdivision
		  title.</official-title>
	</form>
	<preamble>
		<whereas>
      <text>Whereas the North Dakota State University (referred to in
			 this preamble as <quote>NDSU</quote>) Bison won the 2012 National Collegiate
			 Athletic Association (referred to in this preamble as the <quote>NCAA</quote>)
			 Division I Football Championship Subdivision title game in Frisco, Texas, on
			 January 5, 2013, in a hard fought victory over the Sam Houston State University
			 Bearkats by a score of 39 to 13;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the NDSU Bison and coach Craig Bohl had an
			 incredible 2012 season with 14 wins and 1 defeat;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas NDSU has won 10 NCAA Football
			 Championships;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas, during the championship game, the NDSU Bison
			 offense scored 39 points against the Sam Houston State Bearkats;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas Coach Bohl and his staff have instilled character
			 and confidence in the NDSU players and have done an outstanding job with the
			 Bison football program;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the leadership of President Dean Bresciani and
			 Athletic Director Gene Taylor has helped bring both academic and athletic
			 excellence to NDSU; and</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the 2012 NCAA Division I Football Championship
			 Subdivision title was a victory not only for the NDSU football team, but also
			 for the entire State of North Dakota: Now, therefore, be it</text>
		</whereas>
  </preamble>
	<resolution-body>
		<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="S1" section-type="undesignated-section">
      <enum/>
      <text>That the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0010">Senate</cato:entity-ref>—</text>
			<paragraph id="ID30bd4c20e1454fb2a1b52e9544dada87">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text>congratulates the
			 North Dakota State University football team, the 2012 National Collegiate
			 Athletic Association Division I Football Championship Subdivision
			 champions;</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="IDcb2cc271692e4168856506ca1c94179b">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text>commends the
			 North Dakota State University players, coaches, and staff for their hard work
			 and dedication; and</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="ID1dd0c512a78c416196c3af24ed310591">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <text>recognizes the
			 students, alumni, and loyal fans for supporting the Bison on their successful
			 quest to capture another Division I trophy for North Dakota State
			 University.</text>
			</paragraph>
    </section>
  </resolution-body>
</resolution>
</doc>