<doc>
  <docmeta id="113sres35ats">
    <bill congress="113" type="sres" number="35" version="ats"/>
    <revision size="3728" annotations="0" status="complete" id="3" commit-time="2013-08-10T23:09:57Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113sres35ats/3.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <resolution xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>113 SRES 35 ATS: Congratulating the Baltimore Ravens for winning Super Bowl XLVII.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date/>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">113th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session display="yes">1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. RES. 35</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date>February 14, 2013</action-date>
			<action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="S308">Mr. Cardin</sponsor> (for himself
			 and <cosponsor name-id="S182">Ms. Mikulski</cosponsor>) submitted the following
			 resolution; which was considered and agreed to</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">Congratulating the Baltimore Ravens for
		  winning Super Bowl XLVII.</official-title>
	</form>
	<preamble>
		<whereas>
      <text>Whereas, on February 3, 2013, the Baltimore Ravens won
			 Super Bowl XLVII, defeating the San Francisco 49ers by a score of 34 to 31 at
			 the Mercedes-Benz Superdome in New Orleans, Louisiana;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas Super Bowl XLVII marks the second Super Bowl win
			 for the Baltimore Ravens, the third Super Bowl win for a Baltimore football
			 team, and the first time in history that siblings have coached opposing teams
			 in the Super Bowl;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the victory by the Baltimore Ravens was the
			 culmination of a regular season with 10 wins and 6 losses and a series of
			 exhilarating playoff performances;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the Baltimore Ravens exhibited a stellar offensive
			 performance, with 93 rushing yards and 274 passing yards;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the Baltimore Ravens' defense forced turnovers
			 that were critical to achieving a victory;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas middle linebacker Ray Lewis won his second Super
			 Bowl ring in his last game in the National Football League after recovering
			 from a torn tricep earlier in the season;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas linebacker Terrell Suggs tore his achilles tendon
			 in the offseason but made a full recovery to play in the Super Bowl;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas quarterback Joe Flacco led the Baltimore Ravens to
			 victory by throwing for a total of 287 yards, 3 touchdowns, and no
			 interceptions, earning the award for Most Valuable Player;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas receiver Jacoby Jones caught 1 pass for 56 yards
			 and a touchdown and returned a kickoff a record-tying 108 yards for another
			 touchdown;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas receiver Anquan Boldin caught 6 passes for 104
			 yards and a touchdown;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the Baltimore Ravens dedicated their play during
			 the season to the memories of Art Modell, the former owner, and Tevin Jones,
			 the brother of receiver Torrey Smith;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the leadership and vision of head coach John
			 Harbaugh propelled the Baltimore Ravens back to the pinnacle of professional
			 sports;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas members of the Baltimore Ravens organization have
			 helped their community through charitable work and advocacy; and</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the Baltimore Ravens have brought great pride and
			 honor to the City of Baltimore, its loyal fans, and the entire State of
			 Maryland: Now, therefore, be it</text>
		</whereas>
  </preamble>
	<resolution-body>
		<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="S1" section-type="undesignated-section">
      <enum/>
      <text>That the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0010">Senate</cato:entity-ref>—</text>
			<paragraph id="id65d019c804114a17ad184b11657a3c7a">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text>congratulates the
			 Baltimore Ravens for winning Super Bowl XLVII;</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="idf4c62095f5c6414f862c8e40e91cf6ce">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text>recognizes the
			 achievements of all the players, coaches, and staff who contributed to the 2012
			 championship season; and</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id572e9f96e30443a8a0ed0c68c1adc23f">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <text>requests that the
			 Secretary of the Senate prepare an enrolled version of this resolution for
			 presentation to—</text>
				<subparagraph id="id6a1f907c87f34543be4a13ba414f6532">
          <enum>(A)</enum>
          <text>the owner of the
			 Baltimore Ravens, Steve Biscotti;</text>
				</subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="id938772fc8a61414cb43a5c0811743288">
          <enum>(B)</enum>
          <text>the head coach of
			 the Baltimore Ravens, John Harbaugh; and</text>
				</subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="id2dd2cfeab2784a12888a0c736ccd658a">
          <enum>(C)</enum>
          <text>the now-retired
			 field leader of the Baltimore Ravens, Ray Lewis.</text>
				</subparagraph>
      </paragraph>
    </section>
  </resolution-body>
</resolution>
</doc>