<doc>
  <docmeta id="113sconres13is">
    <bill congress="113" type="sconres" number="13" version="is"/>
    <revision size="4385" annotations="0" status="complete" id="5" commit-time="2013-06-26T22:50:34Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113sconres13is/5.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <resolution xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" resolution-type="senate-concurrent" star-print="no-star-print">
	<metadata>
<dublinCore>
<title>113 SCON 13 IS: Commending the Boys ? Girls Clubs of America for its role in improving outcomes for millions of young people and thousands of communities.</title>
<publisher>U.S. Senate</publisher>
<date>2013-04-17</date>
<format>text/xml</format>
<language>EN</language>
<rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">113th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session display="yes">1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. CON. RES. 13</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20130417">April 17, 2013</action-date>
			<action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="S309">Mr. Casey</sponsor> (for himself,
			 <cosponsor name-id="S252">Ms. Collins</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S257">Mr. Johnson of South Dakota</cosponsor>,
			 <cosponsor name-id="S127">Mr. Baucus</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S319">Mr.
			 Begich</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S229">Mrs. Murray</cosponsor>,
			 <cosponsor name-id="S057">Mr. Leahy</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S295">Mr. Pryor</cosponsor>) submitted the following concurrent
			 resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>
      </action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>CONCURRENT RESOLUTION</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">Commending the Boys &amp; Girls Clubs of
		  America for its role in improving outcomes for millions of young people and
		  thousands of communities.</official-title>
	</form>
	<preamble>
		<whereas>
      <text>Whereas, in 1956, the Boys' Clubs of America celebrated
			 its 50th anniversary and became a federally chartered incorporation;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas, in 1991, the Federal charter of the Boys' Clubs
			 of America was amended to reflect the change of the name of the organization to
			 the Boys &amp; Girls Clubs of America;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the Boys &amp; Girls Clubs of America has
			 significantly improved the quality of life for many young people and has helped
			 to transform them into leaders and responsible citizens of the United
			 States;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the Boys &amp; Girls Clubs of America, through its
			 efforts in communities throughout the United States, has a significant impact
			 on the ability of young people to meet various challenges, including by helping
			 them graduate from high school, gain proficiency in science, technology,
			 engineering, and math, and develop skills for the 21st century;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas evaluations of specific programs conducted by, and
			 of the overall experience of participating in, the Boys &amp; Girls Clubs of
			 America demonstrate several positive outcomes linked to participation in the
			 organization, including reduction in delinquent behaviors, increased academic
			 achievement, increased access to and safe use of technology, broadened career
			 goals, and improved attitudes toward school;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the Boys &amp; Girls Clubs of America effectively
			 leverages limited Federal investment to support clubs in underfunded
			 communities, while raising the majority of its funding privately;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the Boys &amp; Girls Clubs of America serves
			 diverse groups of young people in urban, suburban, and rural communities, as
			 well as on military bases and Native American reservations;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the Boys &amp; Girls Clubs of America provides
			 stability, education, youth development, and prevention programs for children
			 of military personnel, who frequently relocate due to station changes and
			 deployments;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas, as of February 2013, there are 3,985 chartered
			 clubs serving approximately 4,100,000 young people; and</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas, on April 28, 2012, the Boys &amp; Girls Clubs of
			 America signed an agreement with For Inspiration and Recognition of Science and
			 Technology (commonly known as <term>FIRST</term>) to bring competitive robotics
			 programs to approximately 4,000,000 young people in the United States by 2015:
			 Now, therefore, be it</text>
		</whereas>
  </preamble>
	<resolution-body>
		<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="S1" section-type="undesignated-section">
      <enum/>
      <text>That the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref>—</text>
			<paragraph id="idE490C57F04FE45E19E6BCD35C6FC3D61">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text>commends the Boys
			 &amp; Girls Clubs of America for its work serving the young people of the
			 United States and strengthening thousands of communities;</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id78ED9E805906449198C28BBFEFB72D5A">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text>recognizes the
			 importance of high-impact mentoring of young people in ensuring positive
			 outcomes for young people of all backgrounds;</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="idF60EAC4776B44FDEABE495AB2B7125DC">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <text>supports
			 mentoring of young people as a strategy to prepare young people for education,
			 careers, and citizenship;</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id144EA88A599442B5B0358A5B889380AE">
        <enum>(4)</enum>
        <text>encourages the
			 Boys &amp; Girls Clubs of America to continue and expand programs that expose
			 young people to science, technology, engineering, and math; and</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="idE1C8CCADDBA7462A84E23C52CE4579F2">
        <enum>(5)</enum>
        <text>commits to
			 strengthening the partnership between the Boys &amp; Girls Clubs of America and
			 various Federal agencies and departments in order to serve an even greater
			 number of young people.</text>
			</paragraph>
    </section>
  </resolution-body>
</resolution>
</doc>