<doc>
  <docmeta id="113s1940is">
    <bill congress="113" type="s" number="1940" version="is"/>
    <revision size="3734" annotations="0" status="complete" id="3" commit-time="2014-01-22T18:51:41Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113s1940is/3.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" public-private="public">
  <metadata>
<dublinCore>
<dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">113 S1940 IS: Recruiting Individuals to Drive Our Elders Act of 2014</dc:title>
<dc:publisher xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">2014-01-16</dc:date>
<dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
    <congress>113th CONGRESS</congress>
    <session>2d Session</session>
    <legis-num>S. 1940</legis-num>
    <current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
    <action>
      <action-date date="20140116">January 16, 2014</action-date>
      <action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="S332">Mr. Franken</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S057">Mr. Leahy</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFI00">Committee on Finance</committee-name>
      </action-desc>
    </action>
    <legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
    <official-title>To provide reimbursement under the Medicaid program to individuals and entities that provide voluntary non-emergency medical transportation to Medicaid beneficiaries for expenses related to no-load travel.</official-title>
  </form>
  <legis-body>
    <section id="S1" section-type="section-one">
      <enum>1.</enum>
      <header>Short
			 title</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as
			 the <quote>
          <short-title>Recruiting Individuals to Drive Our Elders Act of 2014</short-title>
        </quote> or the <quote>
          <short-title>RIDE Act of 2014</short-title>
        </quote>.</text>
    </section>
    <section id="idC6B943F6DEAA4828BB6B4EF83B8727DB">
      <enum>2.</enum>
      <header>Reimbursement
			 for no-load travel costs incurred by volunteers providing non-emergency medical
			 transportation to Medicaid beneficiaries</header>
      <subsection id="idD80896CA72744613891CAA98CA84E13C">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>In
			 general</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90
			 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7500">Secretary of Health and Human
			 Services</cato:entity-ref> shall publish an interim final rule to revise the Medicaid
			 transportation regulations at sections <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/431">431.53</external-xref> and <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/440">440.170</external-xref> of title 42, Code of
			 Federal Regulations, as necessary, to allow a State plan for medical assistance
			 under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Social Security Act/t:XIX">title XIX of the Social Security Act</cato:entity-ref> to provide, at the option of the
			 State, reimbursement for costs attributable to providing no-load volunteer
			 travel services to individuals eligible for medical assistance under the State
			 plan who require transportation to receive non-emergency medical
			 treatment.</text>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="id3294C4F387654A2896823C50DC8E0AAD">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>No-Load
			 volunteer travel service</header>
        <text>For purposes of <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Recruiting Individuals to Drive Our Elders Act of 2014/s:2/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref>, the term
			 <term>no-load volunteer travel service</term> means travel services
			 that—</text>
        <paragraph id="id8C1B018A36C64F5B9B5A5BD32365B6DA">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>are provided by a
			 person who, as determined by a State, local, or tribal government, provides
			 such services on a volunteer basis (referred to in this subsection as a
			 <term>volunteer</term>); and</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="id3FC4E53C71AC4F9A8D21BBFCF1D21E55">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>are necessary for
			 the volunteer to—</text>
          <subparagraph id="id0D676936A25241128E541EE0A2682361">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>travel from the
			 originating location of the volunteer to the location of an individual who is
			 eligible for medical assistance under the State Medicaid plan and requires
			 transportation to receive non-emergency medical treatment (including, for
			 purposes of an individual who requested transportation to receive non-emergency
			 medical treatment and subsequently refused such transportation or was not
			 present at the requested pick-up location, any travel that is necessary for the
			 volunteer to return to their originating location);</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="id62C7E9619AB942AE946FB69EC0E8F1FD">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>for purposes of
			 an individual who has been provided transportation by the volunteer to receive
			 non-emergency medical treatment and is required to remain at the treatment
			 location overnight or for an extended period of time (as determined appropriate
			 by a State, local, or tribal government), return to the originating location of
			 the volunteer and, following the completion of such treatment, travel back to
			 the treatment location; and</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="id218A7813C63D4D46AA32F6B661CB3B5E">
            <enum>(C)</enum>
            <text>following any
			 transportation that is necessary to return an individual who has received
			 non-emergency medical treatment to their pick-up location, return to the
			 originating location of the volunteer.</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
    </section>
  </legis-body>
</bill>
</doc>