<doc>
  <docmeta id="113sconres43is">
    <bill congress="113" type="sconres" number="43" version="is"/>
    <revision size="3262" annotations="0" status="complete" id="4" commit-time="2014-10-24T16:29:56Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113sconres43is/4.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <resolution xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" resolution-type="senate-concurrent" star-print="no-star-print">
	<metadata>
<dublinCore>
<dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">113 SCON 43 IS: Expressing support for designation of a “National Lao-Hmong Recognition Day”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">2014-09-17</dc:date>
<dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">113th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session display="yes">2d Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. CON. RES. 43</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20140917" legis-day="20140916">September 17 (legislative day, September 16), 2014</action-date>
			<action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="S311">Ms. Klobuchar</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="S288">Ms. Murkowski</cosponsor>) submitted the following concurrent resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations</committee-name>
      </action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>CONCURRENT RESOLUTION</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">Expressing support for designation of a <quote>National Lao-Hmong Recognition Day</quote>.</official-title>
	</form>
	<preamble>
		<whereas>
      <text>Whereas the Lao-Hmong, which means <quote>free people</quote>, are Laotian members of the Hmong tribe and are noted for their warrior tradition, loyalty, and
			 bravery;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas beginning in 1960, the United States recruited thousands of the Lao-Hmong to fight against
			 the Communist Pathet Lao and North Vietnamese Army regulars in Laos;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the United States relied heavily on the Lao-Hmong Special Guerrilla Units to engage in
			 direct combat with North Vietnamese troops from 1960 to 1975;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the Lao-Hmong conducted tactical guerrilla actions, flew thousands of deadly combat
			 missions in support of the Armed Forces and the <cato:entity-ref entity-id="5600" entity-type="federal-body">Central Intelligence
			 Agency</cato:entity-ref>, and fought in conventional and guerrilla combat clashes with
			 extreme casualties;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the Lao-Hmong, although outnumbered, fought against enemy forces to disrupt the flow of
			 troops and war supplies along the Ho Chi Minh Trail;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the Lao-Hmong protected United States personnel, guarded United States Air Force radar
			 installations, gathered critical intelligence about enemy operations, and
			 undertook rescue missions to save the lives of downed American
			 pilots;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas more than 35,000 of the Lao-Hmong lost their lives, and many more were seriously injured
			 and disabled;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas thousands of Lao-Hmong suffered grievous injuries and permanent disabilities, and thousands
			 more were captured and sent to concentration camps;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas after the conclusion of the war, many Lao-Hmong soldiers were the victims of acts of
			 retribution and atrocities by the Pathet Lao, causing many of the
			 Lao-Hmong to flee to neighboring Thailand and become refugees; and</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas beginning with the City Council of Golden, Colorado, in 1995, various State and local
			 governments have issued proclamations declaring July 22 as <quote>Lao-Hmong Recognition Day</quote>, and the establishment of a <quote>National Lao-Hmong Recognition Day</quote> would recognize the bravery, sacrifice, and loyalty to the United States exhibited by the
			 Lao-Hmong in Southeast Asia: Now, therefore, be it</text>
		</whereas>
  </preamble>
	<resolution-body>
		<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="S1" section-type="undesignated-section">
      <enum/>
      <text>That Congress—</text>
			<paragraph id="H150122923E5140A5893D8BC666A8B9CB">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">expresses support for the designation of <quote>National Lao-Hmong Recognition Day</quote>; and</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFAA7DC99872A434CB46C8B8D18C1804B">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text>requests that the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> issue a proclamation calling upon the people of the United States to
			 observe <quote>National Lao-Hmong Recognition Day</quote> with appropriate ceremonies and activities.</text>
			</paragraph>
    </section>
  </resolution-body>
</resolution>
</doc>