<doc>
  <docmeta id="113s1955is">
    <bill congress="113" type="s" number="1955" version="is"/>
    <revision size="6341" annotations="0" status="complete" id="6" commit-time="2014-02-03T17:24:35Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113s1955is/6.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" public-private="public">
  <metadata>
<dublinCore>
<dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">113 S1955 IS: Knife Owners’ Protection Act of 2014</dc:title>
<dc:publisher xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">2014-01-16</dc:date>
<dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
    <congress>113th CONGRESS</congress>
    <session>2d Session</session>
    <legis-num>S. 1955</legis-num>
    <current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
    <action>
      <action-date date="20140116">January 16, 2014</action-date>
      <action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="S254">Mr. Enzi</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S346">Mr. Lee</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSCM00">Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation</committee-name>
      </action-desc>
    </action>
    <legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
    <official-title>To protect the right of law-abiding citizens to transport knives interstate, notwithstanding a patchwork of local and State prohibitions.</official-title>
  </form>
  <legis-body id="H5B427DAAC9734E86AF20438817808294" style="OLC">
    <section id="H98A0F33E3B55437B8E21677DB6579D01" section-type="section-one">
      <enum>1.</enum>
      <header>Short title</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote>
          <short-title>
            <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Knife Owners’ Protection Act of 2014" proposed="true">Knife Owners’ Protection Act of 2014</cato:entity-ref>
          </short-title>
        </quote>.</text>
    </section>
    <section id="H55BA4A4F34154AC0BD3A4AE6B8067D03">
      <enum>2.</enum>
      <header>Interstate transport of knives</header>
      <subsection id="idA20A94BC8D3343CFAA912D022803BDD7">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Definition</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <term>transport</term>—</text>
        <paragraph id="idF69BF121F46F42818FAD0AAEE1D8B46E">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">includes staying in temporary lodging overnight, common carrier misrouting or delays, stops for food, fuel, vehicle maintenance, emergencies, medical treatment, and any other activity related to the journey of an individual; and</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="id20A18A29329040D092DD169DB10E204E">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">does not include transport of a knife with the intent to commit an offense punishable by imprisonment for a term exceeding 1 year involving the use or threatened use of force against another person, or with knowledge, or reasonable cause to believe, that such an offense is to be committed in the course of, or arising from, the journey.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="id53F10F9440594452B4F1E83258E9BBCD">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Transport of knives</header>
        <paragraph id="idC66913EBE777427089EF9040BC1E58DD">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>In general</header>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, rule, or regulation of the United States, or of a State or political subdivision of a State, an individual who is not otherwise prohibited by Federal law from possessing, transporting, shipping, or receiving a knife may transport a knife from any State or place where the individual may lawfully possess, carry, or transport the knife to any other State or place where the individual may lawfully possess, carry, or transport the knife if—</text>
          <subparagraph id="HBC776AC9EA9B4D44B7B676AB5A163548">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>in the case of transport by motor vehicle, the knife is not directly accessible from the passenger compartment of the motor vehicle, or, in the case of a motor vehicle without a compartment separate from the passenger compartment, the knife is contained in a locked container, glove compartment, or console; or</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H4DE90A7753BB4BC1A7370C0C84F435DE">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of transport by means other than a motor vehicle, including any transport over land, on or through water, or through the air, the knife is contained in a locked container.</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="idD05C6DD4566841F1876C6E08BAA9BFBB">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Temporary lodging</header>
          <text>An individual transporting a knife in accordance with <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Knife Owners’ Protection Act of 2014/s:2/ss:b/p:1" proposed="true">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref> may have a knife accessible while staying in any form of  temporary lodging.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="HBEBADBEB13BF4121BB6D3A9044500AF0">
        <enum>(c)</enum>
        <header>Emergency knives</header>
        <paragraph id="id085F85209B174CD7BA379AD7AFC82002">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>In general</header>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An individual—</text>
          <subparagraph id="id269B052499A04CD1993F829954568698">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">may carry in the passenger compartment of a motor vehicle a knife or tool designed for enabling escape in an emergency that incorporates a blunt tipped safety blade or a guarded blade or both for cutting safety belts; and</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="id9AEBAA1A6AC7414BBBAD562F6DE70EC1">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall not be required to secure a knife or tool described in subparagraph (A) in a locked container, glove compartment, or console.</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="id22995315FCDD4912B47B73CF0766DD03">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Limitation</header>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This subsection shall not apply to the transport of a  knife or tool in the passenger cabin of an aircraft whose passengers are subject to airport screening procedures of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="7013">Transportation Security Administration</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="H7FF468C4A924402B95B3364A55F7F81A">
        <enum>(d)</enum>
        <header>No arrest or detention</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An individual who is transporting a knife in compliance with this section may not be arrested or otherwise detained for violation of any law, rule, or regulation of a State or political subdivision of a State related to the possession, transport, or carrying of a knife, unless there is probable cause to believe that the individual is not in compliance with <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Knife Owners’ Protection Act of 2014/s:2/ss:b" proposed="true">subsection (b)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="HB315B43C8DC14D278C6D996583168972">
        <enum>(e)</enum>
        <header>Claim or defense</header>
        <text>An individual may assert this section as a claim or defense in any civil or criminal action or proceeding. When an individual asserts this section as a claim or defense in a criminal proceeding, the State or political subdivision has the burden of proving, beyond a reasonable doubt, that the individual was not in compliance with <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Knife Owners’ Protection Act of 2014/s:2/ss:b" proposed="true">subsection (b)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="H6A4461DD2D384C7F984AFE02B390C09B">
        <enum>(f)</enum>
        <header>Right of action</header>
        <paragraph id="idE972AD67DC3A46E7AC7EFF905D149570">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>In general</header>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any individual  who, under color of any statute, ordinance, regulation, custom, or usage, of any State or political subdivision of a State, subjects, or causes to be subjected, any individual to the deprivation of the rights, privileges, or immunities provided for in this section, shall be liable to the individual so deprived in an action at law or equity, or other proper proceeding for redress.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="idD36F8CB5E5FE4B4C8D15BC4D68CF3EFB">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Attorney's Fees</header>
          <subparagraph id="id09D91D3C735E4B659BB5A564B608536D">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <header>In general</header>
            <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If an individual asserts this section as a claim or defense, the court shall award to the prevailing party, as described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Knife Owners’ Protection Act of 2014/s:2/ss:f/p:2/sp:B" proposed="true">subparagraph (B)</cato:entity-ref>, reasonable attorney's fees.</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="idA1D66C025AFB4349A24C5F4DD77416C8">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <header>Prevailing party</header>
            <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A prevailing party described in this subparagraph—</text>
            <clause id="id9BB3F4CBDE04487387FBBF5225C6A110">
              <enum>(i)</enum>
              <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">includes a party who receives a favorable resolution through a decision by a court, settlement of a claim, withdrawal of criminal charges, or change of a statute or regulation; and</text>
            </clause>
            <clause id="id60EB3362AFAC48899037843BC0E2F5F3">
              <enum>(ii)</enum>
              <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">does not include a State or political subdivision of a State, or an employee or representative of a State or political subdivision of a State.</text>
            </clause>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="H2C67FC216AE044E4A732360CFF347C98">
        <enum>(g)</enum>
        <header>Rule of construction</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this section shall be construed to limit any right to possess, carry, or transport a knife under applicable State law.</text>
      </subsection>
    </section>
  </legis-body>
</bill>
</doc>