<doc>
  <docmeta id="113s1434is">
    <bill congress="113" type="s" number="1434" version="is"/>
    <revision size="5294" annotations="0" status="complete" id="5" commit-time="2013-08-13T19:48:54Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113s1434is/5.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public">
	<metadata>
<dublinCore>
<title>113 S1434 IS: To designate the Junction City Community-Based Outpatient Clinic located at 715 Southwind Drive, Junction City, Kansas, as the Lieutenant General Richard J. Seitz Community-Based Outpatient Clinic.</title>
<publisher>U.S. Senate</publisher>
<date>2013-08-01</date>
<format>text/xml</format>
<language>EN</language>
<rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
		<congress>113th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. 1434</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20130801">August 1, 2013</action-date>
			<action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="S347">Mr. Moran</sponsor> (for himself
			 and <cosponsor name-id="S260">Mr. Roberts</cosponsor>) introduced the following
			 bill; which was read twice and referred to the
			 <committee-name committee-id="SSVA00">Committee on Veterans'
			 Affairs</committee-name>
      </action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To designate the Junction City Community-Based Outpatient
		  Clinic located at 715 Southwind Drive, Junction City, Kansas, as the Lieutenant
		  General Richard J. Seitz Community-Based Outpatient Clinic.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body>
		<section id="id316D6B65D34340AEAAA6DD2C228AF9BB" section-type="section-one">
      <enum>1.</enum>
      <header>Lieutenant General Richard J.
			 Seitz Community-Based Outpatient Clinic</header>
			<subsection id="idB495E101E5E84AFD96C5E316EDA3B0DA">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Findings</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">
          <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="0001" entity-type="federal-body">Congress</cato:entity-ref> finds that—</text>
				<paragraph id="ide2d9c7a7cdef4f76b4dc0ed9c15a5c9d">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>Lieutenant
			 General Richard J. Seitz served as the cadet commander of a unit of the Reserve
			 Officers’ Training Corps at Leavenworth High School in Leavenworth, Kansas,
			 where he earned the American Legion Cup as an outstanding cadet;</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="id28831ec812b94de58f66096e9559f18f">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>while attending
			 Kansas State University, Lieutenant General Seitz accepted a commission as a
			 second lieutenant in the Army and was called into active duty in 1940;</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="ide684f5cff5e74d74b08c88804c4ec83e">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <text>Lieutenant
			 General Seitz volunteered to be one of the first paratroopers in the United
			 States;</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="id3BB95FEDED9146B6A3F843D8BDBDDC3E">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
          <text>at age 25,
			 Lieutenant General Seitz as a major, was given command of the 2nd Battalion of
			 the 517th Parachute Infantry Regimental Combat Team, becoming the youngest
			 battalion commander in the Army;</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="id4094812f1b104d87b1154c0e37ad0054">
          <enum>(5)</enum>
          <text>along with the
			 7th Armored Division, the battalion commanded by Lieutenant General Seitz
			 formed what became known as Task Force Seitz at the Battle of the Bulge with
			 the mission to plug the gaps on the north slope of the Bulge when the Germans
			 attempted to break out;</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="ide52efc8ecd104c2aa5bd30d04e090ddc">
          <enum>(6)</enum>
          <text>the service of
			 Lieutenant General Seitz earned him the Silver Star, 2 Bronze Stars, the Purple
			 Heart, and many other acknowledgments during his 37-year career in the
			 Army;</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="id850f98827bc947f1b617c064537487c7">
          <enum>(7)</enum>
          <text>after victory in
			 Europe, Lieutenant General Seitz remained in the Army, commanding the 2nd
			 Airborne Battle Group, 503rd Infantry Regiment, and the 82nd Airborne
			 Division;</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="id0316f9c0203846b7a6058a6186afe63c">
          <enum>(8)</enum>
          <text>on retiring in
			 1978, Lieutenant General Seitz settled in Junction City, Kansas, near Ft.
			 Riley, where he would greet deploying and returning units from Iraq and
			 Afghanistan at all times of the day;</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="id6f743e5f346a4dc79fccbecab70623d0">
          <enum>(9)</enum>
          <text>Lieutenant
			 General Seitz remained active in the wider community, working with the Coronado
			 Area Council of the Boy Scouts of America, the Fort Riley National Bank, Rotary
			 International, and the Association of the United States Army and serving on the
			 board of the Eisenhower Presidential Library and Museum;</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="id44a8e2c148144fdd8e53a4997300b4d8">
          <enum>(10)</enum>
          <text>Lieutenant
			 General Seitz had a passion for mentoring young officers and noncommissioned
			 officers at Fort Riley, never ceasing to be a soldier, according to his son,
			 Richard M. Seitz;</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="id7460eb7fdefe422e8635e2a9f01b6121">
          <enum>(11)</enum>
          <text>Lieutenant
			 General Seitz was named an Outstanding Citizen of Kansas;</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="id3E2CB8C0DD4C436A9A513D9ADE56E916">
          <enum>(12)</enum>
          <text>in 2012 an
			 elementary school at Fort Riley was named in honor of Lieutenant General Seitz,
			 which is meaningful because he believed the fate of the United States relied on
			 young children and the teachers who inspire them;</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="idec074752405c4528801c93f0a5716b07">
          <enum>(13)</enum>
          <text>during visits to
			 the elementary school, Lieutenant General Seitz would talk with the students
			 about what it meant to be a <quote>proud and great American</quote> and his
			 message was always to <quote>respect the teachers and be a
			 learner</quote>;</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="idffbac42a67ce4b66b4459497399a7b2c">
          <enum>(14)</enum>
          <text>the family and
			 friends of Lieutenant General Seitz have described him as a gentleman,
			 compassionate, respected, full of integrity, gracious, giving, and a remarkable
			 individual; and</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd0ea01f08b25471da08f5963d6d0d50d">
          <enum>(15)</enum>
          <text>Lieutenant
			 General Seitz lived each day to its fullest and his commitment to his fellow
			 man serves as an inspiration to all the people of the United States.</text>
				</paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="id24D43A32E7F64DE28C3566F3C251E939">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Designation</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Junction City Community-Based
			 Outpatient Clinic located at 715 Southwind Drive, Junction City, Kansas, shall
			 be known and designated as the <term>Lieutenant General Richard J. Seitz
			 Community-Based Outpatient Clinic</term>.</text>
			</subsection>
      <subsection id="id26AC1DD6E2064DE4A2C814E2BF4014D2">
        <enum>(c)</enum>
        <header>References</header>
        <text>Any
			 reference in any law, map, regulation, document, paper, or other record of the
			 United States to the Junction City Community-Based Outpatient Clinic referred
			 to in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" proposed="true" value="113 S 1434/s:1/ss:b" entity-type="act">subsection (b)</cato:entity-ref> shall be deemed to be a reference to the <term>Lieutenant
			 General Richard J. Seitz Community-Based Outpatient Clinic</term>.</text>
			</subsection>
    </section>
  </legis-body>
</bill>
</doc>