<doc>
  <docmeta id="113sres551is">
    <bill congress="113" type="sres" number="551" version="is"/>
    <revision size="2515" annotations="0" status="complete" id="4" commit-time="2014-10-03T17:46:51Z" committer="mnewby" doc="113sres551is/4.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <resolution xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print">
	<metadata>
<dublinCore>
<dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">113 SRES 551 IS: Recognizing September 2014 as “National Campus Safety Awareness Month” and supporting the goals and ideals of National Campus Safety Awareness Month.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">2014-09-17</dc:date>
<dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">113th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session display="yes">2d Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. RES. 551</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20140917" legis-day="20140916">September 17 (legislative day, September 16), 2014</action-date>
			<action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="S352">Mr. Heller</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S153">Mr. Grassley</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name added-display-style="italic" committee-id="SSHR00" deleted-display-style="strikethrough">Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions</committee-name>
      </action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">Recognizing September 2014 as <quote>National Campus Safety Awareness Month</quote> and supporting the goals and ideals of National Campus Safety Awareness Month.</official-title>
	</form>
	<preamble>
		<whereas>
      <text>Whereas people on college and university campuses are not immune from the potential acts of crime
			 that the rest of society in the United States faces;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas men and women deserve to learn in a positive and safe environment free from sexual assault;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas experts estimate that 1 in 5 female undergraduate students will experience sexual assault
			 or attempted sexual assault;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the aggressor in a sexual assault is usually an acquaintance or friend of the victim;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas a majority of sexual assaults are not reported to law enforcement;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the majority of stalking victims are between the ages of 18 and 24 years old;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas approximately 3 in 10 women are injured emotionally or psychologically from being stalked;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the Clery Center for Security on Campus, a nonprofit group dedicated to preventing
			 violence, substance abuse, and other crimes on college and university
			 campuses, has designated September as <quote>National Campus Safety Awareness Month</quote>; and</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas National Campus Safety Awareness Month provides an opportunity for campus communities to
			 become engaged in efforts to improve campus safety:  
    Now, therefore, be it</text>
		</whereas>
  </preamble>
	<resolution-body>
		<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="S1" section-type="undesignated-section">
      <enum/>
      <text>That the <cato:entity-ref entity-id="0010" entity-type="federal-body">Senate</cato:entity-ref>—</text>
			<paragraph id="idCACC6BF0E1854284B3437E66FB2D24D9">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text>supports the goals and ideals of National Campus Safety Awareness Month; and</text>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="id48F049E4A7A14B34ADD8921EE7E397E2">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text>encourages colleges and universities throughout the United States to provide campus safety and
			 other crime awareness and prevention programs to students throughout the
			 year.</text>
			</paragraph>
    </section>
  </resolution-body>
</resolution>
</doc>