<doc>
  <docmeta id="113sres140ats">
    <bill congress="113" type="sres" number="140" version="ats"/>
    <revision size="2903" annotations="0" status="complete" id="3" commit-time="2013-08-11T17:42:57Z" committer="mbohmer" doc="113sres140ats/3.xml">
      <description>Edited via AKN</description>
    </revision>
  </docmeta>
  <resolution xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>113 SRES 140 ATS: Commemorating and acknowledging the dedication and sacrifices made by the Federal, State, and local law enforcement officers who have been killed or injured in the line of duty.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2013-05-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">113th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session display="yes">1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. RES. 140</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20130514">May 14, 2013</action-date>
			<action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="S057">Mr. Leahy</sponsor> (for himself,
			 <cosponsor name-id="S153">Mr. Grassley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S308">Mr. Cardin</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S351">Mr.
			 Toomey</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was considered
			 and agreed to</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">Commemorating and acknowledging the
		  dedication and sacrifices made by the Federal, State, and local law enforcement
		  officers who have been killed or injured in the line of duty.</official-title>
	</form>
	<preamble>
		<whereas>
      <text>Whereas the well-being of all people in the United States
			 is preserved and enhanced as a direct result of the vigilance and dedication of
			 law enforcement officers;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas more than 900,000 men and women, at great risk to
			 their personal safety, serve the people of the United States as guardians of
			 the peace;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas peace officers are on the front lines in
			 protecting the schools and schoolchildren of the United States;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas, in 2012, 120 peace officers across the United
			 States were killed in the line of duty;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> should strongly support initiatives to
			 reduce violent crime and to increase the factors that contribute to the safety
			 of law enforcement officers;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas more than 19,000 Federal, State, and local law
			 enforcement officers whose names are engraved upon the National Law Enforcement
			 Officers Memorial in Washington, District of Columbia, lost their lives in the
			 line of duty while protecting the people of the United States;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas, in 1962, President John F. Kennedy designated May
			 15 as <quote>National Peace Officers Memorial Day</quote>; and</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas, on May 15, 2013, more than 20,000 peace officers
			 are expected to gather in Washington, District of Columbia, to join the
			 families of their recently-fallen comrades to honor those comrades and all
			 others who went before them: Now, therefore, be it</text>
		</whereas>
  </preamble>
	<resolution-body>
		<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="S1" section-type="undesignated-section">
      <enum/>
      <text>That the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0010">Senate</cato:entity-ref>—</text>
			<paragraph id="id91d2d69a4acc45fba3d01f582509563e">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text>commemorates and
			 acknowledges the dedication and sacrifices made by the Federal, State, and
			 local law enforcement officers who have been killed or injured in the line of
			 duty;</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="ida4ffa98376124ef3811ef54d1b4b3751">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text>recognizes May
			 15, 2013, as <quote>National Peace Officers Memorial Day</quote>; and</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="ida47e7112c3794835a012478d4ec9bc91">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <text>calls on the
			 people of the United States to observe National Peace Officers Memorial Day
			 with appropriate ceremony, solemnity, appreciation, and respect.</text>
			</paragraph>
    </section>
  </resolution-body>
</resolution>
</doc>